<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7276b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7276b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7276b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7276b"><akn:num>7276b</akn:num><akn:heading>Integrated resource plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7276b. Integrated resource plans(a) Review by Western Area Power AdministrationWithin 1 year after October 24, 1992, the Administrator shall, by regulation, revise the Final Amended Guidelines and Acceptance Criteria for Customer Conservation and Renewable Energy Programs published in the Federal Register on August 21, 1985 (50 F.R. 33892), or any subsequent amendments thereto, to require each customer to submit an integrated resource plan to the Administrator within 12 months after such regulations are amended. The regulation shall require a revision of such plan to be submitted every 5 years after the initial submission. The Administrator shall review the initial plan in accordance with a schedule established by the Administrator (which schedule will provide for the review of all initial plans within 24 months after such regulations are amended), and each revision thereof within 120 days after his receipt of the plan or revision and determine whether the customer has in the development of the plan or revision, complied with sections 7275 to 7276c of this title. Plan amendments may be submitted to the Administrator at any time and the Administrator shall review each such amendment within 120 days after receipt thereof to determine whether the customer in amending its plan has complied with sections 7275 to 7276c of this title. If the Administrator determines that the customer, in developing its plan, revision, or amendment, has not complied with the requirements of sections 7275 to 7276c of this title, the customer shall resubmit the plan at any time thereafter. Whenever a plan or revision or amendment is resubmitted the Administrator shall review the plan or revision or amendment within 120 days after his receipt thereof to determine whether the customer has complied with sections 7275 to 7276c of this title.


(b) Criteria for approval of integrated resource plansThe Administrator shall approve an integrated resource plan submitted as required under subsection </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7276b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Western Area Power Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Review by Western Area Power Administration Within 1 year after October 24, 1992, the Administrator shall, by regulation, revise the Final Amended Guidelines and Acceptance Criteria for Customer Conservation and Renewable Energy Programs published in the Federal Register on August 21, 1985 (50 F.R. 33892), or any subsequent amendments thereto, to require each customer to submit an integrated resource plan to the Administrator within 12 months after such regulations are amended. The regulation shall require a revision of such plan to be submitted every 5 years after the initial submission. The Administrator shall review the initial plan in accordance with a schedule established by the Administrator (which schedule will provide for the review of all initial plans within 24 months after such regulations are amended), and each revision thereof within 120 days after his receipt of the plan or revision and determine whether the customer has in the development of the plan or revision, com</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7276b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for approval of integrated resource plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria for approval of integrated resource plans The Administrator shall approve an integrated resource plan submitted as required under subsection (a) if, in developing the plan, the customer has:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7276b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of other integrated resource plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of other integrated resource plans Where a customer or group of customers are implementing integrated resource planning under a program responding to Federal, State, or other initiatives, including integrated resource planning considered and implemented pursuant to section 2621(d) of title 16, in evaluating that customer’s integrated resource plan under sections 7275 to 7276c of this title, the Administrator shall accept such plan as fulfillment of the requirements of sections 7275 to 7276c of this title to the extent such plan substantially complies with the requirements of sections 7275 to 7276c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7276b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with integrated resource plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compliance with integrated resource plans Within 1 year after October 24, 1992, the Administrator shall, by regulation, revise the Final Amended Guidelines and Acceptance Criteria for Customer Conservation and Renewable Energy Programs published in the Federal Register on August 21, 1985 (50 F.R. 33892), or any subsequent amendments thereto, to require each customer to fully comply with the applicable integrated resource plan and submit an annual report to the Administrator (in such form and containing such information as the Administrator may require) describing the customer’s progress to the goals established in such plan. After the initial review under subsection (a) the Administrator shall periodically conduct reviews of a representative sample of applicable integrated resource plans and the customer’s implementation of the applicable integrated resource plan to determine if the customers are in compliance with their plans. If the Administrator finds a customer out-of-complianc</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7276b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7276b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integrated resource planning cooperatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Integrated resource planning cooperatives With the approval of the Administrator, customers within any State or region may form integrated resource planning cooperatives for the purposes of complying with sections 7275 to 7276c of this title, and such customers shall be allowed an additional 6 months to submit an initial integrated resource plan to the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7276b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customers with more than 1 contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Customers with more than 1 contract If more than one long-term firm power service contract exists between the Administrator and a customer, only one integrated resource plan shall be required for that customer under sections 7275 to 7276c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7276b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Program review Within 1 year after January 1, 1999, and at appropriate intervals thereafter, the Administrator shall initiate a public process to review the program established by this section. The Administrator is authorized at that time to revise the criteria set forth in subsection (b) to reflect changes, if any, in technology, needs, or other developments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>