<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381c–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381c–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381c–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7381c_1"><akn:num>7381c–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnerships with historically Black colleges and universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, and t</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7381c–1. Partnerships with historically Black colleges and universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, and tribal colleges(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Hispanic-serving institutionThe term “Hispanic-serving institution” has the meaning given the term in section 1101a(a) of title 20.


(2) Historically Black college or universityThe term “historically Black college or university” has the meaning given the term “part B institution” in section 1061 of title 20.


(3) National LaboratoryThe term “National Laboratory” has the meaning given the term in section 15801 of this title.


(4) Science facilityThe term “science facility” has the meaning given the term “single-purpose research facility” in section 16182 of this title.


(5) Tribal collegeThe term “tribal college” has the meaning given the term “tribally controlled college or university” in section 1801(a) of title 25.



(b) Education partnershipThe Secretary shall require the director of each National Laboratory, and may require the head of any science facility, to increase the participation of historically Black colleges or universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, or tribal colleges in any activity that increases the capacity of the historically Black colleges or universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, or tribal colleges to train personnel in science or engineering.


(c) ActivitiesAn activity described in subsection (b) includes—(1) collaborative research;

(2) equipment transfer;

(3) training activities carried out at a National Laboratory or science facility; and

(4) mentoring activities carried out at a National Laboratory or science facility.


(d) ReportNot later than 2 years after August 8, 2005, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the activities carried out under this section.


(Pub. L. 101–510, div. C, title XXXI, § 3167, as added Pub. L. 109–58, title XI, § 1105(b)(2), Aug. 8, 2005, 119 Stat. 940; amended Pub. L. 110–315, title IX, § 941(k)(2)(M), Aug. 14, 200</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381c_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381c_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education partnership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Education partnership The Secretary shall require the director of each National Laboratory, and may require the head of any science facility, to increase the participation of historically Black colleges or universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, or tribal colleges in any activity that increases the capacity of the historically Black colleges or universities, Hispanic-serving institutions, or tribal colleges to train personnel in science or engineering.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381c_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities An activity described in subsection (b) includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381c_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than 2 years after August 8, 2005, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the activities carried out under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>