<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7381n"><akn:num>7381n</akn:num><akn:heading>Summer institutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7381n. Summer institutes(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible partnerThe term “eligible partner” means—(A) the science, engineering, or mathematics department at an institution of higher education, acting in coordination with a school, department, or program of education at an institution of higher education that provides training for teachers and principals; or

(B) a nonprofit entity with expertise in providing professional development for science, technology, engineering, or mathematics teachers.


(2) Summer instituteThe term “summer institute” means an institute, operated during the summer, that—(A) is hosted by a National Laboratory or an eligible partner;

(B) is operated for a period of not less than 2 weeks;

(C) includes, as a component, a program that provides direct interaction between students and faculty, including personnel of 1 or more National Laboratories who have scientific expertise;

(D) provides for follow-up training, during the academic year, that is conducted in the classroom; and

(E) provides hands-on science, technology, engineering, or mathematics laboratory experience for not less than 2 days.



(b) Summer institute programs authorized(1) Programs at the National LaboratoriesThe Secretary, acting through the Director, shall establish or expand programs of summer institutes at each of the National Laboratories to provide additional training to strengthen the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics teaching skills of teachers employed at public schools for kindergarten through grade 12, in accordance with the activities authorized under paragraphs (3) and (4).


(2) Programs with eligible partners(A) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director, shall identify and provide assistance as described in subparagraph (C) to eligible partners to establish or expand programs of summer institutes that provide additional training to strengthen the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics teaching skills of teache</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Summer institute programs authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Summer institute programs authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority To the maximum extent practicable, the Director shall ensure that each summer institute program authorized under subsection (b) provides training to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination and consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination and consultation The Director shall consult and coordinate with the Secretary of Education and the Director of the National Science Foundation regarding the implementation of the programs authorized under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381n_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and accountability plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation and accountability plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381n_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>