<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7381a"><akn:num>7381a</akn:num><akn:heading>Science education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7381a. Science education programs(a) ProgramsThe Secretary is authorized to establish programs to enhance the quality of mathematics, science, and engineering education. Any such programs shall be operated at or through the support of Department research and development facilities, shall use the scientific resources of the Department, and shall be consistent with the overall Federal plan for education and human resources in science and technology developed by the Federal Coordinating Council for Science, Engineering, and Technology.


(b) Organization of science, engineering, and mathematics education programs(1) Director of Science, Engineering, and Mathematics EducationNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Science (referred to in this subsection as the “Under Secretary”), shall appoint a Director of Science, Engineering, and Mathematics Education (referred to in this subsection as the “Director”) with the principal responsibility for administering science, engineering, and mathematics education programs across all functions of the Department.


(2) QualificationsThe Director shall be an individual, who by reason of professional background and experience, is specially qualified to advise the Under Secretary on all matters pertaining to science, engineering, and mathematics education at the Department.


(3) DutiesThe Director shall—(A) oversee all science, engineering, and mathematics education programs of the Department;

(B) represent the Department as the principal interagency liaison for all science, engineering, and mathematics education programs, unless otherwise represented by the Secretary or the Under Secretary;

(C) prepare the annual budget and advise the Under Secretary on all budgetary issues for science, engineering, and mathematics education programs of the Department;

(D) increase, to the maximum extent practicable, the participation and advancement of women and underrepresented minoriti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Programs The Secretary is authorized to establish programs to enhance the quality of mathematics, science, and engineering education. Any such programs shall be operated at or through the support of Department research and development facilities, shall use the scientific resources of the Department, and shall be consistent with the overall Federal plan for education and human resources in science and technology developed by the Federal Coordinating Council for Science, Engineering, and Technology.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization of science, engineering, and mathematics education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Organization of science, engineering, and mathematics education programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other Department activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Relationship to other Department activities The programs described in subsection (a) shall supplement and be coordinated with current activities of the Department, but shall not supplant them.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Science, Engineering, and Mathematics Education Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Science, Engineering, and Mathematics Education Fund The Secretary shall establish a Science, Engineering, and Mathematics Education Fund, using not less than 0.3 percent of the amount made available to the Department for research, development, demonstration, and commercial application for each fiscal year, to carry out sections 7381b, 7381c, and 7381c–1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual plan for allocation of education funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual plan for allocation of education funding The Secretary shall submit to Congress as part of the annual budget submission for a fiscal year a report describing the manner in which the Department has complied with subsection (d) for the prior fiscal year and the manner in which the Department proposes to comply with subsection (d) during the following fiscal year, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs for students from under-represented groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Programs for students from under-represented groups In carrying out a program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to activities that are designed to encourage students from under-represented groups to pursue scientific and technical careers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>