<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7381b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7381b"><akn:num>7381b</akn:num><akn:heading>Laboratory cooperative science centers and other authorized education activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7381b. Laboratory cooperative science centers and other authorized education activities(a) ActivitiesThe Secretary is authorized to:(1) Support research appointments for college and university science and engineering students, and for faculty-student teams, at Department research and development facilities.

(2) Support research appointments for high school science teachers at Department research and development facilities.

(3) Support research apprenticeship appointments at Department research and development facilities for students underrepresented in science and technology careers.

(4) Support research experience programs at Department research and development facilities for nationally selected high school honor students.

(5) Operate mathematics and science education programs for elementary and secondary students at Department research and development facilities.

(6) Establish a museum-based science education program.

(7) Establish collaborative inner-city and rural partnership programs designed to meet the special mathematics and science education needs of students in inner-city and rural areas.

(8) Provide paid administrative leave for employees of the Department or Department research and development facilities who volunteer to interact with schools, colleges, universities, teachers, or students for the purpose of science, mathematics, and engineering education.

(9) Establish a talent pool of volunteer scientists, mathematicians, and engineers who have retired from the Department or Department research and development facilities to serve at schools and school districts for the purpose of (A) assisting teachers, with activities such as experiments, lectures, or the preparation of materials; (B) serving as counselors to students on science, mathematics, and engineering; and (C) otherwise assisting science, mathematics, and engineering classes. The Secretary, acting through Department research and development facilities, shall, wherever possible, identif</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Activities The Secretary is authorized to:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of facilities Any of the activities authorized by subsection (a) may be conducted through Department research and development facilities. The Secretary may designate facilities conducting such education activities as “Laboratory Cooperative Science Centers”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7381b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funding The Secretary is authorized to accept non-Federal funds to finance education activities described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>