<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7383" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7383/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7383/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7383"><akn:num>7383</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission on Safeguards, Security, and Counterintelligence at Department of Energy Facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7383. Commission on Safeguards, Security, and Counterintelligence at Department of Energy Facilities(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established a commission to be known as the Commission on Safeguards, Security, and Counterintelligence at Department of Energy Facilities (in this section referred to as the “Commission”).


(b) Membership and organization(1) The Commission shall be composed of nine members appointed from among individuals in the public and private sectors who have significant experience in matters related to the security of nuclear weapons and materials, the classification of information, or counterintelligence matters, as follows:(A) Two shall be appointed by the chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, in consultation with the ranking member of that Committee.

(B) One shall be appointed by the ranking member of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, in consultation with the chairman of that Committee.

(C) Two shall be appointed by the chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the ranking member of that Committee.

(D) One shall be appointed by the ranking member of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the chairman of that Committee.

(E) One shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense.

(F) One shall be appointed by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.

(G) One shall be appointed by the Director of Central Intelligence.


(2) Members of the Commission shall be appointed for four year terms, except as follows:(A) One member initially appointed under paragraph (1)(A) shall serve a term of two years, to be designated at the time of appointment.

(B) One member initially appointed under paragraph (1)(C) shall serve a term of two years, to be designated at the time of appointment.

(C) The member initially appointed under paragraph (1)(E) shall serve a term of two years.


(3) Any vacancy in the Commis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7383_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established a commission to be known as the Commission on Safeguards, Security, and Counterintelligence at Department of Energy Facilities (in this section referred to as the “Commission”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7383_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership and organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership and organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7383_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7383_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7383_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Personnel matters</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7383_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicability of chapter 10 of title 5 The provisions of chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the activities of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7383_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>