<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7384n"><akn:num>7384n</akn:num><akn:heading>Exposure in the performance of duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7384n. Exposure in the performance of duty(a) BerylliumA covered beryllium employee shall, in the absence of substantial evidence to the contrary, be determined to have been exposed to beryllium in the performance of duty for the purposes of the compensation program if, and only if, the covered beryllium employee was—(1) employed at a Department of Energy facility; or

(2) present at a Department of Energy facility, or a facility owned and operated by a beryllium vendor, because of employment by the United States, a beryllium vendor, or a contractor or subcontractor of the Department of Energy,


during a period when beryllium dust, particles, or vapor may have been present at such facility.

(b) CancerAn individual with cancer specified in subclause (I), (II), or (III) of section 7384l(9)(B)(ii) of this title shall be determined to have sustained that cancer in the performance of duty for purposes of the compensation program if, and only if, the cancer specified in that subclause was at least as likely as not related to employment at the facility specified in that subclause, as determined in accordance with the guidelines established under subsection (c).


(c) Guidelines(1) For purposes of the compensation program, the President shall by regulation establish guidelines for making the determinations required by subsection (b).

(2) The President shall establish such guidelines after technical review by the Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health under section 7384o of this title.

(3) Such guidelines shall—(A) be based on the radiation dose received by the employee (or a group of employees performing similar work) at such facility and the upper 99 percent confidence interval of the probability of causation in the radioepidemiological tables published under section 7(b) of the Orphan Drug Act (42 U.S.C. 241 note), as such tables may be updated under section 7(b)(3) of such Act from time to time;

(B) incorporate the methods established under subsection (d); </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Beryllium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Beryllium A covered beryllium employee shall, in the absence of substantial evidence to the contrary, be determined to have been exposed to beryllium in the performance of duty for the purposes of the compensation program if, and only if, the covered beryllium employee was— during a period when beryllium dust, particles, or vapor may have been present at such facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cancer An individual with cancer specified in subclause (I), (II), or (III) of section 7384l(9)(B)(ii) of this title shall be determined to have sustained that cancer in the performance of duty for purposes of the compensation program if, and only if, the cancer specified in that subclause was at least as likely as not related to employment at the facility specified in that subclause, as determined in accordance with the guidelines established under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methods for radiation dose reconstructions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Methods for radiation dose reconstructions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384n_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on radiation doses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Information on radiation doses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>