<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384u" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384u/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384u/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7384u"><akn:num>7384u</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate treatment of certain uranium employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7384u. Separate treatment of certain uranium employees(a) Compensation providedAn individual who receives, or has received, $100,000 under section 5 of the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act (42 U.S.C. 2210 note) for a claim made under that Act (hereafter in this section referred to as a “covered uranium employee”), or the survivor of that covered uranium employee if the employee is deceased, shall receive compensation under this section in the amount of $50,000.


(b) Medical benefitsA covered uranium employee shall receive medical benefits under section 7384t of this title for the illness for which that employee received $100,000 under section 5 of that Act.


(c) Coordination with RECAThe compensation and benefits provided in subsections (a) and (b) are separate from any compensation or benefits provided under that Act.


(d) Payment from compensation fundThe compensation provided under this section and the compensation provided under section 5 of the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act, when authorized or approved by the President, shall be paid from the compensation fund established under section 7384e of this title.


(e) Payments in the case of deceased persons(1) In the case of a covered employee who is deceased at the time of payment of compensation under this section, whether or not the death is the result of the covered employee’s occupational illness, such payment may be made only as follows:(A) If the covered employee is survived by a spouse who is living at the time of payment, such payment shall be made to such surviving spouse.

(B) If there is no surviving spouse described in subparagraph (A), such payment shall be made in equal shares to all children of the covered employee who are living at the time of payment.

(C) If there is no surviving spouse described in subparagraph (A) and if there are no children described in subparagraph (B), such payment shall be made in equal shares to the parents of the covered employee who are living at the time o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384u_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compensation provided An individual who receives, or has received, $100,000 under section 5 of the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act (42 U.S.C. 2210 note) for a claim made under that Act (hereafter in this section referred to as a “covered uranium employee”), or the survivor of that covered uranium employee if the employee is deceased, shall receive compensation under this section in the amount of $50,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384u_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Medical benefits A covered uranium employee shall receive medical benefits under section 7384t of this title for the illness for which that employee received $100,000 under section 5 of that Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384u_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with RECA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination with RECA The compensation and benefits provided in subsections (a) and (b) are separate from any compensation or benefits provided under that Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384u_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment from compensation fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment from compensation fund The compensation provided under this section and the compensation provided under section 5 of the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act, when authorized or approved by the President, shall be paid from the compensation fund established under section 7384e of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384u_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments in the case of deceased persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payments in the case of deceased persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384u_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Procedures required The President shall establish procedures to identify and notify each covered uranium employee, or the survivor of that covered uranium employee if that employee is deceased, of the availability of compensation and benefits under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384u_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effective date This section shall take effect on July 31, 2001, unless Congress otherwise provides in an Act enacted before that date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>