<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7384s"><akn:num>7384s</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and benefits to be provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7384s. Compensation and benefits to be provided(a) Compensation provided(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), a covered employee, or the survivor of that covered employee if the employee is deceased, shall receive compensation for the disability or death of that employee from that employee’s occupational illness in the amount of $150,000.

(2) A covered employee shall, to the extent that employee’s occupational illness is established beryllium sensitivity, receive beryllium sensitivity monitoring under subsection (c) in lieu of compensation under paragraph (1).


(b) Medical benefitsA covered employee shall receive medical benefits under section 7384t of this title for that employee’s occupational illness.


(c) Beryllium sensitivity monitoringAn individual receiving beryllium sensitivity monitoring under this subsection shall receive the following:(1) A thorough medical examination to confirm the nature and extent of the individual’s established beryllium sensitivity.

(2) Regular medical examinations thereafter to determine whether that individual has developed established chronic beryllium disease.


(d) Payment from compensation fundThe compensation provided under this section, when authorized or approved by the President, shall be paid from the compensation fund established under section 7384e of this title.


(e) Payments in the case of deceased persons(1) In the case of a covered employee who is deceased at the time of payment of compensation under this section, whether or not the death is the result of the covered employee’s occupational illness, such payment may be made only as follows:(A) If the covered employee is survived by a spouse who is living at the time of payment, such payment shall be made to such surviving spouse.

(B) If there is no surviving spouse described in subparagraph (A), such payment shall be made in equal shares to all children of the covered employee who are living at the time of payment.

(C) If there is no surviving spouse des</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384s_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compensation provided</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Medical benefits A covered employee shall receive medical benefits under section 7384t of this title for that employee’s occupational illness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384s_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Beryllium sensitivity monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Beryllium sensitivity monitoring An individual receiving beryllium sensitivity monitoring under this subsection shall receive the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384s_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment from compensation fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment from compensation fund The compensation provided under this section, when authorized or approved by the President, shall be paid from the compensation fund established under section 7384e of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384s_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments in the case of deceased persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payments in the case of deceased persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384s_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective date This section shall take effect on July 31, 2001, unless Congress otherwise provides in an Act enacted before that date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>