<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7384q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7384q"><akn:num>7384q</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of additional members of special exposure cohort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7384q. Designation of additional members of special exposure cohort(a) Advice on additional members(1) The Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health under section 7384o of this title shall advise the President whether there is a class of employees at any Department of Energy facility who likely were exposed to radiation at that facility but for whom it is not feasible to estimate with sufficient accuracy the radiation dose they received.

(2) The advice of the Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health under paragraph (1) shall be based on exposure assessments by radiation health professionals, information provided by the Department of Energy, and such other information as the Advisory Board considers appropriate.

(3) The President shall request advice under paragraph (1) after consideration of petitions by classes of employees described in that paragraph for such advice. The President shall consider such petitions pursuant to procedures established by the President.


(b) Designation of additional membersSubject to the provisions of section 7384l(14)(C) of this title, the members of a class of employees at a Department of Energy facility, or at an atomic weapons employer facility, may be treated as members of the Special Exposure Cohort for purposes of the compensation program if the President, upon recommendation of the Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health, determines that—(1) it is not feasible to estimate with sufficient accuracy the radiation dose that the class received; and

(2) there is a reasonable likelihood that such radiation dose may have endangered the health of members of the class.


(c) Deadlines(1) Not later than 180 days after the date on which the President receives a petition for designation as members of the Special Exposure Cohort, the Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health shall submit to the Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health a recommendation on that petition, including all support</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advice on additional members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Advice on additional members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of additional members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation of additional members Subject to the provisions of section 7384l(14)(C) of this title, the members of a class of employees at a Department of Energy facility, or at an atomic weapons employer facility, may be treated as members of the Special Exposure Cohort for purposes of the compensation program if the President, upon recommendation of the Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health, determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadlines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deadlines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7384q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Access to information The Secretary of Energy shall provide, in accordance with law, the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the members and staff of the Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health access to relevant information on worker exposures, including access to Restricted Data (as defined in section 2014(y) of this title.11 So in original. A closing parenthesis should probably follow “title”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>