<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385s–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385s–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385s–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7385s_4"><akn:num>7385s–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations regarding contraction of covered illnesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7385s–4. Determinations regarding contraction of covered illnesses(a) Cases determined under part BA determination under part B that a Department of Energy contractor employee is entitled to compensation under that part for an occupational illness shall be treated for purposes of this part as a determination that the employee contracted that illness through exposure at a Department of Energy facility.


(b) Cases determined under former part DIn the case of a covered illness of an employee with respect to which a panel has made a positive determination under section 7385o(d) of this title and the Secretary of Energy has accepted that determination under section 7385o(e)(2) of this title, or with respect to which a panel has made a negative determination under section 7385o(d) of this title and the Secretary of Energy has found significant evidence to the contrary under section 7385o(e)(2) of this title, that determination shall be treated for purposes of this part as a determination that the employee contracted the covered illness through exposure at a Department of Energy facility.


(c) Other cases(1) In any other case, a Department of Energy contractor employee shall be determined for purposes of this part to have contracted a covered illness through exposure at a Department of Energy facility if—(A) it is at least as likely as not that exposure to a toxic substance at a Department of Energy facility was a significant factor in aggravating, contributing to, or causing the illness; and

(B) it is at least as likely as not that the exposure to such toxic substance was related to employment at a Department of Energy facility.


(2) A determination under paragraph (1) shall be made by the Secretary.


(d) Applications by spouses and childrenIf a spouse or child of a Department of Energy contractor employee applies for benefits under this part, the Secretary shall make a determination under this section with respect to that employee without regard to whether the spo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cases determined under part B</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cases determined under part B A determination under part B that a Department of Energy contractor employee is entitled to compensation under that part for an occupational illness shall be treated for purposes of this part as a determination that the employee contracted that illness through exposure at a Department of Energy facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cases determined under former part D</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cases determined under former part D In the case of a covered illness of an employee with respect to which a panel has made a positive determination under section 7385o(d) of this title and the Secretary of Energy has accepted that determination under section 7385o(e)(2) of this title, or with respect to which a panel has made a negative determination under section 7385o(d) of this title and the Secretary of Energy has found significant evidence to the contrary under section 7385o(e)(2) of this title, that determination shall be treated for purposes of this part as a determination that the employee contracted the covered illness through exposure at a Department of Energy facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other cases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications by spouses and children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applications by spouses and children If a spouse or child of a Department of Energy contractor employee applies for benefits under this part, the Secretary shall make a determination under this section with respect to that employee without regard to whether the spouse is a “covered spouse”, or the child is a “covered child”, under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>