<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385s–16" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385s–16/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385s–16/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7385s_16"><akn:num>7385s–16</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Board on Toxic Substances and Worker Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7385s–16. Advisory Board on Toxic Substances and Worker Health(a) Establishment(1) Not later than 120 days after December 19, 2014, the President shall establish and appoint an Advisory Board on Toxic Substances and Worker Health (in this section referred to as the “Board”).

(2) The President shall make appointments to the Board in consultation with organizations with expertise on worker health issues in order to ensure that the membership of the Board reflects a proper balance of perspectives from the scientific, medical, and claimant communities.

(3) The President shall designate a Chair of the Board from among its members.


(b) DutiesThe Board shall—(1) advise the Secretary of Labor with respect to—(A) the site exposure matrices of the Department of Labor;

(B) medical guidance for claims examiners for claims under this part with respect to the weighing of the medical evidence of claimants;

(C) evidentiary requirements for claims under part B related to lung disease;

(D) the work of industrial hygienists and staff physicians and consulting physicians of the Department and reports of such hygienists and physicians to ensure quality, objectivity, and consistency;

(E) the claims adjudication process generally, including review of procedure manual changes prior to incorporation into the manual and claims for medical benefits; and

(F) such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate; and


(2) coordinate exchanges of data and findings with the Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health established under section 7384o of this title to the extent necessary.


(c) Staff and powers(1) The President shall appoint a staff to facilitate the work of the Board. The staff of the Board shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed under subchapter VIII of chapter 33 of title 5.

(2) The President may authorize the detail of employees of Federal agencies to the Board as necessary to enable the Board to carry out its duties under this section. The deta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Board shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff and powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Staff and powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflicts of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conflicts of interest No member, employee, or contractor of the Board shall have any financial interest, employment, or contractual relationship (other than a routine consumer transaction) with any person that has provided, or sought to provide during the two years preceding the appointment or during the service of the member, employee, or contractor under this section, goods or services related to medical benefits under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Expenses Members of the Board, other than full-time employees of the United States, while attending meetings of the Board or while otherwise serving at the request of the President, and while serving away from their homes or regular places of business, shall be allowed travel and meal expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence (as authorized by section 5703 of title 5) for individuals in the Federal Government serving without pay.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security clearances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Security clearances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Information The Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Labor shall each, in accordance with law, provide to the Board and the contractors of the Board, access to any information that the Board considers relevant to carry out its responsibilities under this section, including information such as Restricted Data (as defined in section 2014(y) of this title) and information covered by section 552a of title 5 (commonly known as the “Privacy Act”). The Secretary of Labor shall make available to the Board the program’s medical director, toxicologist, industrial hygienist and program’s support contractors as requested by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response to recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Response to recommendations Not later than 60 days after submission to the Secretary of Labor of the Board’s recommendations, the Secretary shall respond to the Board in writing, and post on the public internet website of the Department of Labor, a response to the recommendations that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_16_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Sunset The Board shall terminate on the date that is 15 years after December 19, 2014.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>