<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385j–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385j–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385j–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7385j_2"><akn:num>7385j–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery and waiver of overpayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7385j–2. Recovery and waiver of overpayments(a) In generalWhen an overpayment has been made to an individual under this subchapter because of an error of fact or law, recovery shall be made under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Labor by decreasing later payments to which the individual is entitled. If the individual dies before the recovery is completed, recovery shall be made by decreasing later benefits payable under this subchapter with respect to the individual’s death.


(b) WaiverRecovery by the United States under this section may not be made when incorrect payment has been made to an individual who is without fault and when adjustment or recovery would defeat the purpose of this subchapter or would be against equity and good conscience.


(c) LiabilityA certifying or disbursing official is not liable for an amount certified or paid by him when recovery of the amount is waived under subsection (b) of this section, or when recovery under subsection (a) of this section is not completed before the death of all individuals against whose benefits deductions are authorized.


(Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. C, title XXXVI, § 3653], as added Pub. L. 108–375, div. C, title XXXI, § 3163(c), Oct. 28, 2004, 118 Stat. 2187.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385j_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general When an overpayment has been made to an individual under this subchapter because of an error of fact or law, recovery shall be made under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Labor by decreasing later payments to which the individual is entitled. If the individual dies before the recovery is completed, recovery shall be made by decreasing later benefits payable under this subchapter with respect to the individual’s death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385j_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Waiver Recovery by the United States under this section may not be made when incorrect payment has been made to an individual who is without fault and when adjustment or recovery would defeat the purpose of this subchapter or would be against equity and good conscience.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385j_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Liability A certifying or disbursing official is not liable for an amount certified or paid by him when recovery of the amount is waived under subsection (b) of this section, or when recovery under subsection (a) of this section is not completed before the death of all individuals against whose benefits deductions are authorized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>