<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385s–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385s–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7385s–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7385s_7"><akn:num>7385s–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Physicians services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7385s–7. Physicians services(a) In generalThe Secretary may utilize the services of physicians for purposes of making determinations under this part.


(b) PhysiciansAny physicians whose services are utilized under subsection (a) of this section shall possess appropriate expertise and experience in the evaluation and determination of the extent of permanent physical impairments or in the evaluation and diagnosis of illnesses or deaths aggravated, contributed to, or caused by exposure to toxic substances.


(c) ArrangementThe Secretary may secure the services of physicians utilized under subsection (a) of this section through the appointment of physicians or by contract.


(Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. C, title XXXVI, § 3678], as added Pub. L. 108–375, div. C, title XXXI, § 3161, Oct. 28, 2004, 118 Stat. 2182.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may utilize the services of physicians for purposes of making determinations under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physicians</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Physicians Any physicians whose services are utilized under subsection (a) of this section shall possess appropriate expertise and experience in the evaluation and determination of the extent of permanent physical impairments or in the evaluation and diagnosis of illnesses or deaths aggravated, contributed to, or caused by exposure to toxic substances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7385s_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Arrangement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Arrangement The Secretary may secure the services of physicians utilized under subsection (a) of this section through the appointment of physicians or by contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>