<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7405" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7405/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7405/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7405"><akn:num>7405</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for support of air pollution planning and control programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7405. Grants for support of air pollution planning and control programs(a) Amounts; limitations; assurances of plan development capability(1)(A) The Administrator may make grants to air pollution control agencies, within the meaning of paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), or (5) of section 7602 of this title, in an amount up to three-fifths of the cost of implementing programs for the prevention and control of air pollution or implementation of national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards. For the purpose of this section, “implementing” means any activity related to the planning, developing, establishing, carrying-out, improving, or maintaining of such programs.

(B) Subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, an air pollution control agency which receives a grant under subparagraph (A) and which contributes less than the required two-fifths minimum shall have 3 years following November 15, 1990, in which to contribute such amount. If such an agency fails to meet and maintain this required level, the Administrator shall reduce the amount of the Federal contribution accordingly.

(C) With respect to any air quality control region or portion thereof for which there is an applicable implementation plan under section 7410 of this title, grants under subparagraph (A) may be made only to air pollution control agencies which have substantial responsibilities for carrying out such applicable implementation plan.


(2) Before approving any grant under this subsection to any air pollution control agency within the meaning of sections 7602(b)(2) and 7602(b)(4) of this title, the Administrator shall receive assurances that such agency provides for adequate representation of appropriate State, interstate, local, and (when appropriate) international, interests in the air quality control region.

(3) Before approving any planning grant under this subsection to any air pollution control agency within the meaning of sections 7602(b)(2) and 7602(b)(4) of this title</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7405_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts; limitations; assurances of plan development capability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amounts; limitations; assurances of plan development capability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7405_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions; regulations; factors for consideration; State expenditure limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions; regulations; factors for consideration; State expenditure limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7405_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maintenance of effort</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7405_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of payments; availability of reduced amounts; reduced amount as deemed paid to agency for purpose of determining amount of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reduction of payments; availability of reduced amounts; reduced amount as deemed paid to agency for purpose of determining amount of grant The Administrator, with the concurrence of any recipient of a grant under this section, may reduce the payments to such recipient by the amount of the pay, allowances, traveling expenses, and any other costs in connection with the detail of any officer or employee to the recipient under section 7601 of this title, when such detail is for the convenience of, and at the request of, such recipient and for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter. The amount by which such payments have been reduced shall be available for payment of such costs by the Administrator, but shall, for the purpose of determining the amount of any grant to a recipient under subsection (a) of this section, be deemed to have been paid to such agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7405_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and opportunity for hearing when affected by adverse action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice and opportunity for hearing when affected by adverse action No application by a State for a grant under this section may be disapproved by the Administrator without prior notice and opportunity for a public hearing in the affected State, and no commitment or obligation of any funds under any such grant may be revoked or reduced without prior notice and opportunity for a public hearing in the affected State (or in one of the affected States if more than one State is affected).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>