<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7409" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7409/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7409/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7409"><akn:num>7409</akn:num><akn:heading>National primary and secondary ambient air quality standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7409. National primary and secondary ambient air quality standards(a) Promulgation(1) The Administrator—(A) within 30 days after December 31, 1970, shall publish proposed regulations prescribing a national primary ambient air quality standard and a national secondary ambient air quality standard for each air pollutant for which air quality criteria have been issued prior to such date; and

(B) after a reasonable time for interested persons to submit written comments thereon (but no later than 90 days after the initial publication of such proposed standards) shall by regulation promulgate such proposed national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards with such modifications as he deems appropriate.


(2) With respect to any air pollutant for which air quality criteria are issued after December 31, 1970, the Administrator shall publish, simultaneously with the issuance of such criteria and information, proposed national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards for any such pollutant. The procedure provided for in paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection shall apply to the promulgation of such standards.


(b) Protection of public health and welfare(1) National primary ambient air quality standards, prescribed under subsection (a) shall be ambient air quality standards the attainment and maintenance of which in the judgment of the Administrator, based on such criteria and allowing an adequate margin of safety, are requisite to protect the public health. Such primary standards may be revised in the same manner as promulgated.

(2) Any national secondary ambient air quality standard prescribed under subsection (a) shall specify a level of air quality the attainment and maintenance of which in the judgment of the Administrator, based on such criteria, is requisite to protect the public welfare from any known or anticipated adverse effects associated with the presence of such air pollutant in the ambient air. Such secondary standards may be revised in t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7409_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Promulgation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7409_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of public health and welfare</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Protection of public health and welfare</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7409_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National primary ambient air quality standard for nitrogen dioxide</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National primary ambient air quality standard for nitrogen dioxide The Administrator shall, not later than one year after August 7, 1977, promulgate a national primary ambient air quality standard for NO2 concentrations over a period of not more than 3 hours unless, based on the criteria issued under section 7408(c) of this title, he finds that there is no significant evidence that such a standard for such a period is requisite to protect public health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7409_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and revision of criteria and standards; independent scientific review committee; appointment; advisory functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review and revision of criteria and standards; independent scientific review committee; appointment; advisory functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>