<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7410" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7410/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7410/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7410"><akn:num>7410</akn:num><akn:heading>State implementation plans for national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7410. State implementation plans for national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards(a) Adoption of plan by State; submission to Administrator; content of plan; revision; new sources; indirect source review program; supplemental or intermittent control systems(1) Each State shall, after reasonable notice and public hearings, adopt and submit to the Administrator, within 3 years (or such shorter period as the Administrator may prescribe) after the promulgation of a national primary ambient air quality standard (or any revision thereof) under section 7409 of this title for any air pollutant, a plan which provides for implementation, maintenance, and enforcement of such primary standard in each air quality control region (or portion thereof) within such State. In addition, such State shall adopt and submit to the Administrator (either as a part of a plan submitted under the preceding sentence or separately) within 3 years (or such shorter period as the Administrator may prescribe) after the promulgation of a national ambient air quality secondary standard (or revision thereof), a plan which provides for implementation, maintenance, and enforcement of such secondary standard in each air quality control region (or portion thereof) within such State. Unless a separate public hearing is provided, each State shall consider its plan implementing such secondary standard at the hearing required by the first sentence of this paragraph.

(2) Each implementation plan submitted by a State under this chapter shall be adopted by the State after reasonable notice and public hearing. Each such plan shall—(A) include enforceable emission limitations and other control measures, means, or techniques (including economic incentives such as fees, marketable permits, and auctions of emissions rights), as well as schedules and timetables for compliance, as may be necessary or appropriate to meet the applicable requirements of this chapter;

(B) provide for establishment and ope</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of plan by State; submission to Administrator; content of plan; revision; new sources; indirect source review program; supplemental or intermittent control systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Adoption of plan by State; submission to Administrator; content of plan; revision; new sources; indirect source review program; supplemental or intermittent control systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of period for submission of plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Extension of period for submission of plans The Administrator may, wherever he determines necessary, extend the period for submission of any plan or portion thereof which implements a national secondary ambient air quality standard for a period not to exceed 18 months from the date otherwise required for submission of such plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation and publication by Administrator of proposed regulations setting forth implementation plan; transportation regulations study and report; parking surcharge; suspension authority; plan implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preparation and publication by Administrator of proposed regulations setting forth implementation plan; transportation regulations study and report; parking surcharge; suspension authority; plan implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (e) Repealed. Pub. L. 101–549, title I, § 101(d)(4), (5), Nov. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 2409</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) , (e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>National or regional energy emergencies; determination by President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) National or regional energy emergencies; determination by President</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governor’s authority to issue temporary emergency suspensions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Governor’s authority to issue temporary emergency suspensions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of comprehensive document for each State setting forth requirements of applicable implementation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Publication of comprehensive document for each State setting forth requirements of applicable implementation plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of requirements prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Modification of requirements prohibited Except for a primary nonferrous smelter order under section 7419 of this title, a suspension under subsection (f) or (g) (relating to emergency suspensions), an exemption under section 7418 of this title (relating to certain Federal facilities), an order under section 7413(d) 1 of this title (relating to compliance orders), a plan promulgation under subsection (c), or a plan revision under subsection (a)(3); no order, suspension, plan revision, or other action modifying any requirement of an applicable implementation plan may be taken with respect to any stationary source by the State or by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technological systems of continuous emission reduction on new or modified stationary sources; compliance with performance standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Technological systems of continuous emission reduction on new or modified stationary sources; compliance with performance standards As a condition for issuance of any permit required under this subchapter, the owner or operator of each new or modified stationary source which is required to obtain such a permit must show to the satisfaction of the permitting authority that the technological system of continuous emission reduction which is to be used at such source will enable it to comply with the standards of performance which are to apply to such source and that the construction or modification and operation of such source will be in compliance with all other requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7410_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Protection Agency action on plan submissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) Environmental Protection Agency action on plan submissions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>