<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7411" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7411/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7411/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7411"><akn:num>7411</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards of performance for new stationary sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7411. Standards of performance for new stationary sources(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) The term “standard of performance” means a standard for emissions of air pollutants which reflects the degree of emission limitation achievable through the application of the best system of emission reduction which (taking into account the cost of achieving such reduction and any nonair quality health and environmental impact and energy requirements) the Administrator determines has been adequately demonstrated.

(2) The term “new source” means any stationary source, the construction or modification of which is commenced after the publication of regulations (or, if earlier, proposed regulations) prescribing a standard of performance under this section which will be applicable to such source.

(3) The term “stationary source” means any building, structure, facility, or installation which emits or may emit any air pollutant. Nothing in subchapter II of this chapter relating to nonroad engines shall be construed to apply to stationary internal combustion engines.

(4) The term “modification” means any physical change in, or change in the method of operation of, a stationary source which increases the amount of any air pollutant emitted by such source or which results in the emission of any air pollutant not previously emitted.

(5) The term “owner or operator” means any person who owns, leases, operates, controls, or supervises a stationary source.

(6) The term “existing source” means any stationary source other than a new source.

(7) The term “technological system of continuous emission reduction” means—(A) a technological process for production or operation by any source which is inherently low-polluting or nonpolluting, or

(B) a technological system for continuous reduction of the pollution generated by a source before such pollution is emitted into the ambient air, including precombustion cleaning or treatment of fuels.


(8) A conversion to coal (A) by rea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of categories of stationary sources; standards of performance; information on pollution control techniques; sources owned or operated by United States; particular systems; revised standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) List of categories of stationary sources; standards of performance; information on pollution control techniques; sources owned or operated by United States; particular systems; revised standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State implementation and enforcement of standards of performance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State implementation and enforcement of standards of performance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards of performance for existing sources; remaining useful life of source</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Standards of performance for existing sources; remaining useful life of source</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibited acts After the effective date of standards of performance promulgated under this section, it shall be unlawful for any owner or operator of any new source to operate such source in violation of any standard of performance applicable to such source.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>New source standards of performance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) New source standards of performance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Revision of regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Design, equipment, work practice, or operational standard; alternative emission limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Design, equipment, work practice, or operational standard; alternative emission limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Country elevators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Country elevators Any regulations promulgated by the Administrator under this section applicable to grain elevators shall not apply to country elevators (as defined by the Administrator) which have a storage capacity of less than two million five hundred thousand bushels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7411_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Innovative technological systems of continuous emission reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Innovative technological systems of continuous emission reduction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>