<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7420" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7420/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7420/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7420"><akn:num>7420</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncompliance penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7420. Noncompliance penalty(a) Assessment and collection(1)(A) Not later than 6 months after August 7, 1977, and after notice and opportunity for a public hearing, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations requiring the assessment and collection of a noncompliance penalty against persons referred to in paragraph (2)(A).

(B)(i) Each State may develop and submit to the Administrator a plan for carrying out this section in such State. If the Administrator finds that the State plan meets the requirements of this section, he may delegate to such State any authority he has to carry out this section.

(ii) Notwithstanding a delegation to a State under clause (i), the Administrator may carry out this section in such State under the circumstances described in subsection (b)(2)(B).



(2)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B) or (C) of this paragraph, the State or the Administrator shall assess and collect a noncompliance penalty against every person who owns or operates—(i) a major stationary source (other than a primary nonferrous smelter which has received a primary nonferrous smelter order under section 7419 of this title), which is not in compliance with any emission limitation, emission standard or compliance schedule under any applicable implementation plan (whether or not such source is subject to a Federal or State consent decree), or

(ii) a stationary source which is not in compliance with an emission limitation, emission standard, standard of performance, or other requirement established under section 7411, 7477, 7603, or 7412 of this title, or

(iii) a stationary source which is not in compliance with any requirement of subchapter IV–A, V, or VI of this chapter, or

(iv) any source referred to in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) (for which an extension, order, or suspension referred to in subparagraph (B), or Federal or State consent decree is in effect), or a primary nonferrous smelter which has received a primary nonferrous smelter order under section 741</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7420_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment and collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessment and collection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7420_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations Regulations under subsection (a) shall— In any case in which the State establishes a noncompliance penalty under this section, the State shall provide notice thereof to the Administrator. A noncompliance penalty established by a State under this section shall apply unless the Administrator, within ninety days after the date of receipt of notice of the State penalty assessment under this section, objects in writing to the amount of the penalty as less than would be required to comply with guidelines established by the Administrator. If the Administrator objects, he shall immediately establish a substitute noncompliance penalty applicable to such source.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7420_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract to assist in determining amount of penalty assessment or payment schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contract to assist in determining amount of penalty assessment or payment schedule If the owner or operator of any stationary source to whom a notice is issued under subsection (b)(3)— fails to submit a calculation of the penalty assessment, a schedule for payment, and the information necessary for independent verification thereof, the State (or the Administrator, as the case may be) may enter into a contract with any person who has no financial interest in the owner or operator of the source (or in any person controlling, controlled by or under common control with such source) to assist in determining the amount of the penalty assessment or payment schedule with respect to such source. The cost of carrying out such contract may be added to the penalty to be assessed against the owner or operator of such source.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7420_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7420_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Judicial review Any action pursuant to this section, including any objection of the Administrator under the last sentence of subsection (b), shall be considered a final action for purposes of judicial review of any penalty under section 7607 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7420_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other orders, payments, sanctions, or requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other orders, payments, sanctions, or requirements Any orders, payments, sanctions, or other requirements under this section shall be in addition to any other permits, orders, payments, sanctions, or other requirements established under this chapter, and shall in no way affect any civil or criminal enforcement proceedings brought under any provision of this chapter or State or local law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7420_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>More stringent emission limitations or other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) More stringent emission limitations or other requirements In the case of any emission limitation or other requirement approved or promulgated by the Administrator under this chapter after August 7, 1977, which is more stringent than the emission limitation or requirement for the source in effect prior to such approval or promulgation, if any, or where there was no emission limitation or requirement approved or promulgated before August 7, 1977, the date for imposition of the non-compliance penalty under this section, shall be either July 1, 1979, or the date on which the source is required to be in full compliance with such emission limitation or requirement, whichever is later, but in no event later than three years after the approval or promulgation of such emission limitation or requirement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>