<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7424" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7424/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7424/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7424"><akn:num>7424</akn:num><akn:heading>Assurance of adequacy of State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7424. Assurance of adequacy of State plans(a) State review of implementation plans which relate to major fuel burning sourcesAs expeditiously as practicable but not later than one year after August 7, 1977, each State shall review the provisions of its implementation plan which relate to major fuel burning sources and shall determine—(1) the extent to which compliance with requirements of such plan is dependent upon the use by major fuel burning stationary sources of petroleum products or natural gas,

(2) the extent to which such plan may reasonably be anticipated to be inadequate to meet the requirements of this chapter in such State on a reliable and long-term basis by reason of its dependence upon the use of such fuels, and

(3) the extent to which compliance with the requirements of such plan is dependent upon use of coal or coal derivatives which is not locally or regionally available.


Each State shall submit the results of its review and its determination under this paragraph to the Administrator promptly upon completion thereof.

(b) Plan revision(1) Not later than eighteen months after August 7, 1977, the Administrator shall review the submissions of the States under subsection (a) and shall require each State to revise its plan if, in the judgment of the Administrator, such plan revision is necessary to assure that such plan will be adequate to assure compliance with the requirements of this chapter in such State on a reliable and long-term basis, taking into account the actual or potential prohibitions on use of petroleum products or natural gas, or both, under any other authority of law.

(2) Before requiring a plan revision under this subsection, with respect to any State the Administrator shall take into account the report of the review conducted by such State under paragraph (1) and shall consult with the Governor of the State respecting such required revision.


(July 14, 1955, ch. 360, title I, § 124, as added Pub. L. 95–95, title I, § 122, Aug.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7424_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State review of implementation plans which relate to major fuel burning sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State review of implementation plans which relate to major fuel burning sources As expeditiously as practicable but not later than one year after August 7, 1977, each State shall review the provisions of its implementation plan which relate to major fuel burning sources and shall determine— Each State shall submit the results of its review and its determination under this paragraph to the Administrator promptly upon completion thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7424_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Plan revision</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>