<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7432" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7432/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7432/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7432"><akn:num>7432</akn:num><akn:heading>Clean heavy-duty vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7432. Clean heavy-duty vehicles(a) Appropriations(1) In generalIn addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Administrator for fiscal year 2022, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $600,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2031, to carry out this section.


(2) Nonattainment areasIn addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Administrator for fiscal year 2022, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $400,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2031, to make awards under this section to eligible recipients and to eligible contractors that propose to replace eligible vehicles to serve 1 or more communities located in an air quality area designated pursuant to section 7407 of this title as nonattainment for any air pollutant.


(3) ReservationOf the funds appropriated by paragraph (1), the Administrator shall reserve 3 percent for administrative costs necessary to carry out this section.



(b) ProgramBeginning not later than 180 days after August 16, 2022, the Administrator shall implement a program to make awards of grants and rebates to eligible recipients, and to make awards of contracts to eligible contractors for providing rebates, for up to 100 percent of costs for—(1) the incremental costs of replacing an eligible vehicle that is not a zero-emission vehicle with a zero-emission vehicle, as determined by the Administrator based on the market value of the vehicles;

(2) purchasing, installing, operating, and maintaining infrastructure needed to charge, fuel, or maintain zero-emission vehicles;

(3) workforce development and training to support the maintenance, charging, fueling, and operation of zero-emission vehicles; and

(4) planning and technical activities to support the adoption and deployment of zero-emission vehicles.


(c) ApplicationsTo seek an award under this section, an eligible recipient or eligible contractor shall submit to th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program Beginning not later than 180 days after August 16, 2022, the Administrator shall implement a program to make awards of grants and rebates to eligible recipients, and to make awards of contracts to eligible contractors for providing rebates, for up to 100 percent of costs for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications To seek an award under this section, an eligible recipient or eligible contractor shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator shall prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>