<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7433" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7433/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7433/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7433"><akn:num>7433</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to reduce air pollution at ports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7433. Grants to reduce air pollution at ports(a) Appropriations(1) General assistanceIn addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Administrator for fiscal year 2022, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $2,250,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2027, to award rebates and grants to eligible recipients on a competitive basis—(A) to purchase or install zero-emission port equipment or technology for use at, or to directly serve, one or more ports;

(B) to conduct any relevant planning or permitting in connection with the purchase or installation of such zero-emission port equipment or technology; and

(C) to develop qualified climate action plans.


(2) Nonattainment areasIn addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Administrator for fiscal year 2022, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $750,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2027, to award rebates and grants to eligible recipients to carry out activities described in paragraph (1) with respect to ports located in air quality areas designated pursuant to section 7407 of this title as nonattainment for an air pollutant.



(b) LimitationFunds awarded under this section shall not be used by any recipient or subrecipient to purchase or install zero-emission port equipment or technology that will not be located at, or directly serve, the one or more ports involved.


(c) Administration of fundsOf the funds made available by this section, the Administrator shall reserve 2 percent for administrative costs necessary to carry out this section.


(d) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible recipientThe term “eligible recipient” means—(A) a port authority;

(B) a State, regional, local, or Tribal agency that has jurisdiction over a port authority or a port;

(C) an air pollution control agency; or

(D) a private entity that—(i) applies for a grant under this section in partnership with an entity d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7433_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7433_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation Funds awarded under this section shall not be used by any recipient or subrecipient to purchase or install zero-emission port equipment or technology that will not be located at, or directly serve, the one or more ports involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7433_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration of funds Of the funds made available by this section, the Administrator shall reserve 2 percent for administrative costs necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7433_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>