<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7474" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7474/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7474/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7474"><akn:num>7474</akn:num><akn:heading>Area redesignation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7474. Area redesignation(a) Authority of States to redesignate areasExcept as otherwise provided under subsection (c), a State may redesignate such areas as it deems appropriate as class I areas. The following areas may be redesignated only as class I or II:(1) an area which exceeds ten thousand acres in size and is a national monument, a national primitive area, a national preserve, a national recreation area, a national wild and scenic river, a national wildlife refuge, a national lakeshore or seashore, and

(2) a national park or national wilderness area established after August 7, 1977, which exceeds ten thousand acres in size.


The extent of the areas referred to in paragraph 11 So in original. Probably should be “paragraphs”. (1) and (2) shall conform to any changes in the boundaries of such areas which have occurred subsequent to August 7, 1977, or which may occur subsequent to November 15, 1990. Any area (other than an area referred to in paragraph (1) or (2) or an area established as class I under the first sentence of section 7472(a) of this title) may be redesignated by the State as class III if—
(A) such redesignation has been specifically approved by the Governor of the State, after consultation with the appropriate Committees of the legislature if it is in session or with the leadership of the legislature if it is not in session (unless State law provides that such redesignation must be specifically approved by State legislation) and if general purpose units of local government representing a majority of the residents of the area so redesignated enact legislation (including for such units of local government resolutions where appropriate) concurring in the State’s redesignation;

(B) such redesignation will not cause, or contribute to, concentrations of any air pollutant which exceed any maximum allowable increase or maximum allowable concentration permitted under the classification of any other area; and

(C) such redesignation otherwise meets the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7474_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of States to redesignate areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of States to redesignate areas Except as otherwise provided under subsection (c), a State may redesignate such areas as it deems appropriate as class I areas. The following areas may be redesignated only as class I or II: The extent of the areas referred to in paragraph 11 So in original. Probably should be “paragraphs”. (1) and (2) shall conform to any changes in the boundaries of such areas which have occurred subsequent to August 7, 1977, or which may occur subsequent to November 15, 1990. Any area (other than an area referred to in paragraph (1) or (2) or an area established as class I under the first sentence of section 7472(a) of this title) may be redesignated by the State as class III if— Subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not apply to area redesignations by Indian tribes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7474_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and hearing; notice to Federal land manager; written comments and recommendations; regulations; disapproval of redesignation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice and hearing; notice to Federal land manager; written comments and recommendations; regulations; disapproval of redesignation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7474_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian reservations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Indian reservations Lands within the exterior boundaries of reservations of federally recognized Indian tribes may be redesignated only by the appropriate Indian governing body. Such Indian governing body shall be subject in all respect to the provisions of subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7474_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of national monuments, primitive areas, and national preserves</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of national monuments, primitive areas, and national preserves The Federal Land Manager shall review all national monuments, primitive areas, and national preserves, and shall recommend any appropriate areas for redesignation as class I where air quality related values are important attributes of the area. The Federal Land Manager shall report such recommendations, within 22 So in original. Probably should be “with”. supporting analysis, to the Congress and the affected States within one year after August 7, 1977. The Federal Land Manager shall consult with the appropriate States before making such recommendations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7474_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolution of disputes between State and Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Resolution of disputes between State and Indian tribes If any State affected by the redesignation of an area by an Indian tribe or any Indian tribe affected by the redesignation of an area by a State disagrees with such redesignation of any area, or if a permit is proposed to be issued for any new major emitting facility proposed for construction in any State which the Governor of an affected State or governing body of an affected Indian tribe determines will cause or contribute to a cumulative change in air quality in excess of that allowed in this part within the affected State or tribal reservation, the Governor or Indian ruling body may request the Administrator to enter into negotiations with the parties involved to resolve such dispute. If requested by any State or Indian tribe involved, the Administrator shall make a recommendation to resolve the dispute and protect the air quality related values of the lands involved. If the parties involved do not reach agreement, the Admi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>