<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7492" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7492/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7492/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7492"><akn:num>7492</akn:num><akn:heading>Visibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7492. Visibility(a) Studies(1) The Administrator, in conjunction with the National Park Service and other appropriate Federal agencies, shall conduct research to identify and evaluate sources and source regions of both visibility impairment and regions that provide predominantly clean air in class I areas. A total of $8,000,000 per year for 5 years is authorized to be appropriated for the Environmental Protection Agency and the other Federal agencies to conduct this research. The research shall include—(A) expansion of current visibility related monitoring in class I areas;

(B) assessment of current sources of visibility impairing pollution and clean air corridors;

(C) adaptation of regional air quality models for the assessment of visibility;

(D) studies of atmospheric chemistry and physics of visibility.


(2) Based on the findings available from the research required in subsection (a)(1) as well as other available scientific and technical data, studies, and other available information pertaining to visibility source-receptor relationships, the Administrator shall conduct an assessment and evaluation that identifies, to the extent possible, sources and source regions of visibility impairment including natural sources as well as source regions of clear air for class I areas. The Administrator shall produce interim findings from this study within 3 years after November 15, 1990.


(b) Impacts of other provisionsWithin 24 months after November 15, 1990, the Administrator shall conduct an assessment of the progress and improvements in visibility in class I areas that are likely to result from the implementation of the provisions of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 other than the provisions of this section. Every 5 years thereafter the Administrator shall conduct an assessment of actual progress and improvement in visibility in class I areas. The Administrator shall prepare a written report on each assessment and transmit copies of these reports to the appropr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7492_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Studies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7492_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impacts of other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Impacts of other provisions Within 24 months after November 15, 1990, the Administrator shall conduct an assessment of the progress and improvements in visibility in class I areas that are likely to result from the implementation of the provisions of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 other than the provisions of this section. Every 5 years thereafter the Administrator shall conduct an assessment of actual progress and improvement in visibility in class I areas. The Administrator shall prepare a written report on each assessment and transmit copies of these reports to the appropriate committees of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7492_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of visibility transport regions and commissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of visibility transport regions and commissions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7492_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of visibility transport commissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties of visibility transport commissions A Visibility Transport Commission—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7492_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duties of Administrator</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7492_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grand Canyon visibility transport commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grand Canyon visibility transport commission The Administrator pursuant to subsection (c)(1) shall, within 12 months, establish a visibility transport commission for the region affecting the visibility of the Grand Canyon National Park.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>