<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7511b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7511b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7511b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7511b"><akn:num>7511b</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal ozone measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7511b. Federal ozone measures(a) Control techniques guidelines for VOC sourcesWithin 3 years after November 15, 1990, the Administrator shall issue control techniques guidelines, in accordance with section 7408 of this title, for 11 categories of stationary sources of VOC emissions for which such guidelines have not been issued as of November 15, 1990, not including the categories referred to in paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (b) of this section. The Administrator may issue such additional control techniques guidelines as the Administrator deems necessary.


(b) Existing and new CTGS(1) Within 36 months after November 15, 1990, and periodically thereafter, the Administrator shall review and, if necessary, update control technique guidance issued under section 7408 of this title before November 15, 1990.

(2) In issuing the guidelines the Administrator shall give priority to those categories which the Administrator considers to make the most significant contribution to the formation of ozone air pollution in ozone nonattainment areas, including hazardous waste treatment, storage, and disposal facilities which are permitted under subtitle C of the Solid Waste Disposal Act [42 U.S.C. 6921 et seq.]. Thereafter the Administrator shall periodically review and, if necessary, revise such guidelines.

(3) Within 3 years after November 15, 1990, the Administrator shall issue control techniques guidelines in accordance with section 7408 of this title to reduce the aggregate emissions of volatile organic compounds into the ambient air from aerospace coatings and solvents. Such control techniques guidelines shall, at a minimum, be adequate to reduce aggregate emissions of volatile organic compounds into the ambient air from the application of such coatings and solvents to such level as the Administrator determines may be achieved through the adoption of best available control measures. Such control technology guidance shall provide for such reductions in such increments </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7511b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control techniques guidelines for VOC sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Control techniques guidelines for VOC sources Within 3 years after November 15, 1990, the Administrator shall issue control techniques guidelines, in accordance with section 7408 of this title, for 11 categories of stationary sources of VOC emissions for which such guidelines have not been issued as of November 15, 1990, not including the categories referred to in paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (b) of this section. The Administrator may issue such additional control techniques guidelines as the Administrator deems necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7511b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing and new CTGS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Existing and new CTGS</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7511b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative control techniques</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Alternative control techniques Within 3 years after November 15, 1990, the Administrator shall issue technical documents which identify alternative controls for all categories of stationary sources of volatile organic compounds and oxides of nitrogen which emit, or have the potential to emit 25 tons per year or more of such air pollutant. The Administrator shall revise and update such documents as the Administrator determines necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7511b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance for evaluating cost-effectiveness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Guidance for evaluating cost-effectiveness Within 1 year after November 15, 1990, the Administrator shall provide guidance to the States to be used in evaluating the relative cost-effectiveness of various options for the control of emissions from existing stationary sources of air pollutants which contribute to nonattainment of the national ambient air quality standards for ozone.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7511b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control of emissions from certain sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Control of emissions from certain sources</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7511b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tank vessel standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Tank vessel standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7511b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ozone design value study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Ozone design value study The Administrator shall conduct a study of whether the methodology in use by the Environmental Protection Agency as of November 15, 1990, for establishing a design value for ozone provides a reasonable indicator of the ozone air quality of ozone nonattainment areas. The Administrator shall obtain input from States, local subdivisions thereof, and others. The study shall be completed and a report submitted to Congress not later than 3 years after November 15, 1990. The results of the study shall be subject to peer and public review before submitting it to Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7511b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vehicles entering ozone nonattainment areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Vehicles entering ozone nonattainment areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>