<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7512" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7512/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7512/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7512"><akn:num>7512</akn:num><akn:heading>Classification and attainment dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7512. Classification and attainment dates(a) Classification by operation of law and attainment dates for nonattainment areas(1) Each area designated nonattainment for carbon monoxide pursuant to section 7407(d) of this title shall be classified at the time of such designation under table 1, by operation of law, as a Moderate Area or a Serious Area based on the design value for the area. The design value shall be calculated according to the interpretation methodology issued by the Administrator most recently before November 15, 1990. For each area classified under this subsection, the primary standard attainment date for carbon monoxide shall be as expeditiously as practicable but not later than the date provided in table 1:








TABLE 3 1


AreaclassificationDesign valuePrimary standard attainment date


Moderate9.1–16.4 ppmDecember 31, 1995
Serious16.5 and aboveDecember 31, 2000


1 So in original. Probably should be “TABLE 1”.

(2) At the time of publication of the notice required under section 7407 of this title (designating carbon monoxide nonattainment areas), the Administrator shall publish a notice announcing the classification of each such carbon monoxide nonattainment area. The provisions of section 7502(a)(1)(B) of this title (relating to lack of notice-and-comment and judicial review) shall apply with respect to such classification.

(3) If an area classified under paragraph (1), table 1, would have been classified in another category if the design value in the area were 5 percent greater or 5 percent less than the level on which such classification was based, the Administrator may, in the Administrator’s discretion, within 90 days after November 15, 1990, by the procedure required under paragraph (2), adjust the classification of the area. In making such adjustment, the Administrator may consider the number of exceedances of the national primary ambient air quality standard for carbon monoxide in the area, the level of pollution transport between th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7512_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classification by operation of law and attainment dates for nonattainment areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Classification by operation of law and attainment dates for nonattainment areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7512_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>New designations and reclassifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) New designations and reclassifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7512_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>References to terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) References to terms Any reference in this subpart to a “Moderate Area” or a “Serious Area” shall be considered a reference to a Moderate Area or a Serious Area, respectively, as classified under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>