<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7513a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7513a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7513a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7513a"><akn:num>7513a</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan provisions and schedules for plan submissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7513a. Plan provisions and schedules for plan submissions(a) Moderate Areas(1) Plan provisionsEach State in which all or part of a Moderate Area is located shall submit, according to the applicable schedule under paragraph (2), an implementation plan that includes each of the following:(A) For the purpose of meeting the requirements of section 7502(c)(5) of this title, a permit program providing that permits meeting the requirements of section 7503 of this title are required for the construction and operation of new and modified major stationary sources of PM–10.

(B) Either (i) a demonstration (including air quality modeling) that the plan will provide for attainment by the applicable attainment date; or (ii) a demonstration that attainment by such date is impracticable.

(C) Provisions to assure that reasonably available control measures for the control of PM–10 shall be implemented no later than December 10, 1993, or 4 years after designation in the case of an area classified as moderate after November 15, 1990.


(2) Schedule for plan submissionsA State shall submit the plan required under subparagraph (1) no later than the following:(A) Within 1 year of November 15, 1990, for areas designated nonattainment under section 7407(d)(4) of this title, except that the provision required under subparagraph (1)(A) shall be submitted no later than June 30, 1992.

(B) 18 months after the designation as nonattainment, for those areas designated nonattainment after the designations prescribed under section 7407(d)(4) of this title.



(b) Serious Areas(1) Plan provisionsIn addition to the provisions submitted to meet the requirements of paragraph 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (a)(1) (relating to Moderate Areas), each State in which all or part of a Serious Area is located shall submit an implementation plan for such area that includes each of the following:(A) A demonstration (including air quality modeling)—(i) that the plan provides for attainment </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7513a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Moderate Areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Moderate Areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7513a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Serious Areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Serious Areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7513a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Milestones</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Milestones</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7513a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to attain</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Failure to attain In the case of a Serious PM–10 nonattainment area in which the PM–10 standard is not attained by the applicable attainment date, the State in which such area is located shall, after notice and opportunity for public comment, submit within 12 months after the applicable attainment date, plan revisions which provide for attainment of the PM–10 air quality standard and, from the date of such submission until attainment, for an annual reduction in PM–10 or PM–10 precursor emissions within the area of not less than 5 percent of the amount of such emissions as reported in the most recent inventory prepared for such area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7513a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>PM–10 precursors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) PM–10 precursors The control requirements applicable under plans in effect under this part for major stationary sources of PM–10 shall also apply to major stationary sources of PM–10 precursors, except where the Administrator determines that such sources do not contribute significantly to PM–10 levels which exceed the standard in the area. The Administrator shall issue guidelines regarding the application of the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>