<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7521" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7521/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7521/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7521"><akn:num>7521</akn:num><akn:heading>Emission standards for new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7521. Emission standards for new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines(a) Authority of Administrator to prescribe by regulationExcept as otherwise provided in subsection (b)—(1) The Administrator shall by regulation prescribe (and from time to time revise) in accordance with the provisions of this section, standards applicable to the emission of any air pollutant from any class or classes of new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines, which in his judgment cause, or contribute to, air pollution which may reasonably be anticipated to endanger public health or welfare. Such standards shall be applicable to such vehicles and engines for their useful life (as determined under subsection (d), relating to useful life of vehicles for purposes of certification), whether such vehicles and engines are designed as complete systems or incorporate devices to prevent or control such pollution.

(2) Any regulation prescribed under paragraph (1) of this subsection (and any revision thereof) shall take effect after such period as the Administrator finds necessary to permit the development and application of the requisite technology, giving appropriate consideration to the cost of compliance within such period.

(3)(A) In general.—(i) Unless the standard is changed as provided in subparagraph (B), regulations under paragraph (1) of this subsection applicable to emissions of hydrocarbons, carbon monoxide, oxides of nitrogen, and particulate matter from classes or categories of heavy-duty vehicles or engines manufactured during or after model year 1983 shall contain standards which reflect the greatest degree of emission reduction achievable through the application of technology which the Administrator determines will be available for the model year to which such standards apply, giving appropriate consideration to cost, energy, and safety factors associated with the application of such technology.

(ii) In establishing classes or categories of vehicles or engines for purp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Administrator to prescribe by regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Administrator to prescribe by regulation Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emissions of carbon monoxide, hydrocarbons, and oxides of nitrogen; annual report to Congress; waiver of emission standards; research objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Emissions of carbon monoxide, hydrocarbons, and oxides of nitrogen; annual report to Congress; waiver of emission standards; research objectives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Feasibility study and investigation by National Academy of Sciences; reports to Administrator and Congress; availability of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Feasibility study and investigation by National Academy of Sciences; reports to Administrator and Congress; availability of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Useful life of vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Useful life of vehicles The Administrator shall prescribe regulations under which the useful life of vehicles and engines shall be determined for purposes of subsection (a)(1) of this section and section 7541 of this title. Such regulations shall provide that except where a different useful life period is specified in this subchapter useful life shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>New power sources or propulsion systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) New power sources or propulsion systems In the event of a new power source or propulsion system for new motor vehicles or new motor vehicle engines is submitted for certification pursuant to section 7525(a) of this title, the Administrator may postpone certification until he has prescribed standards for any air pollutants emitted by such vehicle or engine which in his judgment cause, or contribute to, air pollution which may reasonably be anticipated to endanger the public health or welfare but for which standards have not been prescribed under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>44 Another subsec. (f) is set out after subsec. (m). High altitude regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Light-duty trucks up to 6,000 lbs. GVWR and light-duty vehicles; standards for model years after 1993</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Light-duty trucks up to 6,000 lbs. GVWR and light-duty vehicles; standards for model years after 1993</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Light-duty trucks of more than 6,000 lbs. GVWR; standards for model years after 1995</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Light-duty trucks of more than 6,000 lbs. GVWR; standards for model years after 1995 Effective with respect to the model year 1996 and thereafter, the regulations under subsection (a) applicable to emissions of nonmethane hydrocarbons (NMHC), carbon monoxide (CO), oxides of nitrogen (NOx), and particulate matter (PM) from light-duty trucks (LDTs) of more than 6,000 lbs. gross vehicle weight rating (GVWR) shall contain standards which provide that emissions from a specified percentage of each manufacturer’s sales volume of such trucks shall comply with the levels specified in table H. The specified percentage shall be 50 percent in model year 1996 and 100 percent thereafter.













table h—emission standards for nmhc and co from gasoline and diesel fueled light-duty trucks of more than 6,000 lbs. gvwr


LDT Test weightColumn AColumn B

(5 yrs/50,000 mi)(11 yrs/120,000 mi)

NMHCCONOxNMHCCONOxPM


Standards are expressed in grams per mile (GPM).


For standards under column A, f</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase II study for certain light-duty vehicles and light-duty trucks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Phase II study for certain light-duty vehicles and light-duty trucks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7521_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cold CO standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cold CO standard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>