<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7525" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7525/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7525/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7525"><akn:num>7525</akn:num><akn:heading>Motor vehicle and motor vehicle engine compliance testing and certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7525. Motor vehicle and motor vehicle engine compliance testing and certification(a) Testing and issuance of certificate of conformity(1) The Administrator shall test, or require to be tested in such manner as he deems appropriate, any new motor vehicle or new motor vehicle engine submitted by a manufacturer to determine whether such vehicle or engine conforms with the regulations prescribed under section 7521 of this title. If such vehicle or engine conforms to such regulations, the Administrator shall issue a certificate of conformity upon such terms, and for such period (not in excess of one year), as he may prescribe. In the case of any original equipment manufacturer (as defined by the Administrator in regulations promulgated before November 15, 1990) of vehicles or vehicle engines whose projected sales in the United States for any model year (as determined by the Administrator) will not exceed 300, the Administrator shall not require, for purposes of determining compliance with regulations under section 7521 of this title for the useful life of the vehicle or engine, operation of any vehicle or engine manufactured during such model year for more than 5,000 miles or 160 hours, respectively, unless the Administrator, by regulation, prescribes otherwise. The Administrator shall apply any adjustment factors that the Administrator deems appropriate to assure that each vehicle or engine will comply during its useful life (as determined under section 7521(d) of this title) with the regulations prescribed under section 7521 of this title.

(2) The Administrator shall test any emission control system incorporated in a motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine submitted to him by any person, in order to determine whether such system enables such vehicle or engine to conform to the standards required to be prescribed under section 7521(b) of this title. If the Administrator finds on the basis of such tests that such vehicle or engine conforms to such standards, the Adminis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7525_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing and issuance of certificate of conformity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Testing and issuance of certificate of conformity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7525_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing procedures; hearing; judicial review; additional evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Testing procedures; hearing; judicial review; additional evidence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7525_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inspection For purposes of enforcement of this section, officers or employees duly designated by the Administrator, upon presenting appropriate credentials to the manufacturer or person in charge, are authorized (1) to enter, at reasonable times, any plant or other establishment of such manufacturer, for the purpose of conducting tests of vehicles or engines in the hands of the manufacturer, or (2) to inspect, at reasonable times, records, files, papers, processes, controls, and facilities used by such manufacturer in conducting tests under regulations of the Administrator. Each such inspection shall be commenced and completed with reasonable promptness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7525_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rules and regulations The Administrator shall by regulation establish methods and procedures for making tests under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7525_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of test results</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Publication of test results The Administrator shall make available to the public the results of his tests of any motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine submitted by a manufacturer under subsection (a) as promptly as possible after December 31, 1970, and at the beginning of each model year which begins thereafter. Such results shall be described in such nontechnical manner as will reasonably disclose to prospective ultimate purchasers of new motor vehicles and new motor vehicle engines the comparative performance of the vehicles and engines tested in meeting the standards prescribed under section 7521 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7525_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>High altitude regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) High altitude regulations All light duty 11 So in original. Probably should be “light-duty”. vehicles and engines manufactured during or after model year 1984 and all light-duty trucks manufactured during or after model year 1995 shall comply with the requirements of section 7521 of this title regardless of the altitude at which they are sold.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7525_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonconformance penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nonconformance penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7525_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and revision of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Review and revision of regulations Within 18 months after November 15, 1990, the Administrator shall review and revise as necessary the regulations under subsection 33 So in original. Probably should be “subsections”. (a) and (b) of this section regarding the testing of motor vehicles and motor vehicle engines to insure that vehicles are tested under circumstances which reflect the actual current driving conditions under which motor vehicles are used, including conditions relating to fuel, temperature, acceleration, and altitude.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>