<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7546" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7546/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7546/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7546"><akn:num>7546</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable fuel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7546. Renewable fuel(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Municipal solid wasteThe term “municipal solid waste” has the meaning given the term “solid waste” in section 6903 of this title.


(2) RFG StateThe term “RFG State” means a State in which is located one or more covered areas (as defined in section 7545(k)(10)(D) of this title).


(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.



(b) Cellulosic biomass ethanol and municipal solid waste loan guarantee program(1) In generalFunds may be provided for the cost (as defined in the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (2 U.S.C. 661 et seq.)) of loan guarantees issued under title XIV of the Energy Policy Act 11 See References in Text note below. to carry out commercial demonstration projects for celluosic 22 So in original. biomass and sucrose-derived ethanol.


(2) Demonstration projects(A) In generalThe Secretary shall issue loan guarantees under this section to carry out not more than 4 projects to commercially demonstrate the feasibility and viability of producing cellulosic biomass ethanol or sucrose-derived ethanol, including at least 1 project that uses cereal straw as a feedstock and 1 project that uses municipal solid waste as a feedstock.


(B) Design capacityEach project shall have a design capacity to produce at least 30,000,000 gallons of cellulosic biomass ethanol each year.



(3) Applicant assurancesAn applicant for a loan guarantee under this section shall provide assurances, satisfactory to the Secretary, that—(A) the project design has been validated through the operation of a continuous process facility with a cumulative output of at least 50,000 gallons of ethanol;

(B) the project has been subject to a full technical review;

(C) the project is covered by adequate project performance guarantees;

(D) the project, with the loan guarantee, is economically viable; and

(E) there is a reasonable assurance of repayment of the guaranteed loan.


(4) Limitations(A) Maximum guaranteeExcept </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7546_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7546_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cellulosic biomass ethanol and municipal solid waste loan guarantee program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cellulosic biomass ethanol and municipal solid waste loan guarantee program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7546_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for resource center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations for resource center There is authorized to be appropriated, for a resource center to further develop bioconversion technology using low-cost biomass for the production of ethanol at the Center for Biomass-Based Energy at the Mississippi State University and the Oklahoma State University, $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2007.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7546_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable fuel production research and development grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Renewable fuel production research and development grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7546_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cellulosic biomass ethanol conversion assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cellulosic biomass ethanol conversion assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>