<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7549" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7549/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7549/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7549"><akn:num>7549</akn:num><akn:heading>High altitude performance adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7549. High altitude performance adjustments(a) Instruction of the manufacturer(1) Any action taken with respect to any element of design installed on or in a motor vehicle or motor vehicle engine in compliance with regulations under this subchapter (including any alteration or adjustment of such element), shall be treated as not in violation of section 7522(a) of this title if such action is performed in accordance with high altitude adjustment instructions provided by the manufacturer under subsection (b) and approved by the Administrator.

(2) If the Administrator finds that adjustments or modifications made pursuant to instructions of the manufacturer under paragraph (1) will not insure emission control performance with respect to each standard under section 7521 of this title at least equivalent to that which would result if no such adjustments or modifications were made, he shall disapprove such instructions. Such finding shall be based upon minimum engineering evaluations consistent with good engineering practice.


(b) Regulations(1) Instructions respecting each class or category of vehicles or engines to which this subchapter applies providing for such vehicle and engine adjustments and modifications as may be necessary to insure emission control performance at different altitudes shall be submitted by the manufacturer to the Administrator pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Administrator.

(2) Any knowing violation by a manufacturer of requirements of the Administrator under paragraph (1) shall be treated as a violation by such manufacturer of section 7522(a)(3) of this title for purposes of the penalties contained in section 7524 of this title.

(3) Such instructions shall provide, in addition to other adjustments, for adjustments for vehicles moving from high altitude areas to low altitude areas after the initial registration of such vehicles.


(c) Manufacturer partsNo instructions under this section respecting adjustments or modifications may r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7549_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Instruction of the manufacturer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Instruction of the manufacturer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7549_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7549_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturer parts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Manufacturer parts No instructions under this section respecting adjustments or modifications may require the use of any manufacturer parts (as defined in section 7522(a) of this title) unless the manufacturer demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Administrator that the use of such manufacturer parts is necessary to insure emission control performance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7549_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State inspection and maintenance programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State inspection and maintenance programs Before January 1, 1981 the authority provided by this section shall be available in any high altitude State (as determined under regulations of the Administrator under regulations promulgated before August 7, 1977) but after December 31, 1980, such authority shall be available only in any such State in which an inspection and maintenance program for the testing of motor vehicle emissions has been instituted for the portions of the State where any national ambient air quality standard for auto-related pollutants has not been attained.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7549_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>High altitude testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) High altitude testing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>