<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7572" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7572/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7572/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7572"><akn:num>7572</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7572. Enforcement of standards(a) Regulations to insure compliance with standardsThe Secretary of Transportation, after consultation with the Administrator, shall prescribe regulations to insure compliance with all standards prescribed under section 7571 of this title by the Administrator. The regulations of the Secretary of Transportation shall include provisions making such standards applicable in the issuance, amendment, modification, suspension, or revocation of any certificate authorized by part A of subtitle VII of title 49 or the Department of Transportation Act. Such Secretary shall insure that all necessary inspections are accomplished, and,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. may execute any power or duty vested in him by any other provision of law in the execution of all powers and duties vested in him under this section.


(b) Notice and appeal rightsIn any action to amend, modify, suspend, or revoke a certificate in which violation of an emission standard prescribed under section 7571 of this title or of a regulation prescribed under subsection (a) is at issue, the certificate holder shall have the same notice and appeal rights as are prescribed for such holders in part A of subtitle VII of title 49 or the Department of Transportation Act, except that in any appeal to the National Transportation Safety Board, the Board may amend, modify, or revoke the order of the Secretary of Transportation only if it finds no violation of such standard or regulation and that such amendment, modification, or revocation is consistent with safety in air transportation.


(July 14, 1955, ch. 360, title II, § 232, as added Pub. L. 91–604, § 11(a)(1), Dec. 31, 1970, 84 Stat. 1704.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Department of Transportation Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is Pub. L. 89–670, Oct. 15, 1966, 80 Stat. 931, which was classified principally to sections 1651 to 1660 of former Title 49, Transportation. The Act was repealed a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7572_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations to insure compliance with standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations to insure compliance with standards The Secretary of Transportation, after consultation with the Administrator, shall prescribe regulations to insure compliance with all standards prescribed under section 7571 of this title by the Administrator. The regulations of the Secretary of Transportation shall include provisions making such standards applicable in the issuance, amendment, modification, suspension, or revocation of any certificate authorized by part A of subtitle VII of title 49 or the Department of Transportation Act. Such Secretary shall insure that all necessary inspections are accomplished, and,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. may execute any power or duty vested in him by any other provision of law in the execution of all powers and duties vested in him under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7572_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and appeal rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice and appeal rights In any action to amend, modify, suspend, or revoke a certificate in which violation of an emission standard prescribed under section 7571 of this title or of a regulation prescribed under subsection (a) is at issue, the certificate holder shall have the same notice and appeal rights as are prescribed for such holders in part A of subtitle VII of title 49 or the Department of Transportation Act, except that in any appeal to the National Transportation Safety Board, the Board may amend, modify, or revoke the order of the Secretary of Transportation only if it finds no violation of such standard or regulation and that such amendment, modification, or revocation is consistent with safety in air transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>