<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7586" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7586/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7586/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7586"><akn:num>7586</akn:num><akn:heading>Centrally fueled fleets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7586. Centrally fueled fleets(a) Fleet program required for certain nonattainment areas(1) SIP revisionEach State in which there is located all or part of a covered area (as defined in paragraph (2)) shall submit, within 42 months after November 15, 1990, a State implementation plan revision under section 7410 of this title and part D of subchapter I to establish a clean-fuel vehicle program for fleets under this section.


(2) Covered areasFor purposes of this subsection, each of the following shall be a “covered area”:(A) Ozone nonattainment areasAny ozone nonattainment area with a 1980 population of 250,000 or more classified under subpart 2 of part D of subchapter I of this chapter as Serious, Severe, or Extreme based on data for the calendar years 1987, 1988, and 1989. In determining the ozone nonattainment areas to be treated as covered areas pursuant to this subparagraph, the Administrator shall use the most recent interpretation methodology issued by the Administrator prior to November 15, 1990.


(B) Carbon monoxide nonattainment areasAny carbon monoxide nonattainment area with a 1980 population of 250,000 or more and a carbon monoxide design value at or above 16.0 parts per million based on data for calendar years 1988 and 1989 (as calculated according to the most recent interpretation methodology issued prior to November 15, 1990, by the United States Environmental Protection Agency), excluding those carbon monoxide nonattainment areas in which mobile sources do not contribute significantly to carbon monoxide exceedances.



(3) Plan revisions for reclassified areasIn the case of ozone nonattainment areas reclassified as Serious, Severe, or Extreme under part D of subchapter I with a 1980 population of 250,000 or more, the State shall submit a plan revision meeting the requirements of this subsection within 1 year after reclassification. Such plan revision shall implement the requirements applicable under this subsection at the time of reclassification </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7586_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fleet program required for certain nonattainment areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fleet program required for certain nonattainment areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7586_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase-in of requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Phase-in of requirements The plan revision required under this section shall contain provisions requiring that at least a specified percentage of all new covered fleet vehicles in model year 1998 and thereafter purchased by each covered fleet operator in each covered area shall be clean-fuel vehicles and shall use clean alternative fuels when operating in the covered area. For the applicable model years (MY) specified in the following table and thereafter, the specified percentage shall be as provided in the table for the vehicle types set forth in the table:









Clean Fuel Vehicle Phase-in Requirements for Fleets


Vehicle TypeMY1998MY1999MY2000


The term MY refers to model year.



Light-duty trucks up to 6,000 lbs. GVWR and light-duty vehicles30%50%70%
Heavy-duty trucks above 8,500 lbs. GVWR50%50%50%</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7586_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accelerated standard for light-duty trucks up to 6,000 lbs. GVWR and light-duty vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Accelerated standard for light-duty trucks up to 6,000 lbs. GVWR and light-duty vehicles Notwithstanding the model years for which clean-fuel vehicle standards are applicable as provided in section 7583 of this title, for purposes of this section, light duty 11 So in original. Probably should be “light-duty”. trucks of up to 6,000 lbs. GVWR and light-duty vehicles manufactured in model years 1998 through model year 2000 shall be treated as clean-fuel vehicles only if such vehicles comply with the standards applicable under section 7583 of this title for vehicles in the same class for the model year 2001. The requirements of subsection (b) shall take effect on the earlier of the following: Whenever the effective date of subsection (b) is delayed pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, the phase-in schedule under subsection (b) shall be modified to commence with the model year referred to in paragraph (1) in lieu of model year 1998.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7586_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Choice of vehicles and fuel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Choice of vehicles and fuel The plan revision under this subsection shall provide that the choice of clean-fuel vehicles and clean alternative fuels shall be made by the covered fleet operator subject to the requirements of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7586_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of clean alternative fuel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability of clean alternative fuel The plan revision shall require fuel providers to make clean alternative fuel available to covered fleet operators at locations at which covered fleet vehicles are centrally fueled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7586_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7586_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability to public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Availability to public At any facility owned or operated by a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States where vehicles subject to this subsection are supplied with clean alternative fuel, such fuel shall be offered for sale to the public for use in other vehicles during reasonable business times and subject to national security concerns, unless such fuel is commercially available for vehicles in the vicinity of such Federal facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7586_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation control measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Transportation control measures The Administrator shall by rule, within 1 year after November 15, 1990, ensure that certain transportation control measures including time-of-day or day-of-week restrictions, and other similar measures that restrict vehicle usage, do not apply to any clean-fuel vehicle that meets the requirements of this section. This subsection shall apply notwithstanding subchapter I.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>