<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7605"><akn:num>7605</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation in litigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7605. Representation in litigation(a) Attorney General; attorneys appointed by AdministratorThe Administrator shall request the Attorney General to appear and represent him in any civil action instituted under this chapter to which the Administrator is a party. Unless the Attorney General notifies the Administrator that he will appear in such action, within a reasonable time, attorneys appointed by the Administrator shall appear and represent him.


(b) Memorandum of understanding regarding legal representationIn the event the Attorney General agrees to appear and represent the Administrator in any such action, such representation shall be conducted in accordance with, and shall include participation by, attorneys appointed by the Administrator to the extent authorized by, the memorandum of understanding between the Department of Justice and the Environmental Protection Agency, dated June 13, 1977, respecting representation of the agency by the department in civil litigation.


(July 14, 1955, ch. 360, title III, § 305, as added Pub. L. 91–604, § 12(a), Dec. 31, 1970, 84 Stat. 1707; amended Pub. L. 95–95, title III, § 304(a), Aug. 7, 1977, 91 Stat. 772.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 1857h–3 of this title.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 305 of act July 14, 1955, as added Nov. 21, 1967, Pub. L. 90–148, § 2, 81 Stat. 505, was renumbered section 312 by Pub. L. 91–604 and is classified to section 7612 of this title.
Another prior section 305 of act July 14, 1955, ch. 360, title III, formerly § 12, as added Dec. 17, 1963, Pub. L. 88–206, § 1, 77 Stat. 401, was renumbered section 305 by Pub. L. 89–272, renumbered section 308 by Pub. L. 90–148, and renumbered section 315 by Pub. L. 91–604, and is classified to section 7615 of this title.

Amendments1977—Pub. L. 95–95 designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1977 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney General; attorneys appointed by Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Attorney General; attorneys appointed by Administrator The Administrator shall request the Attorney General to appear and represent him in any civil action instituted under this chapter to which the Administrator is a party. Unless the Attorney General notifies the Administrator that he will appear in such action, within a reasonable time, attorneys appointed by the Administrator shall appear and represent him.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Memorandum of understanding regarding legal representation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Memorandum of understanding regarding legal representation In the event the Attorney General agrees to appear and represent the Administrator in any such action, such representation shall be conducted in accordance with, and shall include participation by, attorneys appointed by the Administrator to the extent authorized by, the memorandum of understanding between the Department of Justice and the Environmental Protection Agency, dated June 13, 1977, respecting representation of the agency by the department in civil litigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>