<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7609" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7609/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7609/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7609"><akn:num>7609</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7609. Policy review(a) Environmental impactThe Administrator shall review and comment in writing on the environmental impact of any matter relating to duties and responsibilities granted pursuant to this chapter or other provisions of the authority of the Administrator, contained in any (1) legislation proposed by any Federal department or agency, (2) newly authorized Federal projects for construction and any major Federal agency action (other than a project for construction) to which section 4332(2)(C) of this title applies, and (3) proposed regulations published by any department or agency of the Federal Government. Such written comment shall be made public at the conclusion of any such review.


(b) Unsatisfactory legislation, action, or regulationIn the event the Administrator determines that any such legislation, action, or regulation is unsatisfactory from the standpoint of public health or welfare or environmental quality, he shall publish his determination and the matter shall be referred to the Council on Environmental Quality.


(July 14, 1955, ch. 360, title III, § 309, as added Pub. L. 91–604, § 12(a), Dec. 31, 1970, 84 Stat. 1709.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 1857h–7 of this title.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 309 of act July 14, 1955, ch. 360, title III, formerly § 13, as added Dec. 17, 1963, Pub. L. 88–206, § 1, 77 Stat. 401; renumbered § 306, Oct. 20, 1965, Pub. L. 89–272, title I, § 101(4), 79 Stat. 992; renumbered § 309, Nov. 21, 1967, Pub. L. 90–148, § 2, 81 Stat. 506; renumbered § 316, Dec. 31, 1970, Pub. L. 91–604, § 12(a), 84 Stat. 1705, related to appropriations and was classified to section 1857l of this title, prior to repeal by section 306 of Pub. L. 95–95. See section 7626 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Modification or Rescission of Rules, Regulations, Orders, Determinations, Contracts, Certifications, Authorizations, Delegations, and Other ActionsAll rules, regul</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7609_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Environmental impact The Administrator shall review and comment in writing on the environmental impact of any matter relating to duties and responsibilities granted pursuant to this chapter or other provisions of the authority of the Administrator, contained in any (1) legislation proposed by any Federal department or agency, (2) newly authorized Federal projects for construction and any major Federal agency action (other than a project for construction) to which section 4332(2)(C) of this title applies, and (3) proposed regulations published by any department or agency of the Federal Government. Such written comment shall be made public at the conclusion of any such review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7609_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unsatisfactory legislation, action, or regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Unsatisfactory legislation, action, or regulation In the event the Administrator determines that any such legislation, action, or regulation is unsatisfactory from the standpoint of public health or welfare or environmental quality, he shall publish his determination and the matter shall be referred to the Council on Environmental Quality.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>