<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7611"><akn:num>7611</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7611. Records and audit(a) Recipients of assistance to keep prescribed rec­ordsEach recipient of assistance under this chapter shall keep such records as the Administrator shall prescribe, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of such assistance, the total cost of the project or undertaking in connection with which such assistance is given or used, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.


(b) AuditsThe Administrator and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access for the purpose of audit and examinations to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipients that are pertinent to the grants received under this chapter.


(July 14, 1955, ch. 360, title III, § 311, formerly § 11, as added Pub. L. 88–206, § 1, Dec. 17, 1963, 77 Stat. 401; renumbered § 304, Pub. L. 89–272, title I, § 101(4), Oct. 20, 1965, 79 Stat. 992; amended Pub. L. 90–148, § 2, Nov. 21, 1967, 81 Stat. 505; renumbered § 311 and amended Pub. L. 91–604, §§ 12(a), 15(c)(2), Dec. 31, 1970, 84 Stat. 1705, 1713.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 1857j of this title.

Amendments1970—Pub. L. 91–604, § 15(c)(2), substituted “Administrator” for “Secretary” and “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare”.
1967—Pub. L. 90–148 reenacted section without change.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Modification or Rescission of Rules, Regulations, Orders, Determinations, Contracts, Certifications, Authorizations, Delegations, and Other ActionsAll rules, regulations, orders, determinations, contracts, certifications, authorizations, delegations, or other actions duly issued, made, or taken by or pursuant to act July 14, 1955, the Clean Air Act, as in effect immediately prior to the date of enactment of Pub. L. </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7611_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recipients of assistance to keep prescribed rec­ords</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recipients of assistance to keep prescribed rec­ords Each recipient of assistance under this chapter shall keep such records as the Administrator shall prescribe, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of such assistance, the total cost of the project or undertaking in connection with which such assistance is given or used, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7611_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Audits The Administrator and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access for the purpose of audit and examinations to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipients that are pertinent to the grants received under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>