<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7616" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7616/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7616/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7616"><akn:num>7616</akn:num><akn:heading>Sewage treatment grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7616. Sewage treatment grants(a) ConstructionNo grant which the Administrator is authorized to make to any applicant for construction of sewage treatment works in any area in any State may be withheld, conditioned, or restricted by the Administrator on the basis of any requirement of this chapter except as provided in subsection (b).


(b) Withholding, conditioning, or restriction of construction grantsThe Administrator may withhold, condition, or restrict the making of any grant for construction referred to in subsection (a) only if he determines that—(1) such treatment works will not comply with applicable standards under section 7411 or 7412 of this title,

(2) the State does not have in effect, or is not carrying out, a State implementation plan approved by the Administrator which expressly quantifies and provides for the increase in emissions of each air pollutant (from stationary and mobile sources in any area to which either part C or part D of subchapter I applies for such pollutant) which increase may reasonably be anticipated to result directly or indirectly from the new sewage treatment capacity which would be created by such construction.11 So in original. The period probably should be a comma.

(3) the construction of such treatment works would create new sewage treatment capacity which—(A) may reasonably be anticipated to cause or contribute to, directly or indirectly, an increase in emissions of any air pollutant in excess of the increase provided for under the provisions referred to in paragraph (2) for any such area, or

(B) would otherwise not be in conformity with the applicable implementation plan, or


(4) such increase in emissions would interfere with, or be inconsistent with, the applicable implementation plan for any other State.


In the case of construction of a treatment works which would result, directly or indirectly, in an increase in emissions of any air pollutant from stationary and mobile sources in an area to which part D of subc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7616_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Construction No grant which the Administrator is authorized to make to any applicant for construction of sewage treatment works in any area in any State may be withheld, conditioned, or restricted by the Administrator on the basis of any requirement of this chapter except as provided in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7616_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding, conditioning, or restriction of construction grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Withholding, conditioning, or restriction of construction grants The Administrator may withhold, condition, or restrict the making of any grant for construction referred to in subsection (a) only if he determines that— In the case of construction of a treatment works which would result, directly or indirectly, in an increase in emissions of any air pollutant from stationary and mobile sources in an area to which part D of subchapter I applies, the quantification of emissions referred to in paragraph (2) shall include the emissions of any such pollutant resulting directly or indirectly from areawide and nonmajor stationary source growth (mobile and stationary) for each such area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7616_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Environmental Policy Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National Environmental Policy Act Nothing in this section shall be construed to amend or alter any provision of the National Environmental Policy Act [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.] or to affect any determination as to whether or not the requirements of such Act have been met in the case of the construction of any sewage treatment works.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>