<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7617" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7617/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7617/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7617"><akn:num>7617</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic impact assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7617. Economic impact assessment(a) Notice of proposed rulemaking; substantial revisionsThis section applies to action of the Administrator in promulgating or revising—(1) any new source standard of performance under section 7411 of this title,

(2) any regulation under section 7411(d) of this title,

(3) any regulation under part B 11 See References in Text note below. of subchapter I (relating to ozone and stratosphere protection),

(4) any regulation under part C of subchapter I (relating to prevention of significant deterioration of air quality),

(5) any regulation establishing emission standards under section 7521 of this title and any other regulation promulgated under that section,

(6) any regulation controlling or prohibiting any fuel or fuel additive under section 7545(c) of this title, and

(7) any aircraft emission standard under section 7571 of this title.


Nothing in this section shall apply to any standard or regulation described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of this subsection unless the notice of proposed rulemaking in connection with such standard or regulation is published in the Federal Register after the date ninety days after August 7, 1977. In the case of revisions of such standards or regulations, this section shall apply only to revisions which the Administrator determines to be substantial revisions.

(b) Preparation of assessment by AdministratorBefore publication of notice of proposed rulemaking with respect to any standard or regulation to which this section applies, the Administrator shall prepare an economic impact assessment respecting such standard or regulation. Such assessment shall be included in the docket required under section 7607(d)(2) of this title and shall be available to the public as provided in section 7607(d)(4) of this title. Notice of proposed rulemaking shall include notice of such availability together with an explanation of the extent and manner in which the Administrator has considered the analysis contained </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7617_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of proposed rulemaking; substantial revisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice of proposed rulemaking; substantial revisions This section applies to action of the Administrator in promulgating or revising— Nothing in this section shall apply to any standard or regulation described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of this subsection unless the notice of proposed rulemaking in connection with such standard or regulation is published in the Federal Register after the date ninety days after August 7, 1977. In the case of revisions of such standards or regulations, this section shall apply only to revisions which the Administrator determines to be substantial revisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7617_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation of assessment by Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preparation of assessment by Administrator Before publication of notice of proposed rulemaking with respect to any standard or regulation to which this section applies, the Administrator shall prepare an economic impact assessment respecting such standard or regulation. Such assessment shall be included in the docket required under section 7607(d)(2) of this title and shall be available to the public as provided in section 7607(d)(4) of this title. Notice of proposed rulemaking shall include notice of such availability together with an explanation of the extent and manner in which the Administrator has considered the analysis contained in such economic impact assessment in proposing the action. The Administrator shall also provide such an explanation in his notice of promulgation of any regulation or standard referred to in subsection (a). Each such explanation shall be part of the statements of basis and purpose required under sections 7607(d)(3) and 7607(d)(6) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7617_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Analysis Subject to subsection (d), the assessment required under this section with respect to any standard or regulation shall contain an analysis of— Nothing in this section shall be construed to provide that the analysis of the factors specified in this subsection affects or alters the factors which the Administrator is required to consider in taking any action referred to in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7617_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extensiveness of assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Extensiveness of assessment The assessment required under this section shall be as extensive as practicable, in the judgment of the Administrator taking into account the time and resources available to the Environmental Protection Agency and other duties and authorities which the Administrator is required to carry out under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7617_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on construction of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations on construction of section Nothing in this section shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7617_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizen suits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Citizen suits The requirements imposed on the Administrator under this section shall be treated as nondiscretionary duties for purposes of section 7604(a)(2) of this title, relating to citizen suits. The sole method for enforcement of the Administrator’s duty under this section shall be by bringing a citizen suit under such section 7604(a)(2) for a court order to compel the Administrator to perform such duty. Violation of any such order shall subject the Administrator to penalties for contempt of court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7617_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Costs In the case of any provision of this chapter in which costs are expressly required to be taken into account, the adequacy or inadequacy of any assessment required under this section may be taken into consideration, but shall not be treated for purposes of judicial review of any such provision as conclusive with respect to compliance or noncompliance with the requirement of such provision to take cost into account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>