<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7651a"><akn:num>7651a</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7651a. Definitions
As used in this subchapter:(1) The term “affected source” means a source that includes one or more affected units.

(2) The term “affected unit” means a unit that is subject to emission reduction requirements or limitations under this subchapter.

(3) The term “allowance” means an authorization, allocated to an affected unit by the Administrator under this subchapter, to emit, during or after a specified calendar year, one ton of sulfur dioxide.

(4) The term “baseline” means the annual quantity of fossil fuel consumed by an affected unit, measured in millions of British Thermal Units (“mmBtu’s”), calculated as follows:(A) For each utility unit that was in commercial operation prior to January 1, 1985, the baseline shall be the annual average quantity of mmBtu’s consumed in fuel during calendar years 1985, 1986, and 1987, as recorded by the Department of Energy pursuant to Form 767. For any utility unit for which such form was not filed, the baseline shall be the level specified for such unit in the 1985 National Acid Precipitation Assessment Program (NAPAP) Emissions Inventory, Version 2, National Utility Reference File (NURF) or in a corrected data base as established by the Administrator pursuant to paragraph (3).11 So in original. The reference to “paragraph (3)” probably should be to “subparagraph (C)”. For nonutility units, the baseline is the NAPAP Emissions Inventory, Version 2. The Administrator, in the Administrator’s sole discretion, may exclude periods during which a unit is shutdown for a continuous period of four calendar months or longer, and make appropriate adjustments under this paragraph. Upon petition of the owner or operator of any unit, the Administrator may make appropriate baseline adjustments for accidents that caused prolonged outages.

(B) For any other nonutility unit that is not included in the NAPAP Emissions Inventory, Version 2, or a corrected data base as established by the Administrator pursuant to paragraph (3)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “affected source” means a source that includes one or more affected units.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “affected unit” means a unit that is subject to emission reduction requirements or limitations under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “allowance” means an authorization, allocated to an affected unit by the Administrator under this subchapter, to emit, during or after a specified calendar year, one ton of sulfur dioxide.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “baseline” means the annual quantity of fossil fuel consumed by an affected unit, measured in millions of British Thermal Units (“mmBtu’s”), calculated as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “capacity factor” means the ratio between the actual electric output from a unit and the potential electric output from that unit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “compliance plan” means, for purposes of the requirements of this subchapter, either—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “continuous emission monitoring system” (CEMS) means the equipment as required by section 7651k of this title, used to sample, analyze, measure, and provide on a continuous basis a permanent record of emissions and flow (expressed in pounds per million British thermal units (lbs/mmBtu), pounds per hour (lbs/hr) or such other form as the Administrator may prescribe by regulations under section 7651k of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “existing unit” means a unit (including units subject to section 7411 of this title) that commenced commercial operation before November 15, 1990. Any unit that commenced commercial operation before November 15, 1990, which is modified, reconstructed, or repowered after November 15, 1990, shall continue to be an existing unit for the purposes of this subchapter. For the purposes of this subchapter, existing units shall not include simple combustion turbines, or units which serve a generator with a nameplate capacity of 25MWe or less.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “generator” means a device that produces electricity and which is reported as a generating unit pursuant to Department of Energy Form 860.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651a_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “new unit” means a unit that commences commercial operation on or after November 15, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>