<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7651c"><akn:num>7651c</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase I sulfur dioxide requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7651c. Phase I sulfur dioxide requirements(a) Emission limitations(1) After January 1, 1995, each source that includes one or more affected units listed in table A is an affected source under this section. After January 1, 1995, it shall be unlawful for any affected unit (other than an eligible phase I unit under subsection (d)(2)) to emit sulfur dioxide in excess of the tonnage limitation stated as a total number of allowances in table A for phase I, unless (A) the emissions reduction requirements applicable to such unit have been achieved pursuant to subsection (b) or (d), or (B) the owner or operator of such unit holds allowances to emit not less than the unit’s total annual emissions, except that, after January 1, 2000, the emissions limitations established in this section shall be superseded by those established in section 7651d of this title. The owner or operator of any unit in violation of this section shall be fully liable for such violation including, but not limited to, liability for fulfilling the obligations specified in section 7651j of this title.

(2) Not later than December 31, 1991, the Administrator shall determine the total tonnage of reductions in the emissions of sulfur dioxide from all utility units in calendar year 1995 that will occur as a result of compliance with the emissions limitation requirements of this section, and shall establish a reserve of allowances equal in amount to the number of tons determined thereby not to exceed a total of 3.50 million tons. In making such a determination, the Administrator shall compute for each unit subject to the emissions limitation requirements of this section the difference between:(A) the product of its baseline multiplied by the lesser of each unit’s allowable 1985 emissions rate and its actual 1985 emissions rate, divided by 2,000, and

(B) the product of each unit’s baseline multiplied by 2.50 lbs/mmBtu divided by 2,000,


and sum the computations. The Administrator shall adjust the foregoing </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emission limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Emission limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substitutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Substitutions The owner or operator of an affected unit under subsection (a) may include in its section 7651g of this title permit application and proposed compliance plan a proposal to reassign, in whole or in part, the affected unit’s sulfur dioxide reduction requirements to any other unit(s) under the control of such owner or operator. Such proposal shall specify—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator’s action on substitution proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrator’s action on substitution proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible phase I extension units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible phase I extension units</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allocation of allowances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy conservation and renewable energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Energy conservation and renewable energy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation and Renewable Energy Reserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Conservation and Renewable Energy Reserve The Administrator shall establish a Conservation and Renewable Energy Reserve under this subsection. Beginning on January 1, 1995, the Administrator may allocate from the Conservation and Renewable Energy Reserve an amount equal to a total of 300,000 allowances for emissions of sulfur dioxide pursuant to section 7651b of this title. In order to provide 300,000 allowances for such reserve, in each year beginning in calendar year 2000 and until calendar year 2009, inclusive, the Administrator shall reduce each unit’s basic Phase II allowance allocation on the basis of its pro rata share of 30,000 allowances. If allowances remain in the reserve after January 2, 2010, the Administrator shall allocate such allowances for affected units under section 7651d of this title on a pro rata basis. For purposes of this subsection, for any unit subject to the emissions limitation requirements of section 7651d of this title, the term “pro rata basis” refer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative allowance allocation for units in certain utility systems with optional baseline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Alternative allowance allocation for units in certain utility systems with optional baseline</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>