<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7651h"><akn:num>7651h</akn:num><akn:heading>Repowered sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7651h. Repowered sources(a) AvailabilityNot later than December 31, 1997, the owner or operator of an existing unit subject to the emissions limitation requirements of section 7651d(b) and (c) of this title may demonstrate to the permitting authority that one or more units will be repowered with a qualifying clean coal technology to comply with the requirements under section 7651d of this title. The owner or operator shall, as part of any such demonstration, provide, not later than January 1, 2000, satisfactory documentation of a preliminary design and engineering effort for such repowering and an executed and binding contract for the majority of the equipment to repower such unit and such other information as the Administrator may require by regulation. The replacement of an existing utility unit with a new utility unit using a repowering technology referred to in section 7651a(2) 11 So in original. Probably should be section “7651a(12)”. of this title which is located at a different site, shall be treated as repowering of the existing unit for purposes of this subchapter, if—(1) the replacement unit is designated by the owner or operator to replace such existing unit, and

(2) the existing unit is retired from service on or before the date on which the designated replacement unit enters commercial operation.


(b) Extension(1) An owner or operator satisfying the requirements of subsection (a) shall be granted an extension of the emission limitation requirement compliance date for that unit from January 1, 2000, to December 31, 2003. The extension shall be specified in the permit issued to the source under section 7651g of this title, together with any compliance schedule and other requirements necessary to meet second phase requirements by the extended date. Any unit that is granted an extension under this section shall not be eligible for a waiver under section 7411(j) of this title, and shall continue to be subject to requirements under this subchapter as if i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Availability Not later than December 31, 1997, the owner or operator of an existing unit subject to the emissions limitation requirements of section 7651d(b) and (c) of this title may demonstrate to the permitting authority that one or more units will be repowered with a qualifying clean coal technology to comply with the requirements under section 7651d of this title. The owner or operator shall, as part of any such demonstration, provide, not later than January 1, 2000, satisfactory documentation of a preliminary design and engineering effort for such repowering and an executed and binding contract for the majority of the equipment to repower such unit and such other information as the Administrator may require by regulation. The replacement of an existing utility unit with a new utility unit using a repowering technology referred to in section 7651a(2) 11 So in original. Probably should be section “7651a(12)”. of this title which is located at a different site, shall be treated </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Extension</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allowances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Control requirements Any unit qualifying for an extension under this section that does not increase actual hourly emissions for any pollutant regulated under the 22 So in original. Probably should be “this”. chapter shall not be subject to any standard of performance under section 7411 of this title. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection, no new unit (1) designated as a replacement for an existing unit, (2) qualifying for the extension under subsection (b), and (3) located at a different site than the existing unit shall receive an exemption from the requirements imposed under section 7411 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited permitting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Expedited permitting State permitting authorities and, where applicable, the Administrator, are encouraged to give expedited consideration to permit applications under parts C and D of subchapter I of this chapter for any source qualifying for an extension under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651h_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition It shall be unlawful for the owner or operator of a repowered source to fail to comply with the requirement of this section, or any regulations of permit requirements to implement this section, including the prohibition against emitting sulfur dioxide in excess of allowances held.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>