<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7651n"><akn:num>7651n</akn:num><akn:heading>Clean coal technology regulatory incentives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7651n. Clean coal technology regulatory incentives(a) “Clean coal technology” definedFor purposes of this section, “clean coal technology” means any technology, including technologies applied at the precombustion, combustion, or post combustion stage, at a new or existing facility which will achieve significant reductions in air emissions of sulfur dioxide or oxides of nitrogen associated with the utilization of coal in the generation of electricity, process steam, or industrial products, which is not in widespread use as of November 15, 1990.


(b) Revised regulations for clean coal technology demonstrations(1) ApplicabilityThis subsection applies to physical or operational changes to existing facilities for the sole purpose of installation, operation, cessation, or removal of a temporary or permanent clean coal technology demonstration project. For the purposes of this section, a clean coal technology demonstration project shall mean a project using funds appropriated under the heading “Department of Energy—Clean Coal Technology”, up to a total amount of $2,500,000,000 for commercial demonstration of clean coal technology, or similar projects funded through appropriations for the Environmental Protection Agency. The Federal contribution for a qualifying project shall be at least 20 percent of the total cost of the demonstration project.


(2) Temporary projectsInstallation, operation, cessation, or removal of a temporary clean coal technology demonstration project that is operated for a period of five years or less, and which complies with the State implementation plans for the State in which the project is located and other requirements necessary to attain and maintain the national ambient air quality standards during and after the project is terminated, shall not subject such facility to the requirements of section 7411 of this title or part C or D of subchapter I.


(3) Permanent projectsFor permanent clean coal technology demonstration projects that constitu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Clean coal technology” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Clean coal technology” defined For purposes of this section, “clean coal technology” means any technology, including technologies applied at the precombustion, combustion, or post combustion stage, at a new or existing facility which will achieve significant reductions in air emissions of sulfur dioxide or oxides of nitrogen associated with the utilization of coal in the generation of electricity, process steam, or industrial products, which is not in widespread use as of November 15, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revised regulations for clean coal technology demonstrations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Revised regulations for clean coal technology demonstrations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for reactivation of very clean units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exemption for reactivation of very clean units Physical changes or changes in the method of operation associated with the commencement of commercial operations by a coal-fired utility unit after a period of discontinued operation shall not subject the unit to the requirements of section 7411 of this title or part C of the Act 2 where the unit (1) has not been in operation for the two-year period prior to the enactment of the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1990 [November 15, 1990], and the emissions from such unit continue to be carried in the permitting authority’s emissions inventory at the time of enactment, (2) was equipped prior to shut-down with a continuous system of emissions control that achieves a removal efficiency for sulfur dioxide of no less than 85 percent and a removal efficiency for particulates of no less than 98 percent, (3) is equipped with low-NOx burners prior to the time of commencement, and (4) is otherwise in compliance with the requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>