<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7651b"><akn:num>7651b</akn:num><akn:heading>Sulfur dioxide allowance program for existing and new units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7651b. Sulfur dioxide allowance program for existing and new units(a) Allocations of annual allowances for existing and new units(1) 11 So in original. No pars. (2) and (3) have been enacted. For the emission limitation programs under this subchapter, the Administrator shall allocate annual allowances for the unit, to be held or distributed by the designated representative of the owner or operator of each affected unit at an affected source in accordance with this subchapter, in an amount equal to the annual tonnage emission limitation calculated under section 7651c, 7651d, 7651e, 7651h, or 7651i of this title except as otherwise specifically provided elsewhere in this subchapter. Except as provided in sections 7651d(a)(2), 7651d(a)(3), 7651h and 7651i of this title, beginning January 1, 2000, the Administrator shall not allocate annual allowances to emit sulfur dioxide pursuant to section 7651d of this title in such an amount as would result in total annual emissions of sulfur dioxide from utility units in excess of 8.90 million tons except that the Administrator shall not take into account unused allowances carried forward by owners and operators of affected units or by other persons holding such allowances, following the year for which they were allocated. If necessary to meeting the restrictions imposed in the preceding sentence, the Administrator shall reduce, pro rata, the basic Phase II allowance allocations for each unit subject to the requirements of section 7651d of this title. Subject to the provisions of section 7651o of this title, the Administrator shall allocate allowances for each affected unit at an affected source annually, as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) 1 and section 7651g of this title. Except as provided in sections 7651h and 7651i of this title, the removal of an existing affected unit or source from commercial operation at any time after November 15, 1990 (whether before or after January 1, 1995, or January 1, 2000) shall not terminat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations of annual allowances for existing and new units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allocations of annual allowances for existing and new units</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance transfer system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allowance transfer system Allowances allocated under this subchapter may be transferred among designated representatives of the owners or operators of affected sources under this subchapter and any other person who holds such allowances, as provided by the allowance system regulations to be promulgated by the Administrator not later than eighteen months after November 15, 1990. Such regulations shall establish the allowance system prescribed under this section, including, but not limited to, requirements for the allocation, transfer, and use of allowances under this subchapter. Such regulations shall prohibit the use of any allowance prior to the calendar year for which the allowance was allocated, and shall provide, consistent with the purposes of this subchapter, for the identification of unused allowances, and for such unused allowances to be carried forward and added to allowances allocated in subsequent years, including allowances allocated to units subject to Phase I requirem</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interpollutant trading</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interpollutant trading Not later than January 1, 1994, the Administrator shall furnish to the Congress a study evaluating the environmental and economic consequences of amending this subchapter to permit trading sulfur dioxide allowances for nitrogen oxides allowances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance tracking system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allowance tracking system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>New utility units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) New utility units After January 1, 2000, it shall be unlawful for a new utility unit to emit an annual tonnage of sulfur dioxide in excess of the number of allowances to emit held for the unit by the unit’s owner or operator. Such new utility units shall not be eligible for an allocation of sulfur dioxide allowances under subsection (a)(1), unless the unit is subject to the provisions of subsection (g)(2) or (3) of section 7651d of this title. New utility units may obtain allowances from any person, in accordance with this subchapter. The owner or operator of any new utility unit in violation of this subsection shall be liable for fulfilling the obligations specified in section 7651j of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nature of allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nature of allowances An allowance allocated under this subchapter is a limited authorization to emit sulfur dioxide in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter. Such allowance does not constitute a property right. Nothing in this subchapter or in any other provision of law shall be construed to limit the authority of the United States to terminate or limit such authorization. Nothing in this section relating to allowances shall be construed as affecting the application of, or compliance with, any other provision of this chapter to an affected unit or source, including the provisions related to applicable National Ambient Air Quality Standards and State implementation plans. Nothing in this section shall be construed as requiring a change of any kind in any State law regulating electric utility rates and charges or affecting any State law regarding such State regulation or as limiting State regulation (including any prudency review) under such a State law. Nothing in this s</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prohibition It shall be unlawful for any person to hold, use, or transfer any allowance allocated under this subchapter, except in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Administrator. It shall be unlawful for any affected unit to emit sulfur dioxide in excess of the number of allowances held for that unit for that year by the owner or operator of the unit. Upon the allocation of allowances under this subchapter, the prohibition contained in the preceding sentence shall supersede any other emission limitation applicable under this subchapter to the units for which such allowances are allocated. Allowances may not be used prior to the calendar year for which they are allocated. Nothing in this section or in the allowance system regulations shall relieve the Administrator of the Administrator’s permitting, monitoring and enforcement obligations under this chapter, nor relieve affected sources of their requirements and liabilities under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive bidding for power supply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Competitive bidding for power supply Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to interfere with or impair any program for competitive bidding for power supply in a State in which such program is established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of antitrust laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Applicability of antitrust laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Utility Holding Company Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Public Utility Holding Company Act The acquisition or disposition of allowances pursuant to this subchapter including the issuance of securities or the undertaking of any other financing transaction in connection with such allowances shall not be subject to the provisions of the Public Utility Holding Company Act of 1935.22 See References in Text note below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>