<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7651f"><akn:num>7651f</akn:num><akn:heading>Nitrogen oxides emission reduction program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7651f. Nitrogen oxides emission reduction program(a) ApplicabilityOn the date that a coal-fired utility unit becomes an affected unit pursuant to sections 7651c, 7651d,11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “or”. 7651h of this title, or on the date a unit subject to the provisions of section 7651c(d) or 7651h(b) of this title, must meet the SO2 reduction requirements, each such unit shall become an affected unit for purposes of this section and shall be subject to the emission limitations for nitrogen oxides set forth herein.


(b) Emission limitations(1) Not later than eighteen months after November 15, 1990, the Administrator shall by regulation establish annual allowable emission limitations for nitrogen oxides for the types of utility boilers listed below, which limitations shall not exceed the rates listed below: Provided, That the Administrator may set a rate higher than that listed for any type of utility boiler if the Administrator finds that the maximum listed rate for that boiler type cannot be achieved using low NOx burner technology. The maximum allowable emission rates are as follows:(A) for tangentially fired boilers, 0.45 lb/mmBtu;

(B) for dry bottom wall-fired boilers (other than units applying cell burner technology), 0.50 lb/mmBtu.


After January 1, 1995, it shall be unlawful for any unit that is an affected unit on that date and is of the type listed in this paragraph to emit nitrogen oxides in excess of the emission rates set by the Administrator pursuant to this paragraph.

(2) Not later than January 1, 1997, the Administrator shall, by regulation, establish allowable emission limitations on a lb/mmBtu, annual average basis, for nitrogen oxides for the following types of utility boilers:(A) wet bottom wall-fired boilers;

(B) cyclones;

(C) units applying cell burner technology;

(D) all other types of utility boilers.


The Administrator shall base such rates on the degree of reduction achievable through the retrofit application </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability On the date that a coal-fired utility unit becomes an affected unit pursuant to sections 7651c, 7651d,11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “or”. 7651h of this title, or on the date a unit subject to the provisions of section 7651c(d) or 7651h(b) of this title, must meet the SO2 reduction requirements, each such unit shall become an affected unit for purposes of this section and shall be subject to the emission limitations for nitrogen oxides set forth herein.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emission limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Emission limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revised performance standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Revised performance standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative emission limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Alternative emission limitations The permitting authority shall, upon request of an owner or operator of a unit subject to this section, authorize an emission limitation less stringent than the applicable limitation established under subsection (b)(1) or (b)(2) upon a determination that— The permitting authority shall base such determination upon a showing satisfactory to the permitting authority, in accordance with regulations established by the Administrator not later than eighteen months after November 15, 1990, that the owner or operator— The permitting authority shall issue an operating permit for the unit in question, in accordance with section 7651g of this title and part B 33 See References in Text note below. of title III— Units subject to subsection (b)(1) for which an alternative emission limitation is established shall not be required to install any additional control technology beyond low NOx burners. Nothing in this section shall preclude an owner or operator from ins</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emissions averaging</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Emissions averaging In lieu of complying with the applicable emission limitations under subsection (b)(1), (2), or (d), the owner or operator of two or more units subject to one or more of the applicable emission limitations set pursuant to these sections,44 So in original. Probably should be “subsections,”. may petition the permitting authority for alternative contemporaneous annual emission limitations for such units that ensure that (1) the actual annual emission rate in pounds of nitrogen oxides per million Btu averaged over the units in question is a rate that is less than or equal to (2) the Btu-weighted average annual emission rate for the same units if they had been operated, during the same period of time, in compliance with limitations set in accordance with the applicable emission rates set pursuant to subsections (b)(1) and (2).
If the permitting authority determines, in accordance with regulations issued by the Administrator not later than eighteen months after Novembe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>