<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7651g"><akn:num>7651g</akn:num><akn:heading>Permits and compliance plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7651g. Permits and compliance plans(a) Permit programThe provisions of this subchapter shall be implemented, subject to section 7651b of this title, by permits issued to units subject to this subchapter (and enforced) in accordance with the provisions of subchapter V, as modified by this subchapter. Any such permit issued by the Administrator, or by a State with an approved permit program, shall prohibit—(1) annual emissions of sulfur dioxide in excess of the number of allowances to emit sulfur dioxide the owner or operator, or the designated representative of the owners or operators, of the unit hold for the unit,

(2) exceedances of applicable emissions rates,

(3) the use of any allowance prior to the year for which it was allocated, and

(4) contravention of any other provision of the permit.


Permits issued to implement this subchapter shall be issued for a period of 5 years, notwithstanding subchapter V. No permit shall be issued that is inconsistent with the requirements of this subchapter, and subchapter V as applicable.

(b) Compliance planEach initial permit application shall be accompanied by a compliance plan for the source to comply with its requirements under this subchapter. Where an affected source consists of more than one affected unit, such plan shall cover all such units, and for purposes of section 7661a(c) of this title, such source shall be considered a “facility”. Nothing in this section regarding compliance plans or in subchapter V shall be construed as affecting allowances. Except as provided under subsection (c)(1)(B), submission of a statement by the owner or operator, or the designated representative of the owners and operators, of a unit subject to the emissions limitation requirements of sections 7651c, 7651d, and 7651f of this title, that the unit will meet the applicable emissions limitation requirements of such sections in a timely manner or that, in the case of the emissions limitation requirements of sections 7651c and 7651d of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Permit program The provisions of this subchapter shall be implemented, subject to section 7651b of this title, by permits issued to units subject to this subchapter (and enforced) in accordance with the provisions of subchapter V, as modified by this subchapter. Any such permit issued by the Administrator, or by a State with an approved permit program, shall prohibit— Permits issued to implement this subchapter shall be issued for a period of 5 years, notwithstanding subchapter V. No permit shall be issued that is inconsistent with the requirements of this subchapter, and subchapter V as applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compliance plan Each initial permit application shall be accompanied by a compliance plan for the source to comply with its requirements under this subchapter. Where an affected source consists of more than one affected unit, such plan shall cover all such units, and for purposes of section 7661a(c) of this title, such source shall be considered a “facility”. Nothing in this section regarding compliance plans or in subchapter V shall be construed as affecting allowances. Except as provided under subsection (c)(1)(B), submission of a statement by the owner or operator, or the designated representative of the owners and operators, of a unit subject to the emissions limitation requirements of sections 7651c, 7651d, and 7651f of this title, that the unit will meet the applicable emissions limitation requirements of such sections in a timely manner or that, in the case of the emissions limitation requirements of sections 7651c and 7651d of this title, the owners and operators will hold </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>First phase permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) First phase permits The Administrator shall issue permits to affected sources under sections 7651c and 7651f of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Second phase permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Second phase permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>New units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) New units The owner or operator of each source that includes a new electric utility steam generating unit shall submit a permit application and compliance plan to the permitting authority not later than 24 months before the later of (1) January 1, 2000, or (2) the date on which the unit commences operation. The permitting authority shall issue a permit to the owner or operator, or the designated representative thereof, of the unit that satisfies the requirements of subchapter V and this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Units subject to certain other limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Units subject to certain other limits The owner or operator, or designated representative thereof, of any unit subject to an emission rate requirement under section 7651f of this title shall submit a permit application and compliance plan for such unit to the permitting authority, not later than January 1, 1998. The permitting authority shall issue a permit to the owner or operator that satisfies the requirements of subchapter V and this subchapter, including any appropriate monitoring and reporting requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of application and compliance plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Amendment of application and compliance plan At any time after the submission of an application and compliance plan under this section, the applicant may submit a revised application and compliance plan, in accordance with the requirements of this section. In considering any permit application and compliance plan under this subchapter, the permitting authority shall ensure coordination with the applicable electric ratemaking authority, in the case of regulated utilities, and with unregulated public utilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prohibition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651g_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiple owners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Multiple owners No permit shall be issued under this section to an affected unit until the designated representative of the owners or operators has filed a certificate of representation with regard to matters under this subchapter, including the holding and distribution of allowances and the proceeds of transactions involving allowances. Where there are multiple holders of a legal or equitable title to, or a leasehold interest in, such a unit, or where a utility or industrial customer purchases power from an affected unit (or units) under life-of-the-unit, firm power contractual arrangements, the certificate shall state (1) that allowances and the proceeds of transactions involving allowances will be deemed to be held or distributed in proportion to each holder’s legal, equitable, leasehold, or contractual reservation or entitlement, or (2) if such multiple holders have expressly provided for a different distribution of allowances by contract, that allowances and the proceeds of tr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>