<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7651d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7651d"><akn:num>7651d</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase II sulfur dioxide requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7651d. Phase II sulfur dioxide requirements(a) Applicability(1) After January 1, 2000, each existing utility unit as provided below is subject to the limitations or requirements of this section. Each utility unit subject to an annual sulfur dioxide tonnage emission limitation under this section is an affected unit under this subchapter. Each source that includes one or more affected units is an affected source. In the case of an existing unit that was not in operation during calendar year 1985, the emission rate for a calendar year after 1985, as determined by the Administrator, shall be used in lieu of the 1985 rate. The owner or operator of any unit operated in violation of this section shall be fully liable under this chapter for fulfilling the obligations specified in section 7651j of this title.

(2) In addition to basic Phase II allowance allocations, in each year beginning in calendar year 2000 and ending in calendar year 2009, inclusive, the Administrator shall allocate up to 530,000 Phase II bonus allowances pursuant to subsections (b)(2), (c)(4), (d)(3)(A) and (B), and (h)(2) of this section and section 7651e of this title. Not later than June 1, 1998, the Administrator shall calculate, for each unit granted an extension pursuant to section 7651h of this title the difference between (A) the number of allowances allocated for the unit in calendar year 2000, and (B) the product of the unit’s baseline multiplied by 1.20 lbs/mmBtu, divided by 2000, and sum the computations. In each year, beginning in calendar year 2000 and ending in calendar year 2009, inclusive, the Administrator shall deduct from each unit’s basic Phase II allowance allocation its pro rata share of 10 percent of the sum calculated pursuant to the preceding sentence.

(3) In addition to basic Phase II allowance allocations and Phase II bonus allowance allocations, beginning January 1, 2000, the Administrator shall allocate for each unit listed on Table A in section 7651c of this title (othe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Units equal to, or above, 75 MWe and 1.20 lbs/mmBtu</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Units equal to, or above, 75 MWe and 1.20 lbs/mmBtu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coal or oil-fired units below 75 MWe and above 1.20 lbs/mmBtu</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coal or oil-fired units below 75 MWe and above 1.20 lbs/mmBtu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coal-fired units below 1.20 lbs/mmBtu</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coal-fired units below 1.20 lbs/mmBtu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oil and gas-fired units equal to or greater than 0.60 lbs/mmBtu and less than 1.20 lbs/mmBtu</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Oil and gas-fired units equal to or greater than 0.60 lbs/mmBtu and less than 1.20 lbs/mmBtu After January 1, 2000, it shall be unlawful for any existing oil and gas-fired utility unit the lesser of whose actual or allowable 1985 sulfur dioxide emission rate is equal to, or greater than, 0.60 lbs/mmBtu, but less than 1.20 lbs/mmBtu to exceed an annual sulfur dioxide tonnage limitation equal to the product of the unit’s baseline multiplied by (A) the lesser of the unit’s allowable 1985 emissions rate or its actual 1985 emissions rate and (B) a numerical factor of 120 percent divided by 2,000, unless the owner or operator of such unit holds allowances to emit not less than the unit’s total annual emissions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oil and gas-fired units less than 0.60 lbs/mmBtu</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Oil and gas-fired units less than 0.60 lbs/mmBtu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Units that commence operation between 1986 and December 31, 1995</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Units that commence operation between 1986 and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oil and gas-fired units less than 10 percent oil consumed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Oil and gas-fired units less than 10 percent oil consumed</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Units in high growth States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Units in high growth States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651d_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain municipally owned power plants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Certain municipally owned power plants Beginning January 1, 2000, in addition to allowances allocated pursuant to this section and section 7651b(a)(1) of this title as basic Phase II allowance allocations, the Administrator shall allocate annually for each existing municipally owned oil and gas-fired utility unit with nameplate capacity equal to, or less than, 40 MWe, the lesser of whose actual or allowable 1985 sulfur dioxide emission rate is less than 1.20 lbs/mmBtu, allowances in an amount equal to the product of the unit’s annual fuel consumption on a Btu basis at a 60 percent capacity factor multiplied by the lesser of its allowable 1985 emission rate or its actual 1985 emission rate, divided by 2,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>