<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7661a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7661a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7661a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7661a"><akn:num>7661a</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7661a. Permit programs(a) ViolationsAfter the effective date of any permit program approved or promulgated under this subchapter, it shall be unlawful for any person to violate any requirement of a permit issued under this subchapter, or to operate an affected source (as provided in subchapter IV–A), a major source, any other source (including an area source) subject to standards or regulations under section 7411 or 7412 of this title, any other source required to have a permit under parts 11 So in original. Probably should be “part”. C or D of subchapter I, or any other stationary source in a category designated (in whole or in part) by regulations promulgated by the Administrator (after notice and public comment) which shall include a finding setting forth the basis for such designation, except in compliance with a permit issued by a permitting authority under this subchapter. (Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to alter the applicable requirements of this chapter that a permit be obtained before construction or modification.) The Administrator may, in the Administrator’s discretion and consistent with the applicable provisions of this chapter, promulgate regulations to exempt one or more source categories (in whole or in part) from the requirements of this subsection if the Administrator finds that compliance with such requirements is impracticable, infeasible, or unnecessarily burdensome on such categories, except that the Administrator may not exempt any major source from such requirements.


(b) RegulationsThe Administrator shall promulgate within 12 months after November 15, 1990, regulations establishing the minimum elements of a permit program to be administered by any air pollution control agency. These elements shall include each of the following:(1) Requirements for permit applications, including a standard application form and criteria for determining in a timely fashion the completeness of applications.

(2) Monitoring and reporting requir</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Violations After the effective date of any permit program approved or promulgated under this subchapter, it shall be unlawful for any person to violate any requirement of a permit issued under this subchapter, or to operate an affected source (as provided in subchapter IV–A), a major source, any other source (including an area source) subject to standards or regulations under section 7411 or 7412 of this title, any other source required to have a permit under parts 11 So in original. Probably should be “part”. C or D of subchapter I, or any other stationary source in a category designated (in whole or in part) by regulations promulgated by the Administrator (after notice and public comment) which shall include a finding setting forth the basis for such designation, except in compliance with a permit issued by a permitting authority under this subchapter. (Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to alter the applicable requirements of this chapter that a permit be obtained bef</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations The Administrator shall promulgate within 12 months after November 15, 1990, regulations establishing the minimum elements of a permit program to be administered by any air pollution control agency. These elements shall include each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Single permit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Single permit A single permit may be issued for a facility with multiple sources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission and approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Submission and approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Suspension The Administrator shall suspend the issuance of permits promptly upon publication of notice of approval of a permit program under this section, but may, in such notice, retain jurisdiction over permits that have been federally issued, but for which the administrative or judicial review process is not complete. The Administrator shall continue to administer and enforce federally issued permits under this subchapter until they are replaced by a permit issued by a permitting program. Nothing in this subsection should be construed to limit the Administrator’s ability to enforce permits issued by a State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition No partial permit program shall be approved unless, at a minimum, it applies, and ensures compliance with, this subchapter and each of the following: Approval of a partial program shall not relieve the State of its obligation to submit a complete program, nor from the application of any sanctions under this chapter for failure to submit an approvable permit program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Interim approval If a program (including a partial permit program) submitted under this subchapter substantially meets the requirements of this subchapter, but is not fully approvable, the Administrator may by rule grant the program interim approval. In the notice of final rulemaking, the Administrator shall specify the changes that must be made before the program can receive full approval. An interim approval under this subsection shall expire on a date set by the Administrator not later than 2 years after such approval, and may not be renewed. For the period of any such interim approval, the provisions of subsection (d)(2), and the obligation of the Administrator to promulgate a program under this subchapter for the State pursuant to subsection (d)(3), shall be suspended. Such provisions and such obligation of the Administrator shall apply after the expiration of such interim approval.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effective date The effective date of a permit program, or partial or interim program, approved under this subchapter, shall be the effective date of approval by the Administrator. The effective date of a permit program, or partial permit program, promulgated by the Administrator shall be the date of promulgation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Administration and enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>