<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7661d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7661d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7661d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7661d"><akn:num>7661d</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to Administrator and contiguous States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7661d. Notification to Administrator and contiguous States(a) Transmission and notice(1) Each permitting authority—(A) shall transmit to the Administrator a copy of each permit application (and any application for a permit modification or renewal) or such portion thereof, including any compliance plan, as the Administrator may require to effectively review the application and otherwise to carry out the Administrator’s responsibilities under this chapter, and

(B) shall provide to the Administrator a copy of each permit proposed to be issued and issued as a final permit.


(2) The permitting authority shall notify all States—(A) whose air quality may be affected and that are contiguous to the State in which the emission originates, or

(B) that are within 50 miles of the source,


of each permit application or proposed permit forwarded to the Administrator under this section, and shall provide an opportunity for such States to submit written recommendations respecting the issuance of the permit and its terms and conditions. If any part of those recommendations are not accepted by the permitting authority, such authority shall notify the State submitting the recommendations and the Administrator in writing of its failure to accept those recommendations and the reasons therefor.


(b) Objection by EPA(1) If any permit contains provisions that are determined by the Administrator as not in compliance with the applicable requirements of this chapter, including the requirements of an applicable implementation plan, the Administrator shall, in accordance with this subsection, object to its issuance. The permitting authority shall respond in writing if the Administrator (A) within 45 days after receiving a copy of the proposed permit under subsection (a)(1), or (B) within 45 days after receiving notification under subsection (a)(2), objects in writing to its issuance as not in compliance with such requirements. With the objection, the Administrator shall provide a statemen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmission and notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transmission and notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objection by EPA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Objection by EPA</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance or denial</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Issuance or denial If the permitting authority fails, within 90 days after the date of an objection under subsection (b), to submit a permit revised to meet the objection, the Administrator shall issue or deny the permit in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter. No objection shall be subject to judicial review until the Administrator takes final action to issue or deny a permit under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of notification requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver of notification requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7661d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refusal of permitting authority to terminate, modify, or revoke and reissue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Refusal of permitting authority to terminate, modify, or revoke and reissue If the Administrator finds that cause exists to terminate, modify, or revoke and reissue a permit under this subchapter, the Administrator shall notify the permitting authority and the source of the Administrator’s finding. The permitting authority shall, within 90 days after receipt of such notification, forward to the Administrator under this section a proposed determination of termination, modification, or revocation and reissuance, as appropriate. The Administrator may extend such 90 day period for an additional 90 days if the Administrator finds that a new or revised permit application is necessary, or that the permitting authority must require the permittee to submit additional information. The Administrator may review such proposed determination under the provisions of subsections (a) and (b). If the permitting authority fails to submit the required proposed determination, or if the Administrator obj</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>