<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7671j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7671j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7671j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7671j"><akn:num>7671j</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7671j. Labeling(a) RegulationsThe Administrator shall promulgate regulations to implement the labeling requirements of this section within 18 months after November 15, 1990, after notice and opportunity for public comment.


(b) Containers containing class I or class II substances and products containing class I substancesEffective 30 months after November 15, 1990, no container in which a class I or class II substance is stored or transported, and no product containing a class I substance, shall be introduced into interstate commerce unless it bears a clearly legible and conspicuous label stating:
“Warning: Contains [insert name of substance], a substance which harms public health and environment by destroying ozone in the upper atmosphere”.


(c) Products containing class II substances(1) After 30 months after November 15, 1990, and before January 1, 2015, no product containing a class II substance shall be introduced into interstate commerce unless it bears the label referred to in subsection (b) if the Administrator determines, after notice and opportunity for public comment, that there are substitute products or manufacturing processes (A) that do not rely on the use of such class II substance, (B) that reduce the overall risk to human health and the environment, and (C) that are currently or potentially available.

(2) Effective January 1, 2015, the requirements of subsection (b) shall apply to all products containing a class II substance.


(d) Products manufactured with class I and class II substances(1) In the case of a class II substance, after 30 months after November 15, 1990, and before January 1, 2015, if the Administrator, after notice and opportunity for public comment, makes the determination referred to in subsection (c) with respect to a product manufactured with a process that uses such class II substance, no such product shall be introduced into interstate commerce unless it bears a clearly legible and conspicuous label stating:“Warning: Manuf</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations The Administrator shall promulgate regulations to implement the labeling requirements of this section within 18 months after November 15, 1990, after notice and opportunity for public comment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Containers containing class I or class II substances and products containing class I substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Containers containing class I or class II substances and products containing class I substances Effective 30 months after November 15, 1990, no container in which a class I or class II substance is stored or transported, and no product containing a class I substance, shall be introduced into interstate commerce unless it bears a clearly legible and conspicuous label stating:
“Warning: Contains [insert name of substance], a substance which harms public health and environment by destroying ozone in the upper atmosphere”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Products containing class II substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Products containing class II substances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Products manufactured with class I and class II substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Products manufactured with class I and class II substances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Petitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671j_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Relationship to other law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>