<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7671c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7671c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7671c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7671c"><akn:num>7671c</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase-out of production and consumption of class I substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7671c. Phase-out of production and consumption of class I substances(a) Production phase-outEffective on January 1 of each year specified in Table 2, it shall be unlawful for any person to produce any class I substance in an annual quantity greater than the relevant percentage specified in Table 2. The percentages in Table 2 refer to a maximum allowable production as a percentage of the quantity of the substance produced by the person concerned in the baseline year.









Table 2


DateCarbon tetrachlorideMethyl chloroformOther class I substances


1991100%100%85%
1992 90%100%80%
1993 80% 90%75%
1994 70% 85%65%
1995 15% 70%50%
1996 15% 50%40%
1997 15% 50%15%
1998 15% 50%15%
1999 15% 50%15%
2000  20% 
2001  20% 





(b) Termination of production of class I substancesEffective January 1, 2000 (January 1, 2002 in the case of methyl chloroform), it shall be unlawful for any person to produce any amount of a class I substance.


(c) Regulations regarding production and consumption of class I substancesThe Administrator shall promulgate regulations within 10 months after November 15, 1990, phasing out the production of class I substances in accordance with this section and other applicable provisions of this subchapter. The Administrator shall also promulgate regulations to insure that the consumption of class I substances in the United States is phased out and terminated in accordance with the same schedule (subject to the same exceptions and other provisions) as is applicable to the phase-out and termination of production of class I substances under this subchapter.


(d) Exceptions for essential uses of methyl chloroform, medical devices, and aviation safety(1) Essential uses of methyl chloroformNotwithstanding the termination of production required by subsection (b), during the period beginning on January 1, 2002, and ending on January 1, 2005, the Administrator, after notice and opportunity for public comment, may, to the extent such action is consistent with t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Production phase-out</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Production phase-out Effective on January 1 of each year specified in Table 2, it shall be unlawful for any person to produce any class I substance in an annual quantity greater than the relevant percentage specified in Table 2. The percentages in Table 2 refer to a maximum allowable production as a percentage of the quantity of the substance produced by the person concerned in the baseline year.









Table 2


DateCarbon tetrachlorideMethyl chloroformOther class I substances


1991100%100%85%
1992 90%100%80%
1993 80% 90%75%
1994 70% 85%65%
1995 15% 70%50%
1996 15% 50%40%
1997 15% 50%15%
1998 15% 50%15%
1999 15% 50%15%
2000  20% 
2001  20%</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of production of class I substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Termination of production of class I substances Effective January 1, 2000 (January 1, 2002 in the case of methyl chloroform), it shall be unlawful for any person to produce any amount of a class I substance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations regarding production and consumption of class I substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations regarding production and consumption of class I substances The Administrator shall promulgate regulations within 10 months after November 15, 1990, phasing out the production of class I substances in accordance with this section and other applicable provisions of this subchapter. The Administrator shall also promulgate regulations to insure that the consumption of class I substances in the United States is phased out and terminated in accordance with the same schedule (subject to the same exceptions and other provisions) as is applicable to the phase-out and termination of production of class I substances under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions for essential uses of methyl chloroform, medical devices, and aviation safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exceptions for essential uses of methyl chloroform, medical devices, and aviation safety</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Developing countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Developing countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>National security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) National security The President may, to the extent such action is consistent with the Montreal Protocol, issue such orders regarding production and use of CFC–114 (chlorofluorocarbon-114), halon-1211, halon-1301, and halon-2402, at any specified site or facility or on any vessel as may be necessary to protect the national security interests of the United States if the President finds that adequate substitutes are not available and that the production and use of such substance are necessary to protect such national security interest. Such orders may include, where necessary to protect such interests, an exemption from any prohibition or requirement contained in this subchapter. The President shall notify the Congress within 30 days of the issuance of an order under this paragraph providing for any such exemption. Such notification shall include a statement of the reasons for the granting of the exemption. An exemption under this paragraph shall be for a specified period which may no</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fire suppression and explosion prevention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fire suppression and explosion prevention</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methyl bromide</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Methyl bromide Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (d), the Administrator shall not terminate production of methyl bromide prior to January 1, 2005. The Administrator shall promulgate rules for reductions in, and terminate the production, importation, and consumption of, methyl bromide under a schedule that is in accordance with, but not more stringent than, the phaseout schedule of the Montreal Protocol Treaty as in effect on October 21, 1998.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>