<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7671" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7671/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7671/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7671"><akn:num>7671</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7671. Definitions
As used in this subchapter—(1) ApplianceThe term “appliance” means any device which contains and uses a class I or class II substance as a refrigerant and which is used for household or commercial purposes, including any air conditioner, refrigerator, chiller, or freezer.


(2) Baseline yearThe term “baseline year” means—(A) the calendar year 1986, in the case of any class I substance listed in Group I or II under section 7671a(a) of this title,

(B) the calendar year 1989, in the case of any class I substance listed in Group III, IV, or V under section 7671a(a) of this title, and

(C) a representative calendar year selected by the Administrator, in the case of—(i) any substance added to the list of class I substances after the publication of the initial list under section 7671a(a) of this title, and

(ii) any class II substance.



(3) Class I substanceThe term “class I substance” means each of the substances listed as provided in section 7671a(a) of this title.


(4) Class II substanceThe term “class II substance” means each of the substances listed as provided in section 7671a(b) of this title.


(5) CommissionerThe term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Food and Drug Administration.


(6) ConsumptionThe term “consumption” means, with respect to any substance, the amount of that substance produced in the United States, plus the amount imported, minus the amount exported to Parties to the Montreal Protocol. Such term shall be construed in a manner consistent with the Montreal Protocol.


(7) ImportThe term “import” means to land on, bring into, or introduce into, or attempt to land on, bring into, or introduce into, any place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, whether or not such landing, bringing, or introduction constitutes an importation within the meaning of the customs laws of the United States.


(8) Medical deviceThe term “medical device” means any device (as defined in the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Appliance The term “appliance” means any device which contains and uses a class I or class II substance as a refrigerant and which is used for household or commercial purposes, including any air conditioner, refrigerator, chiller, or freezer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Baseline year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Baseline year The term “baseline year” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Class I substance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Class I substance The term “class I substance” means each of the substances listed as provided in section 7671a(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Class II substance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Class II substance The term “class II substance” means each of the substances listed as provided in section 7671a(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Commissioner The term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of the Food and Drug Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Consumption The term “consumption” means, with respect to any substance, the amount of that substance produced in the United States, plus the amount imported, minus the amount exported to Parties to the Montreal Protocol. Such term shall be construed in a manner consistent with the Montreal Protocol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Import</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Import The term “import” means to land on, bring into, or introduce into, or attempt to land on, bring into, or introduce into, any place subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, whether or not such landing, bringing, or introduction constitutes an importation within the meaning of the customs laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical device</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Medical device The term “medical device” means any device (as defined in the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 321)), diagnostic product, drug (as defined in the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act), and drug delivery system—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Montreal Protocol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Montreal Protocol The terms “Montreal Protocol” and “the Protocol” mean the Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer, a protocol to the Vienna Convention for the Protection of the Ozone Layer, including adjustments adopted by Parties thereto and amendments that have entered into force.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7671_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ozone-depletion potential</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Ozone-depletion potential The term “ozone-depletion potential” means a factor established by the Administrator to reflect the ozone-depletion potential of a substance, on a mass per kilogram basis, as compared to chlorofluorocarbon-11 (CFC–11). Such factor shall be based upon the substance’s atmospheric lifetime, the molecular weight of bromine and chlorine, and the substance’s ability to be photolytically disassociated, and upon other factors determined to be an accurate measure of relative ozone-depletion potential.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>