<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7912" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7912/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7912/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7912"><akn:num>7912</akn:num><akn:heading>Processing site designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7912. Processing site designations(a) Specific and other site locations; remedial action; consultations; boundaries; Grand Junction, Colorado, site restriction(1) As soon as practicable, but no later than one year after November 8, 1978, the Secretary shall designate processing sites at or near the following locations:Salt Lake City, Utah
Green River, Utah
Mexican Hat, Utah
Durango, Colorado
Grand Junction, Colorado
Rifle, Colorado (two sites)
Gunnison, Colorado
Naturita, Colorado
Maybell, Colorado
Slick Rock, Colorado (two sites)
Shiprock, New Mexico
Ambrosia Lake, New Mexico
Riverton, Wyoming
Converse County, Wyoming
Lakeview, Oregon
Falls City, Texas
Tuba City, Arizona
Monument Valley, Arizona
Lowman, Idaho
Cannonsburg, Pennsylvania

Subject to the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary shall complete remedial action at the above listed sites before his authority terminates under this subchapter. The Secretary shall within one year of November 8, 1978, also designate all other processing sites within the United States which he determines requires remedial action to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. In making such designation, the Secretary shall consult with the Administrator, the Commission, and the affected States, and in the case of Indian lands, the appropriate Indian tribe and the Secretary of the Interior.


(2) As part of his designation under this subsection, the Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall determine the boundaries of each such site.

(3) No site or structure with respect to which remedial action is authorized under Public Law 92–314 in Grand Junction, Colorado, may be designated by the Secretary as a processing site under this section.


(b) Health hazard assessment; priorities for remedial actionWithin one year from November 8, 1978, the Secretary shall assess the potential health hazard to the public from the residual radioactive materials at designated processing sites. Based upon such assessment, the Secreta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7912_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specific and other site locations; remedial action; consultations; boundaries; Grand Junction, Colorado, site restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Specific and other site locations; remedial action; consultations; boundaries; Grand Junction, Colorado, site restriction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7912_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health hazard assessment; priorities for remedial action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Health hazard assessment; priorities for remedial action Within one year from November 8, 1978, the Secretary shall assess the potential health hazard to the public from the residual radioactive materials at designated processing sites. Based upon such assessment, the Secretary shall, within such one year period, establish priorities for carrying out remedial action at each such site. In establishing such priorities, the Secretary shall rely primarily on the advice of the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7912_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification Within thirty days after making designations of processing sites and establishing the priorities for such sites under this section, the Secretary shall notify the Governor of each affected State, and, where appropriate, the Indian tribes and the Secretary of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7912_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Finality of determinations The designations made, and priorities established, by the Secretary under this section shall be final and not be subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7912_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain real property or improved areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certain real property or improved areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7912_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Moab Site as processing site</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Designation of Moab Site as processing site</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>