<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7914" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7914/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7914/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7914"><akn:num>7914</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition and disposition of lands and materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7914. Acquisition and disposition of lands and materials(a) State acquisition; windfall profits preventionEach cooperative agreement under section 7913 of this title shall require the State, where determined appropriate by the Secretary with the concurrence of the Commission, to acquire any designated processing site, including where appropriate any interest therein. In determining whether to require the State to acquire a designated processing site or interest therein, consideration shall be given to the prevention of windfall profits.


(b) Disposition and stabilization site for residual radioactive materials; Federal site available(1) If the Secretary with the concurrence of the Commission determines that removal of residual radioactive material from a processing site is appropriate, the cooperative agreement shall provide that the State shall acquire land (including, where appropriate, any interest therein) to be used as a site for the permanent disposition and stabilization of such residual radioactive materials in a safe and environmentally sound manner.

(2) Acquisition by the State shall not be required under this subsection if a site located on land controlled by the Secretary or made available by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to section 7916(2) of this title is designated by the Secretary, with the concurrence of the Commission, for such disposition and stabilization.


(c) Boundary limitationsNo State shall be required under subsection (a) or (b) to acquire any real property or improvement outside the boundaries of—(1) that portion of the processing site which is described in section 7911(6)(A) of this title, and

(2) the site used for disposition of the residual radioactive materials.


(d) Purchasers of sites; notification; rules and regulationsIn the case of each processing site designated under this subchapter other than a site designated on Indian land, the State shall take such action as may be necessary, and pursuant to regulations of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7914_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State acquisition; windfall profits prevention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State acquisition; windfall profits prevention Each cooperative agreement under section 7913 of this title shall require the State, where determined appropriate by the Secretary with the concurrence of the Commission, to acquire any designated processing site, including where appropriate any interest therein. In determining whether to require the State to acquire a designated processing site or interest therein, consideration shall be given to the prevention of windfall profits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7914_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition and stabilization site for residual radioactive materials; Federal site available</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disposition and stabilization site for residual radioactive materials; Federal site available</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7914_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boundary limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Boundary limitations No State shall be required under subsection (a) or (b) to acquire any real property or improvement outside the boundaries of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7914_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchasers of sites; notification; rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Purchasers of sites; notification; rules and regulations In the case of each processing site designated under this subchapter other than a site designated on Indian land, the State shall take such action as may be necessary, and pursuant to regulations of the Secretary under this subsection, to assure that any person who purchases such a processing site after the removal of radioactive materials from such site shall be notified in an appropriate manner prior to such purchase, of the nature and extent of residual radioactive materials removed from the site, including notice of the date when such action took place, and the condition of such site after such action. If the State is the owner of such site, the State shall so notify any prospective purchaser before entering into a contract, option, or other arrangement to sell or otherwise dispose of such site. The Secretary shall issue appropriate rules and regulations to require notice in the local land records of the residual radioact</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7914_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State disposition; terms and conditions; fair market value; offer of sale to prior owner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State disposition; terms and conditions; fair market value; offer of sale to prior owner</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7914_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of title to Secretary; payment from funds for administrative and legal costs; custody of property; compliance with health and environmental standards for uranium mill tailings; transfer of title restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer of title to Secretary; payment from funds for administrative and legal costs; custody of property; compliance with health and environmental standards for uranium mill tailings; transfer of title restriction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7914_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement; fair market value; deposits in Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reimbursement; fair market value; deposits in Treasury Each agreement under section 7913 of this title which permits any sale described in subsection (e)(1)(A) shall provide for the prompt reimbursement to the Secretary from the proceeds of such sale. Such reimbursement shall be in an amount equal to the lesser of— The fair market value of such lands or interest shall be determined by the Secretary as of the date of the sale by the State. Any amounts received by the Secretary under this subchapter shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7914_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsurface mineral rights; sale, lease, or other disposition; restoration costs for disturbance of residual radioactive materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Subsurface mineral rights; sale, lease, or other disposition; restoration costs for disturbance of residual radioactive materials No provision of any agreement under section 7913 of this title shall prohibit the Secretary of the Interior, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Energy and the Commission, from disposing of any subsurface mineral rights by sale or lease (in accordance with laws of the United States applicable to the sale, lease, or other disposal of such rights) which are associated with land on which residual radioactive materials are disposed and which are transferred to the United States as required under this section if the Secretary of the Interior takes such action as the Commission deems necessary pursuant to a license issued by the Commission to assure that the residual radioactive materials will not be disturbed by reason of any activity carried on following such disposition. If any such materials are disturbed by any such activity, the Secretary of the Int</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>