<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8011" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8011/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8011/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8011"><akn:num>8011</akn:num><akn:heading>Revised congregate housing services program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8011. Revised congregate housing services program(a) Findings and purposes(1) FindingsThe Congress finds that—(A) the effective provision of congregate services may require the redesign of units and buildings to meet the special physical needs of the frail elderly persons and the creation of congregate space to accommodate services that enhance independent living;

(B) congregate housing, coordinated with the delivery of supportive services, offers an innovative, proven, and cost-effective means of enabling frail older persons and persons with disabilities to maintain their dignity and independence;

(C) independent living with assistance is a preferable housing alternative to institutionalization for many frail older persons and persons with disabilities;

(D) 365,000 persons in federally assisted housing experience some form of frailty, and the number is expected to increase as the general population ages;

(E) an estimated 20 to 30 percent of older adults living in federally assisted housing experience some form of frailty;

(F) a large and growing number of frail elderly residents face premature or unnecessary institutionalization because of the absence of or deficiencies in the availability, adequacy, coordination, or delivery of supportive services;

(G) the support service needs of frail residents of assisted housing are beyond the resources and experience that housing managers have for meeting such needs;

(H) supportive services would promote the invaluable option of independent living for nonelderly persons with disabilities in federally assisted housing;

(I) approximately 25 percent of congregate housing services program sites provide congregate services to young individuals with disabilities;

(J) to the extent that institutionalized older adults do not need the full costly support provided by such care, public moneys could be more effectively spent providing the necessary services in a noninstitutional setting; and

(K) the Congregate Housing Service</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings and purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings and purposes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for congregate services programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contracts for congregate services programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reservation of amounts For each State, Indian tribe, unit of general local government, and nonprofit housing sponsor, receiving a contract under this subsection,11 So in original. Probably should be “section,”. the Secretary concerned shall reserve a sum equal to the total approved contract amount from the amount authorized and appropriated for the fiscal year in which the notification date of funding approval occurs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligibility for services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible contract recipients and distribution of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligible contract recipients and distribution of assistance The Secretary concerned may provide assistance under this section and enter into contracts under subsection (b) with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applications The funds made available under this section shall be allocated by the Secretary among approvable applications submitted by or on behalf of owners. Applications for assistance under this section shall be submitted in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary shall establish. Applications for assistance shall contain— The Secretary shall act on each application within 60 days of its submission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection and evaluation of applications and programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Selection and evaluation of applications and programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congregate services program funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Congregate services program funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8011_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Miscellaneous provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>