<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8012" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8012/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8012/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8012"><akn:num>8012</akn:num><akn:heading>Hope for elderly independence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8012. Hope for elderly independence(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to establish a demonstration program to test the effectiveness of combining housing certificates and vouchers with supportive services to assist frail elderly persons to continue to live independently. The demonstration program under this section shall terminate upon the expiration of the 5-year period determined by the Secretary.


(b) Housing assistanceIn connection with this demonstration, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may enter into contracts with public housing agencies to provide not more than 1,500 incremental vouchers and certificates under sections 1437f(b) and 1437f(o) of this title. A public housing agency may not require that a frail elderly person live in a particular structure or unit, but the agency may restrict the program under this section to a geographic area, where necessary to ensure that the provision of supportive services is feasible. At the end of the demonstration period, the public housing agency shall give each frail elderly person the option to continue to receive assistance under the housing certificate or voucher program of the agency. In the demonstration, the Secretary may also provide for supportive services in connection with existing contracts for housing assistance under sections 1437f(b) and 1437f(o) of this title.


(c) Supportive services requirements and matching funding(1) Federal, PHA and,11 So in original. The comma probably should precede “and”. individual contributionsThe amount estimated by the public housing agency and approved by the Secretary as necessary to provide the supportive services for the demonstration period shall be funded as follows:(A) The Secretary shall provide 40 percent, using amounts appropriated under this section.

(B) The public housing agency shall ensure the provision of at least 50 percent from sources other than under this section.

(C) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, each frail elderly</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to establish a demonstration program to test the effectiveness of combining housing certificates and vouchers with supportive services to assist frail elderly persons to continue to live independently. The demonstration program under this section shall terminate upon the expiration of the 5-year period determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Housing assistance In connection with this demonstration, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may enter into contracts with public housing agencies to provide not more than 1,500 incremental vouchers and certificates under sections 1437f(b) and 1437f(o) of this title. A public housing agency may not require that a frail elderly person live in a particular structure or unit, but the agency may restrict the program under this section to a geographic area, where necessary to ensure that the provision of supportive services is feasible. At the end of the demonstration period, the public housing agency shall give each frail elderly person the option to continue to receive assistance under the housing certificate or voucher program of the agency. In the demonstration, the Secretary may also provide for supportive services in connection with existing contracts for housing assistance under sections 1437f(b) and 1437f(o) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supportive services requirements and matching funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Supportive services requirements and matching funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applications An application under this section shall be submitted by a public housing agency in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary shall establish. The Secretary shall require that an application contain at a minimum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Required agreements The Secretary may not approve any assistance for any program under this section unless the public housing agency agrees—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multifamily project demonstration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Multifamily project demonstration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report The Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report evaluating the effectiveness of the demonstrations under this section. The report shall include a statement of the number of persons served, the types of services provided, the cost of providing such services, and any other information the Secretary considers appropriate in evaluating the demonstration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8012_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section 1437f funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Section 1437f funding The budget authority available under section 1437c(c) of this title for assistance under sections 1437f(b) and 1437f(o) of this title is authorized to be increased by $38,288,000 on or after October 1, 1992, and by $39,896,096 on or after October 1, 1993. The amounts made available under this subsection shall be used only in connection with the demonstration under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>