<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_802"><akn:num>802</akn:num><akn:heading>Coronavirus State fiscal recovery fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 802. Coronavirus State fiscal recovery fund(a) AppropriationIn addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated for fiscal year 2021, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated—(1) $219,800,000,000, to remain available through December 31, 2024 (except as provided in subsection (c)(5)), for making payments under this section to States, territories, and Tribal governments to mitigate the fiscal effects stemming from the public health emergency with respect to the Coronavirus Disease (COVID–19); and

(2) $50,000,000, to remain available until expended, for the costs of the Secretary for administration of the funds established under this subchapter.


(b) Authority to make payments(1) Payments to territories(A) In generalThe Secretary shall reserve $4,500,000,000 of the amount appropriated under subsection (a)(1) to make payments to the territories.


(B) AllocationOf the amount reserved under subparagraph (A)—(i) 50 percent of such amount shall be allocated by the Secretary equally to each territory; and

(ii) 50 percent of such amount shall be allocated by the Secretary as an additional amount to each territory in an amount which bears the same proportion to ½ of the total amount reserved under subparagraph (A) as the population of the territory bears to the total population of all such territories.


(C) PaymentThe Secretary shall pay each territory the total of the amounts allocated for the territory under subparagraph (B) in accordance with paragraph (6).



(2) Payments to Tribal governments(A) In generalThe Secretary shall reserve $20,000,000,000 of the amount appropriated under subsection (a)(1) to make payments to Tribal governments.


(B) AllocationOf the amount reserved under subparagraph (A)—(i) $1,000,000,000 shall be allocated by the Secretary equally among each of the Tribal governments; and

(ii) $19,000,000,000 shall be allocated by the Secretary to the Tribal governments in a manner determined by the Secretary.


(C) P</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_802_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appropriation In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated for fiscal year 2021, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_802_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to make payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to make payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_802_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_802_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certifications and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certifications and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_802_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recoupment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recoupment Any State, territory, or Tribal government that has failed to comply with subsection (c) shall be required to repay to the Secretary an amount equal to the amount of funds used in violation of such subsection, provided that, in the case of a violation of subsection (c)(2)(A), the amount the State or territory shall be required to repay shall be lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_802_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Secretary shall have the authority to issue such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_802_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>