<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_803"><akn:num>803</akn:num><akn:heading>Coronavirus local fiscal recovery fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 803. Coronavirus local fiscal recovery fund(a) AppropriationIn addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated for fiscal year 2021, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $130,200,000,000, to remain available through December 31, 2024 (except as provided in subsection (c)(6)), for making payments under this section to metropolitan cities, nonentitlement units of local government, and counties to mitigate the fiscal effects stemming from the public health emergency with respect to the Coronavirus Disease (COVID–19).


(b) Authority to make payments(1) Metropolitan cities(A) In generalOf the amount appropriated under subsection (a), the Secretary shall reserve $45,570,000,000 to make payments to metropolitan cities.


(B) Allocation and paymentFrom the amount reserved under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall allocate and, in accordance with paragraph (7), pay to each metropolitan city an amount determined for the metropolitan city consistent with the formula under section 5306(b) of this title, except that, in applying such formula, the Secretary shall substitute “all metropolitan cities” for “all metropolitan areas” each place it appears.



(2) Nonentitlement units of local government(A) In generalOf the amount appropriated under subsection (a), the Secretary shall reserve $19,530,000,000 to make payments to States for distribution by the State to nonentitlement units of local government in the State.


(B) Allocation and paymentFrom the amount reserved under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall allocate and, in accordance with paragraph (7), pay to each State an amount which bears the same proportion to such reserved amount as the total population of all areas that are non-metropolitan cities in the State bears to the total population of all areas that are non-metropolitan cities in all such States.


(C) Distribution to nonentitlement units of local government(i) In generalNot later than 30 days after a State receives a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appropriation In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated for fiscal year 2021, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $130,200,000,000, to remain available through December 31, 2024 (except as provided in subsection (c)(6)), for making payments under this section to metropolitan cities, nonentitlement units of local government, and counties to mitigate the fiscal effects stemming from the public health emergency with respect to the Coronavirus Disease (COVID–19).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to make payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to make payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting Any metropolitan city, nonentitlement unit of local government, or county receiving funds provided under a payment made under this section shall provide to the Secretary periodic reports providing a detailed accounting of the uses of such funds by such metropolitan city, nonentitlement unit of local government, or county and including such other information as the Secretary may require for the administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recoupment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recoupment Any metropolitan city, nonentitlement unit of local government, or county that has failed to comply with subsection (c) shall be required to repay to the Secretary an amount equal to the amount of funds used in violation of such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Secretary shall have the authority to issue such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_803_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>