<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8105"><akn:num>8105</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8105. Powers and duties of corporation(a) Continuance of work of Urban Reinvestment Task Force regarding neighborhood housing services programs and preservation projects(1) The corporation shall continue the work of the Urban Reinvestment Task Force in establishing neighborhood housing services programs in neighborhoods throughout the United States, monitoring their progress, and providing them with grants and technical assistance. For the purpose of this paragraph, a neighborhood housing services program may involve a partnership of neighborhood residents and representatives of local governmental and financial institutions, organized as a State-chartered non-profit corporation, working to bring about reinvestment in one or more neighborhoods through a program of systematic housing inspections, increased public investment, increased private lending, increased resident investment, and a revolving loan fund to make loans available at flexible rates and terms to homeowners not meeting private lending criteria.

(2) The corporation shall continue the work of the Urban Reinvestment Task Force in identifying, monitoring, evaluating, and providing grants and technical assistance to selected neighborhood preservation projects which show promise as mechanisms for reversing neighborhood decline and improving the quality of neighborhood life.

(3) The corporation shall experimentally replicate neighborhood preservation projects which have demonstrated success, and after creating reliable developmental processes, bring the new programs to neighborhoods throughout the United States which in the judgment of the corporation can benefit therefrom, by providing assistance in organizing programs, providing grants in partial support of program costs, and providing technical assistance to ongoing programs.

(4) The corporation shall continue the work of the Urban Reinvestment Task Force in supporting Neighborhood Housing Services of America, a nonprofit corporation established to pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuance of work of Urban Reinvestment Task Force regarding neighborhood housing services programs and preservation projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Continuance of work of Urban Reinvestment Task Force regarding neighborhood housing services programs and preservation projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General administrative powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General administrative powers To carry out the foregoing purposes and engage in the foregoing activities, the corporation is authorized—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contracting powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8105_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-profit nature of corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Non-profit nature of corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>