<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8106"><akn:num>8106</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8106. Reports and audits(a) Annual report to President and CongressThe corporation shall publish an annual report which shall be transmitted by the corporation to the President and the Congress.


(b) Annual audit of accountsThe accounts of the corporation shall be audited annually. Such audits shall be conducted in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by independent certified public accountants who are certified by a regulatory authority of the jurisdiction in which the audit is undertaken.


(c) Additional audits by Government Accountability OfficeIn addition to the annual audit, the financial transactions of the corporation for any fiscal year during which Federal funds are available to finance any portion of its operations may be audited by the Government Accountability Office in accordance with such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States.


(d) Audit of grantees and contractors of corporationFor any fiscal year during which Federal funds are available to finance any portion of the corporation’s grants or contracts, the Government Accountability Office, in accordance with such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States, may audit the grantees or contractors of the corporation.


(e) Annual financial auditThe corporation shall conduct or require each grantee or contractor to provide for an annual financial audit. The report of each such audit shall be maintained for a period of at least five years at the principal office of the corporation.


(Pub. L. 95–557, title VI, § 607, Oct. 31, 1978, 92 Stat. 2118; Pub. L. 104–66, title II, § 2161, Dec. 21, 1995, 109 Stat. 731; Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b), July 7, 2004, 118 Stat. 814.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2004—Subsecs. (c), (d). Pub. L. 108–271 substituted “Government Accountability Office” for “General Accounting Office”.
1995—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 104–66 struck out at end “The financial transactions of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report to President and Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report to President and Congress The corporation shall publish an annual report which shall be transmitted by the corporation to the President and the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual audit of accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual audit of accounts The accounts of the corporation shall be audited annually. Such audits shall be conducted in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by independent certified public accountants who are certified by a regulatory authority of the jurisdiction in which the audit is undertaken.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional audits by Government Accountability Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional audits by Government Accountability Office In addition to the annual audit, the financial transactions of the corporation for any fiscal year during which Federal funds are available to finance any portion of its operations may be audited by the Government Accountability Office in accordance with such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit of grantees and contractors of corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Audit of grantees and contractors of corporation For any fiscal year during which Federal funds are available to finance any portion of the corporation’s grants or contracts, the Government Accountability Office, in accordance with such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States, may audit the grantees or contractors of the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual financial audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual financial audit The corporation shall conduct or require each grantee or contractor to provide for an annual financial audit. The report of each such audit shall be maintained for a period of at least five years at the principal office of the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>