<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8201" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8201/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8201/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8201"><akn:num>8201</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings and statement of purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8201. Findings and statement of purposes(a) FindingsThe Congress finds that—(1) the United States has survived a period of energy shortage and has made significant progress toward improving energy efficiency in all sectors of the economy;

(2) effective measures must continue to be taken by the Federal Government and other users and suppliers of energy to control the rate of growth of demand for energy and the efficiency of its use;

(3) the continuation of this effort will permit the United States to become increasingly independent of the world oil market, less vulnerable to interruption of foreign oil supplies, and more able to provide energy to meet future needs; and

(4) all sectors of the economy of the United States should continue to reduce significantly the demand for nonrenewable energy resources such as oil and natural gas by implementing and maintaining effective conservation measures for the efficient use of these and other energy sources.


(b) Statement of purposesThe purposes of this chapter are to provide for the regulation of interstate commerce, to reduce the growth in demand for energy in the United States, and to conserve nonrenewable energy resources produced in this Nation and elsewhere, without inhibiting beneficial economic growth.


(Pub. L. 95–619, title I, § 102, Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3208; Pub. L. 99–412, title I, § 101, Aug. 28, 1986, 100 Stat. 932.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 95–619, Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3206, known as the National Energy Conservation Policy Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out below and Tables.

Amendments1986—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 99–412 amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “The Congress finds that—
“(1) the United States faces an energy shortage arising from increasing demand for energy, particularly for oil and natural gas,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8201_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings The Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8201_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Statement of purposes The purposes of this chapter are to provide for the regulation of interstate commerce, to reduce the growth in demand for energy in the United States, and to conserve nonrenewable energy resources produced in this Nation and elsewhere, without inhibiting beneficial economic growth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>