<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8256" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8256/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8256/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8256"><akn:num>8256</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives for agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8256. Incentives for agencies(a) Contracts(1) Each agency shall establish a program of incentives for conserving, and otherwise making more efficient use of, energy as a result of entering into contracts under subchapter VII of this chapter.

(2) The Secretary shall, not later than 18 months after October 24, 1992, and after consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator of General Services, develop appropriate procedures and methods for use by agencies to implement the incentives referred to in paragraph (1).


(b) Federal Energy Efficiency Fund(1) The Secretary shall establish a Federal Energy Efficiency Fund to provide grants to agencies to assist them in meeting the requirements of section 8253 of this title.

(2) Not later than June 30, 1993, the Secretary shall issue guidelines to be followed by agencies submitting proposals for such grants. All agencies shall be eligible to submit proposals for grants under the Fund.

(3) The Secretary shall award grants from the Fund after a competitive assessment of the technical and economic effectiveness of each agency proposal. The Secretary shall consider the following factors in determining whether to provide funding under this subsection:(A) The cost-effectiveness of the project.

(B) The amount of energy and cost savings anticipated to the Federal Government.

(C) The amount of funding committed to the project by the agency requesting financial assistance.

(D) The extent that a proposal leverages financing from other non-Federal sources.

(E) Any other factor which the Secretary determines will result in the greatest amount of energy and cost savings to the Federal Government.


(4) There are authorized to be appropriated, to remain available to be expended, to carry out this subsection not more than $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1994, $50,000,000 for fiscal year 1995, and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years thereafter.


(c) Utility </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8256_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8256_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Energy Efficiency Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal Energy Efficiency Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8256_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utility incentive programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Utility incentive programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8256_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial incentive program for facility energy managers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Financial incentive program for facility energy managers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8256_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of energy and water savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Retention of energy and water savings An agency may retain any funds appropriated to that agency for energy expenditures, water expenditures, or wastewater treatment expenditures, at buildings subject to the requirements of section 8253(a) and (b) of this title, that are not made because of energy savings or water savings. Except as otherwise provided by law, such funds may be used only for energy efficiency, water conservation, or unconventional and renewable energy resources projects. Such projects shall be subject to the requirements of section 3307 of title 40.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>