<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8257" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8257/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8257/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8257"><akn:num>8257</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Energy Management Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8257. Interagency Energy Management Task Force(a) In generalTo assist the interagency committee organized under section 7266 of this title to coordinate the activities of the Federal Government in promoting energy conservation and the efficient use of energy and in informing non-Federal entities of the Federal experience in energy conservation, the Secretary shall establish an Interagency Energy Management Task Force (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Task Force”).


(b) MembersThe Task Force shall be composed of the chief energy managers of agencies represented on the interagency committee organized under section 7266 of this title.


(c) DutiesThe Task Force shall meet when the Secretary requests, but not less often than twice a year, to—(1) assess the progress of the various agencies in achieving energy savings;

(2) collect and disseminate information to agencies, States, local governments, and the public on effective survey techniques, innovative approaches to the efficient use of energy, incentive programs developed under section 8256 of this title, innovative contracting methods developed under subchapter VII of this chapter, the use of cogeneration facilities and renewable resources, and other technologies that promote the conservation and efficient use of energy;

(3) coordinate energy surveys conducted by the agencies;

(4) develop options for use in conserving energy;

(5) report to the committee organized under section 7266 of this title; and

(6) review, from time to time as may be necessary, the regulations relating to building temperature settings to determine whether changes in such regulations would be appropriate to assist in meeting the goals specified in section 8253 of this title.


(Pub. L. 95–619, title V, § 547, Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3279; Pub. L. 100–615, § 2(a), Nov. 5, 1988, 102 Stat. 3187.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1988—Pub. L. 100–615 amended section generally, substituting provisions relating to creation of an Interagen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8257_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To assist the interagency committee organized under section 7266 of this title to coordinate the activities of the Federal Government in promoting energy conservation and the efficient use of energy and in informing non-Federal entities of the Federal experience in energy conservation, the Secretary shall establish an Interagency Energy Management Task Force (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Task Force”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8257_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Members The Task Force shall be composed of the chief energy managers of agencies represented on the interagency committee organized under section 7266 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8257_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Task Force shall meet when the Secretary requests, but not less often than twice a year, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>