<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8262f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8262f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8262f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8262f"><akn:num>8262f</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspector General review and agency accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8262f. Inspector General review and agency accountability(a) Audit surveyNot later than 120 days after October 24, 1992, each Inspector General created to conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to the programs and operations of the establishments listed in section 401(1) of title 5, and the Chief Postal Inspector of the United States Postal Service, in accordance with section 415(f) of title 5 shall—(1) identify agency compliance activities to meet the requirements of section 543 of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act (42 U.S.C. 8253) and any other matters relevant to implementing the goals of such Act; and

(2) determine if the agency has the internal accounting mechanisms necessary to assess the accuracy and reliability of energy consumption and energy cost figures required under such section.


(b) President’s Council on Integrity and Efficiency report to CongressNot later than 150 days after October 24, 1992, the President’s Council on Integrity and Efficiency shall submit a report to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Government Operations, and the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the House of Representatives, on the review conducted by the Inspector General of each agency under this section.


(c) Inspector General reviewEach Inspector General established under section 402 of title 5 is encouraged to conduct periodic reviews of agency compliance with part 3 of title V of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act [42 U.S.C. 8251 et seq.], the provisions of this subtitle,11 See References in Text note below. and other laws relating to energy consumption. Such reviews shall not be inconsistent with the performance of the required duties of the Inspector General’s office.


(Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 160, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2858; Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(b)(82), Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4351.)

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8262f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit survey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Audit survey Not later than 120 days after October 24, 1992, each Inspector General created to conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to the programs and operations of the establishments listed in section 401(1) of title 5, and the Chief Postal Inspector of the United States Postal Service, in accordance with section 415(f) of title 5 shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8262f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>President’s Council on Integrity and Efficiency report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) President’s Council on Integrity and Efficiency report to Congress Not later than 150 days after October 24, 1992, the President’s Council on Integrity and Efficiency shall submit a report to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Government Operations, and the Committee on Public Works and Transportation of the House of Representatives, on the review conducted by the Inspector General of each agency under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8262f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspector General review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inspector General review Each Inspector General established under section 402 of title 5 is encouraged to conduct periodic reviews of agency compliance with part 3 of title V of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act [42 U.S.C. 8251 et seq.], the provisions of this subtitle,11 See References in Text note below. and other laws relating to energy consumption. Such reviews shall not be inconsistent with the performance of the required duties of the Inspector General’s office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>