<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8262d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8262d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8262d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8262d"><akn:num>8262d</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy audit teams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8262d. Energy audit teams(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall assemble from existing personnel with appropriate expertise, and with particular utilization of the national laboratories, and make available to all Federal agencies, one or more energy audit teams which shall be equipped with instruments and other advanced equipment needed to perform energy audits of Federal facilities.


(b) Monitoring programsThe Secretary shall also assist in establishing, at each site that has utilized an energy audit team, a program for monitoring the implementation of energy efficiency improvements based upon energy audit team recommendations, and for recording the operating history of such improvements.


(Pub. L. 102–486, title I, § 158, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2857.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Energy Policy Act of 1992, and not as part of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8262d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall assemble from existing personnel with appropriate expertise, and with particular utilization of the national laboratories, and make available to all Federal agencies, one or more energy audit teams which shall be equipped with instruments and other advanced equipment needed to perform energy audits of Federal facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8262d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Monitoring programs The Secretary shall also assist in establishing, at each site that has utilized an energy audit team, a program for monitoring the implementation of energy efficiency improvements based upon energy audit team recommendations, and for recording the operating history of such improvements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>