<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8276" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8276/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8276/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8276"><akn:num>8276</akn:num><akn:heading>System evaluation and purchase program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8276. System evaluation and purchase program(a) ProgramThe Secretary shall establish, within 60 days after November 9, 1978, a photovoltaic systems evaluation and purchase program to provide such systems as are required by the Federal agencies to carry out this part. In acquiring photovoltaic solar electric systems under this part, the Secretary (or other Federal agency acting under delegation from the Secretary) shall insure that such systems reflect to the maximum extent practicable the most advanced and reliable technologies and shall schedule purchases in a manner which will stimulate the early development of a permanent low-cost private photovoltaic production capability in the United States, and to stimulate the private sector market for photovoltaic power systems. The Secretary and other Federal agencies acting under delegation from the Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriated funds, procure not more than 30 megawatts of photovoltaic solar electric systems during fiscal years ending September 30, 1979, September 30, 1980, and September 30, 1981.


(b) Other procurementNothing in this part shall preclude any Federal agency from directly procuring a photovoltaic solar electric system (in lieu of obtaining one under the program under subsection (a)), except that any such Federal agency shall consult with the Secretary before procuring such a system.


(Pub. L. 95–619, title V, § 567, Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3281; Pub. L. 96–294, title IV, § 407(2)(C), (D), June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 717.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1980—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 96–294 inserted provisions relating to Federal agencies acting under delegations from the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8276_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program The Secretary shall establish, within 60 days after November 9, 1978, a photovoltaic systems evaluation and purchase program to provide such systems as are required by the Federal agencies to carry out this part. In acquiring photovoltaic solar electric systems under this part, the Secretary (or other Federal agency acting under delegation from the Secretary) shall insure that such systems reflect to the maximum extent practicable the most advanced and reliable technologies and shall schedule purchases in a manner which will stimulate the early development of a permanent low-cost private photovoltaic production capability in the United States, and to stimulate the private sector market for photovoltaic power systems. The Secretary and other Federal agencies acting under delegation from the Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriated funds, procure not more than 30 megawatts of photovoltaic solar electric systems during fiscal years ending September 30, 1979</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8276_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other procurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other procurement Nothing in this part shall preclude any Federal agency from directly procuring a photovoltaic solar electric system (in lieu of obtaining one under the program under subsection (a)), except that any such Federal agency shall consult with the Secretary before procuring such a system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>