<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8301"><akn:num>8301</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings; statement of purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8301. Findings; statement of purposes(a) FindingsThe Congress finds that—(1) the protection of public health and welfare, the preservation of national security, and the regulation of interstate commerce require the establishment of a program for the expended 11 So in original. Probably should be “expanded”. use, consistent with applicable environmental requirements, of coal and other alternate fuels as primary energy sources for existing and new electric powerplants; and

(2) the purposes of this chapter are furthered in cases in which coal or other alternate fuels are used by electric powerplants, consistent with applicable environmental requirements, as primary energy sources in lieu of natural gas or petroleum.


(b) Statement of purposesThe purpose 22 So in original. Probably should be “purposes”. of this chapter, which shall be carried out in a manner consistent with applicable environmental requirements, are—(1) to reduce the importation of petroleum and increase the Nation’s capability to use indigenous energy resources of the United States to the extent such reduction and use further the goal of national energy self-sufficiency and otherwise are in the best interests of the United States;

(2) to encourage and foster the greater use of coal and other alternate fuels, in lieu of natural gas and petroleum, as a primary energy source;

(3) to the extent permitted by this chapter, to encourage the use of synthetic gas derived from coal or other alternate fuels;

(4) to encourage the rehabilitation and upgrading of railroad service and equipment necessary to transport coal to regions or States which can use coal in greater quantities;

(5) to encourage the modernization or replacement of existing and new electric powerplants which utilize natural gas or petroleum as a primary energy source and which cannot utilize coal or other alternate fuels where to do so furthers the conservation of natural gas and petroleum;

(6) to require that existing and new electric p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8301_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings The Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8301_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Statement of purposes The purpose 22 So in original. Probably should be “purposes”. of this chapter, which shall be carried out in a manner consistent with applicable environmental requirements, are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>