<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8311"><akn:num>8311</akn:num><akn:heading>Coal capability of new electric powerplants; certification of compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8311. Coal capability of new electric powerplants; certification of compliance(a) General prohibitionExcept to such extent as may be authorized under part B, no new electric powerplant may be constructed or operated as a base load powerplant without the capability to use coal or another alternate fuel as a primary energy source.


(b) Capability to use coal or alternate fuelAn electric powerplant has the capability to use coal or another alternate fuel for purposes of this section if such electric powerplant—(1) has sufficient inherent design characteristics to permit the addition of equipment (including all necessary pollution devices) necessary to render such electric powerplant capable of using coal or another alternate fuel as its primary energy source; and

(2) is not physically, structurally, or technologically precluded from using coal or another alternate fuel as its primary energy source.


Capability to use coal or another alternate fuel shall not be interpreted to require any such powerplant to be immediately able to use coal or another alternate fuel as its primary energy source on its initial day of operation.

(c) Applicability to base load powerplants(1) This section shall apply only to base load powerplants, and shall not apply to peakload powerplants or intermediate load powerplants.

(2) For the purposes of this section, hours of electrical generation pursuant to emergency situations, as defined by the Secretary and reported to the Secretary, shall not be included in a determination of whether a powerplant is being operated as a base load powerplant.


(d) Self-certification(1) In order to meet the requirement of subsection (a), the owner or operator of any new electric powerplant to be operated as a base load powerplant proposing to use natural gas or petroleum as its primary energy source shall certify to the Secretary prior to construction, or prior to operation as a base load powerplant in the case of a new electric powerplant operated as a p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General prohibition Except to such extent as may be authorized under part B, no new electric powerplant may be constructed or operated as a base load powerplant without the capability to use coal or another alternate fuel as a primary energy source.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capability to use coal or alternate fuel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Capability to use coal or alternate fuel An electric powerplant has the capability to use coal or another alternate fuel for purposes of this section if such electric powerplant— Capability to use coal or another alternate fuel shall not be interpreted to require any such powerplant to be immediately able to use coal or another alternate fuel as its primary energy source on its initial day of operation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to base load powerplants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicability to base load powerplants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8311_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Self-certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>