<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8354" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8354/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8354/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8354"><akn:num>8354</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions; compliance plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8354. Terms and conditions; compliance plans(a) Terms and conditions generallyAny exemption from any prohibition under this part shall be on such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate, including terms and conditions requiring the use of effective fuel conservation measures which are practicable and consistent with the purposes of this chapter. In the case of any temporary exemption, the terms and conditions (which may include a compliance plan meeting the requirements of subsection (b)) shall be designed to insure that upon the expiration of such exemption, the persons and powerplant covered by such exemption will comply with the applicable prohibitions.


(b) Compliance plansA compliance plan meets the requirements of this subsection if it is approved by the Secretary and—(1) contains (A) a schedule indicating how compliance with applicable prohibition of this chapter will occur and (B) evidence of binding contracts for fuel, or facilities for the production of fuel, which would allow for such compliance; and

(2) is revised at such times and to such extent as the Secretary may require to reflect changes in circumstances.


(Pub. L. 95–620, title III, § 314, Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3314; Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(10), May 21, 1987, 101 Stat. 313.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b)(1)(A), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 95–620, Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3289, known as the Powerplant and Industrial Fuel Use Act of 1978, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 8301 of this title and Tables.

Amendments1987—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 100–42 struck out “or installation” after “powerplant”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Exemption for Certain Electric Powerplants as Effective Prior to 180 Days After November 9, 1978For effectiveness of exemption for certain electric powerplants </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8354_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Terms and conditions generally Any exemption from any prohibition under this part shall be on such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate, including terms and conditions requiring the use of effective fuel conservation measures which are practicable and consistent with the purposes of this chapter. In the case of any temporary exemption, the terms and conditions (which may include a compliance plan meeting the requirements of subsection (b)) shall be designed to insure that upon the expiration of such exemption, the persons and powerplant covered by such exemption will comply with the applicable prohibitions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8354_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compliance plans A compliance plan meets the requirements of this subsection if it is approved by the Secretary and—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>