<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8411" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8411/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8411/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8411"><akn:num>8411</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8411. Administrative procedures(a) General rulemakingExcept to the extent otherwise provided in this section or other provisions of this chapter, rules prescribed under this chapter shall be made in accordance with the procedures set forth in section 553 of title 5.


(b) Notices of rules and orders imposing prohibitionsBefore the Secretary prescribes any rule or issues any order imposing a prohibition under this chapter, he shall publish such proposed rule or order in the Federal Register, together with a statement of the reasons for such rule or order and, in the case of a rule, a detailed statement of any special circumstances or characteristics required to be taken into account in prescribing such rule. A copy shall be transmitted to the person who operates any such powerplant required to be specifically identified in such rule or order.


(c) Petitions for exemptions(1) Any petition for an exemption from any prohibition under this chapter shall be filed at such time and shall be in such form as the Secretary shall by rule prescribe. The Secretary, upon receipt of such petition, shall publish a notice thereof in the Federal Register together with a statement of the reasons set forth in such a petition for requesting such exemption, and provide a period of public comment of at least 45 days for written comments thereon. Rules required under this paragraph shall be prescribed not later than 120 days after November 9, 1978.

(2) The Secretary, upon receipt of such petition, shall notify the appropriate State agencies having primary authority to permit or regulate the construction or operation of the electric powerplant which is the subject of such petition, and, to the maximum extent practicable, consult with such agencies.

(3) The Secretary, within 6 months after the period for public comment and hearing applicable to any petition for an exemption, shall issue a final order granting or denying the petition for such exemption, except that the Secretary may exten</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rulemaking Except to the extent otherwise provided in this section or other provisions of this chapter, rules prescribed under this chapter shall be made in accordance with the procedures set forth in section 553 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notices of rules and orders imposing prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notices of rules and orders imposing prohibitions Before the Secretary prescribes any rule or issues any order imposing a prohibition under this chapter, he shall publish such proposed rule or order in the Federal Register, together with a statement of the reasons for such rule or order and, in the case of a rule, a detailed statement of any special circumstances or characteristics required to be taken into account in prescribing such rule. A copy shall be transmitted to the person who operates any such powerplant required to be specifically identified in such rule or order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitions for exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Petitions for exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public comment on prohibitions and exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public comment on prohibitions and exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transcript</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transcript A transcript shall be kept of any public hearing made in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Protection Agency comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Environmental Protection Agency comment A copy of any proposed rule or order to be prescribed or issued by the Secretary which imposes a prohibition under this chapter (other than under section 8374 of this title), or a petition for an exemption (or permit) under this chapter (other than under section 8374 of this title), shall be transmitted by the Secretary to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary shall request such agency to comment thereon within the period provided to the public unless a longer period is provided under the Clean Air Act [42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.]. In any such case, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall be afforded the same opportunity to comment and question as is provided other interested persons under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(16)(E), May 21, 1987, 101 Stat. 313</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other provisions of law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Coordination with other provisions of law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>