<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8433" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8433/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8433/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8433"><akn:num>8433</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8433. Civil penalties(a) General civil penaltyAny person who violates any provision of this chapter, or rule or order thereunder, shall be subject to a civil penalty, which shall be assessed by the Secretary, of not more than $25,000 for each violation. Each day of violation shall constitute a separate violation.


(b) Civil penalty for operation in excess of exemptionIn the case of any electric powerplant granted an exemption, any person who operates such powerplant during any 12-calendar-month period in excess of that authorized in such exemption, shall be liable for a civil penalty, which shall be assessed by the Secretary. The amount of such civil penalty may not exceed $10 per barrel of petroleum or $3 per Mcf of natural gas used in operation of such powerplant in excess of that authorized in such exemption.


(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(20)(C), May 21, 1987, 101 Stat. 314

(d) Assessment(1) Before issuing an order assessing a civil penalty against any person under this chapter, the Secretary shall provide to such person notice of the proposed penalty. Such notice shall inform such person of his opportunity to elect in writing within 30 days after the date of receipt of such notice to have the procedures of paragraph (3) (in lieu of those of paragraph (2)) apply with respect to such assessment.

(2)(A) Unless an election is made within 30 calendar days after receipt of notice under paragraph (1) to have paragraph (3) apply with respect to such penalty, the Secretary shall assess the penalty, by order, after a determination of violation has been made on the record after an opportunity for an agency hearing pursuant to section 554 of title 5 before an administrative law judge appointed under section 3105 of such title 5. Such assessment order shall include the administrative law judge’s findings and the basis for such assessment.

(B) Any person against whom a penalty is assessed under this paragraph may, within 60 calendar days after the date of the o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General civil penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General civil penalty Any person who violates any provision of this chapter, or rule or order thereunder, shall be subject to a civil penalty, which shall be assessed by the Secretary, of not more than $25,000 for each violation. Each day of violation shall constitute a separate violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalty for operation in excess of exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil penalty for operation in excess of exemption In the case of any electric powerplant granted an exemption, any person who operates such powerplant during any 12-calendar-month period in excess of that authorized in such exemption, shall be liable for a civil penalty, which shall be assessed by the Secretary. The amount of such civil penalty may not exceed $10 per barrel of petroleum or $3 per Mcf of natural gas used in operation of such powerplant in excess of that authorized in such exemption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 100–42, § 1(c)(20)(C), May 21, 1987, 101 Stat. 314</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>