<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8456" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8456/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8456/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8456"><akn:num>8456</akn:num><akn:heading>Socioeconomic impacts of increased coal production and other energy development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8456. Socioeconomic impacts of increased coal production and other energy development(a) CommitteeThere is hereby established an interagency committee composed of the heads of the Departments of Energy, Commerce, Interior, Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Health and Human Services, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Appalachian Regional Commission, the Farmers’ Home Administration, the Office of Management and Budget, and such other Federal agencies as the Secretary shall designate. In carrying out its functions the committee shall consult with the National Governors’ Conference and interested persons, organizations, and entities. The chairman of the committee shall be designated by the President. The committee shall terminate 90 days after the submission of its report under subsection (c).


(b) Functions of committeeIt is the function of the committee to conduct a study of the socioeconomic impacts of expanded coal production and rapid energy development in general, on States, including local communities, and on the public, including the adequacy of housing and public, recreational, and cultural facilities for coal miners and their families and the effect of any Federal or State laws or regulations on providing such housing and facilities. The committee shall gather data and information on—(1) the level of assistance provided under this chapter and any other programs related to impact assistance,

(2) the timeliness of assistance in meeting impacts caused by Federal decisions on energy policy as well as private sector decisions, and

(3) the obstacles to effective assistance contained in regulations of existing programs related to impact assistance.


(c) ReportWithin 1 year after the effective date of this chapter, the committee shall submit a detailed report on the results of such study to the Congress, together with any recommendations for additional legislation it may consider appropriate.


(Pub. L. 95–620, title VII, § 746, Nov. 9, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8456_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Committee There is hereby established an interagency committee composed of the heads of the Departments of Energy, Commerce, Interior, Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Health and Human Services, the Environmental Protection Agency, the Appalachian Regional Commission, the Farmers’ Home Administration, the Office of Management and Budget, and such other Federal agencies as the Secretary shall designate. In carrying out its functions the committee shall consult with the National Governors’ Conference and interested persons, organizations, and entities. The chairman of the committee shall be designated by the President. The committee shall terminate 90 days after the submission of its report under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8456_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions of committee It is the function of the committee to conduct a study of the socioeconomic impacts of expanded coal production and rapid energy development in general, on States, including local communities, and on the public, including the adequacy of housing and public, recreational, and cultural facilities for coal miners and their families and the effect of any Federal or State laws or regulations on providing such housing and facilities. The committee shall gather data and information on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8456_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report Within 1 year after the effective date of this chapter, the committee shall submit a detailed report on the results of such study to the Congress, together with any recommendations for additional legislation it may consider appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>