<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8511" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8511/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8511/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8511"><akn:num>8511</akn:num><akn:heading>National and State emergency conservation targets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8511. National and State emergency conservation targets(a) Determination and publication of targets(1) Whenever the President finds, with respect to any energy source for which the President determines a severe energy supply interruption exists or is imminent or that actions to restrain domestic energy demand are required in order to fulfill the obligations of the United States under the international energy program, the President, in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter, may establish monthly emergency conservation targets for any such energy source for the Nation generally and for each State.

(2) Any finding of the President under paragraph (1) shall be promptly transmitted to the Congress, accompanied by such information and analysis as is necessary to provide the basis for such finding, and shall be disseminated to the public.

(3)(A) The State conservation target for any energy source shall be equal to (i) the State base period consumption reduced by (ii) a uniform national percentage.

(B) For the purposes of this subsection, the term “State base period consumption” means, for any month, the product of the following factors, as determined by the President:(i) the consumption of the energy source for which a target is established during the corresponding month in the 12-month period prior to the first month for which the target is established; and

(ii) a growth adjustment factor, which shall be determined on the basis of the trends in the use in that State of such energy source during the 36-month period prior to the first month for which the target is established.


(C)(i) The President shall adjust, to the extent he determines necessary, any State base period consumption to insure that achievement of a target established for that State under this subsection will not impair the attainment of the objectives of section 753(b)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 15.

(ii) The President may, to the extent he determines appropriate, further</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8511_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination and publication of targets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination and publication of targets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8511_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification and publication of targets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification and publication of targets The President shall notify the Governor of each State of each target established under subsection (a) for that State, and shall publish in the Federal Register, the targets, the base period consumption for each State and other data on which the targets are based, and the factors considered under subsection (a)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8511_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of targets for Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of targets for Federal agencies In connection with the establishment of any national target under subsection (a) the President shall make effective an emergency energy conservation plan for the Federal Government, which plan shall be designed to achieve an equal or greater reduction in use of the energy source for which a target is established than the national percentage referred to in subsection (a)(3)(D). Such plan shall contain measures which the President will implement, in accordance with other applicable provisions of law, to reduce on an emergency basis the use of energy by the Federal Government. In developing such plan the President shall consider the potential for emergency reductions in energy use—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8511_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of targets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of targets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8511_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination and publication of actual consumption nationally and State-by-State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Determination and publication of actual consumption nationally and State-by-State Each month the Secretary shall determine and publish in the Federal Register (1) the level of consumption for the most recent month for which the President determines accurate data is available, nationally and for each State, of any energy source for which a target under subsection (a) is in effect, and (2) whether the targets under subsection (a) have been substantially met or are likely to be met.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8511_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential authority not to be delegated</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Presidential authority not to be delegated Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the authority vested in the President under this section may not be delegated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>