<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8512" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8512/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8512/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8512"><akn:num>8512</akn:num><akn:heading>State emergency conservation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8512. State emergency conservation plan(a) State emergency conservation plans(1)(A) Not later than 45 days after the date of the publication of an energy conservation target for a State under section 8511(b) of this title, the Governor of that State shall submit to the Secretary a State emergency conservation plan designed to meet or exceed the emergency conservation target in effect for that State under section 8511(a) of this title. Such plan shall contain such information as the Secretary may reasonably require. At any time, the Governor may, with the approval of the Secretary, amend a plan established under this section.

(B) The Secretary may, for good cause shown, extend to a specific date the period for the submission of any State’s plan under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary publishes in the Federal Register notice of that extension together with the reasons therefor.


(2) Each State is encouraged to submit to the Secretary a State emergency conservation plan as soon as possible after November 5, 1979, and in advance of such publication of any such target. The Secretary may tentatively approve such a plan in accordance with the provisions of this section. For the purposes of this subchapter such tentative approval shall not be construed to result in a delegation of Federal authority to administer or enforce any measure contained in a State plan.


(b) Conservation measures under State plans(1) Each State emergency conservation plan under this section shall provide for emergency reduction in the public and private use of each energy source for which an emergency conservation target is in effect under section 8511 of this title. Such State plan shall contain adequate assurances that measures contained therein will be effectively implemented in that State. Such plan may provide for reduced use of that energy source through voluntary programs or through the application of one or more of the following measures described in such plan:(A) measures which are aut</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8512_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State emergency conservation plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State emergency conservation plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8512_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation measures under State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conservation measures under State plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8512_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Approval of State plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8512_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State administration and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State administration and enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8512_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Civil penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>