<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8521" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8521/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8521/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8521"><akn:num>8521</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum automobile fuel purchase measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8521. Minimum automobile fuel purchase measures(a) General ruleIf the provisions of this subsection are made applicable under subsection (c), no person shall purchase motor fuel from a motor fuel retailer in any transaction for use in any automobile or other vehicle unless—(1) the price for the quantity purchased and placed into the fuel tank of that vehicle equals or exceeds $5.00; or

(2) in any case in which the amount paid for the quantity of motor fuel necessary to fill the fuel tank of that vehicle to capacity is less than $5.00, such person pays to the retailer an additional amount so that the total amount paid in that transaction equals $5.00.


Any person selling motor fuel in transactions to which the provisions of this subsection apply shall display at the point of sale notice of such provisions in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.

(b) $7.00 to be applicable in case of 8-cylinder vehiclesIn applying subsection (a) in the case of any vehicle with an engine having 8 cylinders (or more), “$7.00” shall be substituted for “$5.00”.


(c) Applicability(1) Unless applicable pursuant to paragraph (2), the requirements of subsection (a) shall apply in any State and shall be administered and enforced as provided in subsection (g) only if—(A) the Governor of that State submits a request to the Secretary to have such requirements applicable in that State; and

(B) the attorney general of that State has found that (i) absent a delegation of authority under a Federal law, the Governor lacks the authority under the laws of the State to invoke comparable requirements, (ii) under applicable State law, the Governor and other appropriate State officers and employees are not prevented from administering and enforcing such requirements under a delegation of authority pursuant to Federal law, and (iii) if implemented such requirements would not be contrary to State law.


Subject to paragraph (2), such provisions shall cease to apply in any State if th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8521_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule If the provisions of this subsection are made applicable under subsection (c), no person shall purchase motor fuel from a motor fuel retailer in any transaction for use in any automobile or other vehicle unless— Any person selling motor fuel in transactions to which the provisions of this subsection apply shall display at the point of sale notice of such provisions in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8521_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>$7.00 to be applicable in case of 8-cylinder vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) $7.00 to be applicable in case of 8-cylinder vehicles In applying subsection (a) in the case of any vehicle with an engine having 8 cylinders (or more), “$7.00” shall be substituted for “$5.00”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8521_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8521_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemptions The requirements of subsection (a) shall not apply to any motorcycle or motorpowered bicycle, or to any comparable vehicle as may be determined by the Secretary by regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8521_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of minimum levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Adjustment of minimum levels The Secretary may increase the $5.00 and $7.00 amounts specified in subsections (a) and (b) if the Secretary considers it appropriate. Adjustments under this subsection shall be only in even dollar amounts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8521_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Civil penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8521_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and enforcement delegated to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Administration and enforcement delegated to States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8521_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Coordination with other law The charging and collecting of amounts referred to in subsection (a)(2) under the requirements of subsection (a), or similar amounts collected under comparable requirements under any State law, shall not be considered a violation of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>