<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8621" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8621/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8621/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8621"><akn:num>8621</akn:num><akn:heading>Home energy grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8621. Home energy grants(a) AuthorizationThe Secretary is authorized to make grants, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, to States to assist low-income households, particularly those with the lowest incomes, that pay a high proportion of household income for home energy, primarily in meeting their immediate home energy needs.


(b) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this subchapter (other than section 8626a of this title), $2,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1995 through 1999, such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2000 and 2001, and $5,100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2007. The authorizations of appropriations contained in this subsection are subject to the program year provisions of subsection (c).


(c) Availability of appropriationsAmounts appropriated under this section for any fiscal year for programs and activities under this subchapter shall be made available for obligation in the succeeding fiscal year.


(d) Authorization of appropriations for leveraged resources(1) There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 8626a of this title, $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1999 through 2004, except as provided in paragraph (2).

(2) For any of fiscal years 1999 through 2004 for which the amount appropriated under subsection (b) is not less than $1,400,000,000, there is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 to carry out section 8626a of this title.


(e) Emergency fundsThere is authorized to be appropriated in each fiscal year for payments under this subchapter, in addition to amounts appropriated for distribution to all the States in accordance with section 8623 of this title (other than subsection (e) of such section), $600,000,000 to meet the additional home energy assistance needs of one or more States arising from a natural disaster or other emergency. Funds appropriated pursuant to this subsection are hereby designat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8621_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization The Secretary is authorized to make grants, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, to States to assist low-income households, particularly those with the lowest incomes, that pay a high proportion of household income for home energy, primarily in meeting their immediate home energy needs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8621_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this subchapter (other than section 8626a of this title), $2,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1995 through 1999, such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2000 and 2001, and $5,100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2007. The authorizations of appropriations contained in this subsection are subject to the program year provisions of subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8621_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of appropriations Amounts appropriated under this section for any fiscal year for programs and activities under this subchapter shall be made available for obligation in the succeeding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8621_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for leveraged resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations for leveraged resources</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8621_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Emergency funds There is authorized to be appropriated in each fiscal year for payments under this subchapter, in addition to amounts appropriated for distribution to all the States in accordance with section 8623 of this title (other than subsection (e) of such section), $600,000,000 to meet the additional home energy assistance needs of one or more States arising from a natural disaster or other emergency. Funds appropriated pursuant to this subsection are hereby designated to be emergency requirements pursuant to section 251(b)(2)(D) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 [2 U.S.C. 901(b)(2)(D)], except that such funds shall be made available only after the submission to Congress of a formal budget request by the President (for all or a part of the appropriation pursuant to this subsection) that includes a designation of the amount requested as an emergency requirement as defined in such Act [2 U.S.C. 900 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>