<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8622" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8622/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8622/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8622"><akn:num>8622</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8622. Definitions
As used in this subchapter:(1) The term “emergency” means—(A) a natural disaster;

(B) a significant home energy supply shortage or disruption;

(C) a significant increase in the cost of home energy, as determined by the Secretary;

(D) a significant increase in home energy disconnections reported by a utility, a State regulatory agency, or another agency with necessary data;

(E) a significant increase in participation in a public benefit program such as the supplemental nutrition assistance program carried out under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.), the national program to provide supplemental security income carried out under title XVI of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.), or the State temporary assistance for needy families program carried out under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.), as determined by the head of the appropriate Federal agency;

(F) a significant increase in unemployment, layoffs, or the number of households with an individual applying for unemployment benefits, as determined by the Secretary of Labor; or

(G) an event meeting such criteria as the Secretary, in the discretion of the Secretary, may determine to be appropriate.


(2) The term “energy burden” means the expenditures of the household for home energy divided by the income of the household.

(3) The term “energy crisis” means weather-related and supply shortage emergencies and other household energy-related emergencies.

(4) The term “highest home energy needs” means the home energy requirements of a household determined by taking into account both the energy burden of such household and the unique situation of such household that results from having members of vulnerable populations, including very young children, individuals with disabilities, and frail older individuals.

(5) The term “household” means any individual or group of individuals who are living together as one economic unit for</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “emergency” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “energy burden” means the expenditures of the household for home energy divided by the income of the household.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “energy crisis” means weather-related and supply shortage emergencies and other household energy-related emergencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “highest home energy needs” means the home energy requirements of a household determined by taking into account both the energy burden of such household and the unique situation of such household that results from having members of vulnerable populations, including very young children, individuals with disabilities, and frail older individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “household” means any individual or group of individuals who are living together as one economic unit for whom residential energy is customarily purchased in common or who make undesignated payments for energy in the form of rent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “home energy” means a source of heating or cooling in residential dwellings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “natural disaster” means a weather event (relating to cold or hot weather), flood, earthquake, tornado, hurricane, or ice storm, or an event meeting such other criteria as the Secretary, in the discretion of the Secretary, may determine to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “poverty level” means, with respect to a household in any State, the income poverty line as prescribed and revised at least annually pursuant to section 9902(2) of this title, as applicable to such State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8622_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “State” means each of the several States and the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>