<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8624" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8624/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8624/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8624"><akn:num>8624</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications and requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8624. Applications and requirements(a) Form; assurances; public hearings(1) Each State desiring to receive an allotment for any fiscal year under this subchapter shall submit an application to the Secretary. Each such application shall be in such form as the Secretary shall require. Each such application shall contain assurances by the chief executive officer of the State that the State will meet the conditions enumerated in subsection (b).

(2) After the expiration of the first fiscal year for which a State receives funds under this subchapter, no funds shall be allotted to such State for any fiscal year under this subchapter unless such State conducts public hearings with respect to the proposed use and distribution of funds to be provided under this subchapter for such fiscal year.


(b) Certifications required for covered activitiesAs part of the annual application required by subsection (a), the chief executive officer of each State shall certify that the State agrees to—(1) use the funds available under this subchapter to—(A) conduct outreach activities and provide assistance to low income households in meeting their home energy costs, particularly those with the lowest incomes that pay a high proportion of household income for home energy, consistent with paragraph (5);

(B) intervene in energy crisis situations;

(C) provide low-cost residential weatherization and other cost-effective energy-related home repair; and

(D) plan, develop, and administer the State’s program under this subchapter including leveraging programs,


and the State agrees not to use such funds for any purposes other than those specified in this subchapter;

(2) make payments under this subchapter only with respect to—(A) households in which 1 or more individuals are receiving—(i) assistance under the State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.];

(ii) supplemental security income payments under title XVI of the Social Security Act [</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form; assurances; public hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Form; assurances; public hearings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certifications required for covered activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certifications required for covered activities As part of the annual application required by subsection (a), the chief executive officer of each State shall certify that the State agrees to— The Secretary may not prescribe the manner in which the States will comply with the provisions of this subsection. The Secretary shall issue regulations to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse in the programs assisted by this subchapter. Not later than 18 months after May 18, 1994, the Secretary shall develop model performance goals and measurements in consultation with State, territorial, tribal, and local grantees, that the States may use to assess the success of the States in achieving the purposes of this subchapter. The model performance goals and measurements shall be made available to States to be incorporated, at the option of the States, into the plans for fiscal year 1997. The Secretary may request data relevant to the development of model performance goals and measurements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan; revision; public inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State plan; revision; public inspection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expending of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expending of funds The State shall expend funds in accordance with the State plan under this subchapter or in accordance with revisions applicable to such plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conduct of audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conduct of audits Each State shall, in carrying out the requirements of subsection (b)(10), obtain financial and compliance audits of any funds which the State receives under this subchapter. Such audits shall be made public within the State on a timely basis. The audits shall be conducted in accordance with chapter 75 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments or assistance not to be deemed income or resources for any purpose under Federal or State law; determination of excess shelter expense deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Payments or assistance not to be deemed income or resources for any purpose under Federal or State law; determination of excess shelter expense deduction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment of funds expended improperly; offset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Repayment of funds expended improperly; offset The State shall repay to the United States amounts found not to have been expended in accordance with this subchapter or the Secretary may offset such amounts against any other amount to which the State is or may become entitled under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic evaluation of expenditures by Comptroller General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Periodic evaluation of expenditures by Comptroller General The Comptroller General of the United States shall, from time to time 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. evaluate the expenditures by States of grants under this subchapter in order to assure that expenditures are consistent with the provisions of this subchapter and to determine the effectiveness of the State in accomplishing the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain recipients of supplemental security income ineligible for payments or assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Certain recipients of supplemental security income ineligible for payments or assistance A household which is described in subsection (b)(2)(A) solely by reason of clause (ii) thereof shall not be treated as a household described in subsection (b)(2) if the eligibility of the household is dependent upon—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8624_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>State verification of income eligibility; policies and procedures applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) State verification of income eligibility; policies and procedures applicable In verifying income eligibility for purposes of subsection (b)(2)(B), the State may apply procedures and policies consistent with procedures and policies used by the State agency administering programs under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.], under title XX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1397 et seq.], under subtitle B of title VI of this Act (relating to community services block grant program) [42 U.S.C. 9901 et seq.], under any other provision of law which carries out programs which were administered under the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.] before August 13, 1981, or under other income assistance or service programs (as determined by the State).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>