<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8626b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8626b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8626b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8626b"><akn:num>8626b</akn:num><akn:heading>Residential Energy Assistance Challenge option (R.E.A.Ch.)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8626b. Residential Energy Assistance Challenge option (R.E.A.Ch.)(a) PurposeThe purpose of the Residential Energy Assistance Challenge (in this section referred to as “R.E.A.Ch.”) program is to—(1) minimize health and safety risks that result from high energy burdens on low-income Americans;

(2) prevent homelessness as a result of inability to pay energy bills;

(3) increase the efficiency of energy usage by low-income families; and

(4) target energy assistance to individuals who are most in need.


(b) Funding(1) AllocationFor each fiscal year, the Secretary may allocate not more than 25 percent of the amount made available pursuant to section 8621(d) of this title for such fiscal year to a R.E.A.Ch. fund for the purpose of making incentive grants to States that submit qualifying plans that are approved by the Secretary as R.E.A.Ch. initiatives. States may use such grants for the costs of planning, implementing, and evaluating the initiative.


(2) ReservationThe Secretary shall reserve from any funds allocated under this subsection, funds to make additional payments to State R.E.A.Ch. programs that—(A) have energy efficiency education services plans that meet quality standards established by the Secretary in consultation with the Secretary of Energy; and

(B) have the potential for being replicable model designs for other programs.


States shall use such supplemental funds for the implementation and evaluation of the energy efficiency education services.


(c) Criteria(1) In generalNot later than May 31, 1995, the Secretary shall establish criteria for approving State plans required by subsection (a), for energy efficiency education quality standards described in subsection (b)(2)(A), and for the distribution of funds to States with approved plans.


(2) DocumentationNotwithstanding the limitations of section 8624(b) of this title regarding the authority of the Secretary with respect to plans, the Secretary may require a State to provide appropriate documenta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8626b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of the Residential Energy Assistance Challenge (in this section referred to as “R.E.A.Ch.”) program is to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8626b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8626b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8626b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Focus</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Focus The State may designate all or part of the State, or all or part of the client population, as a focus of its R.E.A.Ch. initiative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8626b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8626b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost or function</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cost or function None of the costs of providing services or benefits under this section shall be considered to be an administrative cost or function for purposes of any limitation on administrative costs or functions contained in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>