<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8791...8793" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8791...8793/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8791...8793/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8791___8793"><akn:num>8791...8793</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 8791 to 8793. Omitted
Editorial Notes
Codification
Sections 8791 to 8793 were omitted from the Code in view of termination of United States Synthetic Fuels Corporation. See note below.
Section 8791, Pub. L. 96–294, title I, § 191, June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 681, related to dates for termination of awards or commitments by Corporation.
Section 8792, Pub. L. 96–294, title I, § 192, June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 681, related to termination of Corporation’s affairs.
Section 8793, Pub. L. 96–294, title I, § 193, June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 681, transferred Corporation’s powers to Department of the Treasury.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Termination of United States Synthetic Fuels CorporationPub. L. 99–272, title VII, subtitle E, Apr. 7, 1986, 100 Stat. 143, as amended by Pub. L. 101–508, title VI, § 6401, Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1388–319, provided that:
“SEC. 7401. SHORT TITLE.“This subtitle may be cited as the ‘Synthetic Fuels Corporation Act of 1985’.


“SEC. 7402. CESSATION OF FINANCIAL ASSISTANCE AUTHORITY.“Effective on the date of enactment of this Act [Apr. 7, 1986], the United States Synthetic Fuels Corporation (hereafter in this subtitle referred to as the ‘Corporation’) may not make any legally binding awards or commitments for financial assistance (including any changes in an existing award or commitment) pursuant to the Energy Security Act [Pub. L. 96–294; see Short Title note set out under section 8801 of this title] for synthetic fuel project proposals, except that nothing in this Act [see Tables for classification] shall impair or alter the powers, duties, rights, obligations, privileges, or liabilities of the Corporation, its Board or Chairman, or project sponsors in the performance and completion of the terms and undertakings of a legally binding award or commitment entered into prior to the date of enactment of this Act.


“SEC. 7403. TERMINATION OF THE CORPORATION.“(a) Within 60 days of the date of enactment of this Act [Apr. 7, 1986], the Directors </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>