<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8818" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8818/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8818/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8818"><akn:num>8818</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8818. Reports(a) Repealed. Pub. L. 99–386, title I, § 101(a), Aug. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 821

(b) Comprehensive list of loans, grants, etc.Within 120 days after June 30, 1980, the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Congress a comprehensive list of all the types of loans, grants, incentives, rebates, or any other such private, State, or Federal economic or financial benefits now in effect or proposed which can be or have been used for production of alcohol to be used as a motor fuel or petroleum substitute.


(c) Annual reports; report evaluating overall impact and plan for termination of Office of Alcohol Fuels(1)(A) The Office of Alcohol Fuels shall submit to the Congress and the President annual reports containing a general description of the Office’s operations during the year and a description and evaluation of each biomass energy project for which financial assistance by the Office is then in effect.

(B) Each annual report shall describe progress made toward meeting the goals of this subchapter and contain specific recommendations on what actions the Congress could take in order to facilitate the work of the Office in achieving such goals.

(C) Each annual report under this subsection shall contain financial statements prepared by the Office.


(2) On or before September 30, 1990, the Office shall submit to the Congress and the President a report evaluating the overall impact made by the Office and describing the status of each biomass energy project which has received financial assistance under this subchapter from the Office. Such report shall contain a plan for the termination of the work of the Office.


(Pub. L. 96–294, title II, § 218, June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 695; Pub. L. 99–386, title I, § 101(a), Aug. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 821.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1986—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 99–386 struck out subsec. (a) which related to submission of quarterly reports to the President and Congress by Secretary of Agriculture a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8818_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 99–386, title I, § 101(a), Aug. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 821</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8818_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive list of loans, grants, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Comprehensive list of loans, grants, etc. Within 120 days after June 30, 1980, the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Congress a comprehensive list of all the types of loans, grants, incentives, rebates, or any other such private, State, or Federal economic or financial benefits now in effect or proposed which can be or have been used for production of alcohol to be used as a motor fuel or petroleum substitute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8818_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports; report evaluating overall impact and plan for termination of Office of Alcohol Fuels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual reports; report evaluating overall impact and plan for termination of Office of Alcohol Fuels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>