<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8833" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8833/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8833/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8833"><akn:num>8833</akn:num><akn:heading>Guaranteed construction loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8833. Guaranteed construction loans(a) Authority of Secretary of EnergySubject to sections 8835 and 8836 of this title, the Secretary of Energy may commit to guarantee, and guarantee, against loss on up to 90 per centum of the principal and interest, any loan which is made solely to provide funds for the construction of a municipal waste energy proj­ect and which does not exceed 90 per centum of the cost of the construction of the project involved, as estimated by the Secretary on the date of the guarantee or commitment to guarantee.


(b) Estimated project construction costs as determinative of revised amount of guaranteeIn the event the total estimated costs of construction of the project thereafter exceed the total estimated costs initially determined by the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary may in addition, upon application therefor, guarantee, against loss on up to 90 per centum of the principal and interest, a loan for so much of the additional estimated total costs as does not exceed 10 per centum of the total estimated costs.


(c) Terms and conditionsThe terms and conditions of loan guarantees under this section shall provide that, if the Secretary of Energy makes a payment of principal or interest upon the default by a borrower, the Secretary shall be subrogated to the rights of the recipient of such payment (and such subrogation shall be expressly set forth in the loan guarantee or related agreements).


(d) Termination, cancellation, or revocation, and conclusive nature of guaranteeAny loan guarantee under this section shall not be terminated, canceled, or otherwise revoked, except in accordance with the terms thereof and shall be conclusive evidence that such guarantee complies fully with the provisions of this chapter and of the approval and legality of the principal amount, interest rate, and all other terms of the securities, obligations, or loans and of the guarantee.


(e) Payment to lenderIf the Secretary of Energy determines that—(1) the borro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8833_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary of Energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary of Energy Subject to sections 8835 and 8836 of this title, the Secretary of Energy may commit to guarantee, and guarantee, against loss on up to 90 per centum of the principal and interest, any loan which is made solely to provide funds for the construction of a municipal waste energy proj­ect and which does not exceed 90 per centum of the cost of the construction of the project involved, as estimated by the Secretary on the date of the guarantee or commitment to guarantee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8833_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estimated project construction costs as determinative of revised amount of guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Estimated project construction costs as determinative of revised amount of guarantee In the event the total estimated costs of construction of the project thereafter exceed the total estimated costs initially determined by the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary may in addition, upon application therefor, guarantee, against loss on up to 90 per centum of the principal and interest, a loan for so much of the additional estimated total costs as does not exceed 10 per centum of the total estimated costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8833_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms and conditions The terms and conditions of loan guarantees under this section shall provide that, if the Secretary of Energy makes a payment of principal or interest upon the default by a borrower, the Secretary shall be subrogated to the rights of the recipient of such payment (and such subrogation shall be expressly set forth in the loan guarantee or related agreements).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8833_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination, cancellation, or revocation, and conclusive nature of guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination, cancellation, or revocation, and conclusive nature of guarantee Any loan guarantee under this section shall not be terminated, canceled, or otherwise revoked, except in accordance with the terms thereof and shall be conclusive evidence that such guarantee complies fully with the provisions of this chapter and of the approval and legality of the principal amount, interest rate, and all other terms of the securities, obligations, or loans and of the guarantee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8833_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment to lender</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment to lender If the Secretary of Energy determines that— then the Secretary may pay to the lender under a loan guarantee agreement an amount not greater than the principal and interest which the borrower is obligated to pay to such lender, if the borrower agrees to reimburse the Secretary for such payment on terms and conditions, including interest, which the Secretary determines are sufficient to protect the financial interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8833_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preconditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preconditions A loan may not be guaranteed under this section unless the applicant for such loan has established to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Energy that the lender is not willing without such a guarantee to extend credit to the applicant at reasonable rates and terms, taking into consideration prevailing market rates and terms for loans for similar periods of time, to finance the construction of the project for which such loan is sought.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8833_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of interest; tax consequences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payment of interest; tax consequences</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8833_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>