<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8835" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8835/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8835/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8835"><akn:num>8835</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirements regarding financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8835. General requirements regarding financial assistance(a) Priorities, terms, availability, etc.(1) Priority for financial assistance under the provisions of sections 8832, 8833, and 8834 of this title and the most favorable financial terms available, shall be provided for any municipal waste energy project that will—(A) produce a liquid fuel from municipal waste; or

(B) will displace petroleum or natural gas as a fuel.


(2)(A) With respect to projects producing biomass energy other than biomass fuel, financial assistance under the provisions of sections 8832, 8833, and 8834 of this title shall be available only if the Secretary of Energy finds that the project does not use petroleum or natural gas except for flame stabilization or start-up.

(B) With respect to projects producing biomass fuel, financial assistance under such provisions shall be available to such project only if the Secretary of Energy finds that the Btu content of the biomass fuel produced substantially exceeds the Btu content of any petroleum or natural gas used in the project to produce the biomass fuel.


(3) Financial assistance may not be provided under section 8832, 8833, or 8834 of this title unless the Secretary of Energy finds that necessary municipal waste feedstocks are available and it is reasonable to expect they will continue to be available for the expected economic life of the project.

(4) In providing financial assistance under section 8832, 8833, or 8834 of this title, the Secretary of Energy shall give due consideration to promoting competition.

(5) In determining the amount of financial assistance for any municipal waste energy project which will yield byproducts in addition to biomass energy, the Secretary shall consider the value of such byproducts and the costs attributable to their production.

(6) The Secretary of Energy shall not provide financial assistance under section 8832, 8833, or 8834 of this title for any municipal waste energy unless the Secretary determin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8835_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities, terms, availability, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Priorities, terms, availability, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8835_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms, conditions, maturity, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms, conditions, maturity, etc. Financial assistance may not be provided under section 8832, 8833, or 8834 of this title unless the Secretary of Energy determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8835_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8835_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and recordkeeping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports and recordkeeping</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8835_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of amounts received</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deposit of amounts received All amounts received by the Secretary of Energy as fees, interest, repayment of principal, and any other moneys received by the Secretary from operations under section 8832, 8833, or 8834 of this title shall be deposited in the general fund of 11 So in original. Probably should be “of the”. Treasury of the United States as miscellaneous receipts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8835_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and instruments backed by full faith and credit of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Contracts and instruments backed by full faith and credit of United States All contracts and instruments of the Secretary of Energy to provide, or providing, for financial assistance shall be general obligations of the United States backed by its full faith and credit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8835_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contestability of contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Contestability of contracts Subject to the conditions of any contract for financial assistance, such contract shall be incontestable in the hands of the holder, except as to fraud or material misrepresentation on the part of the holder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8835_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of debt obligations for purchase, sale, or issuance to Federal Financing Bank or any Federal agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Eligibility of debt obligations for purchase, sale, or issuance to Federal Financing Bank or any Federal agency Notwithstanding the provisions of the Federal Financing Bank Act of 1973 (12 U.S.C. 2281 et seq.) or any other provision of law (except as may be specifically provided by reference to this subsection in any Act enacted after June 30, 1980), no debt obligation which is made or committed to be made, or which is guaranteed or committed to be guaranteed by the Secretary of Energy under section 8832, 8833, or 8834 of this title shall be eligible for purchase by, or commitment to purchase by, or sale or issuance to, the Federal Financing Bank or any Federal agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>