<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8871" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8871/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/8871/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8871"><akn:num>8871</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of gasohol in Federal motor vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8871. Use of gasohol in Federal motor vehicles(a) Exercise of President’s authority pursuant to executive order respecting useThe President shall, by executive order, require that motor vehicles which are owned or leased by Federal agencies and are capable of operating on gasohol shall use gasohol where available at reasonable prices and in reasonable quantities.


(b) ExceptionsThe President may provide for exceptions to the requirement of subsection (a) where necessary, including to protect the national security.


(c) Gasohol requirementsSuch executive order shall specify the alcohol-gasoline mixture or mixtures which shall constitute “gasohol” for purposes of such order, as well as specifications for its use.


(Pub. L. 96–294, title II, § 271, June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 710.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Report on Exemptions and Sense of Congress Regarding Purchase of Domestic GasoholPub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VIII, § 841(c), (d), Dec. 5, 1991, 105 Stat. 1449, provided that:
“(c) Report on Exemptions.—The Secretary of Defense shall review all exemptions granted for the Department of Defense, and the Administrator of the General Services Administration shall review all exemptions granted for Federal agencies and departments, to the requirements of section 2398 of title 10, United States Code, and section 271 of the Energy Security Act (Public Law 96–294; 42 U.S.C. 8871) and shall terminate any exemption that the Secretary or the Administrator determines is no longer appropriate. Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [Dec. 5, 1991], the Secretary and the Administrator shall submit jointly to Congress a report on the results of the review, with a justification for the exemptions that remain in effect under those provisions of law.

“(d) Sense of Congress.—It is the sense of Congress that whenever any motor vehicle capable of operating on gasoline or alcohol-gasoline blends that is owned or operated by the Department of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8871_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exercise of President’s authority pursuant to executive order respecting use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Exercise of President’s authority pursuant to executive order respecting use The President shall, by executive order, require that motor vehicles which are owned or leased by Federal agencies and are capable of operating on gasohol shall use gasohol where available at reasonable prices and in reasonable quantities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8871_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions The President may provide for exceptions to the requirement of subsection (a) where necessary, including to protect the national security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8871_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gasohol requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Gasohol requirements Such executive order shall specify the alcohol-gasoline mixture or mixtures which shall constitute “gasohol” for purposes of such order, as well as specifications for its use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>