<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_904"><akn:num>904</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative duties of Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 904. Administrative duties of Commissioner(a) Personnel(1) The Commissioner shall appoint such additional officers and employees as the Commissioner considers necessary to carry out the functions of the Administration under this chapter, and attorneys and experts may be appointed without regard to the civil service laws. Except as otherwise provided in the preceding sentence or in any other provision of law, such officers and employees shall be appointed, and their compensation shall be fixed, in accordance with title 5.

(2) The Commissioner may procure the services of experts and consultants in accordance with the provisions of section 3109 of title 5.

(3) Notwithstanding any requirements of section 3133 of title 5, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall authorize for the Administration a total number of Senior Executive Service positions which is substantially greater than the number of such positions authorized in the Social Security Administration in the Department of Health and Human Services as of immediately before August 15, 1994, to the extent that the greater number of such authorized positions is specified in the comprehensive work force plan as established and revised by the Commissioner under subsection (b)(2). The total number of such positions authorized for the Administration shall not at any time be less than the number of such authorized positions as of immediately before such date.


(b) Budgetary matters(1)(A) The Commissioner shall prepare an annual budget for the Administration, which shall be submitted by the President to the Congress without revision, together with the President’s annual budget for the Administration.

(B) The Commissioner shall include in the annual budget prepared pursuant to subparagraph (A) an itemization of the amount of funds required by the Social Security Administration for the fiscal year covered by the budget to support efforts to combat fraud committed by applicants and beneficiaries.


(2)(A)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Personnel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budgetary matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Budgetary matters</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Employment restriction The total number of positions in the Administration (other than positions established under section 902 of this title) which— may not exceed at any time the equivalent of 20 full-time positions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seal of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Seal of office The Commissioner shall cause a seal of office to be made for the Administration of such design as the Commissioner shall approve. Judicial notice shall be taken of such seal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Data exchanges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>