<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_906"><akn:num>906</akn:num><akn:heading>Training grants for public welfare personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 906. Training grants for public welfare personnel(a) Authorization of appropriationsIn order to assist in increasing the effectiveness and efficiency of administration of public assistance programs by increasing the number of adequately trained public welfare personnel available for work in public assistance programs, there are hereby authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1963, the sum of $3,500,000, and for each fiscal year thereafter the sum of $5,000,000.


(b) Allocation for carrying out direct grant programsSuch portion of the sums appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) for any fiscal year as the Secretary may determine, but not in excess of $1,000,000 in the case of the fiscal year ending June 30, 1963, and $2,000,000 in the case of any fiscal year thereafter, shall be available for carrying out subsection (f). From the remainder of the sums so appropriated for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall make allotments to the States on the basis of (1) population, (2) relative need for trained public welfare personnel, particularly for personnel to provide self-support and self-care services, and (3) financial need.


(c) Payments to States for cost of grant programs to certain agencies and institutionsFrom each State’s allotment under subsection (b), the Secretary shall from time to time pay to such State its costs of carrying out the purposes of this section through (1) grants to public or other nonprofit institutions of higher learning for training personnel employed or preparing for employment in public assistance programs, (2) special courses of study or seminars of short duration conducted for such personnel by experts hired on a temporary basis for the purpose, and (3) establishing and maintaining, directly or through grants to such institutions, fellowships or traineeships for such personnel at such institutions, with such stipends and allowances as may be permitted under regulations of the Secretary.


(d) Advance payments to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations In order to assist in increasing the effectiveness and efficiency of administration of public assistance programs by increasing the number of adequately trained public welfare personnel available for work in public assistance programs, there are hereby authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1963, the sum of $3,500,000, and for each fiscal year thereafter the sum of $5,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation for carrying out direct grant programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocation for carrying out direct grant programs Such portion of the sums appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) for any fiscal year as the Secretary may determine, but not in excess of $1,000,000 in the case of the fiscal year ending June 30, 1963, and $2,000,000 in the case of any fiscal year thereafter, shall be available for carrying out subsection (f). From the remainder of the sums so appropriated for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall make allotments to the States on the basis of (1) population, (2) relative need for trained public welfare personnel, particularly for personnel to provide self-support and self-care services, and (3) financial need.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to States for cost of grant programs to certain agencies and institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments to States for cost of grant programs to certain agencies and institutions From each State’s allotment under subsection (b), the Secretary shall from time to time pay to such State its costs of carrying out the purposes of this section through (1) grants to public or other nonprofit institutions of higher learning for training personnel employed or preparing for employment in public assistance programs, (2) special courses of study or seminars of short duration conducted for such personnel by experts hired on a temporary basis for the purpose, and (3) establishing and maintaining, directly or through grants to such institutions, fellowships or traineeships for such personnel at such institutions, with such stipends and allowances as may be permitted under regulations of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance payments to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Advance payments to States Payments pursuant to subsection (c) shall be made in advance on the basis of estimates by the Secretary and adjustments may be made in future payments under this section to take account of overpayments or underpayments in amounts previously paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reallotments The amount of any allotment to a State under subsection (b) for any fiscal year which the State certifies to the Secretary will not be required for carrying out the purposes of this section in such State shall be available for reallotment from time to time, on such dates as the Secretary may fix, to other States which the Secretary determines have need in carrying out such purposes for sums in excess of those previously allotted to them under this section and will be able to use such excess amounts during such fiscal year; such reallotments to be made on the basis provided in subsection (b) for the initial allotments to the States. Any amount so reallotted to a State shall be deemed part of its allotment under such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct grants to certain agencies and institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Direct grants to certain agencies and institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>