<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9111"><akn:num>9111</akn:num><akn:heading>License for ownership, construction, and operation of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities or </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9111. License for ownership, construction, and operation of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities or plantships(a) License requirementNo person may engage in the ownership, construction, or operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion facility which is documented under the laws of the United States, which is located in whole or in part between the highwater mark and the seaward boundary of the territorial sea of the United States, or which is connected to the United States by pipeline or cable, except in accordance with a license issued pursuant to this chapter. No citizen of the United States may engage in the ownership, construction or operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion plantship except in accordance with a license issued pursuant to this chapter, or in accordance with a license issued by a foreign nation whose licenses are found by the Administrator, after consultation with the Secretary of State, to be compatible with licenses issued pursuant to this chapter.


(b) Documented plantships; documented facilities; facilities located in territorial sea; facilities connected to United States by pipeline or cableThe Administrator shall, upon application and in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, issue, transfer, amend, or renew licenses for the ownership, construction, and operation of—(1) ocean thermal energy conversion plantships documented under the laws of the United States, and

(2) ocean thermal energy conversion facilities documented under the laws of the United States, located in whole or in part between the highwater mark and the seaward boundary of the territorial sea of the United States, or connected to the United States by pipeline or cable.


(c) License issuance prerequisitesThe Administrator may issue a license to a citizen of the United States in accordance with the provisions of this chapter unless—(1) he determines that the applicant cannot or will not comply with applicable laws, regulations, and license conditions</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>License requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) License requirement No person may engage in the ownership, construction, or operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion facility which is documented under the laws of the United States, which is located in whole or in part between the highwater mark and the seaward boundary of the territorial sea of the United States, or which is connected to the United States by pipeline or cable, except in accordance with a license issued pursuant to this chapter. No citizen of the United States may engage in the ownership, construction or operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion plantship except in accordance with a license issued pursuant to this chapter, or in accordance with a license issued by a foreign nation whose licenses are found by the Administrator, after consultation with the Secretary of State, to be compatible with licenses issued pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documented plantships; documented facilities; facilities located in territorial sea; facilities connected to United States by pipeline or cable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Documented plantships; documented facilities; facilities located in territorial sea; facilities connected to United States by pipeline or cable The Administrator shall, upon application and in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, issue, transfer, amend, or renew licenses for the ownership, construction, and operation of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9111_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>License issuance prerequisites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) License issuance prerequisites The Administrator may issue a license to a citizen of the United States in accordance with the provisions of this chapter unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9111_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance conditions; written agreement of compliance; disposal or removal requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Issuance conditions; written agreement of compliance; disposal or removal requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9111_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>License transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) License transfer Upon application, a license issued under this chapter may be transferred if the Administrator determines that such transfer is in the public interest and that the transferee meets the requirements of this chapter and the prerequisites to issuance under subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9111_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>License eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) License eligibility Any United States citizen who otherwise qualifies under the terms of this chapter shall be eligible to be issued a license for the ownership, construction, and operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9111_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>License term and renewal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) License term and renewal Licenses issued under this chapter shall be for a term of not to exceed 25 years. Each licensee shall have a preferential right to renew his license subject to the requirements of subsection (c) of this section, upon such conditions and for such term, not to exceed an additional 10 years upon each renewal, as the Administrator determines to be reasonable and appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>