<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9112"><akn:num>9112</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9112. Procedure(a) Rules and regulationsThe Administrator shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the heads of other Federal agencies, issue regulations to carry out the purposes and provisions of this chapter, in accordance with the provisions of section 553 of title 5, without regard to subsection (a) thereof. Such regulations shall pertain to, but need not be limited to, application for issuance, transfer, renewal, suspension, and termination of licenses. Such regulations shall provide for full consultation and cooperation with all other interested Federal agencies and departments and with any potentially affected coastal State, and for consideration of the views of any interested members of the general public. The Administrator is further authorized, consistent with the purposes and provisions of this chapter, to amend or rescind any such regulation. The Administrator shall complete issuance of final regulations to implement this chapter within 1 year of August 3, 1980.


(b) Site evaluation and preconstruction testingThe Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may, if he determines it to be necessary, prescribe regulations consistent with the purposes of this chapter, relating to those activities in site evaluation and preconstruction testing at potential ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship locations that may (1) adversely affect the environment; (2) interfere with other reasonable uses of the high seas or with authorized uses of the Outer Continental Shelf; or (3) pose a threat to human health and safety. If the Administrator prescribes regulations relating to such activities, such activities may not be undertaken after the effective date of such regulations except in accordance therewith.


(c) Expertise or statutory responsibility descriptionsNot later than 60 days after August 3, 1980, the Secretary of Energy, the Admini</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules and regulations The Administrator shall, after consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the heads of other Federal agencies, issue regulations to carry out the purposes and provisions of this chapter, in accordance with the provisions of section 553 of title 5, without regard to subsection (a) thereof. Such regulations shall pertain to, but need not be limited to, application for issuance, transfer, renewal, suspension, and termination of licenses. Such regulations shall provide for full consultation and cooperation with all other interested Federal agencies and departments and with any potentially affected coastal State, and for consideration of the views of any interested members of the general public. The Administrator is further authorized, consistent with the purposes and provisions of this chapter, to amend or rescind any such regulation. The Administrator shall complete issuance of final regulations to implement this chapter within 1 year of August 3, 1980.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Site evaluation and preconstruction testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Site evaluation and preconstruction testing The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may, if he determines it to be necessary, prescribe regulations consistent with the purposes of this chapter, relating to those activities in site evaluation and preconstruction testing at potential ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship locations that may (1) adversely affect the environment; (2) interfere with other reasonable uses of the high seas or with authorized uses of the Outer Continental Shelf; or (3) pose a threat to human health and safety. If the Administrator prescribes regulations relating to such activities, such activities may not be undertaken after the effective date of such regulations except in accordance therewith.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expertise or statutory responsibility descriptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expertise or statutory responsibility descriptions Not later than 60 days after August 3, 1980, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, the Secretary of the Interior, the Chief of Engineers of the United States Army Corps of Engineers, and the heads of any other Federal departments or agencies having expertise concerning, or jurisdiction over, any aspect of the construction or operation of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities or plantships, shall transmit to the Administrator written description of their expertise or statutory responsibilities pursuant to this chapter or any other Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9112_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9112_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area description; additional license applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Area description; additional license applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9112_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Copies of application to other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Copies of application to other agencies An application filed with the Administrator shall constitute an application for all Federal authorizations required for ownership, construction, and operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship, except for authorizations required by documentation, inspection, certification, construction, and manning laws and regulations administered by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating. At the time notice of any application is published pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, the Administrator shall forward a copy of such application to those Federal agencies and departments with jurisdiction over any aspect of such ownership, construction, or operation for comment, review, or recommendation as to conditions and for such other action as may be required by law. Each agency or department involved shall review the application and, based upon legal considerations within its area of responsibility, r</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9112_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice, comments, and hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notice, comments, and hearing A license may be issued, transferred, or renewed only after public notice, opportunity for comment, and public hearings in accordance with this subsection. At least one such public hearing shall be held in the District of Columbia and in any adjacent coastal State to which a facility is proposed to be directly connected by pipeline or electric transmission cable. Any interested person may present relevant material at any such hearing. After the hearings required by this subsection are concluded, if the Administrator determines that there exist one or more specific and material factual issues which may be resolved by a formal evidentiary hearing, at least one adjudicatory hearing shall be held in the District of Columbia in accordance with the provisions of section 554 of title 5. The record developed in any such adjudicatory hearing shall be part of the basis for the Administrator’s decision to approve or deny a license. Hearings held pursuant to this </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9112_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administrative fee The Administrator shall not take final action on any application unless the applicant has paid to the Administrator a reasonable administrative fee, which shall be deposited into miscellaneous receipts of the Treasury. The amount of the fee imposed by the Administrator on any applicant shall reflect the reasonable administrative costs incurred by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in reviewing and processing the application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9112_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval or denial of application; applications for same area; factors determinative of facility selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Approval or denial of application; applications for same area; factors determinative of facility selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>