<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9117" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9117/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9117/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9117"><akn:num>9117</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of the environment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9117. Protection of the environment(a) Environmental assessment programThe Administrator shall initiate a program to assess the effects on the environment of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships. The program shall include baseline studies of locations where ocean thermal energy conversion facilities or plantships are likely to be sited or operated; and research; and monitoring of the effects of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships in actual operation. The purpose of the program shall be to assess the environmental effects of individual ocean thermal energy facilities and plantships, and to assess the magnitude of any cumulative environmental effects of large numbers of ocean thermal energy facilities and plantships.


(b) Program purposesThe program shall be designed to determine, among other things—(1) any short-term and long-term effects on the environment which may occur as a result of the operation of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships;

(2) the nature and magnitude of any oceanographic, atmospheric, weather, climatic, or biological changes in the environment which may occur as a result of deployment and operation of large numbers of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships;

(3) the nature and magnitude of any oceanographic, biological or other changes in the environment which may occur as a result of the operation of electric transmission cables and equipment located in the water column or on or in the seabed, including the hazards of accidentally severed transmission cables; and

(4) whether the magnitude of one or more of the cumulative environmental effects of deployment and operation of large numbers of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships requires that an upper limit be placed on the number or total capacity of such facilities or plantships to be licensed under this chapter for simultaneous operation, either overall or within specific geographic areas.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9117_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental assessment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Environmental assessment program The Administrator shall initiate a program to assess the effects on the environment of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships. The program shall include baseline studies of locations where ocean thermal energy conversion facilities or plantships are likely to be sited or operated; and research; and monitoring of the effects of ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships in actual operation. The purpose of the program shall be to assess the environmental effects of individual ocean thermal energy facilities and plantships, and to assess the magnitude of any cumulative environmental effects of large numbers of ocean thermal energy facilities and plantships.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9117_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program purposes The program shall be designed to determine, among other things—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9117_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan submittal to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Plan submittal to Congress Within 180 days after August 3, 1980, the Administrator shall prepare a plan to carry out the program described in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, including necessary funding levels for the next 5 fiscal years, and submit the plan to the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9117_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of program to minimum necessary level</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reduction of program to minimum necessary level The program established by subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall be reduced to the minimum necessary to perform baseline studies and to analyze monitoring data, when the Administrator determines that the program has resulted in sufficient knowledge to make the determinations enumerated in subsection (b) of this section with an acceptable level of confidence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9117_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Environmental impact statement The issuance of any license for ownership, construction, and operation of an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship shall be deemed to be a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment for purposes of section 4332(2)(C) of this title. For all timely applications covering proposed facilities in a single application area, and for each application relating to a proposed plantship, the Administrator shall, pursuant to such section 4332(2)(C) of this title and in cooperation with other involved Federal agencies and departments, prepare a single environmental impact statement, which shall fulfill the requirement of all Federal agencies in carrying out their responsibilities pursuant to this chapter to prepare an environmental impact statement. Each such draft environmental impact statement relating to proposed facilities shall be prepared and published within 180 days after notice of the initial applicatio</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9117_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge of pollutants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Discharge of pollutants An ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship licensed under this subchapter shall be deemed not to be a “vessel or other floating craft” for the purposes of section 1362(12)(B) of title 33.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>