<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9141" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9141/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9141/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9141"><akn:num>9141</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations under Merchant Marine Act, 1936</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9141. Determinations under Merchant Marine Act, 1936(a)(1) For the purposes of chapter 535 of title 46, any ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship licensed pursuant to this chapter, and any vessel providing shipping service to or from such an ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship, shall be deemed to be a vessel operated in the foreign commerce of the United States.

(2) The provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection shall apply for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1981.


(b) For the purposes of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 (46 U.S.C. 1177 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. any vessel documented under the laws of the United States and used in providing shipping service to or from any ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship licensed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be deemed to be used in, and used in an essential service in, the foreign commerce or foreign trade of the United States, as defined in section 109 of title 46.

(Pub. L. 96–320, title II, § 201, Aug. 3, 1980, 94 Stat. 991.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(1) and (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 96–320, Aug. 3, 1980, 94 Stat. 974, known as the Ocean Thermal Energy Conversion Act of 1980, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 9101 of this title and Tables.
The Merchant Marine Act, 1936, referred to in subsec. (b), is act June 29, 1936, ch. 858, 49 Stat. 1985, which was classified principally to chapter 27 (§ 1101 et seq.) of the former Appendix to Title 46, Shipping. The Act, with the exception of title V, most of title VI, and sections 301, 801, 802, 809(a), and 909 thereof, was repealed and restated, mainly in subtitle V of Title 46, by Pub. L. 109–304, §§ 8, 19, Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1555, 1710. Title V and sections 301 and 909 of the Act are s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9141_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9141_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For the purposes of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 (46 U.S.C. 1177 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. any vessel documented under the laws of the United States and used in providing shipping service to or from any ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship licensed pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be deemed to be used in, and used in an essential service in, the foreign commerce or foreign trade of the United States, as defined in section 109 of title 46.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>