<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9203" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9203/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9203/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9203"><akn:num>9203</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive program management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9203. Comprehensive program management plan(a) Program activities and periods; consultations with heads of Federal agencies and non-Federal organizationsThe Secretary shall prepare a comprehensive program management plan for the research, development, demonstration, and technology application activities to carry out the purposes of this chapter. The program activities shall be conducted in accordance with such comprehensive plan which shall include—(1) a five-year program for small wind energy systems,

(2) an eight-year program for large wind energy systems, and

(3) a three-year program for wind resource assessment 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.


which shall be consistent with the provisions of sections 9204, 9205, and 9206 of this title. In the preparation of such plan, the Secretary shall consult with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of such other Federal agencies and such public and private organizations as he deems appropriate.

(b) Initial transmittal to Congressional committeesThe Secretary shall transmit the comprehensive program management plan to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate within nine months after September 8, 1980.


(c) Subsequent transmittals to Congress; descriptive statement: current plan, changes, justification for changes, progress, interagency cooperation, and recommendations for achievement of goalsConcurrently with the submission of the President’s annual budget to the Congress for each year after the year in which the comprehensive plan is initially transmitted under subsection (b), the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress a detailed description of the comprehensive plan as then in effect, setting forth the modifications which may be necessary to appropriately revise such plan and any changes in circumstances which may h</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9203_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program activities and periods; consultations with heads of Federal agencies and non-Federal organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program activities and periods; consultations with heads of Federal agencies and non-Federal organizations The Secretary shall prepare a comprehensive program management plan for the research, development, demonstration, and technology application activities to carry out the purposes of this chapter. The program activities shall be conducted in accordance with such comprehensive plan which shall include— which shall be consistent with the provisions of sections 9204, 9205, and 9206 of this title. In the preparation of such plan, the Secretary shall consult with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of such other Federal agencies and such public and private organizations as he deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9203_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial transmittal to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Initial transmittal to Congressional committees The Secretary shall transmit the comprehensive program management plan to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate within nine months after September 8, 1980.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9203_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent transmittals to Congress; descriptive statement: current plan, changes, justification for changes, progress, interagency cooperation, and recommendations for achievement of goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subsequent transmittals to Congress; descriptive statement: current plan, changes, justification for changes, progress, interagency cooperation, and recommendations for achievement of goals Concurrently with the submission of the President’s annual budget to the Congress for each year after the year in which the comprehensive plan is initially transmitted under subsection (b), the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress a detailed description of the comprehensive plan as then in effect, setting forth the modifications which may be necessary to appropriately revise such plan and any changes in circumstances which may have occurred since the plan or the last previous modification thereof was transmitted in accordance with this section. The detailed description of the comprehensive plan under this subsection shall include but need not be limited to a statement setting forth with respect to each of the programs under this chapter any changes in— Such description shall also include a d</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>