<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9305"><akn:num>9305</akn:num><akn:heading>Magnetic fusion engineering center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9305. Magnetic fusion engineering center(a) Development planThe Secretary shall develop a plan for the creation of a national magnetic fusion engineering center for the purpose of accelerating fusion technology development via the concentration and coordination of major magnetic fusion engineering devices and associated activities at such a national center.


(b) Factors considered in formulation of development planIn developing the plan, the Secretary shall include relevant factors including, but not limited to—(1) means of saving cost and time through the establishment of the national center relative to the cost and schedule currently projected for the program;

(2) means of providing common facilities to be shared by many magnetic fusion concepts;

(3) assessment of the environmental and safety-related aspects of the national center;

(4) provisions for international cooperation in magnetic fusion activities at the national center;

(5) provision of access to facilities for the broader technical involvement of domestic industry and universities in the magnetic fusion energy program;

(6) siting criteria for the national center including a list of potential sites;

(7) the advisability of establishing such a center considering all factors, including the alternative means and associated costs of pursuing such technology; and

(8) changes in the management structure of the magnetic fusion program to allow more effective direction of activities related to the national center.


(c) Report to Congressional committeesThe Secretary shall submit not later than July 1, 1981, a report to the House Committee on Science and Technology and the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources characterizing the plan and setting forth the steps necessary for implementation of the plan, including any steps already implemented.


(Pub. L. 96–386, § 6, Oct. 7, 1980, 94 Stat. 1541.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Committee on Science and Technology of H</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development plan The Secretary shall develop a plan for the creation of a national magnetic fusion engineering center for the purpose of accelerating fusion technology development via the concentration and coordination of major magnetic fusion engineering devices and associated activities at such a national center.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors considered in formulation of development plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Factors considered in formulation of development plan In developing the plan, the Secretary shall include relevant factors including, but not limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report to Congressional committees The Secretary shall submit not later than July 1, 1981, a report to the House Committee on Science and Technology and the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources characterizing the plan and setting forth the steps necessary for implementation of the plan, including any steps already implemented.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>