<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9603" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9603/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9603/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9603"><akn:num>9603</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification requirements respecting released substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9603. Notification requirements respecting released substances(a) Notice to National Response Center upon release from vessel or offshore or onshore facility by person in charge; conveyance of notice by CenterAny person in charge of a vessel or an offshore or an onshore facility shall, as soon as he has knowledge of any release (other than a federally permitted release) of a hazardous substance from such vessel or facility in quantities equal to or greater than those determined pursuant to section 9602 of this title, immediately notify the National Response Center established under the Clean Water Act [33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.] of such release. The National Response Center shall convey the notification expeditiously to all appropriate Government agencies, including the Governor of any affected State.


(b) Penalties for failure to notify; use of notice or information pursuant to notice in criminal caseAny person—(1) in charge of a vessel from which a hazardous substance is released, other than a federally permitted release, into or upon the navigable waters of the United States, adjoining shorelines, or into or upon the waters of the contiguous zone, or

(2) in charge of a vessel from which a hazardous substance is released, other than a federally permitted release, which may affect natural resources belonging to, appertaining to, or under the exclusive management authority of the United States (including resources under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act [16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.]), and who is otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the United States at the time of the release, or

(3) in charge of a facility from which a hazardous substance is released, other than a federally permitted release,


in a quantity equal to or greater than that determined pursuant to section 9602 of this title who fails to notify immediately the appropriate agency of the United States Government as soon as he has knowledge of such release or who submits in such</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9603_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to National Response Center upon release from vessel or offshore or onshore facility by person in charge; conveyance of notice by Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice to National Response Center upon release from vessel or offshore or onshore facility by person in charge; conveyance of notice by Center Any person in charge of a vessel or an offshore or an onshore facility shall, as soon as he has knowledge of any release (other than a federally permitted release) of a hazardous substance from such vessel or facility in quantities equal to or greater than those determined pursuant to section 9602 of this title, immediately notify the National Response Center established under the Clean Water Act [33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.] of such release. The National Response Center shall convey the notification expeditiously to all appropriate Government agencies, including the Governor of any affected State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9603_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for failure to notify; use of notice or information pursuant to notice in criminal case</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalties for failure to notify; use of notice or information pursuant to notice in criminal case Any person— in a quantity equal to or greater than that determined pursuant to section 9602 of this title who fails to notify immediately the appropriate agency of the United States Government as soon as he has knowledge of such release or who submits in such a notification any information which he knows to be false or misleading shall, upon conviction, be fined in accordance with the applicable provisions of title 18 or imprisoned for not more than 3 years (or not more than 5 years in the case of a second or subsequent conviction), or both. Notification received pursuant to this subsection or information obtained by the exploitation of such notification shall not be used against any such person in any criminal case, except a prosecution for perjury or for giving a false statement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9603_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Administrator of EPA of existence of storage, etc., facility by owner or operator; exception; time, manner, and form of notice; penalties for failure to notify; use of notice or information pursuant to notice in criminal case</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice to Administrator of EPA of existence of storage, etc., facility by owner or operator; exception; time, manner, and form of notice; penalties for failure to notify; use of notice or information pursuant to notice in criminal case Within one hundred and eighty days after December 11, 1980, any person who owns or operates or who at the time of disposal owned or operated, or who accepted hazardous substances for transport and selected, a facility at which hazardous substances (as defined in section 9601(14)(C) of this title) are or have been stored, treated, or disposed of shall, unless such facility has a permit issued under, or has been accorded interim status under, subtitle C of the Solid Waste Disposal Act [42 U.S.C. 6921 et seq.], notify the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency of the existence of such facility, specifying the amount and type of any hazardous substance to be found there, and any known, suspected, or likely releases of such substances from s</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9603_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping requirements; promulgation of rules and regulations by Administrator of EPA; penalties for violations; waiver of retention requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recordkeeping requirements; promulgation of rules and regulations by Administrator of EPA; penalties for violations; waiver of retention requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9603_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to registered pesticide products and air emissions from animal waste at farms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability to registered pesticide products and air emissions from animal waste at farms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9603_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions from notice and penalty provisions for substances reported under other Federal law or is in continuous release, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemptions from notice and penalty provisions for substances reported under other Federal law or is in continuous release, etc. No notification shall be required under subsection (a) or (b) of this section for any release of a hazardous substance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>