<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9605"><akn:num>9605</akn:num><akn:heading>National contingency plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9605. National contingency plan(a) Revision and republicationWithin one hundred and eighty days after December 11, 1980, the President shall, after notice and opportunity for public comments, revise and republish the national contingency plan for the removal of oil and hazardous substances, originally prepared and published pursuant to section 1321 of title 33, to reflect and effectuate the responsibilities and powers created by this chapter, in addition to those matters specified in section 1321(c)(2) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 33. Such revision shall include a section of the plan to be known as the national hazardous substance response plan which shall establish procedures and standards for responding to releases of hazardous substances, pollutants, and contaminants, which shall include at a minimum:(1) methods for discovering and investigating facilities at which hazardous substances have been disposed of or otherwise come to be located;

(2) methods for evaluating, including analyses of relative cost, and remedying any releases or threats of releases from facilities which pose substantial danger to the public health or the environment;

(3) methods and criteria for determining the appropriate extent of removal, remedy, and other measures authorized by this chapter;

(4) appropriate roles and responsibilities for the Federal, State, and local governments and for interstate and nongovernmental entities in effectuating the plan;

(5) provision for identification, procurement, maintenance, and storage of response equipment and supplies;

(6) a method for and assignment of responsibility for reporting the existence of such facilities which may be located on federally owned or controlled properties and any releases of hazardous substances from such facilities;

(7) means of assuring that remedial action measures are cost-effective over the period of potential exposure to the hazardous substances or contaminated materials;

(8)(A) criteria for det</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision and republication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Revision and republication Within one hundred and eighty days after December 11, 1980, the President shall, after notice and opportunity for public comments, revise and republish the national contingency plan for the removal of oil and hazardous substances, originally prepared and published pursuant to section 1321 of title 33, to reflect and effectuate the responsibilities and powers created by this chapter, in addition to those matters specified in section 1321(c)(2) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 33. Such revision shall include a section of the plan to be known as the national hazardous substance response plan which shall establish procedures and standards for responding to releases of hazardous substances, pollutants, and contaminants, which shall include at a minimum: The plan shall specify procedures, techniques, materials, equipment, and methods to be employed in identifying, removing, or remedying releases of hazardous substances comparable to those required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Revision of plan Not later than 18 months after the enactment of the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act of 1986 [October 17, 1986], the President shall revise the National Contingency Plan to reflect the requirements of such amendments. The portion of such Plan known as “the National Hazardous Substance Response Plan” shall be revised to provide procedures and standards for remedial actions undertaken pursuant to this chapter which are consistent with amendments made by the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act of 1986 relating to the selection of remedial action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazard ranking system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hazard ranking system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition for assessment of release</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Petition for assessment of release Any person who is, or may be, affected by a release or threatened release of a hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant, may petition the President to conduct a preliminary assessment of the hazards to public health and the environment which are associated with such release or threatened release. If the President has not previously conducted a preliminary assessment of such release, the President shall, within 12 months after the receipt of any such petition, complete such assessment or provide an explanation of why the assessment is not appropriate. If the preliminary assessment indicates that the release or threatened release concerned may pose a threat to human health or the environment, the President shall promptly evaluate such release or threatened release in accordance with the hazard ranking system referred to in paragraph (8)(A) of subsection (a) to determine the national priority of such release or threatened release.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Releases from earlier sites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Releases from earlier sites Whenever there has been, after January 1, 1985, a significant release of hazardous substances or pollutants or contaminants from a site which is listed by the President as a “Site Cleaned Up To Date” on the National Priorities List (revised edition, December 1984) the site shall be restored to the National Priorities List, without application of the hazard ranking system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minority contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Minority contractors In awarding contracts under this chapter, the President shall consider the availability of qualified minority firms. The President shall describe, as part of any annual report submitted to the Congress under this chapter, the participation of minority firms in contracts carried out under this chapter. Such report shall contain a brief description of the contracts which have been awarded to minority firms under this chapter and of the efforts made by the President to encourage the participation of such firms in programs carried out under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special study wastes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special study wastes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>NPL deferral</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) NPL deferral</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>