<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9607" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9607/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9607/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9607"><akn:num>9607</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9607. Liability(a) Covered persons; scope; recoverable costs and damages; interest rate; “comparable maturity” dateNotwithstanding any other provision or rule of law, and subject only to the defenses set forth in subsection (b) of this section—(1) the owner and operator of a vessel or a facility,

(2) any person who at the time of disposal of any hazardous substance owned or operated any facility at which such hazardous substances were disposed of,

(3) any person who by contract, agreement, or otherwise arranged for disposal or treatment, or arranged with a transporter for transport for disposal or treatment, of hazardous substances owned or possessed by such person, by any other party or entity, at any facility or incineration vessel owned or operated by another party or entity and containing such hazardous substances, and

(4) any person who accepts or accepted any hazardous substances for transport to disposal or treatment facilities, incineration vessels or sites selected by such person, from which there is a release, or a threatened release which causes the incurrence of response costs, of a hazardous substance, shall be liable for—(A) all costs of removal or remedial action incurred by the United States Government or a State or an Indian tribe not inconsistent with the national contingency plan;

(B) any other necessary costs of response incurred by any other person consistent with the national contingency plan;

(C) damages for injury to, destruction of, or loss of natural resources, including the reasonable costs of assessing such injury, destruction, or loss resulting from such a release; and

(D) the costs of any health assessment or health effects study carried out under section 9604(i) of this title.



The amounts recoverable in an action under this section shall include interest on the amounts recoverable under subparagraphs (A) through (D). Such interest shall accrue from the later of (i) the date payment of a specified amount is demanded in writin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered persons; scope; recoverable costs and damages; interest rate; “comparable maturity” date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Covered persons; scope; recoverable costs and damages; interest rate; “comparable maturity” date Notwithstanding any other provision or rule of law, and subject only to the defenses set forth in subsection (b) of this section— The amounts recoverable in an action under this section shall include interest on the amounts recoverable under subparagraphs (A) through (D). Such interest shall accrue from the later of (i) the date payment of a specified amount is demanded in writing, or (ii) the date of the expenditure concerned. The rate of interest on the outstanding unpaid balance of the amounts recoverable under this section shall be the same rate as is specified for interest on investments of the Hazardous Substance Superfund established under subchapter A of chapter 98 of title 26. For purposes of applying such amendments to interest under this subsection, the term “comparable maturity” shall be determined with reference to the date on which interest accruing under this subsection c</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Defenses There shall be no liability under subsection (a) of this section for a person otherwise liable who can establish by a preponderance of the evidence that the release or threat of release of a hazardous substance and the damages resulting therefrom were caused solely by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination of amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rendering care or advice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rendering care or advice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indemnification, hold harmless, etc., agreements or conveyances; subrogation rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Indemnification, hold harmless, etc., agreements or conveyances; subrogation rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Natural resources liability; designation of public trustees of natural resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Natural resources liability; designation of public trustees of natural resources</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Federal agencies For provisions relating to Federal agencies, see section 9620 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Owner or operator of vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Owner or operator of vessel The owner or operator of a vessel shall be liable in accordance with this section, under maritime tort law, and as provided under section 9614 of this title notwithstanding any provision of the Act of March 3, 1851 (46 U.S.C. 183ff) 11 See References in Text note below. or the absence of any physical damage to the proprietary interest of the claimant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of a registered pesticide product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Application of a registered pesticide product No person (including the United States or any State or Indian tribe) may recover under the authority of this section for any response costs or damages resulting from the application of a pesticide product registered under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act [7 U.S.C. 136 et seq.]. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect or modify in any way the obligations or liability of any person under any other provision of State or Federal law, including common law, for damages, injury, or loss resulting from a release of any hazardous substance or for removal or remedial action or the costs of removal or remedial action of such hazardous substance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9607_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations or liability pursuant to federally permitted release</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Obligations or liability pursuant to federally permitted release Recovery by any person (including the United States or any State or Indian tribe) for response costs or damages resulting from a federally permitted release shall be pursuant to existing law in lieu of this section. Nothing in this paragraph shall affect or modify in any way the obligations or liability of any person under any other provision of State or Federal law, including common law, for damages, injury, or loss resulting from a release of any hazardous substance or for removal or remedial action or the costs of removal or remedial action of such hazardous substance. In addition, costs of response incurred by the Federal Government in connection with a discharge specified in section 9601(10)(B) or (C) of this title shall be recoverable in an action brought under section 1319(b) of title 33.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>