<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9611"><akn:num>9611</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9611. Uses of Fund(a) In generalFor the purposes specified in this section there is authorized to be appropriated from the Hazardous Substance Superfund established under subchapter A of chapter 98 of title 26 not more than $8,500,000,000 for the 5-year period beginning on October 17, 1986, and not more than $5,100,000,000 for the period commencing October 1, 1991, and ending September 30, 1994, and such sums shall remain available until expended. The preceding sentence constitutes a specific authorization for the funds appropriated under title II of Public Law 99-160 (relating to payment to the Hazardous Substances Trust Fund). The President shall use the money in the Fund for the following purposes:(1) Payment of governmental response costs incurred pursuant to section 9604 of this title, including costs incurred pursuant to the Intervention on the High Seas Act [33 U.S.C. 1471 et seq.].

(2) Payment of any claim for necessary response costs incurred by any other person as a result of carrying out the national contingency plan established under section 1321(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 33 and amended by section 9605 of this title: Provided, however, That such costs must be approved under said plan and certified by the responsible Federal official.

(3) Payment of any claim authorized by subsection (b) of this section and finally decided pursuant to section 9612 of this title, including those costs set out in subsection 9612(c)(3) of this title.

(4) Payment of costs specified under subsection (c) of this section.

(5) Grants for technical assistance.—The cost of grants under section 9617(e) of this title (relating to public participation grants for technical assistance).

(6) Lead contaminated soil.—Payment of not to exceed $15,000,000 for the costs of a pilot program for removal, decontamination, or other action with respect to lead-contaminated soil in one to three different metropolitan areas.


The President shall not pay for any adminis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For the purposes specified in this section there is authorized to be appropriated from the Hazardous Substance Superfund established under subchapter A of chapter 98 of title 26 not more than $8,500,000,000 for the 5-year period beginning on October 17, 1986, and not more than $5,100,000,000 for the period commencing October 1, 1991, and ending September 30, 1994, and such sums shall remain available until expended. The preceding sentence constitutes a specific authorization for the funds appropriated under title II of Public Law 99-160 (relating to payment to the Hazardous Substances Trust Fund). The President shall use the money in the Fund for the following purposes: The President shall not pay for any administrative costs or expenses out of the Fund unless such costs and expenses are reasonably necessary for and incidental to the implementation of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional authorized purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional authorized purposes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peripheral matters and limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Peripheral matters and limitations Uses of the Fund under subsection (a) of this section include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding requirements respecting moneys in Fund; limitation on certain claims; Fund use outside Federal property boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Funding requirements respecting moneys in Fund; limitation on certain claims; Fund use outside Federal property boundaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation of moneys by Federal officials; obligation of moneys or settlement of claims by State officials or Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Obligation of moneys by Federal officials; obligation of moneys or settlement of claims by State officials or Indian tribe The President is authorized to promulgate regulations designating one or more Federal officials who may obligate money in the Fund in accordance with this section or portions thereof. The President is also authorized to delegate authority to obligate money in the Fund or to settle claims to officials of a State or Indian tribe operating under a contract or cooperative agreement with the Federal Government pursuant to section 9604(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to potential injured parties by owner and operator of vessel or facility causing release of substance; rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notice to potential injured parties by owner and operator of vessel or facility causing release of substance; rules and regulations The President shall provide for the promulgation of rules and regulations with respect to the notice to be provided to potential injured parties by an owner and operator of any vessel, or facility from which a hazardous substance has been released. Such rules and regulations shall consider the scope and form of the notice which would be appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. Upon promulgation of such rules and regulations, the owner and operator of any vessel or facility from which a hazardous substance has been released shall provide notice in accordance with such rules and regulations. With respect to releases from public vessels, the President shall provide such notification as is appropriate to potential injured parties. Until the promulgation of such rules and regulations, the owner and operator of any vessel or facility from wh</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 99–499, title I, § 111(c)(2), Oct. 17, 1986, 100 Stat. 1643</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restoration, etc., of natural resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Restoration, etc., of natural resources Except in a situation requiring action to avoid an irreversible loss of natural resources or to prevent or reduce any continuing danger to natural resources or similar need for emergency action, funds may not be used under this chapter for the restoration, rehabilitation, or replacement or acquisition of the equivalent of any natural resources until a plan for the use of such funds for such purposes has been developed and adopted by affected Federal agencies and the Governor or Governors of any State having sustained damage to natural resources within its borders, belonging to, managed by or appertaining to such State, and by the governing body of any Indian tribe having sustained damage to natural resources belonging to, managed by, controlled by, or appertaining to such tribe, or held in trust for the benefit of such tribe, or belonging to a member of such tribe if such resources are subject to a trust restriction on alienation, after adequ</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9611_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Post-closure Liability Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Use of Post-closure Liability Fund The President shall use the money in the Post-closure Liability Fund for any of the purposes specified in subsection (a) of this section with respect to a hazardous waste disposal facility for which liability has transferred to such fund under section 9607(k) of this title, and, in addition, for payment of any claim or appropriate request for costs of response, damages, or other compensation for injury or loss under section 9607 of this title or any other State or Federal law, resulting from a release of a hazardous substance from such a facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>