<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9612" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9612/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9612/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9612"><akn:num>9612</akn:num><akn:heading>Claims procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9612. Claims procedure(a) Claims against Fund for response costsNo claim may be asserted against the Fund pursuant to section 9611(a) of this title unless such claim is presented in the first instance to the owner, operator, or guarantor of the vessel or facility from which a hazardous substance has been released, if known to the claimant, and to any other person known to the claimant who may be liable under section 9607 of this title. In any case where the claim has not been satisfied within 60 days of presentation in accordance with this subsection, the claimant may present the claim to the Fund for payment. No claim against the Fund may be approved or certified during the pendency of an action by the claimant in court to recover costs which are the subject of the claim.


(b) Forms and procedures applicable(1) Prescribing forms and proceduresThe President shall prescribe appropriate forms and procedures for claims filed hereunder, which shall include a provision requiring the claimant to make a sworn verification of the claim to the best of his knowledge. Any person who knowingly gives or causes to be given any false information as a part of any such claim shall, upon conviction, be fined in accordance with the applicable provisions of title 18 or imprisoned for not more than 3 years (or not more than 5 years in the case of a second or subsequent conviction), or both.


(2) Payment or request for hearingThe President may, if satisfied that the information developed during the processing of the claim warrants it, make and pay an award of the claim, except that no claim may be awarded to the extent that a judicial judgment has been made on the costs that are the subject of the claim. If the President declines to pay all or part of the claim, the claimant may, within 30 days after receiving notice of the President’s decision, request an administrative hearing.


(3) Burden of proofIn any proceeding under this subsection, the claimant shall bear the burden of provi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9612_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claims against Fund for response costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Claims against Fund for response costs No claim may be asserted against the Fund pursuant to section 9611(a) of this title unless such claim is presented in the first instance to the owner, operator, or guarantor of the vessel or facility from which a hazardous substance has been released, if known to the claimant, and to any other person known to the claimant who may be liable under section 9607 of this title. In any case where the claim has not been satisfied within 60 days of presentation in accordance with this subsection, the claimant may present the claim to the Fund for payment. No claim against the Fund may be approved or certified during the pendency of an action by the claimant in court to recover costs which are the subject of the claim.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9612_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forms and procedures applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Forms and procedures applicable</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9612_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subrogation rights; actions maintainable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subrogation rights; actions maintainable</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9612_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statute of limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Statute of limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9612_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other statutory or common law claims not waived, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other statutory or common law claims not waived, etc. Regardless of any State statutory or common law to the contrary, no person who asserts a claim against the Fund pursuant to this subchapter shall be deemed or held to have waived any other claim not covered or assertable against the Fund under this subchapter arising from the same incident, transaction, or set of circumstances, nor to have split a cause of action. Further, no person asserting a claim against the Fund pursuant to this subchapter shall as a result of any determination of a question of fact or law made in connection with that claim be deemed or held to be collaterally estopped from raising such question in connection with any other claim not covered or assertable against the Fund under this subchapter arising from the same incident, transaction, or set of circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9612_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Double recovery prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Double recovery prohibited Where the President has paid out of the Fund for any response costs or any costs specified under section 9611(c)(1) or (2) of this title, no other claim may be paid out of the Fund for the same costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>