<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9615" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9615/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9615/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9615"><akn:num>9615</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential delegation and assignment of duties or powers and promulgation of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9615. Presidential delegation and assignment of duties or powers and promulgation of regulations
The President is authorized to delegate and assign any duties or powers imposed upon or assigned to him and to promulgate any regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.
(Pub. L. 96–510, title I, § 115, Dec. 11, 1980, 94 Stat. 2796.)

Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 12580. Superfund Implementation
Ex. Ord. No. 12580, Jan. 23, 1987, 52 F.R. 2923, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12777, § 1(a), Oct. 18, 1991, 56 F.R. 54757; Ex. Ord. No. 13016, Aug. 28, 1996, 61 F.R. 45871; Ex. Ord. No. 13286, § 43, Feb. 28, 2003, 68 F.R. 10627; Ex. Ord. No. 13308, June 20, 2003, 68 F.R. 37691, provided:
By the authority vested in me as President of the United States of America by Section 115 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, as amended (42 U.S.C. 9615 et seq.) (“the Act”), and by Section 301 of Title 3 of the United States Code, it is hereby ordered as follows:
Section 1. National Contingency Plan. (a)(1) The National Contingency Plan (“the NCP”), shall provide for a National Response Team (“the NRT”) composed of representatives of appropriate Federal departments and agencies for national planning and coordination of preparedness and response actions, and Regional Response Teams as the regional counterparts to the NRT for planning and coordination of regional preparedness and response actions.
(2) The following agencies (in addition to other appropriate agencies) shall provide representatives to the National and Regional Response Teams to carry out their responsibilities under the NCP: Department of State, Department of Defense, Department of Justice, Department of the Interior, Department of Agriculture, Department of Commerce, Department of Labor, Department of Health and Human Services, Department of Transportation, Department of Energy, Department of Homeland Security, Environmental Protection Agency,, [sic] Un</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>