<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9616" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9616/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9616/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9616"><akn:num>9616</akn:num><akn:heading>Schedules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9616. Schedules(a) Assessment and listing of facilitiesIt shall be a goal of this chapter that, to the maximum extent practicable—(1) not later than January 1, 1988, the President shall complete preliminary assessments of all facilities that are contained (as of October 17, 1986) on the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Information System (CERCLIS) including in each assessment a statement as to whether a site inspection is necessary and by whom it should be carried out; and

(2) not later than January 1, 1989, the President shall assure the completion of site inspections at all facilities for which the President has stated a site inspection is necessary pursuant to paragraph (1).


(b) EvaluationWithin 4 years after October 17, 1986, each facility listed (as of October 17, 1986) in the CERCLIS shall be evaluated if the President determines that such evaluation is warranted on the basis of a site inspection or preliminary assessment. The evaluation shall be in accordance with the criteria established in section 9605 of this title under the National Contingency Plan for determining priorities among release for inclusion on the National Priorities List. In the case of a facility listed in the CERCLIS after October 17, 1986, the facility shall be evaluated within 4 years after the date of such listing if the President determines that such evaluation is warranted on the basis of a site inspection or preliminary assessment.


(c) ExplanationsIf any of the goals established by subsection (a) or (b) are not achieved, the President shall publish an explanation of why such action could not be completed by the specified date.


(d) Commencement of RI/FSThe President shall assure that remedial investigations and feasibility studies (RI/FS) are commenced for facilities listed on the National Priorities List, in addition to those commenced prior to October 17, 1986, in accordance with the following schedule:(1) not fewer than 275 by the date 36 m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9616_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment and listing of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessment and listing of facilities It shall be a goal of this chapter that, to the maximum extent practicable—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9616_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation Within 4 years after October 17, 1986, each facility listed (as of October 17, 1986) in the CERCLIS shall be evaluated if the President determines that such evaluation is warranted on the basis of a site inspection or preliminary assessment. The evaluation shall be in accordance with the criteria established in section 9605 of this title under the National Contingency Plan for determining priorities among release for inclusion on the National Priorities List. In the case of a facility listed in the CERCLIS after October 17, 1986, the facility shall be evaluated within 4 years after the date of such listing if the President determines that such evaluation is warranted on the basis of a site inspection or preliminary assessment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9616_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Explanations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Explanations If any of the goals established by subsection (a) or (b) are not achieved, the President shall publish an explanation of why such action could not be completed by the specified date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9616_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of RI/FS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Commencement of RI/FS The President shall assure that remedial investigations and feasibility studies (RI/FS) are commenced for facilities listed on the National Priorities List, in addition to those commenced prior to October 17, 1986, in accordance with the following schedule:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9616_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of remedial action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Commencement of remedial action The President shall assure that substantial and continuous physical on-site remedial action commences at facilities on the National Priorities List, in addition to those facilities on which remedial action has commenced prior to October 17, 1986, at a rate not fewer than:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>