<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9622" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9622/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9622/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9622"><akn:num>9622</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9622. Settlements(a) Authority to enter into agreementsThe President, in his discretion, may enter into an agreement with any person (including the owner or operator of the facility from which a release or substantial threat of release emanates, or any other potentially responsible person), to perform any response action (including any action described in section 9604(b) of this title) if the President determines that such action will be done properly by such person. Whenever practicable and in the public interest, as determined by the President, the President shall act to facilitate agreements under this section that are in the public interest and consistent with the National Contingency Plan in order to expedite effective remedial actions and minimize litigation. If the President decides not to use the procedures in this section, the President shall notify in writing potentially responsible parties at the facility of such decision and the reasons why use of the procedures is inappropriate. A decision of the President to use or not to use the procedures in this section is not subject to judicial review.


(b) Agreements with potentially responsible parties(1) Mixed fundingAn agreement under this section may provide that the President will reimburse the parties to the agreement from the Fund, with interest, for certain costs of actions under the agreement that the parties have agreed to perform but which the President has agreed to finance. In any case in which the President provides such reimbursement, the President shall make all reasonable efforts to recover the amount of such reimbursement under section 9607 of this title or under other relevant authorities.


(2) ReviewabilityThe President’s decisions regarding the availability of fund financing under this subsection shall not be subject to judicial review under subsection (d).


(3) Retention of fundsIf, as part of any agreement, the President will be carrying out any action and the parties will be paying am</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to enter into agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to enter into agreements The President, in his discretion, may enter into an agreement with any person (including the owner or operator of the facility from which a release or substantial threat of release emanates, or any other potentially responsible person), to perform any response action (including any action described in section 9604(b) of this title) if the President determines that such action will be done properly by such person. Whenever practicable and in the public interest, as determined by the President, the President shall act to facilitate agreements under this section that are in the public interest and consistent with the National Contingency Plan in order to expedite effective remedial actions and minimize litigation. If the President decides not to use the procedures in this section, the President shall notify in writing potentially responsible parties at the facility of such decision and the reasons why use of the procedures is inappropriate. A decisio</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with potentially responsible parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agreements with potentially responsible parties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effect of agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special notice procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special notice procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covenant not to sue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Covenant not to sue</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>De minimis settlements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) De minimis settlements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost recovery settlement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cost recovery settlement authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Settlement procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9622_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Natural resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Natural resources</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>