<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9627" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9627/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9627/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9627"><akn:num>9627</akn:num><akn:heading>Recycling transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9627. Recycling transactions(a) Liability clarification(1) As provided in subsections (b), (c), (d), and (e), a person who arranged for recycling of recyclable material shall not be liable under sections 9607(a)(3) and 9607(a)(4) of this title with respect to such material.

(2) A determination whether or not any person shall be liable under section 9607(a)(3) of this title or section 9607(a)(4) of this title for any material that is not a recyclable material as that term is used in subsections (b) and (c), (d), or (e) of this section shall be made, without regard to subsections 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (b), (c), (d), or (e) of this section.


(b) Recyclable material definedFor purposes of this section, the term “recyclable material” means scrap paper, scrap plastic, scrap glass, scrap textiles, scrap rubber (other than whole tires), scrap metal, or spent lead-acid, spent nickel-cadmium, and other spent batteries, as well as minor amounts of material incident to or adhering to the scrap material as a result of its normal and customary use prior to becoming scrap; except that such term shall not include—(1) shipping containers of a capacity from 30 liters to 3,000 liters, whether intact or not, having any hazardous substance (but not metal bits and pieces or hazardous substance that form an integral part of the container) contained in or adhering thereto; or

(2) any item of material that contained polychlorinated biphenyls at a concentration in excess of 50 parts per million or any new standard promulgated pursuant to applicable Federal laws.


(c) Transactions involving scrap paper, plastic, glass, textiles, or rubberTransactions involving scrap paper, scrap plastic, scrap glass, scrap textiles, or scrap rubber (other than whole tires) shall be deemed to be arranging for recycling if the person who arranged for the transaction (by selling recyclable material or otherwise arranging for the recycling of recyclable material) can demonstrat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability clarification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liability clarification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recyclable material defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recyclable material defined For purposes of this section, the term “recyclable material” means scrap paper, scrap plastic, scrap glass, scrap textiles, scrap rubber (other than whole tires), scrap metal, or spent lead-acid, spent nickel-cadmium, and other spent batteries, as well as minor amounts of material incident to or adhering to the scrap material as a result of its normal and customary use prior to becoming scrap; except that such term shall not include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions involving scrap paper, plastic, glass, textiles, or rubber</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transactions involving scrap paper, plastic, glass, textiles, or rubber Transactions involving scrap paper, scrap plastic, scrap glass, scrap textiles, or scrap rubber (other than whole tires) shall be deemed to be arranging for recycling if the person who arranged for the transaction (by selling recyclable material or otherwise arranging for the recycling of recyclable material) can demonstrate by a preponderance of the evidence that all of the following criteria were met at the time of the transaction:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions involving scrap metal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transactions involving scrap metal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions involving batteries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transactions involving batteries Transactions involving spent lead-acid batteries, spent nickel-cadmium batteries, or other spent batteries shall be deemed to be arranging for recycling if the person who arranged for the transaction (by selling recyclable material or otherwise arranging for the recycling of recyclable material) can demonstrate by a preponderance of the evidence that at the time of the transaction—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exclusions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect on other liability Nothing in this section shall be deemed to affect the liability of a person under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 9607(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Administrator has the authority, under section 9615 of this title, to promulgate additional regulations concerning this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on pending or concluded actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effect on pending or concluded actions The exemptions provided in this section shall not affect any concluded judicial or administrative action or any pending judicial action initiated by the United States prior to November 29, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9627_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for attorney’s fees for certain actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Liability for attorney’s fees for certain actions Any person who commences an action in contribution against a person who is not liable by operation of this section shall be liable to that person for all reasonable costs of defending that action, including all reasonable attorney’s and expert witness fees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>