<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9655" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9655/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9655/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9655"><akn:num>9655</akn:num><akn:heading>Legislative veto of rule or regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9655. Legislative veto of rule or regulation(a) Transmission to Congress upon promulgation or repromulgation of rule or regulation; disapproval proceduresNotwithstanding any other provision of law, simultaneously with promulgation or repromulgation of any rule or regulation under authority of subchapter I of this chapter, the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality promulgating such rule or regulation shall transmit a copy thereof to the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives. Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the rule or regulation shall not become effective, if—(1) within ninety calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date of promulgation, both Houses of Congress adopt a concurrent resolution, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That Congress disapproves the rule or regulation promulgated by the        dealing with the matter of        , which rule or regulation was transmitted to Congress on            .”, the blank spaces therein being appropriately filled; or

(2) within sixty calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date of promulgation, one House of Congress adopts such a concurrent resolution and transmits such resolution to the other House, and such resolution is not disapproved by such other House within thirty calendar days of continuous session of Congress after such transmittal.


(b) Approval; effective datesIf, at the end of sixty calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date of promulgation of a rule or regulation, no committee of either House of Congress has reported or been discharged from further consideration of a concurrent resolution disapproving the rule or regulation and neither House has adopted such a resolution, the rule or regulation may go into effect immediately. If, within such sixty calendar days, such a committee has reported or been discharged from further consideration of such a resolution, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9655_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmission to Congress upon promulgation or repromulgation of rule or regulation; disapproval procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transmission to Congress upon promulgation or repromulgation of rule or regulation; disapproval procedures Notwithstanding any other provision of law, simultaneously with promulgation or repromulgation of any rule or regulation under authority of subchapter I of this chapter, the head of the department, agency, or instrumentality promulgating such rule or regulation shall transmit a copy thereof to the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives. Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the rule or regulation shall not become effective, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9655_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval; effective dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Approval; effective dates If, at the end of sixty calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date of promulgation of a rule or regulation, no committee of either House of Congress has reported or been discharged from further consideration of a concurrent resolution disapproving the rule or regulation and neither House has adopted such a resolution, the rule or regulation may go into effect immediately. If, within such sixty calendar days, such a committee has reported or been discharged from further consideration of such a resolution, or either House has adopted such a resolution, the rule or regulation may go into effect not sooner than ninety calendar days of continuous session of Congress after such rule is prescribed unless disapproved as provided in subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9655_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sessions of Congress as applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sessions of Congress as applicable For purposes of subsections (a) and (b) of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9655_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional inaction on, or rejection of, resolution of disapproval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Congressional inaction on, or rejection of, resolution of disapproval Congressional inaction on, or rejection of, a resolution of disapproval shall not be deemed an expression of approval of such rule or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>