<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9658" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9658/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9658/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9658"><akn:num>9658</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions under State law for damages from exposure to hazardous substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9658. Actions under State law for damages from exposure to hazardous substances(a) State statutes of limitations for hazardous substance cases(1) Exception to State statutesIn the case of any action brought under State law for personal injury, or property damages, which are caused or contributed to by exposure to any hazardous substance, or pollutant or contaminant, released into the environment from a facility, if the applicable limitations period for such action (as specified in the State statute of limitations or under common law) provides a commencement date which is earlier than the federally required commencement date, such period shall commence at the federally required commencement date in lieu of the date specified in such State statute.


(2) State law generally applicableExcept as provided in paragraph (1), the statute of limitations established under State law shall apply in all actions brought under State law for personal injury, or property damages, which are caused or contributed to by exposure to any hazardous substance, or pollutant or contaminant, released into the environment from a facility.


(3) Actions under section 9607Nothing in this section shall apply with respect to any cause of action brought under section 9607 of this title.



(b) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) Subchapter I termsThe terms used in this section shall have the same meaning as when used in subchapter I of this chapter.


(2) Applicable limitations periodThe term “applicable limitations period” means the period specified in a statute of limitations during which a civil action referred to in subsection (a)(1) may be brought.


(3) Commencement dateThe term “commencement date” means the date specified in a statute of limitations as the beginning of the applicable limitations period.


(4) Federally required commencement date(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “federally required commencement date” means the date the plaintiff knew (or reas</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9658_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State statutes of limitations for hazardous substance cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State statutes of limitations for hazardous substance cases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9658_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>