<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9660" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9660/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9660/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9660"><akn:num>9660</akn:num><akn:heading>Research, development, and demonstration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9660. Research, development, and demonstration(a) Hazardous substance research and training(1) Authorities of SecretaryThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the Secretary), in consultation with the Administrator, shall establish and support a basic research and training program (through grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts) consisting of the following:(A) Basic research (including epidemiologic and ecologic studies) which may include each of the following:(i) Advanced techniques for the detection, assessment, and evaluation of the effects on human health of hazardous substances.

(ii) Methods to assess the risks to human health presented by hazardous substances.

(iii) Methods and technologies to detect hazardous substances in the environment and basic biological, chemical, and physical methods to reduce the amount and toxicity of hazardous substances.


(B) Training, which may include each of the following:(i) Short courses and continuing education for State and local health and environment agency personnel and other personnel engaged in the handling of hazardous substances, in the management of facilities at which hazardous substances are located, and in the evaluation of the hazards to human health presented by such facilities.

(ii) Graduate or advanced training in environmental and occupational health and safety and in the public health and engineering aspects of hazardous waste control.

(iii) Graduate training in the geosciences, including hydrogeology, geological engineering, geophysics, geochemistry, and related fields necessary to meet professional personnel needs in the public and private sectors and to effectuate the purposes of this chapter.



(2) Director of NIEHSThe Director of the National Institute for Environmental Health Sciences shall cooperate fully with the relevant Federal agencies referred to in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (5) in carrying out the purposes of this section.


(3)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9660_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous substance research and training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Hazardous substance research and training</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9660_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative or innovative treatment technology research and demonstration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alternative or innovative treatment technology research and demonstration program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9660_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous substance research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hazardous substance research The Administrator may conduct and support, through grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts, research with respect to the detection, assessment, and evaluation of the effects on and risks to human health of hazardous substances and detection of hazardous substances in the environment. The Administrator shall coordinate such research with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the advisory council established under this section, in order to avoid duplication of effort.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9660_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>University hazardous substance research centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) University hazardous substance research centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9660_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report to Congress At the time of the submission of the annual budget request to Congress, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate and to the advisory council established under subsection (a), a report on the progress of the research, development, and demonstration program authorized by subsection (b), including an evaluation of each demonstration project completed in the preceding fiscal year, findings with respect to the efficacy of such demonstrated technologies in achieving permanent and significant reductions in risk from hazardous wastes, the costs of such demonstration projects, and the potential applicability of, and projected costs for, such technologies at other hazardous substance sites.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9660_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Saving provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Saving provision Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the provisions of the Solid Waste Disposal Act [42 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9660_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small business participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Small business participation The Administrator shall ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, an adequate opportunity for small business participation in the program established by subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>