<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/97" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/97/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/97/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_97"><akn:num>97</akn:num><akn:heading>State health laws observed by United States officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 97. State health laws observed by United States officers
The quarantines and other restraints established by the health laws of any State, respecting any vessels arriving in, or bound to, any port or district thereof, shall be duly observed by the officers of the customs revenue of the United States, by the masters and crews of the several Coast Guard vessels, and by the military officers commanding in any fort or station upon the seacoast; and all such officers of the United States shall faithfully aid in the execution of such quarantines and health laws, according to their respective powers and within their respective precincts, and as they shall be directed, from time to time, by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. But nothing in title 58 of the Revised Statutes shall enable any State to collect a duty of tonnage or impost without the consent of Congress.
(R.S. § 4792; Jan. 28, 1915, ch. 20, § 1, 38 Stat. 800; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. I, § 201, eff. July 1, 1939, 4 F.R. 2728, 53 Stat. 1424; Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393, §§ 1, 20, 63 Stat. 496, 561; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. Apr. 11, 1953, 18 F.R. 2053, 67 Stat. 631; Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b), Oct. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 695.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextTitle 58 of the Revised Statutes, referred to in text, was in the original “this Title” meaning title 58 of the Revised Statutes, consisting of R.S. §§ 4792 to 4800, which were classified to sections 88 to 91, 97, and 112 to 114 of this title and section 8 of former Title 4, Flag and Seal, Seat of Government, and the States. Such section 8 of former Title 4 was repealed by act July 30, 1947, ch. 389, § 2, 61 Stat. 645, and reenacted by the first section thereof as section 73 of Title 4. For complete classification of R.S. §§ 4792 to 4800 to the Code, see Tables.

Codification
R.S. § 4792 derived from act Feb. 23, 1799, ch. 12, § 1, 1 Stat. 619.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
“Secretary of Health and Human Services” </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>