<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9806" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9806/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9806/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9806"><akn:num>9806</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and scope of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9806. Establishment and scope of programs(a) The Secretary is authorized to provide financial assistance in the form of grants to nonprofit and for profit community development corporations and other affiliated and supportive agencies and organizations associated with qualifying community development corporations for the payment of all or part of the cost of programs which are designed to carry out the purposes of this part. Financial assistance shall be provided so that each community economic development program is of sufficient size, scope, and duration to have an appreciable impact on the area served. Such programs may include—(1) community business and commercial development programs, including (A) programs which provide financial and other assistance (including equity capital) to start, expand, or locate businesses in or near the area served so as to provide employment and ownership opportunities for residents of such areas; and (B) programs for small businesses located in or owned by residents of such areas;

(2) community physical development programs, including industrial parks and housing activities, which contribute to an improved environment and which create new training, employment and ownership opportunities for residents of such area;

(3) training and public service employment programs and related services for unemployed or low-income persons which support and complement community development programs financed under this part, including, without limitation, activities such as the activities described in title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998; 11 See References in Text note below. and

(4) social service programs which support and complement community business and commercial development programs financed under this part, including child care, educational services, health services, credit counseling, energy conservation, recreation services, and programs for the maintenance of housing facilities.


(b) The Secretary shall conduct programs as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9806_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary is authorized to provide financial assistance in the form of grants to nonprofit and for profit community development corporations and other affiliated and supportive agencies and organizations associated with qualifying community development corporations for the payment of all or part of the cost of programs which are designed to carry out the purposes of this part. Financial assistance shall be provided so that each community economic development program is of sufficient size, scope, and duration to have an appreciable impact on the area served. Such programs may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9806_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall conduct programs assisted under this part so as to contribute, on an equitable basis between urban and rural areas, to the elimination of poverty and the establishment of permanent economic and social benefits in such areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>