<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9819" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9819/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9819/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9819"><akn:num>9819</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of programs; implementation and funding, etc.; research and demonstration projects; imple</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9819. Evaluation of programs; implementation and funding, etc.; research and demonstration projects; implementation and purposes(a) Each program for which grants are made under this subchapter shall provide for a thorough evaluation of the effectiveness of the program in achieving its purposes, which evaluation shall be conducted by such public or private organizations as the Secretary in consultation with existing grantees familiar with programs carried out under the Community Services Block Grant Act [42 U.S.C. 9901 et seq.] may designate, and all or part of the costs of evaluation may be paid from funds appropriated to carry out this part. In evaluating the performance of any community development corporation funded under part A, the criteria for evaluation shall be based upon such program objectives, goals, and priorities as are consistent with the purposes of this subchapter and were set forth by such community development corporation in its proposal for funding as approved and agreed upon by or as subsequently modified from time to time by mutual agreement between the Secretary and such community development corporation.

(b) The Secretary shall conduct, either directly or through grants or other arrangements, research and demonstration projects designed to suggest new programs and policies to achieve the purposes of this subchapter in such ways as to provide opportunities for employment, ownership, and a better quality of life for low-income residents.

(Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 630, Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 497.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Community Services Block Grant Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is subtitle B (§ 671 et seq.) of title VI of Pub. L. 97–35, Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 511, which is classified generally to chapter 106 (§ 9901 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 9901 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9819_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each program for which grants are made under this subchapter shall provide for a thorough evaluation of the effectiveness of the program in achieving its purposes, which evaluation shall be conducted by such public or private organizations as the Secretary in consultation with existing grantees familiar with programs carried out under the Community Services Block Grant Act [42 U.S.C. 9901 et seq.] may designate, and all or part of the costs of evaluation may be paid from funds appropriated to carry out this part. In evaluating the performance of any community development corporation funded under part A, the criteria for evaluation shall be based upon such program objectives, goals, and priorities as are consistent with the purposes of this subchapter and were set forth by such community development corporation in its proposal for funding as approved and agreed upon by or as subsequently modified from time to time by mutual agreement between the Secretary and such community developm</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9819_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall conduct, either directly or through grants or other arrangements, research and demonstration projects designed to suggest new programs and policies to achieve the purposes of this subchapter in such ways as to provide opportunities for employment, ownership, and a better quality of life for low-income residents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>