<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9822" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9822/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9822/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9822"><akn:num>9822</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of certain appropriated funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9822. Availability of certain appropriated funds
Funds appropriated to the Rural Development Loan Fund under title VII of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 2981 et seq.] (as in effect on August 12, 1981), and interest accumulated in such fund, shall be deposited in the Rural Development Loan Fund established under section 9812(c)(1) of this title and shall continue to be available to carry out the purposes of such fund. Funds appropriated to the Community Development Credit Union Revolving Loan Fund under title VII of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 (as in effect on August 12, 1981), and interest accumulated in such fund, shall continue to be available to carry out the purposes of such fund.
(Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 633, Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 498.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 88–452, Aug. 20, 1964, 78 Stat. 508. Title VII of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 was classified generally to subchapter VII (§ 2981 et seq.) of chapter 34 of this title, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 683(a), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 519. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.

Codification
“August 12, 1981” substituted in text for “the day before the date of the enactment of this Act”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Transfer of Community Development Credit Union Revolving Loan FundPub. L. 99–609, Nov. 6, 1986, 100 Stat. 3475, provided that:
“SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.“This Act may be cited as the ‘Community Development Credit Union Revolving Loan Fund Transfer Act’.


“SEC. 2. TRANSFER OF COMMUNITY DEVELOPMENT CREDIT UNION REVOLVING LOAN FUND.“(a) Administration of Fund by NCUA.—“(1) In general.—Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [Nov. 6, 1986], the National Credit Union Administration Board shall administer the Community Development Credit Union Revolving Loan Fund.

“(2) Transfer of authority.—All authority to carry out </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>