<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9835" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9835/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9835/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9835"><akn:num>9835</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9835. Allotment of funds(a) Distribution of appropriations; priorities, etc.(1) Using the sums appropriated pursuant to section 9834 of this title for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall allocate such sums in accordance with paragraphs (2) through (5).

(2)(A) The Secretary shall determine an amount for each fiscal year for each State that is equal to the amount received through base grants for the prior fiscal year by the Head Start agencies (including Early Head Start agencies) in the State that are not described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subparagraph (B).

(B) The Secretary shall reserve for each fiscal year such sums as are necessary—(i) to provide each amount determined for a State under subparagraph (A) to the Head Start agencies (including Early Head Start agencies) in the State that are not described in clause (ii) or (iii), by allotting to each agency described in this clause an amount equal to that agency’s base grant for the prior fiscal year;

(ii) to provide an amount for the Indian Head Start programs that is equal to the amount provided for base grants for such programs under this subchapter for the prior fiscal year, by allotting to each Head Start agency (including each Early Head Start agency) administering an Indian Head Start program an amount equal to that agency’s base grant for the prior fiscal year;

(iii) to provide an amount for the migrant and seasonal Head Start programs, on a nationwide basis, that is equal to the amount provided nationwide for base grants for such programs under this subchapter for the prior fiscal year, by allotting to each Head Start agency administering a migrant or seasonal Head Start program an amount equal to that agency’s base grant for the prior fiscal year;

(iv) to provide an amount for each of Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Republic of Palau, and the Virgin Islands of the United States (for Head Start agencies (including Early Head Start agencies) in the jurisdic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of appropriations; priorities, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Distribution of appropriations; priorities, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal share Financial assistance extended under this subchapter for a Head Start program shall not exceed 80 percent of the approved costs of the assisted program or activities, except that the Secretary may approve assistance in excess of such percentage if the Secretary determines that such action is required in furtherance of the purposes of this subchapter. For the purpose of making such determination, the Secretary shall take into consideration with respect to the Head Start program involved— Non-Federal contributions may be in cash or in kind, fairly evaluated, including plant, equipment, or services. The Secretary shall not require non-Federal contributions in excess of 20 percent of the approved costs of programs or activities assisted under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Services covered No programs shall be approved for assistance under this subchapter unless the Secretary is satisfied that the services to be provided under such program will be in addition to, and not in substitution for, comparable services previously provided without Federal assistance. The requirement imposed by the preceding sentence shall be subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment of children with disabilities and provision of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enrollment of children with disabilities and provision of services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of benefits between residents of rural and urban areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Distribution of benefits between residents of rural and urban areas The Secretary shall adopt appropriate administrative measures to assure that the benefits of this subchapter will be distributed equitably between residents of rural and urban areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines for local service delivery models</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Guidelines for local service delivery models</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of current services; expansion of Head Start programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Maintenance of current services; expansion of Head Start programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Full-working-day services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Full-working-day services Financial assistance provided under this subchapter may be used by each Head Start program to provide full-working-day Head Start services to any eligible child throughout the full calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vehicle safety regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Vehicle safety regulations The Secretary shall issue regulations establishing requirements for the safety features, and the safe operation, of vehicles used by Head Start agencies to transport children participating in Head Start programs. The regulations shall also establish requirements to ensure the appropriate supervision of, and appropriate background checks for, individuals with whom the agencies contract to transport those children.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9835_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Compensation of staff Any agency that receives financial assistance under this subchapter to improve the compensation of staff who provide services under this subchapter 22 See References in Text note below. shall use the financial assistance to improve the compensation of such staff, regardless of whether the agency has the ability to improve the compensation of staff employed by the agency who do not provide Head Start services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>