<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9836" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9836/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9836/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9836"><akn:num>9836</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Head Start agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9836. Designation of Head Start agencies(a) Authority to designate(1) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to designate as a Head Start agency any local public or private nonprofit agency, including community-based and faith-based organizations, or for-profit agency, within a community, pursuant to the requirements of this section.


(2) Interim policyNotwithstanding paragraph (1), until such time as the Secretary develops and implements the system for designation renewal under this section, the Secretary is authorized to designate as a Head Start agency, any local public or private nonprofit agency, including community-based and faith-based organizations, or for-profit agency, within a community, in the manner and process utilized by the Secretary prior to December 12, 2007.



(b) Application for designation renewalTo be considered for designation renewal, an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.


(c) System for designation renewal(1) In generalThe Secretary shall develop a system for designation renewal that integrates the recommendations of the expert panel convened under paragraph (2) to determine if a Head Start agency is delivering a high-quality and comprehensive Head Start program that meets the educational, health, nutritional, and social needs of the children and families it serves, and meets program and financial management requirements and standards described in section 9836a(a)(1) of this title, based on—(A) annual budget and fiscal management data;

(B) program reviews conducted under section 9836a(c) of this title;

(C) annual audits required under section 9842 of this title;

(D) classroom quality as measured under section 9836a(c)(2)(F) of this title; and

(E) Program Information Reports.


(2) Expert panelNot later than 3 months after December 12, 2007, the Secretary shall convene an expert panel of 7 members to make recommendations to the Secretary on the development</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9836_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to designate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to designate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9836_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for designation renewal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application for designation renewal To be considered for designation renewal, an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9836_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>System for designation renewal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) System for designation renewal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9836_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation when no entity is renewed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Designation when no entity is renewed</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9836_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against non-Indian Head Start agency receiving a grant for an Indian Head Start program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition against non-Indian Head Start agency receiving a grant for an Indian Head Start program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9836_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim provider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Interim provider If no agency in a community is designated under subsection (d), and there is no qualified applicant in the community, the Secretary shall designate a qualified agency to carry out the Head Start program in the community on an interim basis until a qualified applicant from the community is designated under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9836_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Parent and community participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Parent and community participation The Secretary shall require that the practice of significantly involving parents and community residents in the area affected by the program involved, in the selection of Head Start agencies, be continued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9836_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Community For purposes of this subchapter, a community may be a city, county, or multicity or multicounty unit within a State, an Indian reservation (including Indians in any off-reservation area designated by an appropriate tribal government in consultation with the Secretary), or a neighborhood or other area (irrespective of boundaries or political subdivisions) that provides a suitable organizational base and possesses the commonality of interest needed to operate a Head Start program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>