<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9837" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9837/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9837/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9837"><akn:num>9837</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and functions of Head Start agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9837. Powers and functions of Head Start agencies(a) AuthorityTo be designated as a Head Start agency under this subchapter, an agency shall have authority under its charter or applicable law to receive and administer funds under this subchapter, funds and contributions from private or local public sources that may be used in support of a Head Start program, and funds under any Federal or State assistance program pursuant to which a public or private nonprofit or for-profit agency (as the case may be) organized in accordance with this subchapter, could act as grantee, contractor, or sponsor of projects appropriate for inclusion in a Head Start program. Such an agency shall also be empowered to transfer funds so received, and to delegate powers to other agencies, subject to the powers of its governing board and its overall program responsibilities. The power to transfer funds and delegate powers shall include the power to make transfers and delegations covering component projects in all cases where this will contribute to efficiency and effectiveness or otherwise further program objectives.


(b) Family and community involvement; family servicesTo be so designated, a Head Start agency shall, at a minimum, do all the following to involve and serve families and communities:(1) Provide for the regular and direct participation of parents and community residents in the implementation of the Head Start program, including decisions that influence the character of such program, consistent with paragraphs (2)(D) and (3)(C) of subsection (c).

(2) Seek the involvement of parents, community residents, and local business in the design and implementation of the program.

(3) Establish effective procedures—(A) to facilitate and seek the involvement of parents of participating children in activities designed to help such parents become full partners in the education of their children; and

(B) to afford such parents the opportunity to participate in the development and overall co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9837_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority To be designated as a Head Start agency under this subchapter, an agency shall have authority under its charter or applicable law to receive and administer funds under this subchapter, funds and contributions from private or local public sources that may be used in support of a Head Start program, and funds under any Federal or State assistance program pursuant to which a public or private nonprofit or for-profit agency (as the case may be) organized in accordance with this subchapter, could act as grantee, contractor, or sponsor of projects appropriate for inclusion in a Head Start program. Such an agency shall also be empowered to transfer funds so received, and to delegate powers to other agencies, subject to the powers of its governing board and its overall program responsibilities. The power to transfer funds and delegate powers shall include the power to make transfers and delegations covering component projects in all cases where this will contribute to efficiency </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9837_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family and community involvement; family services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Family and community involvement; family services To be so designated, a Head Start agency shall, at a minimum, do all the following to involve and serve families and communities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9837_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program governance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program governance Upon receiving designation as a Head Start agency, the agency shall establish and maintain a formal structure for program governance, for the oversight of quality services for Head Start children and families and for making decisions related to program design and implementation. Such structure shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9837_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program governance administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Program governance administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9837_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration and coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Collaboration and coordination To be so designated, a Head Start agency shall collaborate and coordinate with public and private entities, to the maximum extent practicable, to improve the availability and quality of services to Head Start children and families, including carrying out the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9837_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quality standards, curricula, and assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Quality standards, curricula, and assessment To be so designated, each Head Start agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9837_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funded enrollment; waiting list</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Funded enrollment; waiting list Each Head Start agency shall enroll 100 percent of its funded enrollment and maintain an active waiting list at all times with ongoing outreach to the community and activities to identify underserved populations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9837_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance and training plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Technical assistance and training plan In order to receive funds under this subchapter, a Head Start agency shall develop an annual technical assistance and training plan. Such plan shall be based on the agency’s self-assessment, the communitywide strategic planning and needs assessment, the needs of parents and children to be served by such agency, and the results of the reviews conducted under section 9836a(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9837_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Financial management In order to receive funds under this subchapter, a Head Start agency shall document strong fiscal controls, including the employment of well-qualified fiscal staff with a history of successful management of a public or private organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>