<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9839" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9839/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9839/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9839"><akn:num>9839</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative requirements and standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9839. Administrative requirements and standards(a) Employment practices, nonpartisanship, staff accountability, public access to information, etc.(1) Each Head Start agency shall observe standards of organization, management, and administration that will ensure, so far as reasonably possible, that all program activities are conducted in a manner consistent with the purposes of this subchapter and the objective of providing assistance effectively, efficiently, and free of any taint of partisan political bias or personal or family favoritism. Each such agency shall establish or adopt rules to carry out this section, which shall include rules to assure full staff accountability in matters governed by law, regulations, or agency policy. Each agency shall also provide for reasonable public access to information, including public hearings at the request of appropriate community groups and reasonable public access to books and records of the agency or other agencies engaged in program activities or operations involving the use of authority or funds for which it is responsible.

(2) Each Head Start agency shall make available to the public a report published at least once in each fiscal year that discloses the following information from the most recently concluded fiscal year, except that reporting such information shall not reveal personally identifiable information about an individual child or parent:(A) The total amount of public and private funds received and the amount from each source.

(B) An explanation of budgetary expenditures and proposed budget for the fiscal year.

(C) The total number of children and families served, the average monthly enrollment (as a percentage of funded enrollment), and the percentage of eligible children served.

(D) The results of the most recent review by the Secretary and the financial audit.

(E) The percentage of enrolled children that received medical and dental exams.

(F) Information about parent involvement activities.

(G) The</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9839_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment practices, nonpartisanship, staff accountability, public access to information, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employment practices, nonpartisanship, staff accountability, public access to information, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9839_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development and administrative costs of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development and administrative costs of programs Except as provided in subsection (f), no financial assistance shall be extended under this subchapter in any case in which the Secretary determines that the costs of developing and administering a program assisted under this subchapter exceed 15 percent of the total costs, including the required non-Federal contributions to such costs, of such program. The Secretary shall establish by regulation, criteria for determining (1) the costs of developing and administering such program; and (2) the total costs of such program. In any case in which the Secretary determines that the cost of administering such program does not exceed 15 percent of such total costs but is, in the judgment of the Secretary, excessive, the Secretary shall forthwith require the recipient of such financial assistance to take such steps prescribed by the Secretary as will eliminate such excessive administrative cost, including the sharing by one or more Head Start a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9839_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations; special or simplified requirements for small agencies; common or joint use of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rules and regulations; special or simplified requirements for small agencies; common or joint use of facilities The Secretary shall prescribe rules or regulations to supplement subsections (a) and (f), which shall be binding on all agencies carrying on Head Start program activities with financial assistance under this subchapter. The Secretary may, where appropriate, establish special or simplified requirements for smaller agencies or agencies operating in rural areas. Policies and procedures shall be established to ensure that indirect costs attributable to the common or joint use of facilities and services by programs assisted under this subchapter and other programs shall be fairly allocated among the various programs which utilize such facilities and services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9839_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication and notification of proposed rules, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publication and notification of proposed rules, etc. At least 30 days prior to their effective date, all rules, regulations, and application forms shall be published in the Federal Register and shall be sent to each grantee with the notification that each such grantee has the right to submit comments pertaining thereto to the Secretary prior to the final adoption thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9839_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Neutrality concerning union organizing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Neutrality concerning union organizing Funds appropriated to carry out this subchapter shall not be used to assist, promote, or deter union organizing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9839_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of facility; approval requirements; financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Purchase of facility; approval requirements; financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9839_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments for capital expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payments for capital expenditures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9839_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel preferences to Indian tribe members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Personnel preferences to Indian tribe members In all personnel actions of the American Indian Programs Branch of the Head Start Bureau of the Administration for Children and Families, the Secretary shall give the same preference to individuals who are members of an Indian tribe as the Secretary gives to a disabled veteran, as defined in section 2108(3)(C) of title 5. The Secretary shall take such additional actions as may be necessary to promote recruitment of such individuals for employment in the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>