<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9840" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9840/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9840/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9840"><akn:num>9840</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in Head Start programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9840. Participation in Head Start programs(a) Criteria for eligibility

(a)(1)(A) 11 So in original. The “(a)” probably should not appear. The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe eligibility for the participation of persons in Head Start programs assisted under this subchapter.

(B) Except as provided in paragraph (2), such regulation shall provide—(i) that children from low-income families shall be eligible for participation in programs assisted under this subchapter if their families’ incomes are below the poverty line, or if their families are eligible or, in the absence of child care, would potentially be eligible for public assistance;

(ii) that homeless children shall be deemed to be eligible for such participation;

(iii) that programs assisted under this subchapter may include—(I) to a reasonable extent (but not to exceed 10 percent of participants), participation of children in the area served who would benefit from such programs but who are not eligible under clause (i) or (ii); and

(II) from the area served, an additional 35 percent of participants who are not eligible under clause (i) or (ii) and whose families have incomes below 130 percent of the poverty line, if—(aa) the Head Start agency involved establishes and implements outreach and enrollment policies and procedures that ensure such agency is meeting the needs of children eligible under clause (i) or (ii) (or subclause (I) if the child involved has a disability) prior to meeting the needs of children eligible under this subclause; and

(bb) in prioritizing the selection of children to be served, the Head Start agency establishes criteria that provide that the agency will serve children eligible under clause (i) or (ii) prior to serving the children eligible under this subclause;



(iv) that any Head Start agency serving children eligible under clause (iii)(II) shall report annually to the Secretary information on—(I) how such agency is meeting the needs of children eligible under clause </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9840_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Criteria for eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9840_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9840_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of fee schedule or charging of fees; payment by families willing and able to pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of fee schedule or charging of fees; payment by families willing and able to pay The Secretary shall not prescribe any fee schedule or otherwise provide for the charging of any fees for participation in Head Start programs, unless such fees are authorized by legislation hereafter enacted. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent the families of children who participate in Head Start programs and who are willing and able to pay the full cost of such participation from doing so. A Head Start agency that provides a Head Start program with full-working-day services in collaboration with other agencies or entities may collect a family copayment to support extended day services if a copayment is required in conjunction with the collaborative. The copayment charged to families receiving services through the Head Start program shall not exceed the copayment charged to families with similar incomes and circumstances who are receiving the services through partic</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9840_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of more than one year of services; children eligible</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of more than one year of services; children eligible Each Head Start program operated in a community shall be permitted to provide more than 1 year of Head Start services to eligible children in the State. Each Head Start program operated in a community shall be permitted to recruit and accept applications for enrollment of children throughout the year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9840_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Indian tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>