<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9843a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9843a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9843a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9843a"><akn:num>9843a</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff qualifications and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9843a. Staff qualifications and development(a) Classroom teachers(1) Professional requirementsThe Secretary shall ensure that each Head Start classroom in a center-based program is assigned 1 teacher who has demonstrated competency to perform functions that include—(A) planning and implementing learning experiences that advance the intellectual and physical development of children, including improving the readiness of children for school by developing their literacy, phonemic, and print awareness, their understanding and use of language, their understanding and use of increasingly complex and varied vocabulary, their appreciation of books, their understanding of early math and early science, their problem-solving abilities, and their approaches to learning;

(B) establishing and maintaining a safe, healthy learning environment;

(C) supporting the social and emotional development of children; and

(D) encouraging the involvement of the families of the children in a Head Start program and supporting the development of relationships between children and their families.


(2) Degree requirements(A) Head Start teachersThe Secretary shall ensure that not later than September 30, 2013, at least 50 percent of Head Start teachers nationwide in center-based programs have—(i) a baccalaureate or advanced degree in early childhood education; or

(ii) a baccalaureate or advanced degree and coursework equivalent to a major relating to early childhood education, with experience teaching preschool-age children.


(B) Additional staffThe Secretary shall ensure that, not later than September 30, 2013, all—(i) Head Start education coordinators, including those that serve as curriculum specialists, nationwide in center-based programs—(I) have the capacity to offer assistance to other teachers in the implementation and adaptation of curricula to the group and individual needs of children in a Head Start classroom; and

(II) have—(aa) a baccalaureate or advanced degree in early childho</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9843a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classroom teachers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Classroom teachers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9843a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mentor teachers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mentor teachers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9843a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family service workers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Family service workers To improve the quality and effectiveness of staff providing in-home and other services (including needs assessment, development of service plans, family advocacy, and coordination of service delivery) to families of children participating in Head Start programs, the Secretary, in coordination with concerned public and private agencies and organizations examining the issues of standards and training for family service workers, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9843a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Head Start Fellowships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Head Start Fellowships</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9843a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Model staffing plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Model staffing plans Not later than 1 year after May 18, 1994, the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate public agencies, private agencies, and organizations and with individuals with expertise in the field of children and family services, shall develop model staffing plans to provide guidance to local Head Start agencies and programs on the numbers, types, responsibilities, and qualifications of staff required to operate a Head Start program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9843a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Professional development plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Professional development plans Each Head Start agency and program shall create, in consultation with an employee, a professional development plan for all full-time Head Start employees who provide direct services to children and shall ensure that such plans are regularly evaluated for their impact on teacher and staff effectiveness. The agency and the employee shall implement the plan to the extent feasible and practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9843a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff recruitment and selection procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Staff recruitment and selection procedures Before a Head Start agency employs an individual, such agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>