<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9857" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9857/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9857/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9857"><akn:num>9857</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title and purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9857. Short title and purposes(a) Short titleThis subchapter may be cited as the “Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990”.


(b) PurposesThe purposes of this subchapter are—(1) to allow each State maximum flexibility in developing child care programs and policies that best suit the needs of children and parents within that State;

(2) to promote parental choice to empower working parents to make their own decisions regarding the child care services that best suit their family’s needs;

(3) to encourage States to provide consumer education information to help parents make informed choices about child care services and to promote involvement by parents and family members in the development of their children in child care settings;

(4) to assist States in delivering high-quality, coordinated early childhood care and education services to maximize parents’ options and support parents trying to achieve independence from public assistance;

(5) to assist States in improving the overall quality of child care services and programs by implementing the health, safety, licensing, training, and oversight standards established in this subchapter and in State law (including State regulations);

(6) to improve child care and development of participating children; and

(7) to increase the number and percentage of low-income children in high-quality child care settings.


(Pub. L. 97–35, title VI, § 658A, as added Pub. L. 101–508, title V, § 5082(2), Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1388–236; amended Pub. L. 102–401, § 3(a), Oct. 7, 1992, 106 Stat. 1959; Pub. L. 102–586, § 8(c)(1), Nov. 4, 1992, 106 Stat. 5036; Pub. L. 104–193, title VI, § 602, Aug. 22, 1996, 110 Stat. 2279; Pub. L. 113–186, § 2, Nov. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 1971.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Subsection (a) of this section was formerly set out as a note under section 9801 of this title. Subsection (b) of this section was formerly set out as a note under section 9858 of this title.

Amendments2014—Pub. L. 113–186</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9857_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This subchapter may be cited as the “Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9857_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purposes The purposes of this subchapter are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>