<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9858e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9858e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9858e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9858e"><akn:num>9858e</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities to improve the quality of child care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9858e. Activities to improve the quality of child care(a) Reservation(1) Reservation for activities relating to the quality of child care servicesA State that receives funds to carry out this subchapter for a fiscal year referred to in paragraph (2) shall reserve and use a portion of such funds, in accordance with paragraph (2), for activities provided directly, or through grants or contracts with local child care resource and referral organizations or other appropriate entities, that are designed to improve the quality of child care services and increase parental options for, and access to, high-quality child care, and is in alignment with a Statewide assessment of the State’s needs to carry out such services and care, provided in accordance with this subchapter.


(2) Amount of reservationsSuch State shall reserve and use—(A) to carry out the activities described in paragraph (1), not less than—(i) 7 percent of the funds described in paragraph (1), for the first and second full fiscal years after November 19, 2014;

(ii) 8 percent of such funds for the third and fourth full fiscal years after November 19, 2014; and

(iii) 9 percent of such funds for the fifth and each succeeding full fiscal year after November 19, 2014; and


(B) in addition to the funds reserved under subparagraph (A), 3 percent of the funds described in paragraph (1) received not later than the second full fiscal year after November 19, 2014, and received for each succeeding full fiscal year, to carry out the activities described in paragraph (1) and subsection (b)(4), as such activities relate to the quality of care for infants and toddlers.


(3) State reservation amountNothing in this subsection shall preclude the State from reserving a larger percentage of funds to carry out the activities described in paragraph (1) and subsection (b).



(b) ActivitiesFunds reserved under subsection (a) shall be used to carry out no fewer than one of the following activities that will improve the quality </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9858e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reservation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9858e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities Funds reserved under subsection (a) shall be used to carry out no fewer than one of the following activities that will improve the quality of child care services provided in the State:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9858e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certification Beginning with fiscal year 2016, at the beginning of each fiscal year, the State shall annually submit to the Secretary a certification containing an assurance that the State was in compliance with subsection (a) during the preceding fiscal year and a description of how the State used funds received under this subchapter to comply with subsection (a) during that preceding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9858e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting requirements Each State receiving funds under this subchapter shall prepare and submit an annual report to the Secretary, which shall include information about—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9858e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance The Secretary shall offer technical assistance, in accordance with section 9858g(a)(3) of this title, which may include technical assistance through the use of grants or cooperative agreements, to States for the activities described in subsection (b) at the request of the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9858e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Construction Nothing in this section shall be construed as providing the Secretary the authority to regulate, direct, dictate, or place conditions (outside of what is required by this subchapter) on a State adopting specific State child care quality activities or progress in implementing those activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>