<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9858i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9858i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9858i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9858i"><akn:num>9858i</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9858i. Reports and audits(a) Reports(1) Collection of information by States(A) In generalA State that receives funds to carry out this subchapter shall collect the information described in subparagraph (B) on a monthly basis.


(B) Required informationThe information required under this subparagraph shall include, with respect to a family unit receiving assistance under this subchapter 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. information concerning—(i) family income;

(ii) county of residence;

(iii) the gender, race, and age of children receiving such assistance;

(iv) whether the head of the family unit is a single parent;

(v) the sources of family income, including—(I) employment, including self-employment;

(II) cash or other assistance under—(aa) the temporary assistance for needy families program under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.); and

(bb) a State program for which State spending is counted toward the maintenance of effort requirement under section 409(a)(7) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 609(a)(7));


(III) housing assistance;

(IV) assistance under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 [7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.]; and

(V) other assistance programs;


(vi) the number of months the family has received benefits;

(vii) the type of child care in which the child was enrolled (such as family child care, home care, or center-based child care);

(viii) whether the child care provider involved was a relative;

(ix) the cost of child care for such families;

(x) the average hours per month of such care; and

(xi) whether the children receiving assistance under this subchapter are homeless children;


during the period for which such information is required to be submitted.

(C) Submission to SecretaryA State described in subparagraph (A) shall, on a quarterly basis, submit the information required to be collected under subparagraph (B) to the Secretary.


(D) Use of samples(i) AuthorityA State may comply</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9858i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9858i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Audits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>