<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9859c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9859c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9859c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9859c"><akn:num>9859c</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts reserved; allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9859c. Amounts reserved; allotments(a) Amounts reservedThe Secretary shall reserve not more than one-half of 1 percent of the amount appropriated under section 9859a of this title for each fiscal year to make allotments to Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands to be allotted in accordance with their respective needs.


(b) State allotments(1) General ruleFrom the amounts appropriated under section 9859a of this title for each fiscal year and remaining after reservations are made under subsection (a), the Secretary shall allot to each State an amount equal to the sum of—(A) an amount that bears the same ratio to 50 percent of such remainder as the product of the young child factor of the State and the allotment percentage of the State bears to the sum of the corresponding products for all States; and

(B) an amount that bears the same ratio to 50 percent of such remainder as the product of the school lunch factor of the State and the allotment percentage of the State bears to the sum of the corresponding products for all States.


(2) Young child factorIn this subsection, the term “young child factor” means the ratio of the number of children under 5 years of age in a State to the number of such children in all States, as provided by the most recent annual estimates of population in the States by the Census Bureau of the Department of Commerce.


(3) School lunch factorIn this subsection, the term “school lunch factor” means the ratio of the number of children who are receiving free or reduced price lunches under the school lunch program established under the National School Lunch Act (42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.) in the State to the number of such children in all States, as determined annually by the Department of Agriculture.


(4) Allotment percentage(A) In generalFor purposes of this subsection, the allotment percentage for a State shall be determined by dividing the per capita income of all indi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9859c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts reserved</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amounts reserved The Secretary shall reserve not more than one-half of 1 percent of the amount appropriated under section 9859a of this title for each fiscal year to make allotments to Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands to be allotted in accordance with their respective needs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9859c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State allotments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9859c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Data and information The Secretary shall obtain from each appropriate Federal agency, the most recent data and information necessary to determine the allotments provided for in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9859c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definition In this section, the term “State” includes only the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>