<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9859" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9859/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9859/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9859"><akn:num>9859</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9859. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Child with a disability; infant or toddler with a disabilityThe terms “child with a disability” and “infant or toddler with a disability” have the meanings given the terms in sections 1401 and 1431 of title 20.


(2) Eligible child care providerThe term “eligible child care provider” means a provider of child care services for compensation, including a provider of care for a school-age child during non-school hours, that—(A) is licensed, regulated, registered, or otherwise legally operating, under State and local law; and

(B) satisfies the State and local requirements,


applicable to the child care services the provider provides.

(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.


(4) StateThe term “State” means any of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.


(Pub. L. 106–310, div. A, title XIV, § 1401, Oct. 17, 2000, 114 Stat. 1143.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9859_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Child with a disability; infant or toddler with a disability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Child with a disability; infant or toddler with a disability The terms “child with a disability” and “infant or toddler with a disability” have the meanings given the terms in sections 1401 and 1431 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9859_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible child care provider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Eligible child care provider The term “eligible child care provider” means a provider of child care services for compensation, including a provider of care for a school-age child during non-school hours, that— applicable to the child care services the provider provides.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9859_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9859_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) State The term “State” means any of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>