<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9874" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9874/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9874/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9874"><akn:num>9874</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9874. Use of allotments(a) Referral systems; information; contents(1) Subject to the provisions of subsections (c) and (d), amounts paid to a State under section 9873 of this title from its allotment under section 9872 of this title may be used for the planning, development, establishment, operation, expansion, or improvement by the States, directly or by grant or contract with public or private entities, of State and local resource and referral systems to provide information concerning the availability, types, costs, and locations of dependent care services. The information provided by any such system may include—(A) the types of dependent care services available, including services provided by individual homes, religious organizations, community organizations, employers, private industry, and public and private institutions;

(B) the costs of available dependent care services;

(C) the locations in which dependent care services are provided;

(D) the forms of transportation available to such locations;

(E) the hours during which such dependent care services are available;

(F) the dependents eligible to enroll for such dependent care services; and

(G) any resource and referral system planned, developed, established, expanded, or improved with amounts paid to a State under this subchapter.


(2) The State, with respect to the uses of funds described in paragraph (1) of this subsection shall—(A) provide assurances that no information will be included with respect to any dependent care services which are not provided in compliance with the laws of the State and localities in which such services are provided; and

(B) provide assurances that the information provided will be the latest information available and will be kept up to date.



(b) School-age child care services; assurances; estimates(1) Subject to the provisions of subsections (c) and (d), amounts paid to a State under section 9873 of this title from its allotment under section 9872 of this title may be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9874_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral systems; information; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Referral systems; information; contents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9874_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>School-age child care services; assurances; estimates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) School-age child care services; assurances; estimates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9874_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Percentage of allotment; waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Percentage of allotment; waiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9874_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition; use of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition; use of amounts A State may not use amounts paid to it under this subchapter to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9874_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share; cost of administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Federal share; cost of administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9874_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duplication of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Duplication of services Projects supported under this section to plan, develop, establish, expand, operate, or improve a State or local resource and referral system or before or after school child care program shall not duplicate any services which are provided before October 30, 1984, by the State or locality which will be served by such system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9874_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance to States; planning and operational activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Technical assistance to States; planning and operational activities The Secretary may provide technical assistance to States in planning and carrying out activities under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>