<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9917" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9917/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9917/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9917"><akn:num>9917</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability and reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9917. Accountability and reporting requirements(a) State accountability and reporting requirements(1) Performance measurement(A) In generalBy October 1, 2001, each State that receives funds under this chapter shall participate, and shall ensure that all eligible entities in the State participate, in a performance measurement system, which may be a performance measurement system for which the Secretary facilitated development pursuant to subsection (b), or an alternative system that the Secretary is satisfied meets the requirements of subsection (b).


(B) Local agenciesThe State may elect to have local agencies that are subcontractors of the eligible entities under this chapter participate in the performance measurement system. If the State makes that election, references in this section to eligible entities shall be considered to include the local agencies.



(2) Annual reportEach State shall annually prepare and submit to the Secretary a report on the measured performance of the State and the eligible entities in the State. Prior to the participation of the State in the performance measurement system, the State shall include in the report any information collected by the State relating to such performance. Each State shall also include in the report an accounting of the expenditure of funds received by the State through the community services block grant program, including an accounting of funds spent on administrative costs by the State and the eligible entities, and funds spent by eligible entities on the direct delivery of local services, and shall include information on the number of and characteristics of clients served under this chapter in the State, based on data collected from the eligible entities. The State shall also include in the report a summary describing the training and technical assistance offered by the State under section 9915(a)(3) of this title during the year covered by the report.



(b) Secretary’s accountability and reporting requirem</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9917_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State accountability and reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State accountability and reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9917_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary’s accountability and reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Secretary’s accountability and reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>