<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9925" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9925/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/9925/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9925"><akn:num>9925</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration partnership agreements addressing needs of poor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9925. Demonstration partnership agreements addressing needs of poor(a) General authority(1) In order to stimulate the development of new approaches to provide for greater self-sufficiency of the poor, to test and evaluate such new approaches, to disseminate project results and evaluation findings so that such approaches can be replicated, and to strengthen the integration, coordination, and redirection of activities to promote maximum self-sufficiency among the poor, the Secretary may make grants from funds appropriated under subsection (e) to eligible entities for the development and implementation of new and innovative approaches to deal with particularly critical needs or problems of the poor which are common to a number of communities. Grants may be made only with respect to applications which—(A) involve activities which can be incorporated into or be closely coordinated with eligible entities’ ongoing programs;

(B) involve significant new combinations of resources or new and innovative approaches involving partnership agreements;

(C) are structured in a way that will, within the limits of the type of assistance or activities contemplated, most fully and effectively promote the purposes of the Community Services Block Grant Act [42 U.S.C. 9901 et seq.]; and

(D) contain an assurance that the applicant for such grants will obtain an independent, methodologically sound evaluation of the effectiveness of the activities carried out with such grant and will submit such evaluation to the Secretary.


(2) No grant may be made under this section unless an application is submitted to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information, as the Secretary may require.

(3) Initial and subsequent grant awards may fully fund projects for periods of up to 3 years.


(b) Federal share; limitations(1)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), grants awarded pursuant to this section shall be used for programs and shall not exceed 50 per centum</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9925_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9925_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share; limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal share; limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9925_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs directed to special populations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Programs directed to special populations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9925_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of results</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Dissemination of results As soon as practicable, but not later than 180 days after the end of the fiscal year in which a recipient of a grant under this section completes the expenditure of such grant, the Secretary shall prepare and make available to each State and each eligible entity a description of the program carried out with such grant, any relevant information developed and results achieved, and a summary of the evaluation of such program received under subsection (a)(1)(D) so as to provide a model of innovative programs for other eligible entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9925_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Replication of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Replication of programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9925_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9925_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9925_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>