<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/1111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/1111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/1111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1111"><akn:num>1111</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition workforce authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1111. Acquisition workforce authorities(a) Expedited Hiring Authority.—(1) In general.—For the purposes of section 3304 of title 5, the Commandant may—(A) designate any category of acquisition positions within the Coast Guard as shortage category positions; and

(B) use the authorities in such section to recruit and appoint highly qualified persons directly to positions so designated.


(2) Reports.—The Commandant shall include in reports under section 1102 information described in such section regarding positions designated under this subsection.


(b) Reemployment Authority.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), if an annuitant receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund becomes employed in any category of acquisition positions designated by the Commandant under subsection (a), the annuity of the annuitant so employed shall continue. The annuitant so reemployed shall not be considered an employee for purposes of subchapter III of chapter 83 or chapter 84 of title 5.

(2)(A) Election.—An annuitant retired under section 8336(d)(1) or 8414(b)(1)(A) of title 5, receiving an annuity from the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, who becomes employed in any category of acquisition positions designated by the Commandant under subsection (a) after the date of the enactment of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2020, may elect to be subject to section 8344 or 8468 of such title (as the case may be).(i) Deadline.—An election for coverage under this subsection shall be filed not later than 90 days after the Commandant takes reasonable actions to notify an employee who may file an election.

(ii) Coverage.—If an employee files an election under this subsection, coverage shall be effective beginning on the first day of the first applicable pay period beginning on or after the date of the filing of the election.


(B) Application.—Paragraph (1) shall apply to an individual who is eligible to file an el</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited Hiring Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reemployment Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>