<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/1903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/1903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/1903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1903"><akn:num>1903</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Board of Visitors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1903. Annual Board of Visitors(a) In General.—A Board of Visitors to the Coast Guard Academy is established to review and make recommendations on the operation of the Academy.

(b) Membership.—(1) In general.—The membership of the Board shall consist of the following:(A) The chairman of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, or the chairman’s designee.

(B) The chairman of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, or the chairman’s designee.

(C) 3 Members of the Senate designated by the Vice President.

(D) 4 Members of the House of Representatives designated by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.

(E) 6 individuals designated by the President.


(2) Length of service.—(A) Members of congress.—A Member of Congress designated under subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) as a member of the Board shall be designated as a member in the First Session of a Congress and serve for the duration of that Congress.

(B) Individuals designated by the president.—Each individual designated by the President under subparagraph (E) of paragraph (1) shall serve as a member of the Board for 3 years, except that any such member whose term of office has expired shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed by the President.


(3) Death or resignation of a member.—If a member of the Board dies or resigns, a successor shall be designated for any unexpired portion of the term of the member by the official who designated the member.


(c) Academy Visits.—(1) Annual visit.—The Board shall visit the Academy annually to review the operation of the Academy.

(2) Additional visits.—With the approval of the Secretary, the Board or individual members of the Board may make other visits to the Academy in connection with the duties of the Board or to consult with the Superintendent of the Academy.


(d) Scope of Review.—The Board shall review, with respect to the Academy—(1) the state of morale and discipli</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A Board of Visitors to the Coast Guard Academy is established to review and make recommendations on the operation of the Academy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Academy Visits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Board shall review, with respect to the Academy—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than 60 days after the date of an annual visit of the Board under subsection (c)(1), the Board shall submit to the Secretary, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the actions of the Board during such visit and the recommendations of the Board pertaining to the Academy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) If approved by the Secretary, the Board may consult with advisors in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Each member of the Board and each adviser consulted by the Board under subsection (f) shall be reimbursed, to the extent permitted by law, by the Coast Guard for actual expenses incurred while engaged in duties as a member or adviser.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>