<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/1942" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/1942/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/1942/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1942"><akn:num>1942</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent commissioned teaching staff; composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1942. Permanent commissioned teaching staff; composition
The permanent commissioned teaching staff at the Academy shall consist of professors, associate professors, assistant professors and instructors, in such numbers as the needs of the Service require. They shall perform duties as prescribed by the Commandant, and exercise command only in the academic department of the Academy.
(Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393, 63 Stat. 509, § 187; Pub. L. 86–474, § 1(10), May 14, 1960, 74 Stat. 145; renumbered § 1942, Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 110(b), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4212.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 14, U.S.C., 1946 ed., §§ 15b, 15c (Apr. 16, 1937, ch. 107, §§ 1, 2, 50 Stat. 66; May 2, 1942, ch. 273, 56 Stat. 265).
Section 15b of title 14, U.S.C., 1946 ed., has been divided. Part of the provisions of the first sentence is placed in this section, while other provisions are placed in section 188 of this title.
Section 15c of title 14, U.S.C., 1946 ed., has been divided. The last sentence is incorporated in this section, while the other provisions are placed in section 189 of this title.
The composition of the teaching staff at the Academy is changed materially on the recommendation of the Academic Board and the Advisory Committee. The scope of duty of members of the staff is enlarged to include whatever the Commandant prescribes.
Title 14, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 15b provides for five professors as heads or assistant heads of departments at the Academy. The Academic Board of the Academy and the Advisory Committee, after extensive study have recommended the change, as provided in this section, to three professors and twelve others on the permanent teaching staff, with designations to conform generally with the designations and grades of faculty members at other universities. The librarian is given faculty status because of the role of the library as the center of the modern university; this is in conformity with the practice of other higher educational institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>