<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2120a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2120a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2120a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2120a"><akn:num>2120a</akn:num><akn:heading>Special selection review boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2120a. Special selection review boards(a) In General.—(1) If the Secretary determines that a person recommended by a promotion board for promotion to a grade at or below the grade of rear admiral is the subject of credible information of an adverse nature, including any substantiated adverse finding or conclusion described in section 2115(a)(3) of this title that was not furnished to the promotion board during its consideration of the person for promotion as otherwise required by such section, the Secretary shall convene a special selection review board under this section to review the person and recommend whether the recommendation for promotion of the person should be sustained.

(2) If a person and the recommendation for promotion of the person is subject to review under this section by a special selection review board convened under this section, the name of the person—(A) shall not be disseminated or publicly released on the list of officers recommended for promotion by the promotion board recommending the promotion of the person; and

(B) shall not be forwarded to the President or the Senate, as applicable, or included on a promotion list under section 2121 of this title.



(b) Convening.—(1) Any special selection review board convened under this section shall be convened in accordance with the provisions of section 2120(c) of this title.

(2) Any special selection review board convened under this section may review such number of persons, and recommendations for promotion of such persons, as the Secretary shall specify in convening such special selection review board.


(c) Information Considered.—(1) In reviewing a person and recommending whether the recommendation for promotion of the person should be sustained under this section, a special selection review board convened under this section shall be furnished and consider the following:(A) The record and information concerning the person furnished in accordance with section 2115 of this title to the prom</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2120a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2120a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Convening.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2120a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Considered.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2120a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2120a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2120a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Persons.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2120a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2120a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion Board Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “promotion board” means a selection board convened by the Secretary under section 2106 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>