<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2501"><akn:num>2501</akn:num><akn:heading>Grade on retirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2501. Grade on retirement(a) Commissioned Officers.—(1) In general.—A commissioned officer who is retired under any provision of this title, shall be retired from active service with the highest grade held by the commissioned officer for not less than six months while on active duty in which, as determined by the Secretary, the commissioned officer’s performance of duty was satisfactory.

(2) Conditional determination.—When a commissioned officer is under investigation for alleged misconduct at the time of retirement—(A) the Secretary may conditionally determine the highest grade of satisfactory service of the commissioned officer pending completion of the investigation; and

(B) the grade under subparagraph (A) is subject to resolution under subsection (c)(2).



(b) Warrant Officers.—Any warrant officer who is retired under any provision of section 580, 1263, 1293, or 1305 of title 10, shall be retired from active service with the highest commissioned grade above chief warrant officer, W–4, held by the warrant officer for not less than six months on active duty in which, as determined by the Secretary, the warrant officer’s performance of duty was satisfactory.

(c) Retirement in Lower Grade.—(1) Misconduct in lower grade.—In the case of a commissioned officer whom the Secretary determines committed misconduct in a lower grade, the Secretary may determine the commissioned officer has not served satisfactorily in any grade equal to or higher than that lower grade.

(2) Adverse findings.—A determination of the retired grade of a commissioned officer shall be resolved following a conditional determination under subsection (a)(2) if the investigation of or personnel action against the commissioned officer results in adverse findings.

(3) Recalculation of retired pay.—If the retired grade of a commissioned officer is reduced pursuant to this subsection, the retired pay of the commissioned officer shall be recalculated under chapter 71 of title 10, and any modificati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commissioned Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Warrant Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any warrant officer who is retired under any provision of section 580, 1263, 1293, or 1305 of title 10, shall be retired from active service with the highest commissioned grade above chief warrant officer, W–4, held by the warrant officer for not less than six months on active duty in which, as determined by the Secretary, the warrant officer’s performance of duty was satisfactory.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2501_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement in Lower Grade.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2501_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of Retired Grade Determinations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2501_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability to Commissioned Warrant Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) This section, including subsection (b), shall not apply to commissioned warrant officers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>