<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2502"><akn:num>2502</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2502. Retirement(a) Every commissioned officer, warrant officer, or enlisted member who is retired under any provisions of this title shall be retired with the permanent grade or rate held at the time of retirement, unless entitled to retire with a higher grade or rate under any provision of this title or any other law.

(b) Where an officer is entitled, under any provision of law, to retire with one grade higher than the grade in which serving at the time of retirement, the next higher grade in the case of captain shall be rear admiral (lower half), and the next higher grade in the case of commissioned warrant officer shall be lieutenant (junior grade).

(Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393, 63 Stat. 524, § 421; Pub. L. 97–417, § 2(10), Jan. 4, 1983, 96 Stat. 2086; Pub. L. 98–557, § 15(a)(3)(A), Oct. 30, 1984, 98 Stat. 2865; Pub. L. 99–145, title V, § 514(c)(1), Nov. 8, 1985, 99 Stat. 629; Pub. L. 99–348, title II, § 205(b)(10), July 1, 1986, 100 Stat. 700; renumbered § 2502, Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 114(b), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4223.)

Historical and Revision NotesSubsection (a) is new in this form, but the provision contained therein is expressed or implied in numerous statutes relating to the retirement of military personnel.
A provision defining the next higher grade to that of commissioned warrant officer as lieutenant (junior grade), for purposes of retirement, was added.
The other provisions of said section are obsolete and are no longer needed.
Subsection (a) is new, but the provision contained in it is expressed or implied in numerous statutes relating to retirement of military personnel. It is believed desirable to include such a provision to prevent any misconstruction of retirement statutes, even though no change in existing law is intended on the point covered, either by other sections dealing with retirement or by this section.
Subsection (b) is a codification of the only provision of title 14, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 174, that it is desired to retain, and in a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Every commissioned officer, warrant officer, or enlisted member who is retired under any provisions of this title shall be retired with the permanent grade or rate held at the time of retirement, unless entitled to retire with a higher grade or rate under any provision of this title or any other law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Where an officer is entitled, under any provision of law, to retire with one grade higher than the grade in which serving at the time of retirement, the next higher grade in the case of captain shall be rear admiral (lower half), and the next higher grade in the case of commissioned warrant officer shall be lieutenant (junior grade).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>