<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2514" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2514/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2514/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2514"><akn:num>2514</akn:num><akn:heading>Career flexibility to enhance retention of members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2514. Career flexibility to enhance retention of members(a) Programs Authorized.—The Commandant may carry out a program under which members of the Coast Guard may be inactivated from active duty in order to meet personal or professional needs and returned to active duty at the end of such period of inactivation from active duty.

(b) Period of Inactivation From Active Duty; Effect of Inactivation.—(1) In general.—The period of inactivation from active duty under a program under this section of a member participating in the program shall be such period as the Commandant shall specify in the agreement of the member under subsection (c), except that such period may not exceed 3 years.

(2) Exclusion from years of service.—Any service by a Reserve officer while participating in a program under this section shall be excluded from computation of the total years of service of that officer pursuant to section 14706(a) of title 10.

(3) Exclusion from retirement.—Any period of participation of a member in a program under this section shall not count toward—(A) eligibility for retirement or transfer to the Ready Reserve under either chapter 841 or 1223 of title 10; or

(B) computation of retired or retainer pay under chapter 71 or 1223 of title 10.



(c) Agreement.—Each member of the Coast Guard who participates in a program under this section shall enter into a written agreement with the Commandant under which that member shall agree as follows:(1) To accept an appointment or enlist, as applicable, and serve in the Coast Guard Ready Reserve during the period of the inactivation of the member from active duty under the program.

(2) To undergo during the period of the inactivation of the member from active duty under the program such inactive service training as the Commandant shall require in order to ensure that the member retains proficiency, at a level determined by the Commandant to be sufficient, in the military skills, professional qualifications, and physical readi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Commandant may carry out a program under which members of the Coast Guard may be inactivated from active duty in order to meet personal or professional needs and returned to active duty at the end of such period of inactivation from active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of Inactivation From Active Duty; Effect of Inactivation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each member of the Coast Guard who participates in a program under this section shall enter into a written agreement with the Commandant under which that member shall agree as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of Release.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Commandant shall prescribe regulations specifying the guidelines regarding the conditions of release that must be considered and addressed in the agreement required by subsection (c). At a minimum, the Commandant shall prescribe the procedures and standards to be used to instruct a member on the obligations to be assumed by the member under paragraph (2) of such subsection while the member is released from active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order to Active Duty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Under regulations prescribed by the Commandant, a member of the Coast Guard participating in a program under this section may, in the discretion of the Commandant, be required to terminate participation in the program and be ordered to active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pay and Allowances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued Entitlements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) A member participating in a program under this section shall, while participating in the program, be treated as a member of the Armed Forces on active duty for a period of more than 30 days for purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>