<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2704"><akn:num>2704</akn:num><akn:heading>Equipment to prevent accidents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2704. Equipment to prevent accidents
The Coast Guard may make such expenditures as are deemed appropriate for promotion and maintenance of the safety and occupational health of, and the prevention of accidents affecting, personnel of the Coast Guard, including the purchase of clothing, equipment, and other materials necessary thereto.
(Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393, 63 Stat. 532, § 477; renumbered § 2704, Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 116(b), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4226.)

Historical and Revision NotesDerived from title 5, U.S.C., 1946, ed., § 118g (Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 744, § 13, 60 Stat. 809).
Because of the wide variety of tasks assigned to Coast Guard personnel it is deemed advisable to broaden this authority to the more general language as rewritten, insofar as Coast Guard personnel are concerned, thus giving complete authority to protect their health.
Said section would in no way be affected.
Inasmuch as the act cited above applies to executive departments generally, it is not scheduled for repeal by this act. 81st Congress, House Report No. 557.

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 2704 was renumbered section 4904 of this title.

Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–282 renumbered section 477 of this title as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of November 25, 2002, as modified, set out as a note under section 542 of Title 6.

Hypothermia Protective Clothing RequirementPub. L. 107–295, title IV, § 410, Nov. 25, 2002, 116 Stat. 2118, provided that: “The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall ensure that all Coast Guard personnel are equipped wi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>