<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2766" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2766/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2766/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2766"><akn:num>2766</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel card management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2766. Travel card management(a) In General.—The Secretary may require that travel or transportation allowances due a civilian employee or military member of the Coast Guard be disbursed directly to the issuer of a Federal contractor-issued travel charge card, but only in an amount not to exceed the authorized travel expenses charged by that Coast Guard member to that travel charge card issued to that employee or member.

(b) Withholding of Nondisputed Obligations.—The Secretary may also establish requirements similar to those established by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to section 2784a of title 10 for deduction or withholding of pay or retired pay from a Coast Guard employee, member, or retired member who is delinquent in payment under the terms of the contract under which the card was issued and does not dispute the amount of the delinquency.

(Added Pub. L. 108–293, title II, § 210(a), Aug. 9, 2004, 118 Stat. 1036, § 517; renumbered § 2766, Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 116(b), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4226.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–282 renumbered section 517 of this title as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2766_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary may require that travel or transportation allowances due a civilian employee or military member of the Coast Guard be disbursed directly to the issuer of a Federal contractor-issued travel charge card, but only in an amount not to exceed the authorized travel expenses charged by that Coast Guard member to that travel charge card issued to that employee or member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2766_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding of Nondisputed Obligations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may also establish requirements similar to those established by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to section 2784a of title 10 for deduction or withholding of pay or retired pay from a Coast Guard employee, member, or retired member who is delinquent in payment under the terms of the contract under which the card was issued and does not dispute the amount of the delinquency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>