<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2779" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2779/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2779/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2779"><akn:num>2779</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation to and from certain places of employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2779. Transportation to and from certain places of employment(a) Whenever the Secretary determines that it is necessary for the effective conduct of the affairs of the Coast Guard, he may, at reasonable rates of fare fixed under regulations to be prescribed by him, provide assured and adequate transportation by motor vehicle or water carrier to and from their places of employment for individuals attached to, or employed by, the Coast Guard; and during a war or during a national emergency declared by Congress or the President, for individuals attached to, or employed in, a private plant that is manufacturing material for the Coast Guard.

(b) Transportation may not be provided under subsection (a) unless the Secretary or an officer designated by the Secretary, determines that—(1) other transportation facilities are inadequate and cannot be made adequate;

(2) a reasonable effort has been made to induce operators of private facilities to provide the necessary transportation; and

(3) the service to be furnished will make proper use of transportation facilities and will supply the most efficient transportation to the individuals concerned.


(c) To provide transportation under subsection (a), the Secretary may—(1) buy, lease, or charter motor vehicles or water carriers having a seating capacity of 12 or more passengers;

(2) maintain and operate that equipment by enlisted members or employees of the Coast Guard, or by private individuals under contract; and

(3) lease or charter the equipment to private or public carriers for operation under terms that are considered necessary by the Secretary or by an officer designated by the Secretary, and that may provide for the pooling of government-owned and privately owned equipment and facilities and for the reciprocal use of that equipment.


(d) Fares received under subsection (a), and proceeds of the leasing or chartering of equipment under subsection (c)(3), shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2779_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whenever the Secretary determines that it is necessary for the effective conduct of the affairs of the Coast Guard, he may, at reasonable rates of fare fixed under regulations to be prescribed by him, provide assured and adequate transportation by motor vehicle or water carrier to and from their places of employment for individuals attached to, or employed by, the Coast Guard; and during a war or during a national emergency declared by Congress or the President, for individuals attached to, or employed in, a private plant that is manufacturing material for the Coast Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2779_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transportation may not be provided under subsection (a) unless the Secretary or an officer designated by the Secretary, determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2779_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To provide transportation under subsection (a), the Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2779_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fares received under subsection (a), and proceeds of the leasing or chartering of equipment under subsection (c)(3), shall be covered into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>