<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2924" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2924/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/2924/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2924"><akn:num>2924</akn:num><akn:heading>Child development center employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2924. Child development center employees(a) Training.—(1) In general.—The Commandant shall establish a training program for Coast Guard child development center employees and satisfactory completion of the training program shall be a condition of employment for each employee of a Coast Guard child development center.

(2) Timing for new hires.—The Commandant shall require each employee of a Coast Guard child development center to complete the training program established under paragraph (1) not later than 6 months after the date on which the employee is hired.

(3) Minimum requirements.—The training program established under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, instruction with respect to—(A) early childhood development;

(B) activities and disciplinary techniques appropriate to children of different ages;

(C) child abuse and neglect prevention and detection; and

(D) cardiopulmonary resuscitation and other emergency medical procedures.


(4) Use of department of defense programs.—The Commandant may use Department of Defense training programs, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis, for purposes of this subsection.


(b) Training and Curriculum Specialists.—(1) Specialist required.—The Commandant shall require that at least 1 employee at each Coast Guard child development center be a specialist in training and curriculum development with appropriate credentials and experience.

(2) Duties.—The duties of the specialist described in paragraph (1) shall include—(A) special teaching activities;

(B) daily oversight and instruction of other child care employees;

(C) daily assistance in the preparation of lesson plans;

(D) assisting with child abuse and neglect prevention and detection; and

(E) advising the director of the center on the performance of the other child care employees.


(3) Competitive service.—Each specialist described in paragraph (1) shall be an employee in a competitive service position.


(Added Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 214(a), Dec.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2924_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2924_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and Curriculum Specialists.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>