<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_313"><akn:num>313</akn:num><akn:heading>Centers of expertise for Coast Guard prevention and response</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 313. Centers of expertise for Coast Guard prevention and response(a) Establishment.—The Commandant may establish and operate one or more centers of expertise for prevention and response missions of the Coast Guard (in this section referred to as a “center”).

(b) Missions.—Any center established under subsection (a) shall—(1) promote, facilitate, and conduct—(A) education;

(B) training; and

(C) activities authorized under section 504(a)(4);


(2) be a repository of information on operations, practices, and resources related to the mission for which the center was established; and

(3) perform and support the mission for which the center was established.


(c) Joint Operation With Educational Institution Authorized.—The Commandant may enter into an agreement with an appropriate official of an institution of higher education to—(1) provide for joint operation of a center; and

(2) provide necessary administrative services for a center, including administration and allocation of funds.


(d) Acceptance of Donations.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Commandant may accept, on behalf of a center, donations to be used to defray the costs of the center or to enhance the operation of the center. Those donations may be accepted from any State or local government, any foreign government, any foundation or other charitable organization (including any that is organized or operates under the laws of a foreign country), or any individual.

(2) The Commandant may not accept a donation under paragraph (1) if the acceptance of the donation would compromise or appear to compromise—(A) the ability of the Coast Guard or the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, any employee of the Coast Guard or the department, or any member of the Armed Forces to carry out any responsibility or duty in a fair and objective manner; or

(B) the integrity of any program of the Coast Guard, the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, or of any individual involved in su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Commandant may establish and operate one or more centers of expertise for prevention and response missions of the Coast Guard (in this section referred to as a “center”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Missions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any center established under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint Operation With Educational Institution Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Commandant may enter into an agreement with an appropriate official of an institution of higher education to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of Donations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>