<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_323"><akn:num>323</akn:num><akn:heading>Western Alaska Oil Spill Planning Criteria Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 323. Western Alaska Oil Spill Planning Criteria Program(a) Establishment.—There is established within the Coast Guard a Western Alaska Oil Spill Planning Criteria Program (referred to in this section as the “Program”) to develop and administer the Western Alaska oil spill planning criteria.

(b) Program Manager.—(1) In general.—Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Commandant shall select a permanent civilian career employee through a competitive search process for a term of not less than 5 years to serve as the Western Alaska Oil Spill Criteria Program Manager (referred to in this section as the “Program Manager”)—(A) the primary duty of whom shall be to administer the Program; and

(B) who shall not be subject to frequent or routine reassignment.


(2) Conflicts of interest.—The individual selected to serve as the Program Manager shall not have conflicts of interest relating to entities regulated by the Coast Guard.

(3) Duties.—(A) Development of guidance.—The Program Manager shall develop guidance for—(i) approval, drills, and testing relating to the Western Alaska oil spill planning criteria; and

(ii) gathering input concerning such planning criteria from Federal agencies, State and local governments, Tribes, and relevant industry and nongovernmental entities.


(B) Assessments.—Not less frequently than once every 5 years, the Program Manager shall—(i) assess whether such existing planning criteria adequately meet the needs of vessels operating in the geographic area; and

(ii) identify methods for advancing response capability so as to achieve, with respect to a vessel, compliance with national planning criteria.


(C) Onsite verifications.—The Program Manager shall address the relatively small number and limited nature of verifications of response capabilities for vessel response plans by increasing, within the Seventeenth Coast Guard District, the quantity and frequency of onsite verifications of the providers identified i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established within the Coast Guard a Western Alaska Oil Spill Planning Criteria Program (referred to in this section as the “Program”) to develop and administer the Western Alaska oil spill planning criteria.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_323_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Manager.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_323_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Commandant shall enhance the knowledge and proficiency of Coast Guard personnel with respect to the Program by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_323_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>