<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/3740" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/3740/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/3740/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3740"><akn:num>3740</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion; recommendations of selection boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3740. Promotion; recommendations of selection boards(a) Except as otherwise provided by law, a Reserve officer shall only be promoted pursuant to the recommendation of a selection board.

(b) The Secretary shall convene selection boards from time to time to recommend Reserve officers for promotion to the next higher grade. A board may be convened to consider officers in one or more grades.

(c) A selection board shall, from among the names of those eligible Reserve officers submitted to it, recommend for promotion to the next higher grade:(1) those officers serving in the grade of lieutenant (junior grade) or above whom it considers to be best qualified; and

(2) those officers serving in the grade of ensign whom it considers to be fully qualified.


(d)(1) Before convening a selection board to recommend Reserve officers for promotion, the Secretary shall establish a promotion zone for officers serving in each grade to be considered by the board. The Secretary shall determine the number of officers in the promotion zone for officers serving in any grade from among officers who are eligible for promotion in that grade.

(2)(A) Before convening a selection board to recommend Reserve officers for promotion to a grade (other than the grade of lieutenant (junior grade)), the Secretary shall determine the maximum number of officers in that grade that the board may recommend for promotion.

(B) The Secretary shall make the determination under subparagraph (A) of the maximum number that may be recommended with a view to having in an active status a sufficient number of Reserve officers in each grade to meet the needs of the Coast Guard for Reserve officers in an active status.

(C) In order to make the determination under subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall determine the following:(i) The number of positions needed to accomplish mission objectives that require officers in the grade to which the board will recommend officers for promotion.

(ii) The estimated number of o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3740_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as otherwise provided by law, a Reserve officer shall only be promoted pursuant to the recommendation of a selection board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3740_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall convene selection boards from time to time to recommend Reserve officers for promotion to the next higher grade. A board may be convened to consider officers in one or more grades.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3740_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A selection board shall, from among the names of those eligible Reserve officers submitted to it, recommend for promotion to the next higher grade:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3740_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3740_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The law and regulations relating to the selection for promotion of a commissioned officer of the Regular Coast Guard to the grades of rear admiral (lower half) and rear admiral apply to a Reserve officer, except that to be eligible for consideration for promotion to the grade of rear admiral (lower half) an officer shall have completed at least ten years commissioned service, of which the last five years shall have been served in the Coast Guard Reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3740_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The provisions of section 2117 of this title apply to boards convened under this section. The Secretary shall determine the procedure to be used by a selection board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3740_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The report of a selection board shall be submitted to the Secretary for review and transmission to the President for approval. When an officer recommended by a board for promotion is not acceptable to the President, the President may remove the name of that officer from the report of the board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3740_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The recommendations of a selection board, as approved by the President, constitute a list of selectees from which the promotions of Reserve officers shall be made. An officer on a list of selectees remains thereon until promoted unless removed by the President under section 3749 of this title. If an existing list of selectees has not been exhausted by the time a later list has been approved, all officers remaining on the older list shall be tendered appointments prior to those on the later list.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3740_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A Reserve officer whose name is on a list of selectees for promotion shall, unless that officer’s promotion is lawfully withheld, be tendered an appointment in the next higher grade on the date a vacancy occurs, or as soon thereafter as practicable in the grade to which the officer was selected for promotion or, if promotion was determined in accordance with a running mate system, at the same time, or as soon thereafter as practicable, as that officer’s running mate is tendered a similar appointment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>