<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/509" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/509/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/509/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_509"><akn:num>509</akn:num><akn:heading>Space-available travel on Coast Guard aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 509. Space-available travel on Coast Guard aircraft(a) Establishment.—(1) In general.—The Commandant may establish a program to provide transportation on Coast Guard aircraft on a space-available basis to the categories of eligible individuals described in subsection (c) (in this section referred to as the “program”).

(2) Policy development.—Not later than 1 year after the date on which the program is established, the Commandant shall develop a policy for the operation of the program.


(b) Operation of Program.—(1) In general.—The Commandant shall operate the program in a budget-neutral manner.

(2) Limitations.—(A) In general.—Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no additional funds may be used, or flight hours performed, for the purpose of providing transportation under the program.

(B) De minimis expenditures.—The Commandant may make de minimis expenditures of resources required for the administrative aspects of the program.


(3) Reimbursement not required.—Eligible individuals described in subsection (c) shall not be required to reimburse the Coast Guard for travel provided under this section.


(c) Categories of Eligible Individuals.—Subject to subsection (d), the categories of eligible individuals described in this subsection are the following:(1) Members of the armed forces on active duty.

(2) Members of the Selected Reserve who hold a valid Uniformed Services Identification and Privilege Card.

(3) Retired members of a regular or reserve component of the armed forces, including retired members of reserve components who, but for being under the eligibility age applicable under section 12731 of title 10, would be eligible for retired pay under chapter 1223 of title 10.

(4) Subject to subsection (f), veterans with a permanent service-connected disability rated as total.

(5) Such categories of dependents of individuals described in paragraphs (1) through (3) as the Commandant shall specify in the policy under subsection (a)(2), under such conditions </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Categories of Eligible Individuals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subject to subsection (d), the categories of eligible individuals described in this subsection are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In operating the program, the Commandant shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Travel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Section.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The authority to provide transportation under the program is in addition to any other authority under law to provide transportation on Coast Guard aircraft on a space-available basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>