<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/5109" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/5109/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/5109/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5109"><akn:num>5109</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on gender diversity in the Coast Guard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5109. Report on gender diversity in the Coast Guard(a) In General.—Not later than January 15, 2022, and biennially thereafter, the Commandant shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on gender diversity in the Coast Guard.

(b) Contents.—The report required under subsection (a) shall contain the following:(1) Gender diversity overview.—An overview of Coast Guard active duty and reserve members, including the number of officers and enlisted members and the percentages of men and women in each.

(2) Recruitment and retention.—(A) An analysis of the changes in the recruitment and retention of women over the previous 2 years.

(B) A discussion of any changes to Coast Guard recruitment and retention over the previous 2 years that were aimed at increasing the recruitment and retention of female members.


(3) Parental leave.—(A) The number of men and women who took parental leave during each year covered by the report, including the average length of such leave periods.

(B) A discussion of the ways in which the Coast Guard worked to mitigate the impacts of parental leave on Coast Guard operations and on the careers of the members taking such leave.


(4) Limitations.—An analysis of current gender-based limitations on Coast Guard career opportunities, including discussion of—(A) shipboard opportunities;

(B) opportunities to serve at remote units; and

(C) any other limitations on the opportunities of female members.


(5) Progress update.—An update on the Coast Guard’s progress on the implementation of the action plan required under subsection (a) of section 8215 of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2020.


(Added Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXII [LXXXII], § 8215(d)(1), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4652.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSubsection (a) of section 8215 of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5109_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than January 15, 2022, and biennially thereafter, the Commandant shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on gender diversity in the Coast Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5109_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The report required under subsection (a) shall contain the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>