<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/5110" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/5110/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/5110/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5110"><akn:num>5110</akn:num><akn:heading>Mission need statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5110. Mission need statement(a) In General.—On the date on which the President submits to Congress a budget for fiscal year 2019 under section 1105 of title 31 and every 4 years thereafter, the Commandant shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate an integrated major acquisition mission need statement.

(b) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Integrated major acquisition mission need statement.—The term “integrated major acquisition mission need statement” means a document that—(A) identifies current and projected gaps in Coast Guard mission capabilities using mission hour targets;

(B) explains how each major acquisition program addresses gaps identified under subparagraph (A) if funded at the levels provided for such program in the most recently submitted capital investment plan; and

(C) describes the missions the Coast Guard will not be able to achieve, by fiscal year, for each gap identified under subparagraph (A).


(2) Major acquisition program.—The term “major acquisition program” has the meaning given that term in section 5103.

(3) Capital investment plan.—The term “capital investment plan” means the plan required under section 5102(a)(1).


(Added Pub. L. 111–281, title IV, § 402(a), Oct. 15, 2010, 124 Stat. 2940, § 569; amended Pub. L. 112–213, title II, § 217(8), Dec. 20, 2012, 126 Stat. 1558; Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 215(a), Dec. 18, 2014, 128 Stat. 3034; Pub. L. 114–120, title I, § 102(f), Feb. 8, 2016, 130 Stat. 33; Pub. L. 115–232, div. C, title XXXV, § 3536, Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 2322; renumbered § 1110 and amended Pub. L. 115–282, title I, §§ 108(b), 123(b)(2), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4208, 4240; renumbered § 5110, Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV [LXXXV], § 8501(a)(3), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4745.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2021—Pub. L. 116–283 renumbered section 1110 of thi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5110_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) On the date on which the President submits to Congress a budget for fiscal year 2019 under section 1105 of title 31 and every 4 years thereafter, the Commandant shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate an integrated major acquisition mission need statement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5110_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>