<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/542" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/542/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/542/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_542"><akn:num>542</akn:num><akn:heading>Unauthorized aids to maritime navigation; penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 542. Unauthorized aids to maritime navigation; penalty
No person, or public body, or instrumentality, excluding the armed services, shall establish, erect, or maintain any aid to maritime navigation in or adjacent to the waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, its territories or possessions, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, or on the high seas if that person, or public body, or instrumentality is subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, without first obtaining authority to do so from the Coast Guard in accordance with applicable regulations. Whoever violates the provisions of this section or any of the regulations issued by the Secretary in accordance herewith shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be fined not more than $1,500 for each offense. Each day during which such violation continues shall be considered as a new offense.
(Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393, 63 Stat. 500, § 83; Pub. L. 93–283, § 1(1), May 14, 1974, 88 Stat. 139; Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 205(a)(1), Dec. 18, 2014, 128 Stat. 3025; renumbered § 542, Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4200.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 33, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 759 (June 20, 1906, ch. 3447, § 3, 34 Stat. 324; June 17, 1910, ch. 301, § 6, 36 Stat. 538; Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 1, 37 Stat. 736; 1939 Reorg. Plan No. II, § 2(a), eff. July 1, 1939, 4 F.R. 2731, 53 Stat. 1432).
Changes were made in phraseology. 81st Congress, House Report No. 557.

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 542 was renumbered section 2904 of this title.

Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–282 renumbered section 83 of this title as this section.
2014—Pub. L. 113–281 substituted “$1,500” for “$100”.
1974—Pub. L. 93–283 substituted “maritime navigation in or adjacent to the waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, its territories or possessions, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, or on the high seas if that person, or public body, or instr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>