<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/544" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/544/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/544/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_544"><akn:num>544</akn:num><akn:heading>Aids to maritime navigation; penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 544. Aids to maritime navigation; penalty
The Secretary shall prescribe and enforce necessary and reasonable rules and regulations, for the protection of maritime navigation, relative to the establishment, maintenance, and operation of lights and other signals on fixed and floating structures in or over waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and in the high seas for structures owned or operated by persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States. Any owner or operator of such a structure, excluding an agency of the United States, who violates any of the rules or regulations prescribed hereunder, commits a misdemeanor and shall be punished, upon conviction thereof, by a fine of not exceeding $1,500 for each day which such violation continues.
(Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393, 63 Stat. 501, § 85; June 4, 1956, ch. 351, § 1, 70 Stat. 226; Pub. L. 93–283, § 1(2), May 14, 1974, 88 Stat. 139; Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 205(a)(3), Dec. 18, 2014, 128 Stat. 3025; renumbered § 544, Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4200.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 33, U.S.C., 1946 ed., § 760 (May 14, 1908, ch. 168, § 5, 35 Stat. 162).
Changes were made in phraseology. 81st Congress, House Report No. 557.

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 544 was renumbered section 2906 of this title.

Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–282 renumbered section 85 of this title as this section.
2014—Pub. L. 113–281 substituted “$1,500” for “$100”.
1974—Pub. L. 93–283 struck out “on fixed structures” after “maritime navigation” in section catchline and in text substituted “fixed and floating structures in or over waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and in the high seas for structures owned or operated by persons subject to the jurisdiction of the United States” for “fixed structures in or over navigable waters of the United States”.
1956—Act June 4, 1956, amended section generally, vesting in Secretary rule-making authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>