<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/563" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/563/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/563/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_563"><akn:num>563</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of certain determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 563. Notification of certain determinations(a) In General.—At least 90 days prior to making a final determination that a waterway, or a portion thereof, is navigable for purposes of the jurisdiction of the Coast Guard, the Commandant shall provide notification regarding the proposed determination to—(1) the Governor of each State in which such waterway, or portion thereof, is located;

(2) the public; and

(3) the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.


(b) Content Requirement.—Each notification provided under subsection (a) to an entity specified in paragraph (3) of that subsection shall include—(1) an analysis of whether vessels operating on the waterway, or portion thereof, subject to the proposed determination are subject to inspection or similar regulation by State or local officials;

(2) an analysis of whether operators of commercial vessels on such waterway, or portion thereof, are subject to licensing or similar regulation by State or local officials; and

(3) an estimate of the annual costs that the Coast Guard may incur in conducting operations on such waterway, or portion thereof.


(Added Pub. L. 113–281, title II, § 210(a), Dec. 18, 2014, 128 Stat. 3027, § 103; renumbered § 563, Pub. L. 115–282, title I, § 105(b), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4200.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsFor redesignation of prior sections 563 to 688 not listed below as having been previously repealed or renumbered, see Table Showing Redesignations Made by Title I of Pub. L. 115–282 preceding section 101 of this title.
Prior sections 563 to 567 were repealed by act May 5, 1950, ch. 169, §§ 5, 14(v), 64 Stat. 145, 148, effective May 31, 1951.
Section 563, act Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393, 63 Stat. 539; Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 28, 64 Stat. 407, related to summary courts-martial.
Section 564, act Aug. 4, 1949, ch. 393, 63 Stat. 540; Aug. 3, 1950, ch. 536, § 29, 64 Stat. 407</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_563_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) At least 90 days prior to making a final determination that a waterway, or a portion thereof, is navigable for purposes of the jurisdiction of the Coast Guard, the Commandant shall provide notification regarding the proposed determination to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_563_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Each notification provided under subsection (a) to an entity specified in paragraph (3) of that subsection shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>