<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/564" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/564/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/14/564/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_564"><akn:num>564</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of sexual assault forensic examination kits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 564. Administration of sexual assault forensic examination kits(a) Sexual Assault Forensic Exam Procedure.—(1) In general.—Before embarking on any prescheduled voyage, a Coast Guard vessel shall have in place a written operating procedure that ensures that an embarked victim of sexual assault shall have access to a sexual assault forensic examination—(A) as soon as possible after the victim requests an examination; and

(B) that is treated with the same level of urgency as emergency medical care.


(2) Requirements.—The written operating procedure required by paragraph (1),11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. shall, at a minimum, account for—(A) the health, safety, and privacy of a victim of sexual assault;

(B) the proximity of ashore or afloat medical facilities, including coordination as necessary with the Department of Defense, including other military departments (as defined in section 101 of title 10);

(C) the availability of aeromedical evacuation;

(D) the operational capabilities of the vessel concerned;

(E) the qualifications of medical personnel onboard;

(F) coordination with law enforcement and the preservation of evidence;

(G) the means of accessing a sexual assault forensic examination and medical care with a restricted report of sexual assault;

(H) the availability of nonprescription pregnancy prophylactics; and

(I) other unique military considerations.



(Added Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11272(a), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 4066.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Annual ReportPub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXII, § 11272(c)(5), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 4067, provided that: “The Commandant [of the Coast Guard] shall submit to the Transportation and Infrastructure Committee of the House and the Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee of the Senate a report containing the number of sexual assault forensic examinations that were requested by, but not administered within 3 days to, alleged victims of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_564_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sexual Assault Forensic Exam Procedure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>