<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1124" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1124/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1124/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1124"><akn:num>1124</akn:num><akn:heading>Program or project grants and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1124. Program or project grants and contracts(a) Authorization; purposes; limitation on amountThe Secretary may make grants and enter into contracts under this subsection to assist any sea grant program or project if the Secretary finds that such program or project will—(1) implement the objective set forth in section 1121(b) of this title; and

(2) be responsive to the needs or problems of individual States or regions.


The total amount paid pursuant to any such grant or contract may equal 66⅔ percent, or any lesser percent, of the total cost of the sea grant program or project involved; except that this limitation shall not apply in the case of grants or contracts paid for with funds accepted by the Secretary under section 1123(c)(4)(F) of this title or that are appropriated under section 1127(b) of this title.

(b) Special grants; maximum amount; prerequisitesThe Secretary may make special grants under this subsection to implement the objective set forth in section 1121(b) of this title. The amount of any such grant may equal 100 percent, or any lesser percent, of the total cost of the project involved. No grant may be made under this subsection unless the Secretary finds that—(1) no reasonable means is available through which the applicant can meet the matching requirement for a grant under subsection (a);

(2) the probable benefit of such project outweighs the public interest in such matching requirement; and

(3) the same or equivalent benefit cannot be obtained through the award of a contract or grant under subsection (a).


The total amount that may be provided for grants under this subsection during any fiscal year shall not exceed an amount equal to 5 percent of the total funds appropriated for such year under section 1131 of this title.

(c) Eligibility and procedureAny person may apply to the Secretary for a grant or contract under this section. Application shall be made in such form and manner, and with such content and other submissions, as the Secr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1124_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization; purposes; limitation on amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization; purposes; limitation on amount The Secretary may make grants and enter into contracts under this subsection to assist any sea grant program or project if the Secretary finds that such program or project will— The total amount paid pursuant to any such grant or contract may equal 66⅔ percent, or any lesser percent, of the total cost of the sea grant program or project involved; except that this limitation shall not apply in the case of grants or contracts paid for with funds accepted by the Secretary under section 1123(c)(4)(F) of this title or that are appropriated under section 1127(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1124_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special grants; maximum amount; prerequisites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special grants; maximum amount; prerequisites The Secretary may make special grants under this subsection to implement the objective set forth in section 1121(b) of this title. The amount of any such grant may equal 100 percent, or any lesser percent, of the total cost of the project involved. No grant may be made under this subsection unless the Secretary finds that— The total amount that may be provided for grants under this subsection during any fiscal year shall not exceed an amount equal to 5 percent of the total funds appropriated for such year under section 1131 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1124_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility and procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility and procedure Any person may apply to the Secretary for a grant or contract under this section. Application shall be made in such form and manner, and with such content and other submissions, as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe. The Secretary shall act upon each such application within 6 months after the date on which all required information is received.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1124_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>