<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1126" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1126/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1126/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1126"><akn:num>1126</akn:num><akn:heading>Sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1126. Sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes(a) Designation(1) A sea grant college or sea grant institute shall meet the following qualifications—(A) have an existing broad base of competence in fields related to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources;

(B) make a long-term commitment to the objective in section 1121(b) of this title, as determined by the Secretary;

(C) cooperate with other sea grant colleges and institutes and other persons to solve problems or meet needs relating to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources;

(D) have received financial assistance under section 1124 of this title;

(E) be recognized for excellence in fields related to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources (including marine resources management and science), as determined by the Secretary; and

(F) meet such other qualifications as the Secretary, in consultation with the Board, considers necessary or appropriate.


(2) The Secretary may designate an institution, or an association or alliance of two or more such institutions, as a sea grant college if the institution, association, or alliance—(A) meets the qualifications in paragraph (1); and

(B) maintains a program of research, extension services, training, and education in fields related to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources.


(3) The Secretary may designate an institution, or an association or alliance of two or more such institutions, as a sea grant institute if the institution, association, or alliance—(A) meets the qualifications in paragraph (1); and

(B) maintains a program which includes, at a minimum, research and extension services.



(b) Additional designations(1) Notification to Congress of designations(A) In generalNot less than 30 days before designating an institution, or an association or alliance of two or more such institutions, as a sea grant college or sea grant institute under subsection (a), the Secretary shall notify Congress in writing of the proposed designation. The notification sh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1126_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1126_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional designations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1126_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension or termination of designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Suspension or termination of designation The Secretary may, for cause and after an opportunity for hearing, suspend or terminate any designation under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1126_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties Subject to any regulations prescribed or guidelines established by the Secretary, it shall be the responsibility of each sea grant college and sea grant institute—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>