<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1128" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1128/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1128/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1128"><akn:num>1128</akn:num><akn:heading>National Sea Grant Advisory Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1128. National Sea Grant Advisory Board(a) EstablishmentThere shall be an independent committee to be known as the National Sea Grant Advisory Board.


(b) Duties(1) In generalThe Board shall advise the Secretary and the Director concerning—(A) strategies for utilizing the sea grant college program to address the Nation’s highest priorities regarding the understanding, assessment, development, management, utilization, and conservation of ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources;

(B) the designation of sea grant colleges and sea grant institutes; and

(C) such other matters as the Secretary refers to the Board for review and advice.


(2) Periodic reportThe Board shall report to Congress at least once every four years on the state of the national sea grant college program and shall notify Congress of any significant changes to the state of the program not later than two years after the submission of such a report. The Board shall indicate in each such report the progress made toward meeting the priorities identified in the strategic plan in effect under section 1123(c) of this title and provide a summary of research conducted under the program.


(3) Availability of resources of Department of CommerceThe Secretary shall make available to the Board such information, personnel, and administrative services and assistance as it may reasonably require to carry out its duties under this subchapter.



(c) Membership, terms, and powers(1) The Board shall consist of 15 voting members who shall be appointed by the Secretary. The Director and a director of a sea grant program who is elected by the various directors of sea grant programs shall serve as nonvoting members of the Board. Not less than 8 of the voting members of the Board shall be individuals who, by reason of knowledge, experience, or training, are especially qualified in one or more of the disciplines and fields included in marine science. The other voting members shall be individuals who, by reason of knowled</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1128_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There shall be an independent committee to be known as the National Sea Grant Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1128_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1128_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership, terms, and powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership, terms, and powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>