<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1270" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1270/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1270/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1270"><akn:num>1270</akn:num><akn:heading>Patrick Leahy Lake Champlain Basin Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1270. Patrick Leahy Lake Champlain Basin Program(a) Establishment(1) In generalThere is established a Lake Champlain Management Conference to develop a comprehensive pollution prevention, control, and restoration plan for Lake Champlain. The Administrator shall convene the management conference within ninety days of November 16, 1990.


(2) ImplementationThe Administrator—(A) may provide support to the State of Vermont, the State of New York, and the New England Interstate Water Pollution Control Commission for the implementation of the Patrick Leahy Lake Champlain Basin Program; and

(B) shall coordinate actions of the Environmental Protection Agency under subparagraph (A) with the actions of other appropriate Federal agencies.



(b) MembershipThe Members of the Management Conference shall be comprised of—(1) the Governors of the States of Vermont and New York;

(2) each interested Federal agency, not to exceed a total of five members;

(3) the Vermont and New York Chairpersons of the Vermont, New York, Quebec Citizens Advisory Committee for the Environmental Management of Lake Champlain;

(4) four representatives of the State legislature of Vermont;

(5) four representatives of the State legislature of New York;

(6) six persons representing local governments having jurisdiction over any land or water within the Lake Champlain basin, as determined appropriate by the Governors; and

(7) eight persons representing affected industries, nongovernmental organizations, public and private educational institutions, and the general public, as determined appropriate by the trigovernmental Citizens Advisory Committee for the Environmental Management of Lake Champlain, but not to be current members of the Citizens Advisory Committee.


(c) Technical Advisory Committee(1) The Management Conference shall, not later than one hundred and twenty days after November 16, 1990, appoint a Technical Advisory Committee.

(2) Such Technical Advisory Committee shall consist of official</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1270_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1270_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The Members of the Management Conference shall be comprised of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1270_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1270_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Research program The Management Conference shall establish a multi-disciplinary environmental research program for Lake Champlain. Such research program shall be planned and conducted jointly with the Lake Champlain Research Consortium.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1270_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pollution prevention, control, and restoration plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Pollution prevention, control, and restoration plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1270_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grant assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1270_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1270_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>No effect on certain authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No effect on certain authority Nothing in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1270_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>