<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1273" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1273/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1273/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1273"><akn:num>1273</akn:num><akn:heading>Lake Pontchartrain Basin</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1273. Lake Pontchartrain Basin(a) Establishment of restoration programThe Administrator shall establish within the Environmental Protection Agency the Lake Pontchartrain Basin Restoration Program.


(b) PurposeThe purpose of the program shall be to restore the ecological health of the Basin by developing and funding restoration projects and related scientific and public education projects.


(c) DutiesIn carrying out the program, the Administrator shall—(1) provide administrative and technical assistance to a management conference convened for the Basin under section 1330 of this title;

(2) assist and support the activities of the management conference, including the implementation of recommendations of the management conference;

(3) support environmental monitoring of the Basin and research to provide necessary technical and scientific information;

(4) develop a comprehensive research plan to address the technical needs of the program;

(5) coordinate the grant, research, and planning programs authorized under this section;

(6) collect and make available to the public publications, and other forms of information the management conference determines to be appropriate, relating to the environmental quality of the Basin; and

(7) ensure that the comprehensive conservation and management plan approved for the Basin under section 1330 of this title is reviewed and revised in accordance with section 1330 of this title not less often than once every 5 years, beginning on December 23, 2022.


(d) GrantsThe Administrator may make grants to pay not more than 75 percent of the costs—(1) for restoration projects and studies identified in the comprehensive conservation and management plan approved for the Basin under section 1330 of this title; and

(2) for public education projects recommended by the management conference.


(e) DefinitionsIn this section, the following definitions apply:(1) BasinThe term “Basin” means the Lake Pontchartrain Basin, a 10,000 square mile w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1273_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of restoration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of restoration program The Administrator shall establish within the Environmental Protection Agency the Lake Pontchartrain Basin Restoration Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1273_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the program shall be to restore the ecological health of the Basin by developing and funding restoration projects and related scientific and public education projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1273_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties In carrying out the program, the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1273_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grants The Administrator may make grants to pay not more than 75 percent of the costs—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1273_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1273_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>