<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1276a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1276a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1276a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1276a"><akn:num>1276a</akn:num><akn:heading>San Francisco Bay restoration grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1276a. San Francisco Bay restoration grant program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Estuary PartnershipThe term “Estuary Partnership” means the San Francisco Estuary Partnership, designated as the management conference for the San Francisco Bay under section 1330 of this title.


(2) San Francisco Bay PlanThe term “San Francisco Bay Plan” means—(A) until the date of the completion of the plan developed by the Director under subsection (d), the comprehensive conservation and management plan approved under section 1330 of this title for the San Francisco Bay estuary; and

(B) on and after the date of the completion of the plan developed by the Director under subsection (d), the plan developed by the Director under subsection (d).



(b) Program Office(1) EstablishmentThe Administrator shall establish in the Environmental Protection Agency a San Francisco Bay Program Office. The Office shall be located at the headquarters of Region 9 of the Environmental Protection Agency.


(2) Appointment of DirectorThe Administrator shall appoint a Director of the Office, who shall have management experience and technical expertise relating to the San Francisco Bay and be highly qualified to direct the development and implementation of projects, activities, and studies necessary to implement the San Francisco Bay Plan.


(3) Delegation of authority; staffingThe Administrator shall delegate to the Director such authority and provide such staff as may be necessary to carry out this section.



(c) Annual priority list(1) In generalAfter providing public notice, the Director shall annually compile a priority list, consistent with the San Francisco Bay Plan, identifying and prioritizing the projects, activities, and studies to be carried out with amounts made available under subsection (e).


(2) InclusionsThe annual priority list compiled under paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) Projects, activities, and studies, including restoration projects and habitat improvement for </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1276a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1276a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program Office</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1276a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual priority list</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual priority list</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1276a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>San Francisco Bay Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) San Francisco Bay Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1276a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1276a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>