<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1281" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1281/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1281/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1281"><akn:num>1281</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional declaration of purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1281. Congressional declaration of purpose(a) Development and implementation of waste treatment management plans and practicesIt is the purpose of this subchapter to require and to assist the development and implementation of waste treatment management plans and practices which will achieve the goals of this chapter.


(b) Application of technology: confined disposal of pollutants; consideration of advanced techniquesWaste treatment management plans and practices shall provide for the application of the best practicable waste treatment technology before any discharge into receiving waters, including reclaiming and recycling of water, and confined disposal of pollutants so they will not migrate to cause water or other environmental pollution and shall provide for consideration of advanced waste treatment techniques.


(c) Waste treatment management area and scopeTo the extent practicable, waste treatment management shall be on an areawide basis and provide control or treatment of all point and nonpoint sources of pollution, including in place or accumulated pollution sources.


(d) Waste treatment management construction of revenue producing facilitiesThe Administrator shall encourage waste treatment management which results in the construction of revenue producing facilities providing for—(1) the recycling of potential sewage pollutants through the production of agriculture, silviculture, or aquaculture products, or any combination thereof;

(2) the confined and contained disposal of pollutants not recycled;

(3) the reclamation of wastewater; and

(4) the ultimate disposal of sludge in a manner that will not result in environmental hazards.


(e) Waste treatment management integration of facilitiesThe Administrator shall encourage waste treatment management which results in integrating facilities for sewage treatment and recycling with facilities to treat, dispose of, or utilize other industrial and municipal wastes, including but not limited to solid waste and w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development and implementation of waste treatment management plans and practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development and implementation of waste treatment management plans and practices It is the purpose of this subchapter to require and to assist the development and implementation of waste treatment management plans and practices which will achieve the goals of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of technology: confined disposal of pollutants; consideration of advanced techniques</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of technology: confined disposal of pollutants; consideration of advanced techniques Waste treatment management plans and practices shall provide for the application of the best practicable waste treatment technology before any discharge into receiving waters, including reclaiming and recycling of water, and confined disposal of pollutants so they will not migrate to cause water or other environmental pollution and shall provide for consideration of advanced waste treatment techniques.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waste treatment management area and scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waste treatment management area and scope To the extent practicable, waste treatment management shall be on an areawide basis and provide control or treatment of all point and nonpoint sources of pollution, including in place or accumulated pollution sources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waste treatment management construction of revenue producing facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waste treatment management construction of revenue producing facilities The Administrator shall encourage waste treatment management which results in the construction of revenue producing facilities providing for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waste treatment management integration of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Waste treatment management integration of facilities The Administrator shall encourage waste treatment management which results in integrating facilities for sewage treatment and recycling with facilities to treat, dispose of, or utilize other industrial and municipal wastes, including but not limited to solid waste and waste heat and thermal discharges. Such integrated facilities shall be designed and operated to produce revenues in excess of capital and operation and maintenance costs and such revenues shall be used by the designated regional management agency to aid in financing other environmental improvement programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waste treatment management “open space” and recreational considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Waste treatment management “open space” and recreational considerations The Administrator shall encourage waste treatment management which combines “open space” and recreational considerations with such management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to construct publicly owned treatment works</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Grants to construct publicly owned treatment works</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to construct privately owned treatment works</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Grants to construct privately owned treatment works A grant may be made under this section to construct a privately owned treatment works serving one or more principal residences or small commercial establishments constructed prior to, and inhabited on, December 27, 1977, where the Administrator finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waste treatment management methods, processes, and techniques to reduce energy requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Waste treatment management methods, processes, and techniques to reduce energy requirements The Administrator shall encourage waste treatment management methods, processes, and techniques which will reduce total energy requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1281_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for treatment works utilizing processes and techniques of guidelines under section 1314(d)(3) of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Grants for treatment works utilizing processes and techniques of guidelines under The Administrator is authorized to make a grant for any treatment works utilizing processes and techniques meeting the guidelines promulgated under section 1314(d)(3) of this title, if the Administrator determines it is in the public interest and if in the cost effectiveness study made of the construction grant application for the purpose of evaluating alternative treatment works, the life cycle cost of the treatment works for which the grant is to be made does not exceed the life cycle cost of the most cost effective alternative by more than 15 per centum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>