<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1283" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1283/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1283/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1283"><akn:num>1283</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans, specifications, estimates, and payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1283. Plans, specifications, estimates, and payments(a) Submission; contractual nature of approval by Administrator; agreement on eligible costs; single grant(1) Each applicant for a grant shall submit to the Administrator for his approval, plans, specifications, and estimates for each proposed project for the construction of treatment works for which a grant is applied for under section 1281(g)(1) of this title from funds allotted to the State under section 1285 of this title and which otherwise meets the requirements of this chapter. The Administrator shall act upon such plans, specifications, and estimates as soon as practicable after the same have been submitted, and his approval of any such plans, specifications, and estimates shall be deemed a contractual obligation of the United States for the payment of its proportional contribution to such project.

(2) Agreement on eligible costs.—(A) Limitation on modifications.—Before taking final action on any plans, specifications, and estimates submitted under this subsection after the 60th day following February 4, 1987, the Administrator shall enter into a written agreement with the applicant which establishes and specifies which items of the proposed project are eligible for Federal payments under this section. The Administrator may not later modify such eligibility determinations unless they are found to have been made in violation of applicable Federal statutes and regulations.

(B) Limitation on effect.—Eligibility determinations under this paragraph shall not preclude the Administrator from auditing a project pursuant to section 1361 of this title, or other authority, or from withholding or recovering Federal funds for costs which are found to be unreasonable, unsupported by adequate documentation, or otherwise unallowable under applicable Federal cost principles, or which are incurred on a project which fails to meet the design specifications or effluent limitations contained in the grant agreement and permi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1283_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission; contractual nature of approval by Administrator; agreement on eligible costs; single grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission; contractual nature of approval by Administrator; agreement on eligible costs; single grant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1283_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Periodic payments The Administrator shall, from time to time as the work progresses, make payments to the recipient of a grant for costs of construction incurred on a project. These payments shall at no time exceed the Federal share of the cost of construction incurred to the date of the voucher covering such payment plus the Federal share of the value of the materials which have been stockpiled in the vicinity of such construction in conformity to plans and specifications for the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1283_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Final payments After completion of a project and approval of the final voucher by the Administrator, he shall pay out of the appropriate sums the unpaid balance of the Federal share payable on account of such project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1283_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects eligible</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Projects eligible Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to require, or to authorize the Administrator to require, that grants under this chapter for construction of treatment works be made only for projects which are operable units usable for sewage collection, transportation, storage, waste treatment, or for similar purposes without additional construction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1283_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical and legal assistance in administration and enforcement of contracts; intervention in civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical and legal assistance in administration and enforcement of contracts; intervention in civil actions At the request of a grantee under this subchapter, the Administrator is authorized to provide technical and legal assistance in the administration and enforcement of any contract in connection with treatment works assisted under this subchapter, and to intervene in any civil action involving the enforcement of such a contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1283_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Design/build projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Design/build projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>