<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1288" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1288/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1288/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1288"><akn:num>1288</akn:num><akn:heading>Areawide waste treatment management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1288. Areawide waste treatment management(a) Identification and designation of areas having substantial water quality control problemsFor the purpose of encouraging and facilitating the development and implementation of areawide waste treatment management plans—(1) The Administrator, within ninety days after October 18, 1972, and after consultation with appropriate Federal, State, and local authorities, shall by regulation publish guidelines for the identification of those areas which, as a result of urban-industrial concentrations or other factors, have substantial water quality control problems.

(2) The Governor of each State, within sixty days after publication of the guidelines issued pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection, shall identify each area within the State which, as a result of urban-industrial concentrations or other factors, has substantial water quality control problems. Not later than one hundred and twenty days following such identification and after consultation with appropriate elected and other officials of local governments having jurisdiction in such areas, the Governor shall designate (A) the boundaries of each such area, and (B) a single representative organization, including elected officials from local governments or their designees, capable of developing effective areawide waste treatment management plans for such area. The Governor may in the same manner at any later time identify any additional area (or modify an existing area) for which he determines areawide waste treatment management to be appropriate, designate the boundaries of such area, and designate an organization capable of developing effective areawide waste treatment management plans for such area.

(3) With respect to any area which, pursuant to the guidelines published under paragraph (1) of this subsection, is located in two or more States, the Governors of the respective States shall consult and cooperate in carrying out the provisions of paragraph (2), with a v</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification and designation of areas having substantial water quality control problems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Identification and designation of areas having substantial water quality control problems For the purpose of encouraging and facilitating the development and implementation of areawide waste treatment management plans—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Planning process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional operating agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regional operating agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conformity of works with area plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conformity of works with area plan After a waste treatment management agency having the authority required by subsection (c) has been designated under such subsection for an area and a plan for such area has been approved under subsection (b) of this section, the Administrator shall not make any grant for construction of a publicly owned treatment works under section 1281(g)(1) of this title within such area except to such designated agency and for works in conformity with such plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permits not to conflict with approved plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Permits not to conflict with approved plans No permit under section 1342 of this title shall be issued for any point source which is in conflict with a plan approved pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance by Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Technical assistance by Administrator The Administrator is authorized, upon request of the Governor or the designated planning agency, and without reimbursement, to consult with, and provide technical assistance to, any agency designated under subsection (a) of this section in the development of areawide waste treatment management plans under subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance by Secretary of the Army</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Technical assistance by Secretary of the Army</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>State best management practices program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) State best management practices program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1288_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Agricultural cost sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>