<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1293a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1293a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1293a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1293a"><akn:num>1293a</akn:num><akn:heading>Contained spoil disposal facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1293a. Contained spoil disposal facilities(a) Construction, operation, and maintenance; period; conditions; requirementsThe Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain, subject to the provisions of subsection (c), contained spoil disposal facilities of sufficient capacity for a period not to exceed ten years, to meet the requirements of this section. Before establishing each such facility, the Secretary of the Army shall obtain the concurrence of appropriate local governments and shall consider the views and recommendations of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and shall comply with requirements of section 1171 of this title, and of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.]. Section 401 of this title shall not apply to any facility authorized by this section.


(b) Time for establishment; consideration of area needs; requirementsThe Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall establish the contained spoil disposal facilities authorized in subsection (a) at the earliest practicable date, taking into consideration the views and recommendations of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency as to those areas which, in the Administrator’s judgment, are most urgently in need of such facilities and pursuant to the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.] and the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.].


(c) Written agreement requirement; terms of agreementPrior to construction of any such facility, the appropriate State or States, interstate agency, municipality, or other appropriate political subdivision of the State shall agree in writing to (1) furnish all lands, easements, and rights-of-way necessary for the construction, operation, and maintenance of the facility; (2) contribute to the United States 25 per centum of the construction costs, such </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction, operation, and maintenance; period; conditions; requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Construction, operation, and maintenance; period; conditions; requirements The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to construct, operate, and maintain, subject to the provisions of subsection (c), contained spoil disposal facilities of sufficient capacity for a period not to exceed ten years, to meet the requirements of this section. Before establishing each such facility, the Secretary of the Army shall obtain the concurrence of appropriate local governments and shall consider the views and recommendations of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and shall comply with requirements of section 1171 of this title, and of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.]. Section 401 of this title shall not apply to any facility authorized by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for establishment; consideration of area needs; requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Time for establishment; consideration of area needs; requirements The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall establish the contained spoil disposal facilities authorized in subsection (a) at the earliest practicable date, taking into consideration the views and recommendations of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency as to those areas which, in the Administrator’s judgment, are most urgently in need of such facilities and pursuant to the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.] and the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written agreement requirement; terms of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Written agreement requirement; terms of agreement Prior to construction of any such facility, the appropriate State or States, interstate agency, municipality, or other appropriate political subdivision of the State shall agree in writing to (1) furnish all lands, easements, and rights-of-way necessary for the construction, operation, and maintenance of the facility; (2) contribute to the United States 25 per centum of the construction costs, such amount to be payable either in cash prior to construction, in installments during construction, or in installments, with interest at a rate to be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, as of the beginning of the fiscal year in which construction is initiated, on the basis of the computed average interest rate payable by the Treasury upon its outstanding marketable public obligations, which are neither due or callable for redemption for fifteen years from date of issue; (3) hold and save the United States free from damages due to con</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of construction costs contribution from non-Federal interests; findings of participation in waste treatment facilities for general geographical area and compliance with water quality standards; waiver of payments in event of written agreement before occurrence of findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver of construction costs contribution from non-Federal interests; findings of participation in waste treatment facilities for general geographical area and compliance with water quality standards; waiver of payments in event of written agreement before occurrence of findings The requirement for appropriate non-Federal interest or interests to furnish an agreement to contribute 25 per centum of the construction costs as set forth in subsection (c) shall be waived by the Secretary of the Army upon a finding by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency that for the area to which such construction applies, the State or States involved, interstate agency, municipality, and other appropriate political subdivision of the State and industrial concerns are participating in and in compliance with an approved plan for the general geographical area of the dredging activity for construction, modification, expansion, or rehabilitation of waste treatment facilities and the Admi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal payment of costs for disposal of dredged spoil from project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Federal payment of costs for disposal of dredged spoil from project Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all costs of disposal of dredged spoil from the project for the Great Lakes connecting channels, Michigan, shall be borne by the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Title to lands, easements, and rights-of-way; retention by non-Federal interests; conveyance of facilities; agreement of transferee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Title to lands, easements, and rights-of-way; retention by non-Federal interests; conveyance of facilities; agreement of transferee The participating non-Federal interest or interests shall retain title to all lands, easements, and rights-of-way furnished by it pursuant to subsection (c). A spoil disposal facility owned by a non-Federal interest or interests may be conveyed to another party only after completion of the facility’s use for disposal purposes and after the transferee agrees in writing to use or maintain the facility in a manner which the Secretary of the Army determines to be satisfactory.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal licenses or permits; charges; remission of charge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Federal licenses or permits; charges; remission of charge Any spoil disposal facilities constructed under the provisions of this section shall be made available to Federal licensees or permittees upon payment of an appropriate charge for such use. Twenty-five per centum of such charge shall be remitted to the participating non-Federal interest or interests except for those excused from contributing to the construction costs under subsections (d) and (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions applicable to Great Lakes and their connecting channels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Provisions applicable to Great Lakes and their connecting channels This section, other than subsection (i), shall be applicable only to the Great Lakes and their connecting channels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research, study, and experimentation program relating to dredged spoil extended to navigable waters, etc.; cooperative program; scope of program; utilization of facilities and personnel of Federal agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Research, study, and experimentation program relating to dredged spoil extended to navigable waters, etc.; cooperative program; scope of program; utilization of facilities and personnel of Federal agency The Chief of Engineers, under the direction of the Secretary of the Army, is hereby authorized to extend to all navigable waters, connecting channels, tributary streams, other waters of the United States and waters contiguous to the United States, a comprehensive program of research, study, and experimentation relating to dredged spoil. This program shall be carried out in cooperation with other Federal and State agencies, and shall include, but not be limited to, investigations on the characteristics of dredged spoil, and alternative methods of its disposal. To the extent that such study shall include the effects of such dredge spoil on water quality, the facilities and personnel of the Environmental Protection Agency shall be utilized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1293a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period for depositing dredged materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Period for depositing dredged materials The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to continue to deposit dredged materials into a contained spoil disposal facility constructed under this section until the Secretary determines that such facility is no longer needed for such purpose or that such facility is completely full.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>