<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1311"><akn:num>1311</akn:num><akn:heading>Effluent limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1311. Effluent limitations(a) Illegality of pollutant discharges except in compliance with lawExcept as in compliance with this section and sections 1312, 1316, 1317, 1328, 1342, and 1344 of this title, the discharge of any pollutant by any person shall be unlawful.


(b) Timetable for achievement of objectivesIn order to carry out the objective of this chapter there shall be achieved—(1)(A) not later than July 1, 1977, effluent limitations for point sources, other than publicly owned treatment works, (i) which shall require the application of the best practicable control technology currently available as defined by the Administrator pursuant to section 1314(b) of this title, or (ii) in the case of a discharge into a publicly owned treatment works which meets the requirements of subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, which shall require compliance with any applicable pretreatment requirements and any requirements under section 1317 of this title; and

(B) for publicly owned treatment works in existence on July 1, 1977, or approved pursuant to section 1283 of this title prior to June 30, 1974 (for which construction must be completed within four years of approval), effluent limitations based upon secondary treatment as defined by the Administrator pursuant to section 1314(d)(1) of this title; or,

(C) not later than July 1, 1977, any more stringent limitation, including those necessary to meet water quality standards, treatment standards, or schedules of compliance, established pursuant to any State law or regulations (under authority preserved by section 1370 of this title) or any other Federal law or regulation, or required to implement any applicable water quality standard established pursuant to this chapter.


(2)(A) for pollutants identified in subparagraphs (C), (D), and (F) of this paragraph, effluent limitations for categories and classes of point sources, other than publicly owned treatment works, which (i) shall require application of the best available tec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Illegality of pollutant discharges except in compliance with law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Illegality of pollutant discharges except in compliance with law Except as in compliance with this section and sections 1312, 1316, 1317, 1328, 1342, and 1344 of this title, the discharge of any pollutant by any person shall be unlawful.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timetable for achievement of objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Timetable for achievement of objectives In order to carry out the objective of this chapter there shall be achieved—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of timetable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Modification of timetable The Administrator may modify the requirements of subsection (b)(2)(A) of this section with respect to any point source for which a permit application is filed after July 1, 1977, upon a showing by the owner or operator of such point source satisfactory to the Administrator that such modified requirements (1) will represent the maximum use of technology within the economic capability of the owner or operator; and (2) will result in reasonable further progress toward the elimination of the discharge of pollutants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and revision of effluent limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review and revision of effluent limitations Any effluent limitation required by paragraph (2) of subsection (b) of this section shall be reviewed at least every five years and, if appropriate, revised pursuant to the procedure established under such paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>All point discharge source application of effluent limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) All point discharge source application of effluent limitations Effluent limitations established pursuant to this section or section 1312 of this title shall be applied to all point sources of discharge of pollutants in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Illegality of discharge of radiological, chemical, or biological warfare agents, high-level radioactive waste, or medical waste</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Illegality of discharge of radiological, chemical, or biological warfare agents, high-level radioactive waste, or medical waste Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter it shall be unlawful to discharge any radiological, chemical, or biological warfare agent, any high-level radioactive waste, or any medical waste, into the navigable waters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modifications for certain nonconventional pollutants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Modifications for certain nonconventional pollutants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of secondary treatment requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Modification of secondary treatment requirements The Administrator, with the concurrence of the State, may issue a permit under section 1342 of this title which modifies the requirements of subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section with respect to the discharge of any pollutant from a publicly owned treatment works into marine waters, if the applicant demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Administrator that— For the purposes of this subsection the phrase “the discharge of any pollutant into marine waters” refers to a discharge into deep waters of the territorial sea or the waters of the contiguous zone, or into saline estuarine waters where there is strong tidal movement and other hydrological and geological characteristics which the Administrator determines necessary to allow compliance with paragraph (2) of this subsection, and section 1251(a)(2) of this title. For the purposes of paragraph (9), “primary or equivalent treatment” means treatment by screening, sedimentation, and skimm</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Municipal time extensions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Municipal time extensions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Modification procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>