<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1313"><akn:num>1313</akn:num><akn:heading>Water quality standards and implementation plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1313. Water quality standards and implementation plans(a) Existing water quality standards(1) In order to carry out the purpose of this chapter, any water quality standard applicable to interstate waters which was adopted by any State and submitted to, and approved by, or is awaiting approval by, the Administrator pursuant to this Act as in effect immediately prior to October 18, 1972, shall remain in effect unless the Administrator determined that such standard is not consistent with the applicable requirements of this Act as in effect immediately prior to October 18, 1972. If the Administrator makes such a determination he shall, within three months after October 18, 1972, notify the State and specify the changes needed to meet such requirements. If such changes are not adopted by the State within ninety days after the date of such notification, the Administrator shall promulgate such changes in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.

(2) Any State which, before October 18, 1972, has adopted, pursuant to its own law, water quality standards applicable to intrastate waters shall submit such standards to the Administrator within thirty days after October 18, 1972. Each such standard shall remain in effect, in the same manner and to the same extent as any other water quality standard established under this chapter unless the Administrator determines that such standard is inconsistent with the applicable requirements of this Act as in effect immediately prior to October 18, 1972. If the Administrator makes such a determination he shall not later than the one hundred and twentieth day after the date of submission of such standards, notify the State and specify the changes needed to meet such requirements. If such changes are not adopted by the State within ninety days after such notification, the Administrator shall promulgate such changes in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.

(3)(A) Any State which prior to October 18, 1972, has not adopted pu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing water quality standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Existing water quality standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposed regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Proposed regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review; revised standards; publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review; revised standards; publication</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of areas with insufficient controls; maximum daily load; certain effluent limitations revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Identification of areas with insufficient controls; maximum daily load; certain effluent limitations revision</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing planning process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Continuing planning process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Earlier compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Earlier compliance Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any effluent limitation, or schedule of compliance required by any State to be implemented prior to the dates set forth in sections 1311(b)(1) and 1311(b)(2) of this title nor to preclude any State from requiring compliance with any effluent limitation or schedule of compliance at dates earlier than such dates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Heat standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Heat standards Water quality standards relating to heat shall be consistent with the requirements of section 1326 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Thermal water quality standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Thermal water quality standards For the purposes of this chapter the term “water quality standards” includes thermal water quality standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal recreation water quality criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Coastal recreation water quality criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>