<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1319" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1319/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1319/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1319"><akn:num>1319</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1319. Enforcement(a) State enforcement; compliance orders(1) Whenever, on the basis of any information available to him, the Administrator finds that any person is in violation of any condition or limitation which implements section 1311, 1312, 1316, 1317, 1318, 1328, or 1345 of this title in a permit issued by a State under an approved permit program under section 1342 or 1344 of this title he shall proceed under his authority in paragraph (3) of this subsection or he shall notify the person in alleged violation and such State of such finding. If beyond the thirtieth day after the Administrator’s notification the State has not commenced appropriate enforcement action, the Administrator shall issue an order requiring such person to comply with such condition or limitation or shall bring a civil action in accordance with subsection (b) of this section.

(2) Whenever, on the basis of information available to him, the Administrator finds that violations of permit conditions or limitations as set forth in paragraph (1) of this subsection are so widespread that such violations appear to result from a failure of the State to enforce such permit conditions or limitations effectively, he shall so notify the State. If the Administrator finds such failure extends beyond the thirtieth day after such notice, he shall give public notice of such finding. During the period beginning with such public notice and ending when such State satisfies the Administrator that it will enforce such conditions and limitations (hereafter referred to in this section as the period of “federally assumed enforcement”), except where an extension has been granted under paragraph (5)(B) of this subsection, the Administrator shall enforce any permit condition or limitation with respect to any person—(A) by issuing an order to comply with such condition or limitation, or

(B) by bringing a civil action under subsection (b) of this section.


(3) Whenever on the basis of any information available to him</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1319_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State enforcement; compliance orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State enforcement; compliance orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1319_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil actions The Administrator is authorized to commence a civil action for appropriate relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction, for any violation for which he is authorized to issue a compliance order under subsection (a) of this section. Any action under this subsection may be brought in the district court of the United States for the district in which the defendant is located or resides or is doing business, and such court shall have jurisdiction to restrain such violation and to require compliance. Notice of the commencement of such action shall be given immediately to the appropriate State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1319_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criminal penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1319_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties; factors considered in determining amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Civil penalties; factors considered in determining amount Any person who violates section 1311, 1312, 1316, 1317, 1318, 1322(p), 1328,,11 So in original. or 1345 of this title, or any permit condition or limitation implementing any of such sections in a permit issued under section 1342 of this title by the Administrator, or by a State, or in a permit issued under section 1344 of this title by a State, or any requirement imposed in a pretreatment program approved under section 1342(a)(3) or 1342(b)(8) of this title, and any person who violates any order issued by the Administrator under subsection (a) of this section, shall be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed $25,000 per day for each violation. In determining the amount of a civil penalty the court shall consider the seriousness of the violation or violations, the economic benefit (if any) resulting from the violation, any history of such violations, any good-faith efforts to comply with the applicable requirements, the econ</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1319_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State liability for judgments and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State liability for judgments and expenses Whenever a municipality is a party to a civil action brought by the United States under this section, the State in which such municipality is located shall be joined as a party. Such State shall be liable for payment of any judgment, or any expenses incurred as a result of complying with any judgment, entered against the municipality in such action to the extent that the laws of that State prevent the municipality from raising revenues needed to comply with such judgment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1319_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wrongful introduction of pollutant into treatment works</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Wrongful introduction of pollutant into treatment works Whenever, on the basis of any information available to him, the Administrator finds that an owner or operator of any source is introducing a pollutant into a treatment works in violation of subsection (d) of section 1317 of this title, the Administrator may notify the owner or operator of such treatment works and the State of such violation. If the owner or operator of the treatment works does not commence appropriate enforcement action within 30 days of the date of such notification, the Administrator may commence a civil action for appropriate relief, including but not limited to, a permanent or temporary injunction, against the owner or operator of such treatment works. In any such civil action the Administrator shall join the owner or operator of such source as a party to the action. Such action shall be brought in the district court of the United States in the district in which the treatment works is located. Such court s</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1319_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Administrative penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1319_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of integrated plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Implementation of integrated plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>