<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1322"><akn:num>1322</akn:num><akn:heading>Marine sanitation devices; discharges incidental to the normal operation of vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1322. Marine sanitation devices; discharges incidental to the normal operation of vessels(a) DefinitionsIn this section, the term—(1) “new vessel” includes every description of watercraft or other artificial contrivance used, or capable of being used, as a means of transportation on the navigable waters, the construction of which is initiated after promulgation of standards and regulations under this section;

(2) “existing vessel” includes every description of watercraft or other artificial contrivance used, or capable of being used, as a means of transportation on the navigable waters, the construction of which is initiated before promulgation of standards and regulations under this section;

(3) “public vessel” means a vessel owned or bareboat chartered and operated by the United States, by a State or political subdivision thereof, or by a foreign nation, except when such vessel is engaged in commerce;

(4) “United States” includes the States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Canal Zone, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands;

(5) “marine sanitation device” includes any equipment for installation on board a vessel which is designed to receive, retain, treat, or discharge sewage, and any process to treat such sewage;

(6) “sewage” means human body wastes and the wastes from toilets and other receptacles intended to receive or retain body wastes except that, with respect to commercial vessels on the Great Lakes, such term shall include graywater;

(7) “manufacturer” means any person engaged in the manufacturing, assembling, or importation of marine sanitation devices, marine pollution control device equipment, or vessels subject to standards and regulations promulgated under this section;

(8) “person” means an individual, partnership, firm, corporation, association, or agency of the United States, but does not include an individual on board a public vessel;

(9) “discharge” includes</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section, the term—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal standards of performance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal standards of performance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial standards; effective dates; revision; waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Initial standards; effective dates; revision; waiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels owned and operated by the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Vessels owned and operated by the United States The provisions of this section and the standards and regulations promulgated hereunder apply to vessels owned and operated by the United States unless the Secretary of Defense finds that compliance would not be in the interest of national security. With respect to vessels owned and operated by the Department of Defense, regulations under the last sentence of subsection (b)(1) of this section and certifications under subsection (g)(2) of this section shall be promulgated and issued by the Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pre-promulgation consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Pre-promulgation consultation Before the standards and regulations under this section are promulgated, the Administrator and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall consult with the Secretary of State; the Secretary of Health and Human Services; the Secretary of Defense; the Secretary of the Treasury; the Secretary of Commerce; other interested Federal agencies; and the States and industries interested; and otherwise comply with the requirements of section 553 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation by States or political subdivisions thereof; complete prohibition upon discharge of sewage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulation by States or political subdivisions thereof; complete prohibition upon discharge of sewage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales limited to certified devices; certification of test device; recordkeeping; reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sales limited to certified devices; certification of test device; recordkeeping; reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale and resale of properly equipped vessels; operability of certified marine sanitation devices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Sale and resale of properly equipped vessels; operability of certified marine sanitation devices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction to restrain violations; contempts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Jurisdiction to restrain violations; contempts The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdictions to restrain violations of subsection (g)(1) of this section and subsections (h)(1) through (3) of this section. Actions to restrain such violations shall be brought by, and in, the name of the United States. In case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpena served upon any person under this subsection, the district court of the United States for any district in which such person is found or resides or transacts business, upon application by the United States and after notice to such person, shall have jurisdiction to issue an order requiring such person to appear and give testimony or to appear and produce documents, and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Penalties Any person who violates subsection (g)(1), clause (1) or (2) of subsection (h), or subsection (n)(8) shall be liable to a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each violation. Any person who violates clause (4) of subsection (h) of this section or any regulation issued pursuant to this section shall be liable to a civil penalty of not more than $2,000 for each violation. Each violation shall be a separate offense. The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may assess and compromise any such penalty. No penalty shall be assessed until the person charged shall have been given notice and an opportunity for a hearing on such charge. In determining the amount of the penalty, or the amount agreed upon in compromise, the gravity of the violation, and the demonstrated good faith of the person charged in attempting to achieve rapid compliance, after notification of a violation, shall be considered by said Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>