<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1329" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1329/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1329/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1329"><akn:num>1329</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonpoint source management programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1329. Nonpoint source management programs(a) State assessment reports(1) ContentsThe Governor of each State shall, after notice and opportunity for public comment, prepare and submit to the Administrator for approval, a report which—(A) identifies those navigable waters within the State which, without additional action to control nonpoint sources of pollution, cannot reasonably be expected to attain or maintain applicable water quality standards or the goals and requirements of this chapter;

(B) identifies those categories and subcategories of nonpoint sources or, where appropriate, particular nonpoint sources which add significant pollution to each portion of the navigable waters identified under subparagraph (A) in amounts which contribute to such portion not meeting such water quality standards or such goals and requirements;

(C) describes the process, including intergovernmental coordination and public participation, for identifying best management practices and measures to control each category and subcategory of nonpoint sources and, where appropriate, particular nonpoint sources identified under subparagraph (B) and to reduce, to the maximum extent practicable, the level of pollution resulting from such category, subcategory, or source; and

(D) identifies and describes State and local programs for controlling pollution added from nonpoint sources to, and improving the quality of, each such portion of the navigable waters, including but not limited to those programs which are receiving Federal assistance under subsections (h) and (i).


(2) Information used in preparationIn developing the report required by this section, the State (A) may rely upon information developed pursuant to sections 1288, 1313(e), 1314(f), 1315(b), and 1324 of this title, and other information as appropriate, and (B) may utilize appropriate elements of the waste treatment management plans developed pursuant to sections 1288(b) and 1313 of this title, to the extent such elements ar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State assessment reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State assessment reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State management programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State management programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval or disapproval of reports and management programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Approval or disapproval of reports and management programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local management programs; technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Local management programs; technical assistance If a State fails to submit a management program under subsection (b) or the Administrator does not approve such a management program, a local public agency or organization which has expertise in, and authority to, control water pollution resulting from nonpoint sources in any area of such State which the Administrator determines is of sufficient geographic size may, with approval of such State, request the Administrator to provide, and the Administrator shall provide, technical assistance to such agency or organization in developing for such area a management program which is described in subsection (b) and can be approved pursuant to subsection (d). After development of such management program, such agency or organization shall submit such management program to the Administrator for approval. If the Administrator approves such management program, such agency or organization shall be eligible to receive financial assistance under subs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance for States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Technical assistance for States Upon request of a State, the Administrator may provide technical assistance to such State in developing a management program approved under subsection (b) for those portions of the navigable waters requested by such State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate management conference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Interstate management conference</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Grant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for protecting groundwater quality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Grants for protecting groundwater quality</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1329_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out subsections (h) and (i) $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027; except that for each of such fiscal years not to exceed $7,500,000 may be made available to carry out subsection (i). Sums appropriated pursuant to this subsection shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>