<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1344" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1344/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1344/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1344"><akn:num>1344</akn:num><akn:heading>Permits for dredged or fill material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1344. Permits for dredged or fill material(a) Discharge into navigable waters at specified disposal sitesThe Secretary may issue permits, after notice and opportunity for public hearings for the discharge of dredged or fill material into the navigable waters at specified disposal sites. Not later than the fifteenth day after the date an applicant submits all the information required to complete an application for a permit under this subsection, the Secretary shall publish the notice required by this subsection.


(b) Specification for disposal sitesSubject to subsection (c) of this section, each such disposal site shall be specified for each such permit by the Secretary (1) through the application of guidelines developed by the Administrator, in conjunction with the Secretary, which guidelines shall be based upon criteria comparable to the criteria applicable to the territorial seas, the contiguous zone, and the ocean under section 1343(c) of this title, and (2) in any case where such guidelines under clause (1) alone would prohibit the specification of a site, through the application additionally of the economic impact of the site on navigation and anchorage.


(c) Denial or restriction of use of defined areas as disposal sitesThe Administrator is authorized to prohibit the specification (including the withdrawal of specification) of any defined area as a disposal site, and he is authorized to deny or restrict the use of any defined area for specification (including the withdrawal of specification) as a disposal site, whenever he determines, after notice and opportunity for public hearings, that the discharge of such materials into such area will have an unacceptable adverse effect on municipal water supplies, shellfish beds and fishery areas (including spawning and breeding areas), wildlife, or recreational areas. Before making such determination, the Administrator shall consult with the Secretary. The Administrator shall set forth in writing and make public his</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge into navigable waters at specified disposal sites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Discharge into navigable waters at specified disposal sites The Secretary may issue permits, after notice and opportunity for public hearings for the discharge of dredged or fill material into the navigable waters at specified disposal sites. Not later than the fifteenth day after the date an applicant submits all the information required to complete an application for a permit under this subsection, the Secretary shall publish the notice required by this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specification for disposal sites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Specification for disposal sites Subject to subsection (c) of this section, each such disposal site shall be specified for each such permit by the Secretary (1) through the application of guidelines developed by the Administrator, in conjunction with the Secretary, which guidelines shall be based upon criteria comparable to the criteria applicable to the territorial seas, the contiguous zone, and the ocean under section 1343(c) of this title, and (2) in any case where such guidelines under clause (1) alone would prohibit the specification of a site, through the application additionally of the economic impact of the site on navigation and anchorage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial or restriction of use of defined areas as disposal sites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Denial or restriction of use of defined areas as disposal sites The Administrator is authorized to prohibit the specification (including the withdrawal of specification) of any defined area as a disposal site, and he is authorized to deny or restrict the use of any defined area for specification (including the withdrawal of specification) as a disposal site, whenever he determines, after notice and opportunity for public hearings, that the discharge of such materials into such area will have an unacceptable adverse effect on municipal water supplies, shellfish beds and fishery areas (including spawning and breeding areas), wildlife, or recreational areas. Before making such determination, the Administrator shall consult with the Secretary. The Administrator shall set forth in writing and make public his findings and his reasons for making any determination under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Secretary” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Secretary” defined The term “Secretary” as used in this section means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>General permits on State, regional, or nationwide basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) General permits on State, regional, or nationwide basis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-prohibited discharge of dredged or fill ma­terial</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Non-prohibited discharge of dredged or fill ma­terial</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>State administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) State administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of State’s authority to issue permits under State program; approval; notification; transfers to State program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Determination of State’s authority to issue permits under State program; approval; notification; transfers to State program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Withdrawal of approval Whenever the Administrator determines after public hearing that a State is not administering a program approved under subsection (h)(2)(A) of this section, in accordance with this section, including, but not limited to, the guidelines established under subsection (b)(1) of this section, the Administrator shall so notify the State, and, if appropriate corrective action is not taken within a reasonable time, not to exceed ninety days after the date of the receipt of such notification, the Administrator shall (1) withdraw approval of such program until the Administrator determines such corrective action has been taken, and (2) notify the Secretary that the Secretary shall resume the program for the issuance of permits under subsections (a) and (e) of this section for activities with respect to which the State was issuing permits and that such authority of the Secretary shall continue in effect until such time as the Administrator makes the determination describe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Copies of applications for State permits and proposed general permits to be transmitted to Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Copies of applications for State permits and proposed general permits to be transmitted to Administrator Each State which is administering a permit program pursuant to this section shall transmit to the Administrator (1) a copy of each permit application received by such State and provide notice to the Administrator of every action related to the consideration of such permit application, including each permit proposed to be issued by such State, and (2) a copy of each proposed general permit which such State intends to issue. Not later than the tenth day after the date of the receipt of such permit application or such proposed general permit, the Administrator shall provide copies of such permit application or such proposed general permit to the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service. If the Administrator intends to provide written comments to such State with respect to such permit application or such </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>