<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1345" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1345/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1345/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1345"><akn:num>1345</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposal or use of sewage sludge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1345. Disposal or use of sewage sludge(a) PermitNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or of any other law, in any case where the disposal of sewage sludge resulting from the operation of a treatment works as defined in section 1292 of this title (including the removal of in-place sewage sludge from one location and its deposit at another location) would result in any pollutant from such sewage sludge entering the navigable waters, such disposal is prohibited except in accordance with a permit issued by the Administrator under section 1342 of this title.


(b) Issuance of permit; regulationsThe Administrator shall issue regulations governing the issuance of permits for the disposal of sewage sludge subject to subsection (a) of this section and section 1342 of this title. Such regulations shall require the application to such disposal of each criterion, factor, procedure, and requirement applicable to a permit issued under section 1342 of this title.


(c) State permit programEach State desiring to administer its own permit program for disposal of sewage sludge subject to subsection (a) of this section within its jurisdiction may do so in accordance with section 1342 of this title.


(d) Regulations(1) RegulationsThe Administrator, after consultation with appropriate Federal and State agencies and other interested persons, shall develop and publish, within one year after December 27, 1977, and from time to time thereafter, regulations providing guidelines for the disposal of sludge and the utilization of sludge for various purposes. Such regulations shall—(A) identify uses for sludge, including disposal;

(B) specify factors to be taken into account in determining the measures and practices applicable to each such use or disposal (including publication of information on costs);

(C) identify concentrations of pollutants which interfere with each such use or disposal.


The Administrator is authorized to revise any regulation issued under this subsectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1345_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Permit Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter or of any other law, in any case where the disposal of sewage sludge resulting from the operation of a treatment works as defined in section 1292 of this title (including the removal of in-place sewage sludge from one location and its deposit at another location) would result in any pollutant from such sewage sludge entering the navigable waters, such disposal is prohibited except in accordance with a permit issued by the Administrator under section 1342 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1345_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of permit; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Issuance of permit; regulations The Administrator shall issue regulations governing the issuance of permits for the disposal of sewage sludge subject to subsection (a) of this section and section 1342 of this title. Such regulations shall require the application to such disposal of each criterion, factor, procedure, and requirement applicable to a permit issued under section 1342 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1345_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State permit program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State permit program Each State desiring to administer its own permit program for disposal of sewage sludge subject to subsection (a) of this section within its jurisdiction may do so in accordance with section 1342 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1345_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1345_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of sludge disposal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Manner of sludge disposal The determination of the manner of disposal or use of sludge is a local determination, except that it shall be unlawful for any person to dispose of sludge from a publicly owned treatment works or any other treatment works treating domestic sewage for any use for which regulations have been established pursuant to subsection (d) of this section, except in accordance with such regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1345_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Implementation of regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1345_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies and projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Studies and projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>