<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1365" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1365/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1365/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1365"><akn:num>1365</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizen suits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1365. Citizen suits(a) Authorization; jurisdictionExcept as provided in subsection (b) of this section and section 1319(g)(6) of this title, any citizen may commence a civil action on his own behalf—(1) against any person (including (i) the United States, and (ii) any other governmental instrumentality or agency to the extent permitted by the eleventh amendment to the Constitution) who is alleged to be in violation of (A) an effluent standard or limitation under this chapter or (B) an order issued by the Administrator or a State with respect to such a standard or limitation, or

(2) against the Administrator where there is alleged a failure of the Administrator to perform any act or duty under this chapter which is not discretionary with the Administrator.


The district courts shall have jurisdiction, without regard to the amount in controversy or the citizenship of the parties, to enforce such an effluent standard or limitation, or such an order, or to order the Administrator to perform such act or duty, as the case may be, and to apply any appropriate civil penalties under section 1319(d) of this title.

(b) NoticeNo action may be commenced—(1) under subsection (a)(1) of this section—(A) prior to sixty days after the plaintiff has given notice of the alleged violation (i) to the Administrator, (ii) to the State in which the alleged violation occurs, and (iii) to any alleged violator of the standard, limitation, or order, or

(B) if the Administrator or State has commenced and is diligently prosecuting a civil or criminal action in a court of the United States, or a State to require compliance with the standard, limitation, or order, but in any such action in a court of the United States any citizen may intervene as a matter of right.


(2) under subsection (a)(2) of this section prior to sixty days after the plaintiff has given notice of such action to the Administrator,


except that such action may be brought immediately after such notification in the case of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1365_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization; jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization; jurisdiction Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section and section 1319(g)(6) of this title, any citizen may commence a civil action on his own behalf— The district courts shall have jurisdiction, without regard to the amount in controversy or the citizenship of the parties, to enforce such an effluent standard or limitation, or such an order, or to order the Administrator to perform such act or duty, as the case may be, and to apply any appropriate civil penalties under section 1319(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1365_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice No action may be commenced— except that such action may be brought immediately after such notification in the case of an action under this section respecting a violation of sections 1316 and 1317(a) of this title. Notice under this subsection shall be given in such manner as the Administrator shall prescribe by regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1365_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venue; intervention by Administrator; United States interests protected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Venue; intervention by Administrator; United States interests protected</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1365_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Litigation costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Litigation costs The court, in issuing any final order in any action brought pursuant to this section, may award costs of litigation (including reasonable attorney and expert witness fees) to any prevailing or substantially prevailing party, whenever the court determines such award is appropriate. The court may, if a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction is sought, require the filing of a bond or equivalent security in accordance with the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1365_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory or common law rights not restricted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Statutory or common law rights not restricted Nothing in this section shall restrict any right which any person (or class of persons) may have under any statute or common law to seek enforcement of any effluent standard or limitation or to seek any other relief (including relief against the Administrator or a State agency).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1365_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effluent standard or limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effluent standard or limitation For purposes of this section, the term “effluent standard or limitation under this chapter” means (1) effective July 1, 1973, an unlawful act under subsection (a) of section 1311 of this title; (2) an effluent limitation or other limitation under section 1311 or 1312 of this title; (3) standard of performance under section 1316 of this title; (4) prohibition, effluent standard or pretreatment standards under section 1317 of this title; (5) a standard of performance or requirement under section 1322(p) of this title; (6) a certification under section 1341 of this title; (7) a permit or condition of a permit issued under section 1342 of this title that is in effect under this chapter (including a requirement applicable by reason of section 1323 of this title); or (8) a regulation under section 1345(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1365_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Citizen” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) “Citizen” defined For the purposes of this section the term “citizen” means a person or persons having an interest which is or may be adversely affected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1365_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil action by State Governors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Civil action by State Governors A Governor of a State may commence a civil action under subsection (a), without regard to the limitations of subsection (b) of this section, against the Administrator where there is alleged a failure of the Administrator to enforce an effluent standard or limitation under this chapter the violation of which is occurring in another State and is causing an adverse effect on the public health or welfare in his State, or is causing a violation of any water quality requirement in his State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>