<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1375a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1375a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1375a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1375a"><akn:num>1375a</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on coastal recreation waters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1375a. Report on coastal recreation waters(a) In generalNot later than 4 years after October 10, 2000, and every 4 years thereafter, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall submit to Congress a report that includes—(1) recommendations concerning the need for additional water quality criteria for pathogens and pathogen indicators and other actions that should be taken to improve the quality of coastal recreation waters;

(2) an evaluation of Federal, State, and local efforts to implement this Act, including the amendments made by this Act; and

(3) recommendations on improvements to methodologies and techniques for monitoring of coastal recreation waters.


(b) CoordinationThe Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency may coordinate the report under this section with other reporting requirements under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.).


(Pub. L. 106–284, § 7, Oct. 10, 2000, 114 Stat. 876.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is Pub. L. 106–284, Oct. 10, 2000, 114 Stat. 870, known as the Beaches Environmental Assessment and Coastal Health Act of 2000. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2000 Amendment note set out under section 1251 of this title and Tables.
The Federal Water Pollution Control Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is act June 30, 1948, ch. 758, as amended generally by Pub. L. 92–500, § 2, Oct. 18, 1972, 86 Stat. 816, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1251 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Beaches Environmental Assessment and Coastal Health Act of 2000, and not as part of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 4 years after October 10, 2000, and every 4 years thereafter, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1375a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency may coordinate the report under this section with other reporting requirements under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>