<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1383" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1383/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1383/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1383"><akn:num>1383</akn:num><akn:heading>Water pollution control revolving loan funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1383. Water pollution control revolving loan funds(a) Requirements for obligation of grant fundsBefore a State may receive a capitalization grant with funds made available under this subchapter and section 1285(m) of this title, the State shall first establish a water pollution control revolving fund which complies with the requirements of this section.


(b) AdministrationEach State water pollution control revolving fund shall be administered by an instrumentality of the State with such powers and limitations as may be required to operate such fund in accordance with the requirements and objectives of this chapter.


(c) Projects and activities eligible for assistanceThe amounts of funds available to each State water pollution control revolving fund shall be used only for providing financial assistance—(1) to any municipality or intermunicipal, interstate, or State agency for construction of publicly owned treatment works (as defined in section 1292 of this title);

(2) for the implementation of a management program established under section 1329 of this title;

(3) for development and implementation of a conservation and management plan under section 1330 of this title;

(4) for the construction, repair, or replacement of decentralized wastewater treatment systems that treat municipal wastewater or domestic sewage;

(5) for measures to manage, reduce, treat, or recapture stormwater or subsurface drainage water;

(6) to any municipality or intermunicipal, interstate, or State agency for measures to reduce the demand for publicly owned treatment works capacity through water conservation, efficiency, or reuse;

(7) for the development and implementation of watershed projects meeting the criteria set forth in section 1274 of this title;

(8) to any municipality or intermunicipal, interstate, or State agency for measures to reduce the energy consumption needs for publicly owned treatment works;

(9) for reusing or recycling wastewater, stormwater, or subsurface drain</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for obligation of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements for obligation of grant funds Before a State may receive a capitalization grant with funds made available under this subchapter and section 1285(m) of this title, the State shall first establish a water pollution control revolving fund which complies with the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration Each State water pollution control revolving fund shall be administered by an instrumentality of the State with such powers and limitations as may be required to operate such fund in accordance with the requirements and objectives of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects and activities eligible for assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Projects and activities eligible for assistance The amounts of funds available to each State water pollution control revolving fund shall be used only for providing financial assistance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Types of assistance Except as otherwise limited by State law and provided in subsection (k), a water pollution control revolving fund of a State under this section may be used only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation to prevent double benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation to prevent double benefits If a State makes, from its water pollution revolving fund, a loan which will finance the cost of facility planning and the preparation of plans, specifications, and estimates for construction of publicly owned treatment works, the State shall ensure that if the recipient of such loan receives a grant under section 1281(g) of this title for construction of such treatment works and an allowance under section 1281(l)(1) of this title for non-Federal funds expended for such planning and preparation, such recipient will promptly repay such loan to the extent of such allowance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency with planning requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consistency with planning requirements A State may provide financial assistance from its water pollution control revolving fund only with respect to a project which is consistent with plans, if any, developed under sections 1285(j), 1288, 1313(e), 1329, and 1330 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority list requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Priority list requirement The State may provide financial assistance from its water pollution control revolving fund only with respect to a project for construction of a treatment works described in subsection (c)(1) if such project is on the State’s priority list under section 1296 of this title. Such assistance may be provided regardless of the rank of such project on such list.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of non-Federal share of construction grant projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Eligibility of non-Federal share of construction grant projects A State water pollution control revolving fund may provide assistance (other than under subsection (d)(1) of this section) to a municipality or intermunicipal or interstate agency with respect to the non-Federal share of the costs of a treatment works project for which such municipality or agency is receiving assistance from the Administrator under any other authority only if such assistance is necessary to allow such project to proceed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional subsidization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Additional subsidization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of eligible individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definition of eligible individual In subsection (c)(12), the term “eligible individual” means a member of a household, the members of which have a combined income (for the most recent 12-month period for which information is available) equal to not more than 50 percent of the median nonmetropolitan household income for the State in which the household is located, according to the most recent decennial census.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>