<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1411" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1411/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1411/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1411"><akn:num>1411</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1411. Prohibited acts(a) Except as may be authorized by a permit issued pursuant to section 1412 or section 1413 of this title, and subject to regulations issued pursuant to section 1418 of this title,(1) no person shall transport from the United States, and

(2) in the case of a vessel or aircraft registered in the United States or flying the United States flag or in the case of a United States department, agency, or instrumentality, no person shall transport from any location


any material for the purpose of dumping it into ocean waters.

(b) Except as may be authorized by a permit issued pursuant to section 1412 of this title, and subject to regulations issued pursuant to section 1418 of this title, no person shall dump any material transported from a location outside the United States (1) into the territorial sea of the United States, or (2) into a zone contiguous to the territorial sea of the United States, extending to a line twelve nautical miles seaward from the base line from which the breadth of the territorial sea is measured, to the extent that it may affect the territorial sea or the territory of the United States.

(Pub. L. 92–532, title I, § 101, Oct. 23, 1972, 86 Stat. 1053; Pub. L. 93–254, § 1(3), Mar. 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 51.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1974—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 93–254 incorporated existing provisions in introductory text, substituting reference to permits issued under section 1412 or section 1413 of this title for prior reference to such issuance under this subchapter; incorporated existing provisions in item designated (1); added item (2); and substituted prohibition against transportation of any material for ocean dumping for former prohibition against such dumping of any radiological, chemical, or biological warfare agent or any high-level radioactive waste, or any other material.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 93–254 substituted reference to permits issued under section 1412 of this title for former reference to such issuance under thi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1411_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as may be authorized by a permit issued pursuant to section 1412 or section 1413 of this title, and subject to regulations issued pursuant to section 1418 of this title, any material for the purpose of dumping it into ocean waters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1411_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as may be authorized by a permit issued pursuant to section 1412 of this title, and subject to regulations issued pursuant to section 1418 of this title, no person shall dump any material transported from a location outside the United States (1) into the territorial sea of the United States, or (2) into a zone contiguous to the territorial sea of the United States, extending to a line twelve nautical miles seaward from the base line from which the breadth of the territorial sea is measured, to the extent that it may affect the territorial sea or the territory of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>