<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1414" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1414/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1414/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1414"><akn:num>1414</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1414. Permit conditions(a) Designated and included conditionsPermits issued under this subchapter shall designate and include (1) the type of material authorized to be transported for dumping or to be dumped; (2) the amount of material authorized to be transported for dumping or to be dumped; (3) the location where such transport for dumping will be terminated or where such dumping will occur; (4) such requirements, limitations, or conditions as are necessary to assure consistency with any site management plan approved pursuant to section 1412(c) of this title; (5) any special provisions deemed necessary by the Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, after consultation with the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, for the monitoring and surveillance of the transportation or dumping; and (6) such other matters as the Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, deems appropriate. Permits issued under this subchapter shall be issued for a period of not to exceed 7 years.


(b) Permit processing fees; reporting requirementsThe Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, may prescribe such processing fees for permits and such reporting requirements for actions taken pursuant to permits issued by him under this subchapter as he deems appropriate.


(c) General permitsConsistent with the requirements of sections 1412 and 1413 of this title, but in lieu of a requirement for specific permits in such case, the Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, may issue general permits for the transportation for dumping, or dumping, or both, of specified materials or classes of materials for which he may issue permits, which he determines will have a minimal adverse environmental impact.


(d) ReviewAny permit issued under this subchapter shall be reviewed periodically and, if appropriate, revised. The Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, may limit or deny the issuance of permits, or he may alter or r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated and included conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designated and included conditions Permits issued under this subchapter shall designate and include (1) the type of material authorized to be transported for dumping or to be dumped; (2) the amount of material authorized to be transported for dumping or to be dumped; (3) the location where such transport for dumping will be terminated or where such dumping will occur; (4) such requirements, limitations, or conditions as are necessary to assure consistency with any site management plan approved pursuant to section 1412(c) of this title; (5) any special provisions deemed necessary by the Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, after consultation with the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating, for the monitoring and surveillance of the transportation or dumping; and (6) such other matters as the Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, deems appropriate. Permits issued under this subchapter shall be issued for a period of not to excee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit processing fees; reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Permit processing fees; reporting requirements The Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, may prescribe such processing fees for permits and such reporting requirements for actions taken pursuant to permits issued by him under this subchapter as he deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General permits Consistent with the requirements of sections 1412 and 1413 of this title, but in lieu of a requirement for specific permits in such case, the Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, may issue general permits for the transportation for dumping, or dumping, or both, of specified materials or classes of materials for which he may issue permits, which he determines will have a minimal adverse environmental impact.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review Any permit issued under this subchapter shall be reviewed periodically and, if appropriate, revised. The Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, may limit or deny the issuance of permits, or he may alter or revoke partially or entirely the terms of permits issued by him under this subchapter, for the transportation for dumping, or for the dumping, or both, of specified materials or classes of materials, where he finds, based upon monitoring data from the dump site and surrounding area, that such materials cannot be dumped consistently with the criteria and other factors required to be applied in evaluating the permit application. No action shall be taken under this subsection unless the affected person or permittee shall have been given notice and opportunity for a hearing on such action as proposed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information for review and evaluation of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Information for review and evaluation of applications The Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, shall require an applicant for a permit under this subchapter to provide such information as he may consider necessary to review and evaluate such application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public information Information received by the Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, as a part of any application or in connection with any permit granted under this subchapter shall be available to the public as a matter of public record, at every stage of the proceeding. The final determination of the Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, shall be likewise available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Display of issued permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Display of issued permits A copy of any permit issued under this subchapter shall be placed in a conspicuous place in the vessel which will be used for the transportation or dumping authorized by such permit, and an additional copy shall be furnished by the issuing official to the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, or its designee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-level radioactive waste; research purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Low-level radioactive waste; research purposes Notwithstanding any provision of this subchapter to the contrary, during the two-year period beginning on January 6, 1983, no permit may be issued under this subchapter that authorizes the dumping of any low-level radioactive waste unless the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency determines— Each permit issued pursuant to this subsection shall be subject to such conditions and restrictions as the Administrator determines to be necessary to minimize possible adverse impacts of such dumping.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Radioactive Material Disposal Impact Assessment; Congressional approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Radioactive Material Disposal Impact Assessment; Congressional approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>