<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1415" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1415/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1415/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1415"><akn:num>1415</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1415. Penalties(a) Assessment of civil penalty by Administrator; remission or mitigation; court action for appropriate reliefAny person who violates any provision of this subchapter, or of the regulations promulgated under this subchapter, or a permit issued under this subchapter shall be liable to a civil penalty of not more than $50,000 for each violation to be assessed by the Administrator. In addition, any person who violates this subchapter or any regulation issued under this subchapter by engaging in activity involving the dumping of medical waste shall be liable for a civil penalty of not more than $125,000 for each violation, to be assessed by the Administrator after written notice and an opportunity for a hearing. No penalty shall be assessed until the person charged shall have been given notice and an opportunity for a hearing of such violation. In determining the amount of the penalty, the gravity of the violation, prior violations, and the demonstrated good faith of the person charged in attempting to achieve rapid compliance after notification of a violation shall be considered by said Administrator. For good cause shown, the Administrator may remit or mitigate such penalty. Upon failure of the offending party to pay the penalty, the Administrator may request the Attorney General to commence an action in the appropriate district court of the United States for such relief as may be appropriate.


(b) Criminal penaltiesIn addition to any action that may be brought under subsection (a)—(1) any person who knowingly violates any provision of this subchapter, any regulation promulgated under this subchapter, or a permit issued under this subchapter, shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both; and

(2) any person who is convicted of such a violation pursuant to paragraph (1) shall forfeit to the United States—(A) any property constituting or derived from any proceeds that the person obtained, directly or indirectly, as a r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of civil penalty by Administrator; remission or mitigation; court action for appropriate relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessment of civil penalty by Administrator; remission or mitigation; court action for appropriate relief Any person who violates any provision of this subchapter, or of the regulations promulgated under this subchapter, or a permit issued under this subchapter shall be liable to a civil penalty of not more than $50,000 for each violation to be assessed by the Administrator. In addition, any person who violates this subchapter or any regulation issued under this subchapter by engaging in activity involving the dumping of medical waste shall be liable for a civil penalty of not more than $125,000 for each violation, to be assessed by the Administrator after written notice and an opportunity for a hearing. No penalty shall be assessed until the person charged shall have been given notice and an opportunity for a hearing of such violation. In determining the amount of the penalty, the gravity of the violation, prior violations, and the demonstrated good faith of the person charged in</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criminal penalties In addition to any action that may be brought under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate offenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Separate offenses For the purpose of imposing civil penalties and criminal fines under this section, each day of a continuing violation shall constitute a separate offense as shall the dumping from each of several vessels, or other sources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctive relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Injunctive relief The Attorney General or his delegate may bring actions for equitable relief to enjoin an imminent or continuing violation of this subchapter, of regulations promulgated under this subchapter, or of permits issued under this subchapter, and the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction to grant such relief as the equities of the case may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of vessels in rem</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Liability of vessels in rem A vessel, except a public vessel within the meaning of section 13 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, as amended, used in a violation, shall be liable in rem for any civil penalty assessed or criminal fine imposed and may be proceeded against in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction thereof; but no vessel shall be liable unless it shall appear that one or more of the owners, or bareboat charterers, was at the time of the violation a consenting party or privy to such violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation and suspension of permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Revocation and suspension of permits If the provisions of any permit issued under section 1412 or 1413 of this title are violated, the Administrator or the Secretary, as the case may be, may revoke the permit or may suspend the permit for a specified period of time. No permit shall be revoked or suspended unless the permittee shall have been given notice and opportunity for a hearing on such violation and proposed suspension or revocation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil suits by private persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Civil suits by private persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Emergencies No person shall be subject to a civil penalty or to a criminal fine or imprisonment for dumping materials from a vessel if such materials are dumped in an emergency to safeguard life at sea. Any such emergency dumping shall be reported to the Administrator under such conditions as he may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seizure and forfeiture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Seizure and forfeiture</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>