<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1442" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1442/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1442/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1442"><akn:num>1442</akn:num><akn:heading>Research program respecting possible long-range effects of pollution, overfishing, and man-induced c</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1442. Research program respecting possible long-range effects of pollution, overfishing, and man-induced changes of ocean ecosystems(a) Secretary of Commerce(1) The Secretary of Commerce, in close consultation with other appropriate Federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities shall, within six months of October 23, 1972, initiate a comprehensive and continuing program of research with respect to the possible long-range effects of pollution, overfishing, and man-induced changes of ocean ecosystems. These responsibilities shall include the scientific assessment of damages to the natural resources from spills of petroleum or petroleum products. In carrying out such research, the Secretary of Commerce shall take into account such factors as existing and proposed international policies affecting oceanic problems, economic considerations involved in both the protection and the use of the oceans, possible alternatives to existing programs, and ways in which the health of the oceans may best be preserved for the benefit of succeeding generations of mankind.

(2) The Secretary of Commerce shall ensure that the program under this section complements, when appropriate, the activities undertaken by other Federal agencies pursuant to subchapter I and section 1443 of this title. That program shall include but not be limited to—(A) the development and assessment of scientific techniques to define and quantify the degradation of the marine environment;

(B) the assessment of the capacity of the marine environment to receive materials without degradation;

(C) continuing monitoring programs to assess the health of the marine environment, including but not limited to the monitoring of bottom oxygen concentrations, contaminant levels in biota, sediments, and the water column, diseases in fish and shellfish, and changes in types and abundance of indicator species;

(D) the development of methodologies, techniques, and equipment for disposal of waste materials to minimize deg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Secretary of Commerce</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action with other nations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Action with other nations In carrying out his responsibilities under this section, the Secretary of Commerce, under the foreign policy guidance of the President and pursuant to international agreements and treaties made by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate, may act alone or in conjunction with any other nation or group of nations, and shall make known the results of his activities by such channels of communication as may appear appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation of other departments, agencies, and independent instrumentalities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperation of other departments, agencies, and independent instrumentalities Each department, agency, and independent instrumentality of the Federal Government is authorized and directed to cooperate with the Secretary of Commerce in carrying out the purposes of this section and, to the extent permitted by law, to furnish such information as may be requested.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1442_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of personnel, services, and facilities; inter-agency agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Utilization of personnel, services, and facilities; inter-agency agreements The Secretary of Commerce, in carrying out his responsibilities under this section, shall, to the extent feasible utilize the personnel, services, and facilities of other Federal departments, agencies, and instrumentalities (including those of the Coast Guard for monitoring purposes), and is authorized to enter into appropriate inter-agency agreements to accomplish this action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>