<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1502"><akn:num>1502</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1502. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Adjacent coastal State.—The term “adjacent coastal State” means any coastal State which (A) would be directly connected by pipeline to a deepwater port, as proposed in an application; (B) would be located within 15 miles of any such proposed deepwater port; or (C) is designated by the Secretary in accordance with section 1508(a)(2) of this title.

(2) Affiliate.—The term “affiliate” means any entity owned or controlled by, any person who owns or controls, or any entity which is under common ownership or control with an applicant, licensee, or any person required to be disclosed pursuant to section subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 1504(c)(2) of this title.

(3) Application.—The term “application” means an application submitted under this Act for a license for the ownership, construction, and operation of a deepwater port.

(4) Citizen of the United States.—The term “citizen of the United States” means any person who is a United States citizen by law, birth, or naturalization, any State, any agency of a State or a group of States, or any corporation, partnership, or association organized under the laws of any State which has as its president or other executive officer and as its chairman of the board of directors, or holder of a similar office, a person who is a United States citizen by law, birth or naturalization and which has no more of its directors who are not United States citizens by law, birth or naturalization than constitute a minority of the number required for a quorum necessary to conduct the business of the board.

(5) Coastal environment.—The term “coastal environment” means the navigable waters (including the lands therein and thereunder) and the adjacent shorelines including 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by an opening parenthesis. waters therein and thereunder). The term includes transitional and intertidal areas, bays, lagoons, salt marshes, estuaries, and beaches; the fish, wildlife and othe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjacent coastal State.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “adjacent coastal State” means any coastal State which (A) would be directly connected by pipeline to a deepwater port, as proposed in an application; (B) would be located within 15 miles of any such proposed deepwater port; or (C) is designated by the Secretary in accordance with section 1508(a)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affiliate.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “affiliate” means any entity owned or controlled by, any person who owns or controls, or any entity which is under common ownership or control with an applicant, licensee, or any person required to be disclosed pursuant to section subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 1504(c)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “application” means an application submitted under this Act for a license for the ownership, construction, and operation of a deepwater port.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizen of the United States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “citizen of the United States” means any person who is a United States citizen by law, birth, or naturalization, any State, any agency of a State or a group of States, or any corporation, partnership, or association organized under the laws of any State which has as its president or other executive officer and as its chairman of the board of directors, or holder of a similar office, a person who is a United States citizen by law, birth or naturalization and which has no more of its directors who are not United States citizens by law, birth or naturalization than constitute a minority of the number required for a quorum necessary to conduct the business of the board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal environment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “coastal environment” means the navigable waters (including the lands therein and thereunder) and the adjacent shorelines including 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by an opening parenthesis. waters therein and thereunder). The term includes transitional and intertidal areas, bays, lagoons, salt marshes, estuaries, and beaches; the fish, wildlife and other living resources thereof; and the recreational and scenic values of such lands, waters and resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coastal State.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “coastal State” means any State of the United States in or bordering on the Atlantic, Pacific, or Arctic Oceans, or the Gulf of Mexico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “construction” means the supervising, inspection, actual building, and all other activities incidental to the building, repairing, or expanding of a deepwater port or any of its components, including, but not limited to, pile driving and bulkheading, and alterations, modifications, or additions to the deepwater port.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “control” means the power, directly or indirectly, to determine the policy, business practices, or decisionmaking process of another person, whether by stock or other ownership interest, by representation on a board of directors or similar body, by contract or other agreement with stockholders or others, or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deepwater port.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “deepwater port”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governor.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “Governor” means the Governor of a State or the person designated by State law to exercise the powers granted to the Governor pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>