<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1504"><akn:num>1504</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1504. Procedure(a) Regulations; issuance, amendment, or rescission; scopeThe Secretary shall, as soon as practicable after January 3, 1975, and after consultation with other Federal agencies, issue regulations to carry out the purposes and provisions of this chapter in accordance with the provisions of section 553 of title 5, without regard to subsection (a) thereof. Such regulations shall pertain to, but need not be limited to, application, issuance, transfer, renewal, suspension, and termination of licenses. Such regulations shall provide for full consultation and cooperation with all other interested Federal agencies and departments and with any potentially affected coastal State, and for consideration of the views of any interested members of the general public. The Secretary is further authorized, consistent with the purposes and provisions of this chapter, to amend or rescind any such regulation.


(b) Additional regulations; criteria for site evaluation and preconstruction testingThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall, as soon as practicable after January 3, 1975, prescribe regulations relating to those activities involved in site evaluation and preconstruction testing at potential deepwater port locations that may (1) adversely affect the environment; (2) interfere with authorized uses of the Outer Continental Shelf; or (3) pose a threat to human health and welfare. Such activity may thenceforth not be undertaken except in accordance with regulations prescribed pursuant to this subsection. Such regulations shall be consistent with the purposes of this chapter.


(c) Applications(1) Requirements.—(A) In general.—Each person that submits to the Secretary an application shall include in the application a detailed plan that contains all information required under paragraph (2).

(B) Action by secretary.—Not later than 21 days after the date of receipt</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; issuance, amendment, or rescission; scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations; issuance, amendment, or rescission; scope The Secretary shall, as soon as practicable after January 3, 1975, and after consultation with other Federal agencies, issue regulations to carry out the purposes and provisions of this chapter in accordance with the provisions of section 553 of title 5, without regard to subsection (a) thereof. Such regulations shall pertain to, but need not be limited to, application, issuance, transfer, renewal, suspension, and termination of licenses. Such regulations shall provide for full consultation and cooperation with all other interested Federal agencies and departments and with any potentially affected coastal State, and for consideration of the views of any interested members of the general public. The Secretary is further authorized, consistent with the purposes and provisions of this chapter, to amend or rescind any such regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional regulations; criteria for site evaluation and preconstruction testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional regulations; criteria for site evaluation and preconstruction testing The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, shall, as soon as practicable after January 3, 1975, prescribe regulations relating to those activities involved in site evaluation and preconstruction testing at potential deepwater port locations that may (1) adversely affect the environment; (2) interfere with authorized uses of the Outer Continental Shelf; or (3) pose a threat to human health and welfare. Such activity may thenceforth not be undertaken except in accordance with regulations prescribed pursuant to this subsection. Such regulations shall be consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application area; publication in Federal Register; “application area” defined; submission of other applications; notice of intent and submission of completed applications; denial of pending application prior to consideration of other untimely applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application area; publication in Federal Register; “application area” defined; submission of other applications; notice of intent and submission of completed applications; denial of pending application prior to consideration of other untimely applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations to Secretary of Transportation; application for all Federal authorizations; copies of application to Federal agencies and departments with jurisdiction; recommendation of approval or disapproval and of manner of amendment to comply with laws or regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recommendations to Secretary of Transportation; application for all Federal authorizations; copies of application to Federal agencies and departments with jurisdiction; recommendation of approval or disapproval and of manner of amendment to comply with laws or regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>NEPA compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) NEPA compliance For all applications, the Secretary, in cooperation with other involved Federal agencies and departments, shall comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4332) [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.]. Such compliance shall fulfill the requirement of all Federal agencies in carrying out their responsibilities under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public notice and hearings; evidentiary hearing in District of Columbia; decision of Secretary based on evidentiary record; consolidation of hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Public notice and hearings; evidentiary hearing in District of Columbia; decision of Secretary based on evidentiary record; consolidation of hearings A license may be issued only after public notice and public hearings in accordance with this subsection. At least one such public hearing shall be held in each adjacent coastal State. Any interested person may present relevant material at any hearing. After hearings in each adjacent coastal State are concluded if the Secretary determines that there exists one or more specific and material factual issues which may be resolved by a formal evidentiary hearing, at least one adjudicatory hearing shall be held in accordance with the provisions of section 554 of title 5 in the District of Columbia. The record developed in any such adjudicatory hearing shall be basis for the Secretary’s decision to approve or deny a license. Hearings held pursuant to this subsection shall be consolidated insofar as practicable with hearings held by other agen</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application approval; period for determination; priorities; criteria for determination of application best serving national interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Application approval; period for determination; priorities; criteria for determination of application best serving national interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>LNG tankers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) LNG tankers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>