<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1507" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1507/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1507/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1507"><akn:num>1507</akn:num><akn:heading>Common carrier status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1507. Common carrier status(a) Status of deepwater ports and storage facilitiesA deepwater port and a storage facility serviced directly by that deepwater port shall operate as a common carrier under applicable provisions of part I of the Interstate Commerce Act and subtitle IV of title 49, and shall accept, transport, or convey without discrimination all oil delivered to the deepwater port with respect to which its license is issued, except as provided by subsection (b) of this section.


(b) Discrimination prohibition; exceptionsA licensee is not discriminating under this section and is not subject to common carrier regulations under subsection (a) of this section when that licensee—(1) is subject to effective competition for the transportation of oil from alternative transportation systems; and

(2) sets its rates, fees, charges, and conditions of service on the basis of competition, giving consideration to other relevant business factors such as the market value of services provided, licensee’s cost of operation, and the licensee’s investment in the deepwater port and a storage facility, and components thereof, serviced directly by that deepwater port.


(c) Enforcement, suspension, or termination proceedingsWhen the Secretary has reason to believe that a licensee is not in compliance with this section, the Secretary shall commence an appropriate proceeding before the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission or request the Attorney General to take appropriate steps to enforce compliance with this section and, when appropriate, to secure the imposition of appropriate sanctions. In addition, the Secretary may suspend or revoke the license of a licensee not complying with its obligations under this section.


(d) Managed accessSubsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to deepwater ports for natural gas. A licensee of a deepwater port for natural gas, or an affiliate thereof, may exclusively utilize the entire capacity of the deepwater port and storage facilities for th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of deepwater ports and storage facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Status of deepwater ports and storage facilities A deepwater port and a storage facility serviced directly by that deepwater port shall operate as a common carrier under applicable provisions of part I of the Interstate Commerce Act and subtitle IV of title 49, and shall accept, transport, or convey without discrimination all oil delivered to the deepwater port with respect to which its license is issued, except as provided by subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discrimination prohibition; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Discrimination prohibition; exceptions A licensee is not discriminating under this section and is not subject to common carrier regulations under subsection (a) of this section when that licensee—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement, suspension, or termination proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement, suspension, or termination proceedings When the Secretary has reason to believe that a licensee is not in compliance with this section, the Secretary shall commence an appropriate proceeding before the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission or request the Attorney General to take appropriate steps to enforce compliance with this section and, when appropriate, to secure the imposition of appropriate sanctions. In addition, the Secretary may suspend or revoke the license of a licensee not complying with its obligations under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Managed access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Managed access Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to deepwater ports for natural gas. A licensee of a deepwater port for natural gas, or an affiliate thereof, may exclusively utilize the entire capacity of the deepwater port and storage facilities for the acceptance, transport, storage, regasification, or conveyance of natural gas produced, processed, marketed, or otherwise obtained by agreement by such licensee or its affiliates. The licensee may make unused capacity of the deepwater port and storage facilities available to other persons, pursuant to reasonable terms and conditions imposed by the licensee, if such use does not otherwise interfere in any way with the acceptance, transport, storage, regasification, or conveyance of natural gas produced, processed, marketed, or otherwise obtained by agreement by such licensee or its affiliates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1507_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Jurisdiction Notwithstanding any provision of the Natural Gas Act (15 U.S.C. 717 et seq.), any regulation or rule issued thereunder, or section 1518 of this title as it pertains to such Act, this chapter shall apply with respect to the licensing, siting, construction, or operation of a deepwater natural gas port or the acceptance, transport, storage, regasification, or conveyance of natural gas at or through a deepwater port, to the exclusion of the Natural Gas Act or any regulation or rule issued thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>