<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1508" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1508/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1508/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1508"><akn:num>1508</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjacent coastal States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1508. Adjacent coastal States(a) DesignationIn issuing a notice relating to an application for a deepwater port under section 1504(c)(1)(B)(ii)(I) of this title, the Secretary shall designate as an adjacent coastal State, with respect to the deepwater port, any coastal State that would be—(1) directly connected by pipeline to that deepwater port; or

(2) located within 15 miles of that deepwater port.


(b) Input from adjacent coastal States and other interested states(1) Submission of applications to governors for approval(A) In generalNot later than 10 days after the date on which the Secretary designates adjacent coastal States under subsection (a) with respect to a deepwater port proposed in an application, the Secretary shall transmit a complete copy of the application to the Governor of each adjacent coastal State.


(B) ProhibitionThe Secretary shall not issue a license without the approval of the Governor of each adjacent coastal State.


(C) Presumed approvalIf the Governor of an adjacent coastal State fails to transmit a required approval or disapproval to the Secretary not later than 45 days after the last public hearing on applications for a particular application area, such approval shall be conclusively presumed.


(D) Inconsistency with certain state programsIf the Governor of an adjacent coastal State notifies the Secretary that an application, which would otherwise be approved pursuant to this paragraph, is inconsistent with State programs relating to environmental protection, land and water use, and coastal zone management, the Secretary shall condition the license granted so as to make it consistent with such State programs.



(2) Other interested statesAny other State with an interest relating to a deepwater port proposed in an application shall have the opportunity to make its views known to, and shall be given full consideration by, the Secretary regarding the location, construction, and operation of the deepwater port.



(c) Reasonable pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation In issuing a notice relating to an application for a deepwater port under section 1504(c)(1)(B)(ii)(I) of this title, the Secretary shall designate as an adjacent coastal State, with respect to the deepwater port, any coastal State that would be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Input from adjacent coastal States and other interested states</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Input from adjacent coastal States and other interested states</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable progress toward development of coastal zone management program; planning grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reasonable progress toward development of coastal zone management program; planning grants The Secretary shall not issue a license unless the adjacent coastal State to which the deepwater port is to be directly connected by pipeline has developed, or is making, at the time the application is submitted, reasonable progress toward developing an approved coastal zone management program pursuant to the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 [16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.] in the area to be directly and primarily impacted by land and water development in the coastal zone resulting from such deepwater port. For the purposes of this chapter, a State shall be considered to be making reasonable progress if it is receiving a planning grant pursuant to section 305 of the Coastal Zone Management Act [16 U.S.C. 1454].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State agreements or compacts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State agreements or compacts The consent of Congress is given to two or more coastal States to negotiate and enter into agreements or compacts, not in conflict with any law or treaty of the United States, (1) to apply for a license for the ownership, construction, and operation of a deepwater port or for the transfer of such license, and (2) to establish such agencies, joint or otherwise, as are deemed necessary or appropriate for implementing and carrying out the provisions of any such agreement or compact. Such agreement or compact shall be binding and obligatory upon any State or party thereto without further approval by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>