<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1520" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1520/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1520/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1520"><akn:num>1520</akn:num><akn:heading>Pipeline safety and operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1520. Pipeline safety and operation(a) Standards and regulations for Outer Continental ShelfThe Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall establish and enforce such standards and regulations as may be necessary to assure the safe construction and operation of oil or natural gas pipelines on the Outer Continental Shelf.


(b), (c) Omitted

(Pub. L. 93–627, § 21, Jan. 3, 1975, 88 Stat. 2146; Pub. L. 107–295, title I, § 106(a)(3), Nov. 25, 2002, 116 Stat. 2086.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Subsec. (b) directed the Secretary to report to the Congress within 60 days after Jan. 3, 1975, on appropriations and staffing needed to monitor pipelines on Federal lands and the Outer Continental Shelf.
Subsec. (c) directed the Secretary to review all laws and regulations relating to the construction, operation, and maintenance of pipelines on Federal lands and the Outer Continental Shelf and to report to Congress within 6 months after Jan. 3, 1975, on administrative changes needed and recommendations for new legislation.

Amendments2002—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 107–295 inserted “or natural gas” after “oil”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1520_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards and regulations for Outer Continental Shelf</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Standards and regulations for Outer Continental Shelf The Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall establish and enforce such standards and regulations as may be necessary to assure the safe construction and operation of oil or natural gas pipelines on the Outer Continental Shelf.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1520_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (c) Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) , (c) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>