<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1605"><akn:num>1605</akn:num><akn:heading>Navy and Coast Guard vessels of special construction or purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1605. Navy and Coast Guard vessels of special construction or purpose(a) Certification for alternative complianceAny requirement of the International Regulations with respect to the number, position, range, or arc of visibility of lights, with respect to shapes, or with respect to the disposition and characteristics of sound-signaling appliances, shall not be applicable to a vessel of special construction or purpose, whenever the Secretary of the Navy, for any vessel of the Navy, or the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, for any other vessel of the United States, shall certify that the vessel cannot comply fully with that requirement without interfering with the special function of the vessel.


(b) Closest possible compliance by vessels covered by certification for alternative complianceWhenever a certification is issued under the authority of subsection (a) of this section, the vessel involved shall comply with the requirement as to which the certification is made to the extent that the Secretary issuing the certification shall certify as the closest possible compliance by that vessel.


(c) Publication of certifications in Federal RegisterNotice of the certifications issued pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall be published in the Federal Register.


(d) Issuance of certification for a class of vesselsA certification authorized by this section may be issued for a class of vessels.


(Pub. L. 95–75, § 6, July 27, 1977, 91 Stat. 309; Pub. L. 96–591, § 6(2), Dec. 24, 1980, 94 Stat. 3434.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1980—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 96–591 added subsec. (d).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification for alternative compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Certification for alternative compliance Any requirement of the International Regulations with respect to the number, position, range, or arc of visibility of lights, with respect to shapes, or with respect to the disposition and characteristics of sound-signaling appliances, shall not be applicable to a vessel of special construction or purpose, whenever the Secretary of the Navy, for any vessel of the Navy, or the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, for any other vessel of the United States, shall certify that the vessel cannot comply fully with that requirement without interfering with the special function of the vessel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Closest possible compliance by vessels covered by certification for alternative compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Closest possible compliance by vessels covered by certification for alternative compliance Whenever a certification is issued under the authority of subsection (a) of this section, the vessel involved shall comply with the requirement as to which the certification is made to the extent that the Secretary issuing the certification shall certify as the closest possible compliance by that vessel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of certifications in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Publication of certifications in Federal Register Notice of the certifications issued pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall be published in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of certification for a class of vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Issuance of certification for a class of vessels A certification authorized by this section may be issued for a class of vessels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>