<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1606" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1606/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1606/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1606"><akn:num>1606</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for ships of war, vessels proceeding under convoy, and fishing vessels engaged in fish</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1606. Special rules for ships of war, vessels proceeding under convoy, and fishing vessels engaged in fishing as a fleet(a) The Secretary of the Navy is authorized to promulgate special rules with respect to additional station or signal lights or whistle signals for ships of war or vessels proceeding under convoy, and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating is authorized to promulgate special rules with respect to additional station or signal lights for fishing vessels engaged in fishing as a fleet.

(b) The additional station or signal lights or whistle signals contained in the special rules authorized under subsection (a) of this section shall be, as far as possible, such that they cannot be mistaken for any light or signal authorized by the International Regulations. Notice of such special rules shall be published in the Federal Register and, after the effective date specified in such notice, they shall have effect as if they were a part of the International Regulations.

(Pub. L. 95–75, § 7, July 27, 1977, 91 Stat. 310.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 468(b), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Department of Homeland Security Reorganization Plan of November 25, 2002, as modified, set out as a note under section 542 of Title 6.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Navy is authorized to promulgate special rules with respect to additional station or signal lights or whistle signals for ships of war or vessels proceeding under convoy, and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating is authorized to promulgate special rules with respect to additional station or signal lights for fishing vessels engaged in fishing as a fleet.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1606_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The additional station or signal lights or whistle signals contained in the special rules authorized under subsection (a) of this section shall be, as far as possible, such that they cannot be mistaken for any light or signal authorized by the International Regulations. Notice of such special rules shall be published in the Federal Register and, after the effective date specified in such notice, they shall have effect as if they were a part of the International Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>