<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1902"><akn:num>1902</akn:num><akn:heading>Ships subject to preventive measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1902. Ships subject to preventive measures(a) Included vesselsThis chapter shall apply—(1) to a ship of United States registry or nationality, or one operated under the authority of the United States, wherever located;

(2) with respect to Annexes I and II to the Convention, to a ship, other than a ship referred to in paragraph (1), while in the navigable waters of the United States;

(3) with respect to the requirements of Annex V to the Convention, to a ship, other than a ship referred to in paragraph (1), while in the navigable waters or the exclusive economic zone of the United States;

(4) with respect to regulations prescribed under section 1905 of this title, any port or terminal in the United States; and

(5) with respect to Annex VI to the Convention, and other than with respect to a ship referred to in paragraph (1)—(A) to a ship that is in a port, shipyard, offshore terminal, or the internal waters of the United States;

(B) to a ship that is bound for, or departing from, a port, shipyard, offshore terminal, or the internal waters of the United States, and is in—(i) the navigable waters or the exclusive economic zone of the United States;

(ii) an emission control area designated pursuant to section 1903 of this title; or

(iii) any other area that the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary and each State in which any part of the area is located, has designated by order as being an area from which emissions from ships are of concern with respect to protection of public health, welfare, or the environment;


(C) to a ship that is entitled to fly the flag of, or operating under the authority of, a party to Annex VI, and is in—(i) the navigable waters or the exclusive economic zone of the United States;

(ii) an emission control area designated under section 1903 of this title; or

(iii) any other area that the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary and each State in which any part of the area is located, has designated by order as be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Included vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Included vessels This chapter shall apply—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excluded vessels; discharge requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Excluded vessels; discharge requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to other persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application to other persons This chapter shall apply to all persons to the extent necessary to ensure compliance with Annex VI to the Convention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharges in special areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Discharges in special areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge of agricultural cargo residue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Discharge of agricultural cargo residue Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the discharge from a vessel of any agricultural cargo residue material in the form of hold washings shall be governed exclusively by the provisions of this chapter that implement Annex V to the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Secretary or the Administrator, consistent with section 1903 of this title, shall prescribe regulations applicable to the ships of a country not a party to the MARPOL Protocol (or the applicable Annex), including regulations conforming to and giving effect to the requirements of Annex V and Annex VI as they apply under subsection (a) of this section, to ensure that their treatment is not more favorable than that accorded ships to parties to the MARPOL Protocol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance by excluded vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compliance by excluded vessels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Waiver authority The President may waive the effective dates of the requirements set forth in subsection (c) 11 See References in Text note below. of this section and in subsection 1003(e) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1994 if the President determines it to be in the paramount interest of the United States to do so. Any such waiver shall be for a period not in excess of one year. The President shall submit to the Congress each January a report on all waivers from the requirements of this section granted during the preceding calendar year, together with the reasons for granting such waivers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncommercial shipping standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Noncommercial shipping standards The heads of Federal departments and agencies shall prescribe standards applicable to ships excluded from this chapter by subsection (b)(1) of this section and for which they are responsible. Standards prescribed under this subsection shall ensure, so far as is reasonable and practicable without impairing the operations or operational capabilities of such ships, that such ships act in a manner consistent with the MARPOL Protocol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Savings clause Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict in a manner inconsistent with international law navigational rights and freedoms as defined by United States law, treaty, convention, or customary international law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>