<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/1903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1903"><akn:num>1903</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1903. Administration and enforcement(a) Duty of Secretary; Annexes of Convention applicable to seagoing vesselsUnless otherwise specified in this chapter, the Secretary shall administer and enforce the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, and this chapter. In the administration and enforcement of the MARPOL Protocol and this chapter, Annexes I and II of the Convention apply only to seagoing ships.


(b) Duty of the AdministratorIn addition to other duties specified in this chapter, the Administrator and the Secretary, respectively, shall have the following duties and authorities:(1) The Administrator shall, and no other person may, issue Engine International Air Pollution Prevention certificates in accordance with Annex VI and the International Maritime Organization’s Technical Code on Control of Emissions of Nitrogen Oxides from Marine Diesel Engines, on behalf of the United States for a vessel of the United States as that term is defined in section 116 of title 46. The issuance of Engine International Air Pollution Prevention certificates shall be consistent with any applicable requirements of the Clean Air Act [42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.] or regulations prescribed under that Act.

(2) The Administrator shall have authority to administer regulations 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, and 19 of Annex VI to the Convention.

(3) The Administrator shall, only as specified in section 1907(f) of this title, have authority to enforce Annex VI of the Convention.


(c) Regulations; refuse record books; waste management plans; notification of crew and passengers(1) The Secretary shall prescribe any necessary or desired regulations to carry out the provisions of the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, or this chapter.

(2) In addition to the authority the Secretary has to prescribe regulations under this chapter, the Administrator shall also prescribe any necessary or desired regulations to carry out the provisions of regulations 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of Secretary; Annexes of Convention applicable to seagoing vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Duty of Secretary; Annexes of Convention applicable to seagoing vessels Unless otherwise specified in this chapter, the Secretary shall administer and enforce the MARPOL Protocol, Annex IV to the Antarctic Protocol, and this chapter. In the administration and enforcement of the MARPOL Protocol and this chapter, Annexes I and II of the Convention apply only to seagoing ships.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of the Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duty of the Administrator In addition to other duties specified in this chapter, the Administrator and the Secretary, respectively, shall have the following duties and authorities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; refuse record books; waste management plans; notification of crew and passengers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations; refuse record books; waste management plans; notification of crew and passengers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of personnel, facilities, or equipment of other Federal departments and agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Utilization of personnel, facilities, or equipment of other Federal departments and agencies The Secretary may utilize by agreement, with or without reimbursement, personnel, facilities, or equipment of other Federal departments and agencies in administering the MARPOL Protocol, this chapter, or the regulations thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>