<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2202" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2202/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2202/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2202"><akn:num>2202</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal engagement and review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2202. Non-Federal engagement and review(a) IssuanceThe Secretary shall expeditiously issue guidance to implement each covered provision of law in accordance with this section.


(b) Public notice(1) In generalPrior to developing and issuing any new or revised implementation guidance for a covered water resources development law, the Secretary shall issue a public notice that—(A) informs potentially interested non-Federal stakeholders of the Secretary’s intent to develop and issue such guidance; and

(B) provides an opportunity for interested non-Federal stakeholders to engage with, and provide input and recommendations to, the Secretary on the development and issuance of such guidance.


(2) Issuance of noticeThe Secretary shall issue the notice under paragraph (1) through a posting on a publicly accessible website dedicated to providing notice on the development and issuance of implementation guidance for a covered water resources development law.



(c) Stakeholder engagement(1) InputThe Secretary shall allow a minimum of 60 days after issuance of the public notice under subsection (b) for non-Federal stakeholders to provide input and recommendations to the Secretary, prior to finalizing implementation guidance for a covered water resources development law.


(2) OutreachThe Secretary may, as appropriate (as determined by the Secretary), reach out to non-Federal stakeholders and circulate drafts of implementation guidance for a covered water resources development law for informal input and recommendations.



(d) SubmissionThe Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a copy of all input and recommendations received pursuant to subsection (c) and a description of any consideration of such input and recommendations.


(e) Development of guidanceWhen developing implementation guidance for a covered water resources development law, the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Issuance The Secretary shall expeditiously issue guidance to implement each covered provision of law in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stakeholder engagement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Stakeholder engagement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Submission The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a copy of all input and recommendations received pursuant to subsection (c) and a description of any consideration of such input and recommendations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Development of guidance When developing implementation guidance for a covered water resources development law, the Secretary shall take into consideration the input and recommendations received from non-Federal stakeholders, and make the final guidance available to the public on the publicly accessible website described in subsection (b)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>