<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2211a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2211a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2211a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2211a"><akn:num>2211a</akn:num><akn:heading>Preserving United States harbors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2211a. Preserving United States harbors(a) In generalUpon a request from a non-Federal interest, the Secretary shall review a report developed by the non-Federal interest that provides an economic justification for Federal investment in the operation and maintenance of a federally authorized harbor or inland harbor (referred to in this section as a “federally authorized harbor”).


(b) Justification of investmentA report submitted under subsection (a) may provide for an economic justification of Federal investment in the operation and maintenance of a federally authorized harbor based on—(1) the projected economic benefits, including transportation savings and job creation; and

(2) other factors, including navigation safety, national security, and sustainability of subsistence harbors.


(c) Written responseNot later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a report under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide to the non-Federal interest a written response to the report, including an assessment of the information provided by the non-Federal interest.


(d) PrioritizationAs the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the Secretary may use the information provided in the report under subsection (a) to justify additional operation and maintenance funding for a federally authorized harbor in accordance with section 2211(b) of this title.


(e) Limitation on statutory constructionNothing in this section may be construed to preclude the operation and maintenance of a federally authorized harbor under section 2211(b) of this title.


(Pub. L. 113–121, title II, § 2107, June 10, 2014, 128 Stat. 1281.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014, and not as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

“Secretary” Defined
Secretary means the Secretary of the Army, see section 2 of Pub. L. 113–121, s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Upon a request from a non-Federal interest, the Secretary shall review a report developed by the non-Federal interest that provides an economic justification for Federal investment in the operation and maintenance of a federally authorized harbor or inland harbor (referred to in this section as a “federally authorized harbor”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Justification of investment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Justification of investment A report submitted under subsection (a) may provide for an economic justification of Federal investment in the operation and maintenance of a federally authorized harbor based on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written response</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Written response Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary receives a report under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide to the non-Federal interest a written response to the report, including an assessment of the information provided by the non-Federal interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prioritization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prioritization As the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the Secretary may use the information provided in the report under subsection (a) to justify additional operation and maintenance funding for a federally authorized harbor in accordance with section 2211(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on statutory construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on statutory construction Nothing in this section may be construed to preclude the operation and maintenance of a federally authorized harbor under section 2211(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>