<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2211" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2211/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2211/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2211"><akn:num>2211</akn:num><akn:heading>Harbors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2211. Harbors(a) Construction(1) Payments during constructionThe non-Federal interests for a navigation project for a harbor or inland harbor, or any separable element thereof, on which a contract for physical construction has not been awarded before June 10, 2014, shall pay, during the period of construction of the project, the following costs associated with general navigation features:(A) 10 percent of the cost of construction of the portion of the project which has a depth not in excess of 20 feet; plus

(B) 25 percent of the cost of construction of the portion of the project which has a depth in excess of 20 feet but not in excess of 55 feet; plus

(C) 50 percent of the cost of construction of the portion of the project which has a depth in excess of 55 feet.


(2) Additional 10 percent payment over 30 yearsThe non-Federal interests for a project to which paragraph (1) applies shall pay an additional 10 percent of the cost of the general navigation features of the project in cash over a period not to exceed 30 years, at an interest rate determined pursuant to section 2216 of this title. The value of lands, easements, rights-of-way, and relocations provided under paragraph (3) and the costs of relocations borne by the non-Federal interests under paragraph (4) shall be credited toward the payment required under this paragraph.


(3) Lands, easements, and rights-of-wayExcept as provided under section 2283(c) of this title, the non-Federal interests for a project to which paragraph (1) applies shall provide the lands, easements, rights-of-way, and relocations (other than utility relocations under paragraph (4)) necessary for the project, including any lands, easements, rights-of-way, and relocations (other than utility relocations accomplished under paragraph (4)) that are necessary for dredged material disposal facilities.


(4) Utility relocationsThe non-Federal interests for a project to which paragraph (1) applies shall perform or assure the performance of al</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Construction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation and maintenance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Operation and maintenance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Erosion or shoaling attributable to Federal navigation works</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Erosion or shoaling attributable to Federal navigation works Costs of constructing projects or measures for the prevention or mitigation of erosion or shoaling damages attributable to Federal navigation works shall be shared in the same proportion as the cost sharing provisions applicable to the project causing such erosion or shoaling. The non-Federal interests for the project causing the erosion or shoaling shall agree to operate and maintain such measures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal payments during construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Non-Federal payments during construction The amount of any non-Federal share of the cost of any navigation project for a harbor or inland harbor shall be paid to the Secretary. Amounts required to be paid during construction shall be paid on an annual basis during the period of construction, beginning not later than one year after construction is initiated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Agreement Before initiation of construction of a project to which this section applies, the Secretary and the non-Federal interests shall enter into a cooperative agreement according to the provisions of section 1962d–5b of title 42. The non-Federal interests shall agree to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of funding requirements and equitable apportionment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consideration of funding requirements and equitable apportionment The Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>