<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2238" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2238/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2238/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2238"><akn:num>2238</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2238. Authorization of appropriations(a) Trust fundThere are authorized to be appropriated out of the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund, established by section 9505 of title 26, for each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to pay—(1) 100 percent of the eligible operations and maintenance costs of those portions of the Saint Lawrence Seaway operated and maintained by the Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation for such fiscal year; and

(2) up to 100 percent of the eligible operations and maintenance costs assigned to commercial navigation of all harbors and inland harbors within the United States.


(b) General fundThere are authorized to be appropriated out of the general fund of the Treasury of the United States for each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to pay the balance of all eligible operations and maintenance costs not provided by payments from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund under this section.


(c) Operation and maintenance of harbor projects(1) In generalTo the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall make expenditures to pay for operation and maintenance costs of the harbors and inland harbors referred to in subsection (a)(2), including expenditures of funds appropriated from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund, based on an equitable allocation of funds among all such harbors and inland harbors.


(2) Criteria(A) In generalIn determining an equitable allocation of funds under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—(i) consider the information obtained in the assessment conducted under subsection (e);

(ii) consider the national and regional significance of harbor operations and maintenance; and

(iii) as appropriate, consider national security and military readiness needs.


(B) LimitationThe Secretary shall not allocate funds under paragraph (1) based solely on the tonnage transiting through a harbor.



(3) Emerging harbor projects(A) AllocationNotwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, in making expenditure</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trust fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Trust fund There are authorized to be appropriated out of the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund, established by section 9505 of title 26, for each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to pay—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General fund There are authorized to be appropriated out of the general fund of the Treasury of the United States for each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to pay the balance of all eligible operations and maintenance costs not provided by payments from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation and maintenance of harbor projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operation and maintenance of harbor projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prioritization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prioritization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of harbors and inland harbors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assessment of harbors and inland harbors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>