<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2238c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2238c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2238c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2238c"><akn:num>2238c</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional measures at donor ports and energy transfer ports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2238c. Additional measures at donor ports and energy transfer ports(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Cargo containerThe term “cargo container” means a cargo container that is 1 Twenty-foot Equivalent Unit.


(2) Discretionary cargoThe term “discretionary cargo” means maritime cargo for which the United States port of unlading is different than the United States port of entry.


(3) Donor port(A) In generalThe term “donor port” means a port—(i) that is subject to the harbor maintenance fee under section 24.24 of title 19, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation);

(ii) at which the total amount of harbor maintenance taxes collected (including the estimated taxes related to domestic cargo and cruise passengers) comprise not less than $15,000,000 annually of the total funding of the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund on an average annual basis for the previous 3 fiscal years;

(iii) that received less than 25 percent of the total amount of harbor maintenance taxes collected (including the estimated taxes related to domestic cargo and cruise passengers) at that port in the previous 3 fiscal years; and

(iv) that is located in a State in which more than 2,000,000 cargo containers were unloaded from or loaded on to vessels on an average annual basis for the previous 3 fiscal years.


(B) CalculationFor the purpose of calculating the percentage described in subparagraph (A)(iii), payments described under subsection (c)(1) shall not be included.



(4) Energy commodityThe term “energy commodity” includes—(A) petroleum products;

(B) natural gas;

(C) coal;

(D) wind and solar energy components; and

(E) biofuels.


(5) Energy transfer portThe term “energy transfer port” means a port—(A) that is subject to the harbor maintenance fee under section 24.24 of title 19, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation); and

(B)(i) at which energy commodities comprised greater than 25 percent of all commercial activity by tonnage on an average annual basis fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds Amounts provided under this section may be used by a donor port, a medium-sized donor port, or an energy transfer port—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration of payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2238c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Savings clause Nothing in this section waives any statutory requirement related to the transportation of merchandise as authorized under chapter 551 of title 46.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>