<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2241" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2241/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2241/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2241"><akn:num>2241</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2241. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter—(1) Deep-draft harborThe term “deep-draft harbor” means a harbor which is authorized to be constructed to a depth of more than 45 feet (other than a project which is authorized by section 202 of this title).


(2) Eligible operations and maintenance(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “eligible operations and maintenance” means all Federal operations, maintenance, repair, and rehabilitation, including (i) maintenance dredging reasonably necessary to maintain the width and nominal depth of any harbor or inland harbor; (ii) the construction of dredged material disposal facilities that are necessary for the operation and maintenance of any harbor or inland harbor; (iii) dredging and disposing of contaminated sediments that are in or that affect the maintenance of Federal navigation channels; (iv) mitigating for impacts resulting from Federal navigation operation and maintenance activities; and (v) operating and maintaining dredged material disposal facilities.

(B) As applied to the Saint Lawrence Seaway, the term “eligible operations and maintenance” means all operations, maintenance, repair, and rehabilitation, including maintenance dredging reasonably necessary to keep such Seaway or navigation improvements operated or maintained by the Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation in operation and reasonable state of repair.

(C) The term “eligible operations and maintenance” does not include providing any lands, easements, or rights-of-way, or performing relocations required for project operations and maintenance.


(3) General cargo harborThe term “general cargo harbor” means a harbor for which a project is authorized by section 202 of this title and any other harbor which is authorized to be constructed to a depth of more than 20 feet but not more than 45 feet;


(4) HarborThe term “harbor” means any channel or harbor, or element thereof, in the United States, capable of being utilized</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deep-draft harbor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Deep-draft harbor The term “deep-draft harbor” means a harbor which is authorized to be constructed to a depth of more than 45 feet (other than a project which is authorized by section 202 of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible operations and maintenance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Eligible operations and maintenance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>General cargo harbor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) General cargo harbor The term “general cargo harbor” means a harbor for which a project is authorized by section 202 of this title and any other harbor which is authorized to be constructed to a depth of more than 20 feet but not more than 45 feet;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Harbor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Harbor The term “harbor” means any channel or harbor, or element thereof, in the United States, capable of being utilized in the transportation of commercial cargo in domestic or foreign waterborne commerce by commercial vessels. The term does not include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inland harbor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Inland harbor The term “inland harbor” means a navigation project which is used principally for the accommodation of commercial vessels and the receipt and shipment of waterborne cargoes on inland waters. The term does not include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nominal depth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Nominal depth The term “nominal depth” means, in relation to the stated depth for any navigation improvement project, such depth, including any greater depths which must be maintained for any harbor or inland harbor or element thereof included within such project in order to ensure the safe passage at mean low tide of any vessel requiring the stated depth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Non-Federal interest The term “non-Federal interest” has the meaning such term has under section 1962d–5b of title 42 and includes any interstate agency and port authority established under a compact entered into between two or more States with the consent of Congress under section 10 of Article I of the Constitution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) United States The term “United States” means all areas included within the territorial boundaries of the United States, including the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession over which the United States exercises jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>