<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2281b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2281b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2281b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2281b"><akn:num>2281b</akn:num><akn:heading>Corps of Engineers support for underserved communities; outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2281b. Corps of Engineers support for underserved communities; outreach(a) In generalIt is the policy of the United States for the Corps of Engineers to strive to understand and accommodate and, in coordination with non-Federal interests, seek to address the water resources development needs of all communities in the United States.


(b) Outreach and access(1) In generalThe Secretary shall, at Federal expense, develop, support, and implement public awareness, education, and regular outreach and engagement efforts for potential non-Federal interests with respect to the water resources development authorities of the Secretary, with particular emphasis on—(A) technical service programs, including the authorities under—(i) section 709a of this title;

(ii) section 1962d–16 of title 42; and

(iii) section 2269 of this title;


(B) continuing authority programs, as such term is defined in section 2282d(c)(1)(D) of this title; and

(C) ensuring that a potential non-Federal interest is aware of the roles, responsibilities, and financial commitments associated with a completed water resources development project prior to initiating a feasibility study (as defined in section 2215(d) of this title), including operations, maintenance, repair, replacement, and rehabilitation responsibilities.


(2) ImplementationIn carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall—(A) develop and make publicly available (including on a publicly available website), technical assistance materials, guidance, and other information with respect to the water resources development authorities of the Secretary;

(B) designate and make publicly available a community project advisor at each district and division office of the Corps of Engineers for—(i) inquiries from potential non-Federal interests relating to the water resources development authorities of the Secretary; and

(ii) any other responsibilities as determined by the Secretary that are appropriate to carry out this section;


(C) conduct regu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general It is the policy of the United States for the Corps of Engineers to strive to understand and accommodate and, in coordination with non-Federal interests, seek to address the water resources development needs of all communities in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach and access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Outreach and access</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>