<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2281a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2281a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2281a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2281a"><akn:num>2281a</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal Liaison</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2281a. Tribal Liaison(a) In generalBeginning not later than 1 year after December 23, 2022, the District Commander for each Corps of Engineers district that contains a Tribal community shall have on staff a Tribal Liaison.


(b) DutiesEach Tribal Liaison shall make recommendations to the applicable District Commander regarding, and be responsible for—(1) removing barriers to access to, and participation in, Corps of Engineers programs for Tribal communities, including by improving implementation of section 2213(m) of this title;

(2) improving outreach to, and engagement with, Tribal communities about relevant Corps of Engineers programs and services;

(3) identifying and engaging with Tribal communities suffering from water resources challenges;

(4) improving, expanding, and facilitating government-to-government consultation between Tribal communities and the Corps of Engineers;

(5) coordinating and implementing all relevant Tribal consultation policies and associated guidelines, including the requirements of section 2356 of title;

(6) training and tools to facilitate the ability of Corps of Engineers staff to effectively engage with Tribal communities in a culturally competent manner, especially in regards to lands of ancestral, historic, or cultural significance to a Tribal community, including burial sites; and

(7) such other issues identified by the Secretary.


(c) UniformityNot later than 120 days after December 23, 2022, the Secretary shall finalize guidelines for—(1) a position description for Tribal Liaisons; and

(2) required qualifications for Tribal Liaisons, including experience and expertise relating to Tribal communities and water resource issues.


(d) FundingFunding for the position of Tribal Liaison shall be allocated from the budget line item provided for the expenses necessary for the supervision and general administration of the civil works program, and filling the position shall not be dependent on any increase in this budget line item.
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Beginning not later than 1 year after December 23, 2022, the District Commander for each Corps of Engineers district that contains a Tribal community shall have on staff a Tribal Liaison.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties Each Tribal Liaison shall make recommendations to the applicable District Commander regarding, and be responsible for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniformity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Uniformity Not later than 120 days after December 23, 2022, the Secretary shall finalize guidelines for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding Funding for the position of Tribal Liaison shall be allocated from the budget line item provided for the expenses necessary for the supervision and general administration of the civil works program, and filling the position shall not be dependent on any increase in this budget line item.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>