<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2282d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2282d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2282d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2282d"><akn:num>2282d</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2282d. Annual report to Congress(a) In generalNot later than February 1 of each year, the Secretary shall develop and submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives an annual report, to be entitled “Report to Congress on Future Water Resources Development”, that identifies the following:(1) Feasibility reportsEach feasibility report that meets the criteria established in subsection (c)(1)(A).


(2) Proposed feasibility studiesAny proposed feasibility study submitted to the Secretary by a non-Federal interest pursuant to subsection (b) that meets the criteria established in subsection (c)(1)(A).


(3) Proposed modificationsAny proposed modification to an authorized water resources development project or feasibility study that meets the criteria established in subsection (c)(1)(A) that—(A) is submitted to the Secretary by a non-Federal interest pursuant to subsection (b); or

(B) is identified by the Secretary for authorization.


(4) Programmatic modificationsAny programmatic modification for an environmental infrastructure assistance program.



(b) Requests for proposals(1) PublicationNot later than May 1 of each year, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a notice requesting proposals from non-Federal interests for proposed feasibility studies, proposed modifications to authorized water resources development projects and feasibility studies, and proposed modifications for an environmental infrastructure program to be included in the annual report.


(2) Deadline for requestsThe Secretary shall include in each notice required by this subsection a requirement that non-Federal interests submit to the Secretary any proposals described in paragraph (1) by not later than 120 days after the date of publication of the notice in the Federal Register in order for the proposals to be considered for inclusion in the annual report.


(3) NotificationOn </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2282d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than February 1 of each year, the Secretary shall develop and submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives an annual report, to be entitled “Report to Congress on Future Water Resources Development”, that identifies the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2282d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requests for proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requests for proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2282d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2282d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programmatic modifications in annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Programmatic modifications in annual report The Secretary shall include in the annual report only proposed modifications for an environmental infrastructure assistance program that have not been included in any previous annual report. For each proposed modification, the Secretary shall include a letter or statement of support for the proposed modification from each associated non-Federal interest, description of assistance provided, and total Federal cost of assistance provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2282d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for initial annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rule for initial annual report Notwithstanding any other deadlines required by this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2282d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Publication Upon submission of an annual report to Congress, the Secretary shall make the annual report publicly available, including through publication on the Internet.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2282d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal interest notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Non-Federal interest notification After the publication of the annual report under subsection (f), if the proposal of a non-Federal interest submitted under subsection (b) was included by the Secretary in the appendix under subsection (c)(4), the Secretary shall provide written notification to the non-Federal interest of such inclusion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2282d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Congressional notification Not later than 30 days after the publication of the annual report under subsection (f), for each proposal included in that annual report or appendix, the Secretary shall notify each Member of Congress that represents the State in which that proposal will be located that the proposal was included the annual report or the appendix.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2282d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>