<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2289a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2289a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2289a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2289a"><akn:num>2289a</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2289a. Consideration of measures(a) DefinitionsIn this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Natural featureThe term “natural feature” means a feature that is created through the action of physical, geological, biological, and chemical processes over time.


(2) Nature-based featureThe term “nature-based feature” means a feature that is created by human design, engineering, and construction to provide risk reduction by acting in concert with natural processes.



(b) RequirementIn studying the feasibility of projects for flood risk management, hurricane and storm damage reduction, and ecosystem restoration the Secretary shall, with the consent of the non-Federal sponsor of the feasibility study, consider, as appropriate—(1) natural features;

(2) nature-based features;

(3) nonstructural measures; and

(4) structural measures.


(c) Report to Congress(1) In generalNot later than February 1, 2020, and 5 and 10 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the implementation of subsection (b).


(2) ContentsThe report under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, the following:(A) A description of guidance or instructions issued, and other measures taken, by the Secretary and the Chief of Engineers to implement subsection (b).

(B) An assessment of the costs, benefits, impacts, and trade-offs associated with measures recommended by the Secretary for coastal risk reduction and the effectiveness of those measures.

(C) A description of any statutory, fiscal, or regulatory barriers to the appropriate consideration and use of a full array of measures for coastal risk reduction.



(Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1184, Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1679; Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1149(b), Oct. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 3787.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Water Resources Developme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2289a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2289a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement In studying the feasibility of projects for flood risk management, hurricane and storm damage reduction, and ecosystem restoration the Secretary shall, with the consent of the non-Federal sponsor of the feasibility study, consider, as appropriate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2289a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>