<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2307"><akn:num>2307</akn:num><akn:heading>Control of ice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2307. Control of ice(a) Program authorityThe Secretary shall undertake a program of research for the control of ice, and to assist communities in breaking up ice, which otherwise is likely to cause or aggravate flood damage or severe streambank erosion.


(b) Assistance to units of local governmentThe Secretary is further authorized to provide technical assistance to units of local government to implement local plans to control or break up such ice. As part of such authority, the Secretary shall acquire necessary ice-control or ice-breaking equipment, which shall be loaned to units of local government together with operating assistance, where appropriate.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 per fiscal year for each of the fiscal years 1988, 1989, 1990, 1991, and 1992 for purposes of carrying out subsections (a) and (b) of this section, such sums to remain available until expended.


(d) Hardwick, Vermont, demonstration programTo implement further the purposes of this section, the Secretary, in consultation and cooperation with local officials, is authorized and directed to undertake a demonstration program for the control of ice at Hardwick, Vermont. The work authorized by this subsection shall be designed to minimize the danger of flooding due to ice problems in the vicinity of such community. In the design, construction, and location of ice-control structures for this project, full consideration will be given to the recreational, scenic, and environmental values of the reach of river affected by the project, in order to minimize project impacts on these values. Full opportunity shall be given to interested environmental and recreational organizations to participate in such planning. There is authorized to be appropriated $900,000 for fiscal years beginning after September 30, 1986, for the purposes of carrying out this subsection, such sum to remain available until expended.


(e) Salmon, Idaho, experimental pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authority The Secretary shall undertake a program of research for the control of ice, and to assist communities in breaking up ice, which otherwise is likely to cause or aggravate flood damage or severe streambank erosion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to units of local government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assistance to units of local government The Secretary is further authorized to provide technical assistance to units of local government to implement local plans to control or break up such ice. As part of such authority, the Secretary shall acquire necessary ice-control or ice-breaking equipment, which shall be loaned to units of local government together with operating assistance, where appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 per fiscal year for each of the fiscal years 1988, 1989, 1990, 1991, and 1992 for purposes of carrying out subsections (a) and (b) of this section, such sums to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hardwick, Vermont, demonstration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hardwick, Vermont, demonstration program To implement further the purposes of this section, the Secretary, in consultation and cooperation with local officials, is authorized and directed to undertake a demonstration program for the control of ice at Hardwick, Vermont. The work authorized by this subsection shall be designed to minimize the danger of flooding due to ice problems in the vicinity of such community. In the design, construction, and location of ice-control structures for this project, full consideration will be given to the recreational, scenic, and environmental values of the reach of river affected by the project, in order to minimize project impacts on these values. Full opportunity shall be given to interested environmental and recreational organizations to participate in such planning. There is authorized to be appropriated $900,000 for fiscal years beginning after September 30, 1986, for the purposes of carrying out this subsection, such sum to remain available u</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Salmon, Idaho, experimental program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Salmon, Idaho, experimental program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2307_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wilmington, Illinois, project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Wilmington, Illinois, project</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2307_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cost sharing Cost sharing applicable to flood control projects under section 2213 of this title shall apply to projects under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2307_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report to Congress Not later than March 1, 1989, the Secretary shall report to the Congress on activities under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>