<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2317" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2317/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2317/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2317"><akn:num>2317</akn:num><akn:heading>Wetlands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2317. Wetlands(a) Goals and action plan(1) GoalsThere is established, as part of the Corps of Engineers water resources development program, an interim goal of no overall net loss of the Nation’s remaining wetlands base, as defined by acreage and function, and a long-term goal to increase the quality and quantity of the Nation’s wetlands, as defined by acreage and function.


(2) Use of authoritiesThe Secretary shall utilize all appropriate authorities, including those to restore and create wetlands, in meeting the interim and long-term goals.


(3) Action plan(A) DevelopmentThe Secretary shall develop, in consultation with the Environmental Protection Agency, the Fish and Wildlife Service, and other appropriate Federal agencies, a wetlands action plan to achieve the goals established by this subsection as soon as possible.


(B) ContentsThe plan shall include and identify actions to be taken by the Secretary in achieving the goals and any new authorities which may be necessary to accelerate attainment of the goals.


(C) Completion deadlineThe Secretary shall complete the plan not later than 1 year after November 28, 1990.




(b) Constructed wetlands for Mud Creek, ArkansasNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized and directed to establish and carry out a research and pilot project to evaluate and demonstrate—(1) the use of constructed wetlands for wastewater treatment, and

(2) methods by which such projects contribute—(A) to meeting the objective of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.] to restore and maintain the physical, chemical, and biological integrity of the Nation’s waters, and

(B) to attaining the goals established by subsection (a).



The project under this subsection shall be carried out to improve the quality of effluent discharged from publicly owned treatment works operated by the city of Fayetteville, Arkansas, into Mud Creek or its tributaries.

(c) Non-Federal responsibilitiesFor the p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2317_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals and action plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Goals and action plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2317_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Constructed wetlands for Mud Creek, Arkansas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Constructed wetlands for Mud Creek, Arkansas Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized and directed to establish and carry out a research and pilot project to evaluate and demonstrate— The project under this subsection shall be carried out to improve the quality of effluent discharged from publicly owned treatment works operated by the city of Fayetteville, Arkansas, into Mud Creek or its tributaries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2317_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Non-Federal responsibilities For the project conducted under subsection (b), the non-Federal interest shall agree— The value of the non-Federal lands, easements, rights-of-way, relocations, and dredged material disposal areas provided by the non-Federal interest shall be credited toward the non-Federal share of project design and construction costs. The non-Federal share of project design and construction costs shall be 25 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2317_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wetlands restoration and enhancement demonstration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Wetlands restoration and enhancement demonstration program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2317_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and certification of delineators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Training and certification of delineators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>