<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2320" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2320/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2320/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2320"><akn:num>2320</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of recreational and commercial uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2320. Protection of recreational and commercial uses(a) General ruleIn planning any water resources project, the Secretary shall consider the impact of the project on existing and future recreational and commercial uses in the area surrounding the project.


(b) MaintenanceWhenever the Secretary maintains, repairs, rehabilitates, or reconstructs a water resources project which will result in a change in the configuration of a structure which is a part of such project, the Secretary, to the maximum extent practicable, shall carry out such maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, or reconstruction in a manner which will not adversely affect any recreational use established with respect to such project before the date of such maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, or reconstruction.


(c) Mitigation(1) In generalIf maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, or reconstruction of a water resources project by the Secretary results in a change in the configuration of any structure which is a part of such project and has an adverse effect on a recreational use established with respect to such project before the date of such maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, or reconstruction, the Secretary, to the maximum extent practicable, shall take such actions as may be necessary to restore such recreational use or provide alternative opportunities for comparable recreational use.


(2) Maximum amountThe Secretary may not expend more than $2,000,000 in a fiscal year to carry out this subsection.


(3) Termination dateThis subsection shall not be effective after the last day of the 5-year period beginning on November 28, 1990; except that the Secretary may complete any restoration commenced under this subsection on or before such last day.



(d) Applicability(1) General ruleSubsections (b) and (c) shall apply to maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, or reconstruction for which physical construction is initiated after May 1, 1988.


(2) LimitationSubsections (b) and (c) shall not apply to any a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2320_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In planning any water resources project, the Secretary shall consider the impact of the project on existing and future recreational and commercial uses in the area surrounding the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2320_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Maintenance Whenever the Secretary maintains, repairs, rehabilitates, or reconstructs a water resources project which will result in a change in the configuration of a structure which is a part of such project, the Secretary, to the maximum extent practicable, shall carry out such maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, or reconstruction in a manner which will not adversely affect any recreational use established with respect to such project before the date of such maintenance, repair, rehabilitation, or reconstruction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2320_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mitigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mitigation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2320_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2320_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cost sharing Costs incurred by the Secretary to carry out the objectives of this section shall be allocated to recreation and shall be payable by the beneficiaries of the recreation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>