<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2325" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2325/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2325/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2325"><akn:num>2325</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary contributions for environmental and recreation projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2325. Voluntary contributions for environmental and recreation projects(a) AcceptanceIn connection with carrying out a water resources project for environmental protection and restoration or a water resources project for recreation, the Secretary is authorized to accept contributions of cash, funds, materials, and services from persons, including governmental entities but excluding the project sponsor.


(b) DepositAny cash or funds received by the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be deposited into the account in the Treasury of the United States entitled “Contributions and Advances, Rivers and Harbors, Corps of Engineers (8862)” and shall be available until expended to carry out water resources projects described in subsection (a).


(Pub. L. 102–580, title II, § 203, Oct. 31, 1992, 106 Stat. 4826; Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 236(a), Oct. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 3705.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 1992, and not as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 which comprises this chapter.

Amendments1996—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 104–303 substituted “(8862)” for “(8662)”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

“Secretary” Defined
Secretary means the Secretary of the Army, see section 3 of Pub. L. 102–580, set out as a note under section 2201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2325_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Acceptance In connection with carrying out a water resources project for environmental protection and restoration or a water resources project for recreation, the Secretary is authorized to accept contributions of cash, funds, materials, and services from persons, including governmental entities but excluding the project sponsor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2325_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deposit Any cash or funds received by the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be deposited into the account in the Treasury of the United States entitled “Contributions and Advances, Rivers and Harbors, Corps of Engineers (8862)” and shall be available until expended to carry out water resources projects described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>