<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2326e"><akn:num>2326e</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal interest dredging authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2326e. Non-Federal interest dredging authority(a) In generalThe Secretary may permit a non-Federal interest to carry out, for an authorized navigation project (or a separable element of an authorized navigation project), such maintenance activities as are necessary to ensure that the project is maintained to not less than the minimum project dimensions.


(b) Cost limitationsExcept as provided in this section and subject to the availability of appropriations, the costs incurred by a non-Federal interest in performing the maintenance activities described in subsection (a) shall be eligible for reimbursement, not to exceed an amount that is equal to the estimated Federal cost for the performance of the maintenance activities, with any reimbursement subject to the non-Federal interest complying with all Federal laws and regulations that would apply to such maintenance activities if carried out by the Secretary.


(c) AgreementBefore initiating maintenance activities under this section, a non-Federal interest shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary that specifies, for the performance of the maintenance activities, the terms and conditions that are acceptable to the non-Federal interest and the Secretary.


(d) Provision of equipmentIn carrying out maintenance activities under this section, a non-Federal interest shall—(1) provide equipment at no cost to the Federal Government; and

(2) hold and save the United States free from any and all damage that arises from the use of the equipment of the non-Federal interest, except for damage due to the fault or negligence of a contractor of the Federal Government.


(e) Reimbursement eligibility limitationsCosts that are eligible for reimbursement under this section are the costs of maintenance activities directly related to the costs associated with operation and maintenance of a dredge based on the lesser of—(1) the costs associated with operation and maintenance of the dredge during the period of time that the dred</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may permit a non-Federal interest to carry out, for an authorized navigation project (or a separable element of an authorized navigation project), such maintenance activities as are necessary to ensure that the project is maintained to not less than the minimum project dimensions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cost limitations Except as provided in this section and subject to the availability of appropriations, the costs incurred by a non-Federal interest in performing the maintenance activities described in subsection (a) shall be eligible for reimbursement, not to exceed an amount that is equal to the estimated Federal cost for the performance of the maintenance activities, with any reimbursement subject to the non-Federal interest complying with all Federal laws and regulations that would apply to such maintenance activities if carried out by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreement Before initiating maintenance activities under this section, a non-Federal interest shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary that specifies, for the performance of the maintenance activities, the terms and conditions that are acceptable to the non-Federal interest and the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provision of equipment In carrying out maintenance activities under this section, a non-Federal interest shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement eligibility limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reimbursement eligibility limitations Costs that are eligible for reimbursement under this section are the costs of maintenance activities directly related to the costs associated with operation and maintenance of a dredge based on the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Audit Not earlier than 5 years after December 16, 2016, the Secretary may conduct an audit on any maintenance activities for an authorized navigation project (or a separable element of an authorized navigation project) carried out under this section to determine if permitting a non-Federal interest to carry out maintenance activities under this section has resulted in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Termination of authority The authority of the Secretary under this section terminates on the date that is 10 years after December 16, 2016.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>