<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2326j"><akn:num>2326j</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of suitable dredged material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2326j. Transfer of suitable dredged material(1) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to make available to a non-Federal interest, at no additional cost, dredged material that the Secretary has determined is in excess of the amounts identified as needed for use by the Secretary.


(2) ResponsibilityThe non-Federal interest shall be responsible for all costs to remove and transport such material, and shall certify that the non-Federal interest is responsible for any and all liability related to the removal of such material or the use of such material once it is removed.


(Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1130(e), Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 3020.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 2024, and also as part of the Thomas R. Carper Water Resources Development Act of 2024, and not as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

“Secretary” Defined
Secretary means the Secretary of the Army, see section 1002 of Pub. L. 118–272, set out as a note under section 2201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326j_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) In general The Secretary is authorized to make available to a non-Federal interest, at no additional cost, dredged material that the Secretary has determined is in excess of the amounts identified as needed for use by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326j_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Responsibility The non-Federal interest shall be responsible for all costs to remove and transport such material, and shall certify that the non-Federal interest is responsible for any and all liability related to the removal of such material or the use of such material once it is removed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>