<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2326i"><akn:num>2326i</akn:num><akn:heading>Beneficial use of dredged material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2326i. Beneficial use of dredged material(a) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to carry out projects for the beneficial use of dredged material, including projects for the purposes of—(1) promoting resiliency and reducing the risk to property and infrastructure of flooding and storm damage;

(2) promoting public safety;

(3) protecting, restoring, and creating aquatic ecosystem habitats;

(4) stabilizing stream systems and enhancing shorelines;

(5) promoting recreation;

(6) supporting risk management adaptation strategies;

(7) reducing the costs of dredging and dredged material placement or disposal, such as projects that use dredged material for—(A) construction or fill material;

(B) civic improvement objectives; and

(C) other innovative uses and placement alternatives that produce public economic or environmental benefits; and


(8) recovering lost storage capacity in reservoirs due to sediment accumulation, if the project also has a purpose described in any of paragraphs (1) through (7).


(b) Project selectionIn carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—(1) identify and carry out projects for the beneficial use of dredged material;

(2) consult with relevant State agencies in selecting projects; and

(3) select projects solely on the basis of—(A) the environmental, economic, and social benefits of the projects, including monetary and nonmonetary benefits; and

(B) the need for a diversity of project types and geographical project locations.



(c) Regional beneficial use teams(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish regional beneficial use teams to identify and assist in the implementation of projects under this section.


(2) Composition(A) LeadershipFor each regional beneficial use team established under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall appoint the Commander of the relevant division of the Corps of Engineers to serve as the head of the team.


(B) Membership
The membership of each regional beneficial use team shall include—(i) representati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary is authorized to carry out projects for the beneficial use of dredged material, including projects for the purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Project selection In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional beneficial use teams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regional beneficial use teams</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Considerations The Secretary shall carry out this section in a manner that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326i_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cost sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326i_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Not later than 2 years after December 16, 2016, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326i_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from other standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exemption from other standards The projects carried out under this section shall be carried out notwithstanding the definition of the term “Federal standard” in section 335.7 of title 33, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326i_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redesignated (g)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Redesignated (g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326i_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (j) Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) , (j) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>