<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2326"><akn:num>2326</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional sediment management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2326. Regional sediment management(a) In general(1) Sediment use(A) Sediment from Federal water resources projectsFor sediment obtained through or used in the construction, operation, or maintenance of an authorized Federal water resources project, including a project authorized for flood control, the Secretary shall develop, at Federal expense, regional sediment management plans and carry out projects at locations identified in plans developed under this section, or identified jointly by the non-Federal interest and the Secretary, for use in the construction, repair, modification, or rehabilitation of projects, including projects for the beneficial use of dredged materials described in section 1122 of the Water Resources Development Act of 2016 (33 U.S.C. 2326 note),11 See References in Text note below. associated with Federal water resources projects for purposes listed in paragraph (3).


(B) Sediment from other Federal sources and non-Federal sourcesFor purposes of projects carried out under this section, the Secretary may include sediment from other Federal sources and non-Federal sources, subject to the requirement that any sediment obtained from a non-Federal source shall not be obtained at Federal expense.



(2) CooperationThe Secretary shall develop plans under this subsection in cooperation with the appropriate Federal, State, regional, and local agencies.


(3) Purposes for sediment use in projectsThe purposes of using sediment for the construction, repair, modification, or rehabilitation of Federal water resources projects are—(A) to reduce storm damage to property;

(B) to protect, restore, and create aquatic and ecologically related habitats, including wetlands; and

(C) to transport and place suitable sediment for the purposes of improving environmental conditions in marsh and littoral systems, stabilizing stream channels, enhancing shorelines, and supporting State and local risk management adaptation strategies.


(4) Reducing costsTo reduce or av</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Secretarial findings Subject to subsection (c), projects carried out under subsection (a) may be carried out in any case in which the Secretary finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of project costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination of project costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of dredged material disposal method for purposes related to environmental restoration or storm damage and flood reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Selection of dredged material disposal method for purposes related to environmental restoration or storm damage and flood reduction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and regional plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State and regional plans The Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Priority areas In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall give priority to a regional sediment management project in the vicinity of each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $62,500,000 per fiscal year, of which not more than $5,000,000 per fiscal year may be used for the development of regional sediment management plans authorized by subsection (e) and of which not more than $3,000,000 per fiscal year may be used for construction of projects to which subsection (c)(1)(B)(ii) applies. Such funds shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>