<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2326a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2326a"><akn:num>2326a</akn:num><akn:heading>Dredged material disposal facility partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2326a. Dredged material disposal facility partnerships(a) Additional capacity or replacement capacity(1) Provided by Secretary(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B), at the request of a non-Federal interest with respect to a project, the Secretary may—(i) provide additional capacity at a dredged material disposal facility constructed by the Secretary beyond the capacity that would be required for project purposes; or

(ii) permit the use of dredged material disposal facility capacity required for project purposes by the non-Federal interest if the Secretary determines that replacement capacity can be constructed at the facility or another facility or site before such capacity is needed for project purposes.


(B) AgreementBefore the Secretary takes an action under subparagraph (A), the non-Federal interest shall agree to pay—(i) all costs associated with the construction of the additional capacity or replacement capacity in advance of construction of such capacity; and

(ii) in the case of use by a non-Federal interest of dredged material disposal capacity required for project purposes under subparagraph (A)(ii), any increase in the cost of operation and maintenance of the project that the Secretary determines results from the use of the project capacity by the non-Federal interest in advance of each cycle of dredging.


(C) CreditIn the event the Secretary determines that the cost to operate or maintain the project decreases as a result of use by the non-Federal interest of dredged material disposal capacity required for project purposes under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Secretary, at the request of the non-Federal interest, shall credit the amount of the decrease toward any cash contribution of the non-Federal interest required thereafter for construction, operation, or maintenance of the project, or of another navigation project.



(2) Cost recovery authorityThe non-Federal interest may recover the costs assigned to the additional capacity under paragraph (1)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional capacity or replacement capacity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Additional capacity or replacement capacity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal use of disposal facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Non-Federal use of disposal facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dredged material facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dredged material facility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2326a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public-private partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public-private partnerships</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>