<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2328" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2328/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2328/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2328"><akn:num>2328</akn:num><akn:heading>Challenge cost-sharing program for management of recreation facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2328. Challenge cost-sharing program for management of recreation facilities(a) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to develop and implement a program to share the cost of managing recreation facilities and natural resources at water resource development projects under the Secretary’s jurisdiction.


(b) Cooperative agreements(1) In generalTo implement the program under this section, the Secretary is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements with non-Federal public entities and private nonprofit entities to provide for operation and management of recreation facilities and natural resources at civil works projects under the Secretary’s jurisdiction where such facilities and resources are being maintained at complete Federal expense.


(2) RequirementsBefore entering into an agreement under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that the non-Federal public entity or private nonprofit entity has the authority and capability—(A) to carry out the terms of the agreement; and

(B) to pay damages, if necessary, in the event of a failure to perform.



(c) User fees(1) Collection of fees(A) In generalThe Secretary may allow a non-Federal public entity or private nonprofit entity that has entered into an agreement pursuant to subsection (b) to collect user fees for the use of developed recreation sites and facilities, whether developed or constructed by the non-Federal public entity or private nonprofit entity or the Department of the Army.


(B) Use of visitor reservation services(i) In generalA non-Federal public entity or a private nonprofit entity described in subparagraph (A) may use, to manage fee collections and reservations under this section, any visitor reservation service that the Secretary has provided for by contract or interagency agreement, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.


(ii) TransferThe Secretary may transfer, or cause to be transferred by another Federal agency, to a non-Federal public entity</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2328_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary is authorized to develop and implement a program to share the cost of managing recreation facilities and natural resources at water resource development projects under the Secretary’s jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2328_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cooperative agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2328_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>User fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) User fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2328_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2328_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>