<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2330c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2330c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2330c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2330c"><akn:num>2330c</akn:num><akn:heading>Aquatic ecosystem restoration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2330c. Aquatic ecosystem restoration(a) Definition of eligible entityIn this section, the term “eligible entity” means—(1) any State, Indian Tribe, irrigation district, or water district;

(2) any State, regional, or local authority, the members of which include 1 or more organizations with water or power delivery authority;

(3) any other entity or organization that owns a facility that is eligible for upgrade, modification or removal under this section;

(4) any nonprofit conservation organization, acting in partnership with any entity listed in paragraphs (1) through (3), with respect to a project involving land or infrastructure owned by the entity; and

(5) an agency established under State law for the joint exercise of powers or a combination of entities described in paragraphs (1) through (4).


(b) General authority(1) In generalSubject to the requirements of this section and paragraph (2), on request of any eligible entity the Secretary may negotiate and enter into an agreement on behalf of the United States to fund the design, study, and construction of an aquatic ecosystem restoration and protection project in a Reclamation State if the Secretary determines that the project is likely to improve the health of fisheries, wildlife or aquatic habitat, including through habitat restoration and improved fish passage via the removal or bypass of barriers to fish passage.


(2) ExceptionWith respect to an aquatic ecosystem restoration and protection project under this section that removes a dam or modifies a dam in a manner that reduces storage or diversion capacity, the Secretary may only negotiate and enter into an agreement to fund—(A) the design or study of such project if the Secretary has received consent from the owner of the applicable dam; or

(B) the construction of such project if the Secretary—(i) identifies any eligible entity that receives water or power from the facility that is under consideration for removal or modification at the time of the r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of eligible entity In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compliance required The Secretary shall comply with applicable State water laws in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority for projects providing regional benefits and assistance for aging assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Priority for projects providing regional benefits and assistance for aging assets When funding projects under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize projects that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>