<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2330a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2330a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2330a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2330a"><akn:num>2330a</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring ecosystem restoration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2330a. Monitoring ecosystem restoration(a) In generalIn conducting a feasibility study for a project (or a component of a project) for ecosystem restoration, the Secretary shall ensure that the recommended project includes, as an integral part of the project, a plan for monitoring the success of the ecosystem restoration.


(b) Monitoring planThe monitoring plan shall—(1) include a description of the monitoring activities to be carried out, the criteria for ecosystem restoration success, and the estimated cost and duration of the monitoring; and

(2) specify that the monitoring shall continue until such time as the Secretary determines that the criteria for ecosystem restoration success will be met.


(c) Cost shareFor a period of 10 years from completion of construction of a project (or a component of a project) for ecosystem restoration, the Secretary shall consider the cost of carrying out the monitoring as a project cost. If the monitoring plan under subsection (b) requires monitoring beyond the 10-year period, the cost of monitoring shall be a non-Federal responsibility.


(d) InclusionsA monitoring plan under subsection (b) shall include a description of—(1) the types and number of restoration activities to be conducted;

(2) the physical action to be undertaken to achieve the restoration objectives of the project;

(3) the functions and values that will result from the restoration plan; and

(4) a contingency plan for taking corrective actions in cases in which monitoring demonstrates that restoration measures are not achieving ecological success in accordance with criteria described in the monitoring plan.


(e) Conclusion of operation and maintenance responsibilityThe responsibility of a non-Federal interest for operation and maintenance of the nonstructural and nonmechanical elements of a project, or a component of a project, for ecosystem restoration shall cease 10 years after the date on which the Secretary makes a determination of success under subsec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In conducting a feasibility study for a project (or a component of a project) for ecosystem restoration, the Secretary shall ensure that the recommended project includes, as an integral part of the project, a plan for monitoring the success of the ecosystem restoration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Monitoring plan The monitoring plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cost share For a period of 10 years from completion of construction of a project (or a component of a project) for ecosystem restoration, the Secretary shall consider the cost of carrying out the monitoring as a project cost. If the monitoring plan under subsection (b) requires monitoring beyond the 10-year period, the cost of monitoring shall be a non-Federal responsibility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inclusions A monitoring plan under subsection (b) shall include a description of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conclusion of operation and maintenance responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conclusion of operation and maintenance responsibility The responsibility of a non-Federal interest for operation and maintenance of the nonstructural and nonmechanical elements of a project, or a component of a project, for ecosystem restoration shall cease 10 years after the date on which the Secretary makes a determination of success under subsection (b)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2330a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal obligations The Secretary is not responsible for the operation or maintenance of any components of a project with respect to which a non-Federal interest is released from obligations under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>