<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2332" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2332/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2332/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2332"><akn:num>2332</akn:num><akn:heading>Shoreline and riverine protection and restoration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2332. Shoreline and riverine protection and restoration(a) In generalThe Secretary may carry out studies and projects to—(1) reduce flood and hurricane and storm damage hazards; or

(2) restore the natural functions and values of rivers and shorelines throughout the United States.


(b) Studies and projects(1) Authority(A) StudiesIn carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may carry out studies to identify appropriate measures for—(i) the reduction of flood and hurricane and storm damage hazards, including measures for erosion mitigation and bank stabilization; or

(ii) the conservation and restoration of the natural functions and values of rivers and shorelines.


(B) ProjectsSubject to subsection (f)(2), in carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may design and implement projects described in subsection (a).



(2) Consultation and coordinationThe studies and projects carried out under this section shall be conducted, to the maximum extent practicable, in consultation and coordination with the Federal Emergency Management Agency and other appropriate Federal agencies, and in consultation and coordination with appropriate State and local agencies and tribes.


(3) Nonstructural approachesThe studies and projects shall emphasize, to the maximum extent practicable and appropriate, nonstructural approaches to preventing or reducing flood and hurricane and storm damages, including the use of natural features or nature-based features.


(4) ParticipationThe studies and projects shall be conducted, to the maximum extent practicable, in cooperation with State and local agencies and tribes to ensure the coordination of local flood and hurricane and storm damage reduction or riverine, shoreline, and wetland restoration studies with projects that conserve, restore, and manage hydrologic and hydraulic regimes and restore the natural functions and values of floodplains and coastal barriers.



(c) Cost-sharing requirements(1) StudiesStudies conducted under this section </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may carry out studies and projects to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies and projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Studies and projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-sharing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cost-sharing requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project justification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Project justification Notwithstanding any requirement for economic justification established under section 1962–2 of title 42, the Secretary may implement a project under this section if the Secretary determines that the project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Areas for Examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Areas for Examination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>