<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2340" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2340/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2340/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2340"><akn:num>2340</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of project partnership agreement; cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2340. Revision of project partnership agreement; cost sharing(a) Federal allocationUpon authorization by law of an increase in the maximum amount of Federal funds that may be allocated for a water resources project or an increase in the total cost of a water resources project authorized to be carried out by the Secretary, the Secretary shall enter into a revised partnership agreement for the project to take into account the change in Federal participation in the project.


(b) Cost sharingAn increase in the maximum amount of Federal funds that may be allocated for a water resources project, or an increase in the total cost of a water resources project, authorized to be carried out by the Secretary shall not affect any cost-sharing requirement applicable to the project.


(c) Cost estimatesThe estimated Federal and non-Federal costs of water resources projects authorized to be carried out by the Secretary before, on, or after November 8, 2007, are for informational purposes only and shall not be interpreted as affecting the cost-sharing responsibilities established by law.


(Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2008, Nov. 8, 2007, 121 Stat. 1073.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 2007, and not as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Reference to Partnership Agreement Deemed Reference to Cooperation Agreement
Reference to partnership agreement deemed to be reference to cooperation agreement, see section 2003(f)(3) of Pub. L. 110–114, set out as a note under section 1962d–5b of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare.


“Secretary” Defined
Secretary means the Secretary of the Army, see section 2 of Pub. L. 110–114, set out as a note under section 2201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2340_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal allocation Upon authorization by law of an increase in the maximum amount of Federal funds that may be allocated for a water resources project or an increase in the total cost of a water resources project authorized to be carried out by the Secretary, the Secretary shall enter into a revised partnership agreement for the project to take into account the change in Federal participation in the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2340_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cost sharing An increase in the maximum amount of Federal funds that may be allocated for a water resources project, or an increase in the total cost of a water resources project, authorized to be carried out by the Secretary shall not affect any cost-sharing requirement applicable to the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2340_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost estimates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cost estimates The estimated Federal and non-Federal costs of water resources projects authorized to be carried out by the Secretary before, on, or after November 8, 2007, are for informational purposes only and shall not be interpreted as affecting the cost-sharing responsibilities established by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>