<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2342" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2342/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2342/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2342"><akn:num>2342</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to water resource data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2342. Access to water resource data(a) In generalUsing available funds, the Secretary shall make publicly available, including on the Internet, all data in the custody of the Corps of Engineers on—(1) the planning, design, construction, operation, and maintenance of water resources development projects; and

(2) water quality and water management of projects owned, operated, or managed by the Corps of Engineers.


(b) LimitationNothing in this section may be construed to compel or authorize the disclosure of data or other information determined by the Secretary to be confidential information, privileged information, law enforcement information, national security information, infrastructure security information, personal information, or information the disclosure of which is otherwise prohibited by law.


(c) TimingThe Secretary shall ensure that data is made publicly available under subsection (a) as quickly as practicable after the data is generated by the Corps of Engineers.


(d) PartnershipsIn carrying out this section, the Secretary may develop partnerships, including through cooperative agreements, with State, tribal, and local governments and other Federal agencies.


(Pub. L. 110–114, title II, § 2017, Nov. 8, 2007, 121 Stat. 1077; Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1135, Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1656.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 2007, and not as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 which comprises this chapter.

Amendments2016—Pub. L. 114–322 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section related to access to water resource data.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Data TransparencyPub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title I, § 158(b), Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2662, provided that: “The Secretary [of the Army] shall prioritize making publicly available water resources data in the custody of the Corps of Engineers, as authorized by section 2017 of the Water Resources Develo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2342_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Using available funds, the Secretary shall make publicly available, including on the Internet, all data in the custody of the Corps of Engineers on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2342_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation Nothing in this section may be construed to compel or authorize the disclosure of data or other information determined by the Secretary to be confidential information, privileged information, law enforcement information, national security information, infrastructure security information, personal information, or information the disclosure of which is otherwise prohibited by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2342_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Timing The Secretary shall ensure that data is made publicly available under subsection (a) as quickly as practicable after the data is generated by the Corps of Engineers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2342_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Partnerships In carrying out this section, the Secretary may develop partnerships, including through cooperative agreements, with State, tribal, and local governments and other Federal agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>