<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2343" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2343/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2343/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2343"><akn:num>2343</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent peer review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2343. Independent peer review(a) Project studies subject to independent peer review(1) In generalProject studies shall be subject to a peer review by an independent panel of experts as determined under this section.


(2) ScopeThe peer review may include a review of the economic and environmental assumptions and projections, project evaluation data, economic analyses, environmental analyses, engineering analyses, formulation of alternative plans, methods for integrating risk and uncertainty, models used in evaluation of economic or environmental impacts of proposed projects, and any biological opinions of the project study.


(3) Project studies subject to peer review(A) MandatoryA project study shall be subject to peer review under paragraph (1) if—(i) the project has an estimated total cost of more than $200,000,000, including mitigation costs, and is not determined by the Chief of Engineers to be exempt from peer review under paragraph (6);

(ii) the Governor of an affected State requests a peer review by an independent panel of experts; or

(iii) the Chief of Engineers determines that the project study is controversial considering the factors set forth in paragraph (4).


(B) Discretionary(i) Agency requestA project study shall be considered by the Chief of Engineers for peer review under this section if the head of a Federal or State agency charged with reviewing the project study determines that the project is likely to have a significant adverse impact on environmental, cultural, or other resources under the jurisdiction of the agency after implementation of proposed mitigation plans and requests a peer review by an independent panel of experts.


(ii) Deadline for decisionA decision of the Chief of Engineers under this subparagraph whether to conduct a peer review shall be made within 21 days of the date of receipt of the request by the head of the Federal or State agency under clause (i).


(iii) Reasons for not conducting peer reviewIf the Chief of Engin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project studies subject to independent peer review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Project studies subject to independent peer review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of peer review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Timing of peer review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of panels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of panels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of panels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties of panels A panel of experts established for a peer review for a project study under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of project study peer reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duration of project study peer reviews</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations of panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Recommendations of panel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nonapplicability of chapter 10 of title 5 Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to a peer review panel established under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Savings clause Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any authority of the Chief of Engineers to cause or conduct a peer review of a water resources project existing on November 8, 2007.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>