<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2347c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2347c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2347c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2347c"><akn:num>2347c</akn:num><akn:heading>Small water storage projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2347c. Small water storage projects(a) In generalThe Secretary shall carry out a program to study and construct new, or enlarge existing, small water storage projects, in partnership with a non-Federal interest.


(b) RequirementsTo be eligible to participate in the program under this section, a small water storage project shall—(1) in the case of a new small water storage project, have a water storage capacity of not less than 2,000 acre-feet and not more than 30,000 acre-feet;

(2) in the case of an enlargement of an existing small water storage project, be for an enlargement of not less than 1,000 acre-feet and not more than 30,000 acre-feet;

(3) provide—(A) flood risk management benefits;

(B) ecological benefits; or

(C) water management, water conservation, or water supply; and


(4) be—(A) economically justified, environmentally acceptable, and technically feasible; or

(B) in the case of a project providing ecological benefits, cost-effective with respect to such benefits.



(c) ScopeIn carrying out the program under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to a small water storage project located in a State with a population of less than 1,000,000.


(d) Expedited projectsFor the 10-year period beginning on December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall expedite small water storage projects under this section for which applicable Federal permitting requirements have been completed.


(e) Use of dataIn conducting a study under this section, to the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall—(1) as the Secretary determines appropriate, consider and utilize any applicable hydrologic, economic, or environmental data that is prepared for a small water storage project under State law as the documentation, or part of the documentation, required to complete State water plans or other State planning documents relating to water resources management; and

(2) consider information developed by the non-Federal interest in relation to another study, to the exten</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2347c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall carry out a program to study and construct new, or enlarge existing, small water storage projects, in partnership with a non-Federal interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2347c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements To be eligible to participate in the program under this section, a small water storage project shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2347c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Scope In carrying out the program under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to a small water storage project located in a State with a population of less than 1,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2347c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expedited projects For the 10-year period beginning on December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall expedite small water storage projects under this section for which applicable Federal permitting requirements have been completed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2347c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of data In conducting a study under this section, to the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2347c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cost share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2347c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>OMRRR responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) OMRRR responsibility The costs of operation, maintenance, repair, and replacement and rehabilitation for a small water storage project constructed under this section shall be the responsibility of the non-Federal interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2347c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individual project limit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Individual project limit Not more than $65,000,000 in Federal funds may be made available to a small water storage project under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2347c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $130,000,000 annually through fiscal year 2030.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>