<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2348a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2348a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2348a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2348a"><akn:num>2348a</akn:num><akn:heading>NEPA reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2348a. NEPA reporting(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Categorical exclusionThe term “categorical exclusion” has the meaning given the term in section 1508.1 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).


(2) Environmental assessmentThe term “environmental assessment” has the meaning given the term in section 1508.1 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).


(3) Environmental impact statementThe term “environmental impact statement” means a detailed written statement required under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)).


(4) Finding of no significant impactThe term “finding of no significant impact” has the meaning given the term in section 1508.1 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).


(5) Project studyThe term “project study” means a feasibility study for a project carried out pursuant to section 2282 of this title for which a categorical exclusion may apply, or an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement is required, pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).



(b) Reports(1) NEPA data(A) In generalThe Secretary shall carry out a process to track, and annually submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, a report containing the information described in subparagraph (B).


(B) Information describedThe information referred to in subparagraph (A) is, with respect to the Corps of Engineers—(i) the number of project studies for which a categorical exclusion was used during the reporting period;

(ii) the number of project studies for which the decision to use a categorical exclusion, to prepare an environmental assessment, or to prepare an environmental impact statement is pending on the date on which the report is submitted;

(iii) the number of project s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2348a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2348a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>