<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2354" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2354/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2354/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2354"><akn:num>2354</akn:num><akn:heading>Easements for electric, telephone, or broadband service facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2354. Easements for electric, telephone, or broadband service facilities(a) Definition of water resources development projectIn this section, the term “water resources development project” means a project under the administrative jurisdiction of the Corps of Engineers that is subject to part 327 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).


(b) No consideration for easementsThe Secretary may not collect consideration for an easement across water resources development project land for the electric, telephone, or broadband service facilities of nonprofit organizations eligible for financing under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (7 U.S.C. 901 et seq.).


(c) Administrative expensesNothing in this section affects the authority of the Secretary under section 2695 of title 10 or under section 9701 of title 31 to collect funds to cover reasonable administrative expenses incurred by the Secretary.


(Pub. L. 114–322, title I, § 1172, Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1671.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Rural Electrification Act of 1936, referred to in subsec. (b), is act May 20, 1936, ch. 432, 49 Stat. 1363, which is classified generally to chapter 31 (§ 901 et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 901 of Title 7 and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 2016, and also as part of the Water Infrastructure Improvements for the Nation Act, also known as the WIIN Act, and not as part of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Nonrecreation Outgrant PolicyPub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1113, Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 3010, provided that:
“(a) In General.—Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [Jan. 4, 2025], the Secretary [of the Army] shall update the policy guidance of the Corps of Engineers for the evaluation and approval of nonr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2354_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of water resources development project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of water resources development project In this section, the term “water resources development project” means a project under the administrative jurisdiction of the Corps of Engineers that is subject to part 327 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2354_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>No consideration for easements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No consideration for easements The Secretary may not collect consideration for an easement across water resources development project land for the electric, telephone, or broadband service facilities of nonprofit organizations eligible for financing under the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (7 U.S.C. 901 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2354_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative expenses Nothing in this section affects the authority of the Secretary under section 2695 of title 10 or under section 9701 of title 31 to collect funds to cover reasonable administrative expenses incurred by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>