<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2706" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2706/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2706/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2706"><akn:num>2706</akn:num><akn:heading>Natural resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2706. Natural resources(a) LiabilityIn the case of natural resource damages under section 2702(b)(2)(A) of this title, liability shall be—(1) to the United States Government for natural resources belonging to, managed by, controlled by, or appertaining to the United States;

(2) to any State for natural resources belonging to, managed by, controlled by, or appertaining to such State or political subdivision thereof;

(3) to any Indian tribe for natural resources belonging to, managed by, controlled by, or appertaining to such Indian tribe; and

(4) in any case in which section 2707 of this title applies, to the government of a foreign country for natural resources belonging to, managed by, controlled by, or appertaining to such country.


(b) Designation of trustees(1) In generalThe President, or the authorized representative of any State, Indian tribe, or foreign government, shall act on behalf of the public, Indian tribe, or foreign country as trustee of natural resources to present a claim for and to recover damages to the natural resources.


(2) Federal trusteesThe President shall designate the Federal officials who shall act on behalf of the public as trustees for natural resources under this Act.


(3) State trusteesThe Governor of each State shall designate State and local officials who may act on behalf of the public as trustee for natural resources under this Act and shall notify the President of the designation.


(4) Indian tribe trusteesThe governing body of any Indian tribe shall designate tribal officials who may act on behalf of the tribe or its members as trustee for natural resources under this Act and shall notify the President of the designation.


(5) Foreign trusteesThe head of any foreign government may designate the trustee who shall act on behalf of that government as trustee for natural resources under this Act.



(c) Functions of trustees(1) Federal trusteesThe Federal officials designated under subsection (b)(2)—(A) shall assess natura</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2706_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liability In the case of natural resource damages under section 2702(b)(2)(A) of this title, liability shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2706_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of trustees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation of trustees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2706_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of trustees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions of trustees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2706_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Measure of damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Measure of damages</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2706_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Damage assessment regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Damage assessment regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2706_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of recovered sums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of recovered sums Sums recovered under this Act by a Federal, State, Indian, or foreign trustee for natural resource damages under section 2702(b)(2)(A) of this title shall be retained by the trustee in a revolving trust account, without further appropriation, for use only to reimburse or pay costs incurred by the trustee under subsection (c) with respect to the damaged natural resources. Any amounts in excess of those required for these reimbursements and costs shall be deposited in the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2706_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compliance Review of actions by any Federal official where there is alleged to be a failure of that official to perform a duty under this section that is not discretionary with that official may be had by any person in the district court in which the person resides or in which the alleged damage to natural resources occurred. The court may award costs of litigation (including reasonable attorney and expert witness fees) to any prevailing or substantially prevailing party. Nothing in this subsection shall restrict any right which any person may have to seek relief under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>