<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2713" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2713/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2713/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2713"><akn:num>2713</akn:num><akn:heading>Claims procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2713. Claims procedure(a) PresentationExcept as provided in subsection (b), all claims for removal costs or damages shall be presented first to the responsible party or guarantor of the source designated under section 2714(a) of this title.


(b) Presentation to Fund(1) In generalClaims for removal costs or damages may be presented first to the Fund—(A) if the President has advertised or otherwise notified claimants in accordance with section 2714(c) of this title;

(B) by a responsible party who may assert a claim under section 2708 of this title;

(C) by the Governor of a State for removal costs incurred by that State; or

(D) by a United States claimant in a case where a foreign offshore unit has discharged oil causing damage for which the Fund is liable under section 2712(a) of this title.


(2) Limitation on presenting claimNo claim of a person against the Fund may be approved or certified during the pendency of an action by the person in court to recover costs which are the subject of the claim.



(c) ElectionIf a claim is presented in accordance with subsection (a) and—(1) each person to whom the claim is presented denies all liability for the claim, or

(2) the claim is not settled by any person by payment within 90 days after the date upon which (A) the claim was presented, or (B) advertising was begun pursuant to section 2714(b) of this title, whichever is later,


the claimant may elect to commence an action in court against the responsible party or guarantor or to present the claim to the Fund.

(d) Uncompensated damagesIf a claim is presented in accordance with this section, including a claim for interim, short-term damages representing less than the full amount of damages to which the claimant ultimately may be entitled, and full and adequate compensation is unavailable, a claim for the uncompensated damages and removal costs may be presented to the Fund.


(e) Procedure for claims against FundThe President shall promulgate, and may from time to tim</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2713_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presentation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Presentation Except as provided in subsection (b), all claims for removal costs or damages shall be presented first to the responsible party or guarantor of the source designated under section 2714(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2713_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presentation to Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Presentation to Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2713_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Election If a claim is presented in accordance with subsection (a) and— the claimant may elect to commence an action in court against the responsible party or guarantor or to present the claim to the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2713_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uncompensated damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Uncompensated damages If a claim is presented in accordance with this section, including a claim for interim, short-term damages representing less than the full amount of damages to which the claimant ultimately may be entitled, and full and adequate compensation is unavailable, a claim for the uncompensated damages and removal costs may be presented to the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2713_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for claims against Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Procedure for claims against Fund The President shall promulgate, and may from time to time amend, regulations for the presentation, filing, processing, settlement, and adjudication of claims under this Act against the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>