<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2718" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2718/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2718/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2718"><akn:num>2718</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2718. Relationship to other law(a) Preservation of State authorities; Solid Waste Disposal ActNothing in this Act or the Act of March 3, 1851 shall—(1) affect, or be construed or interpreted as preempting, the authority of any State or political subdivision thereof from imposing any additional liability or requirements with respect to—(A) the discharge of oil or other pollution by oil within such State; or

(B) any removal activities in connection with such a discharge; or


(2) affect, or be construed or interpreted to affect or modify in any way the obligations or liabilities of any person under the Solid Waste Disposal Act (42 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.) or State law, including common law.


(b) Preservation of State fundsNothing in this Act or in section 9509 of title 26 shall in any way affect, or be construed to affect, the authority of any State—(1) to establish, or to continue in effect, a fund any purpose of which is to pay for costs or damages arising out of, or directly resulting from, oil pollution or the substantial threat of oil pollution; or

(2) to require any person to contribute to such a fund.


(c) Additional requirements and liabilities; penaltiesNothing in this Act, the Act of March 3, 1851 (46 U.S.C. 183 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. or section 9509 of title 26, shall in any way affect, or be construed to affect, the authority of the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof—(1) to impose additional liability or additional requirements; or

(2) to impose, or to determine the amount of, any fine or penalty (whether criminal or civil in nature) for any violation of law;


relating to the discharge, or substantial threat of a discharge, of oil.

(d) Federal employee liabilityFor purposes of section 2679(b)(2)(B) of title 28, nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize or create a cause of action against a Federal officer or employee in the officer’s or employee’s personal or individual capacity for any act or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2718_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of State authorities; Solid Waste Disposal Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preservation of State authorities; Solid Waste Disposal Act Nothing in this Act or the Act of March 3, 1851 shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2718_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of State funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preservation of State funds Nothing in this Act or in section 9509 of title 26 shall in any way affect, or be construed to affect, the authority of any State—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2718_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements and liabilities; penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional requirements and liabilities; penalties Nothing in this Act, the Act of March 3, 1851 (46 U.S.C. 183 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. or section 9509 of title 26, shall in any way affect, or be construed to affect, the authority of the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof— relating to the discharge, or substantial threat of a discharge, of oil.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2718_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal employee liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal employee liability For purposes of section 2679(b)(2)(B) of title 28, nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize or create a cause of action against a Federal officer or employee in the officer’s or employee’s personal or individual capacity for any act or omission while acting within the scope of the officer’s or employee’s office or employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>