<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2731" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2731/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2731/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2731"><akn:num>2731</akn:num><akn:heading>Oil Spill Recovery Institute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2731. Oil Spill Recovery Institute(a) Establishment of InstituteThe Secretary of Commerce shall provide for the establishment of a Prince William Sound Oil Spill Recovery Institute (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Institute”) through the Prince William Sound Science and Technology Institute located in Cordova, Alaska.


(b) FunctionsThe Institute shall conduct research and carry out educational and demonstration projects designed to—(1) identify and develop the best available techniques, equipment, and materials for dealing with oil spills in the arctic and subarctic marine environment; and

(2) complement Federal and State damage assessment efforts and determine, document, assess, and understand the long-range effects of Arctic or Subarctic oil spills on the natural resources of Prince William Sound and its adjacent waters (as generally depicted on the map entitled “EXXON VALDEZ oil spill dated March 1990”), and the environment, the economy, and the lifestyle and well-being of the people who are dependent on them, except that the Institute shall not conduct studies or make recommendations on any matter which is not directly related to Arctic or Subarctic oil spills or the effects thereof.


(c) Advisory board(1) In generalThe policies of the Institute shall be determined by an advisory board, composed of 16 members appointed as follows:(A) One representative appointed by each of the Commissioners of Fish and Game, Environmental Conservation, and Natural Resources of the State of Alaska, all of whom shall be State employees.

(B) One representative appointed by each of the Secretaries of Commerce and the Interior and the Commandant of the Coast Guard, who shall be Federal employees.

(C) Two representatives from the fishing industry appointed by the Governor of the State of Alaska from among residents of communities in Alaska that were affected by the EXXON VALDEZ oil spill, who shall serve terms of 2 years each. Interested organizations from withi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Institute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Institute The Secretary of Commerce shall provide for the establishment of a Prince William Sound Oil Spill Recovery Institute (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Institute”) through the Prince William Sound Science and Technology Institute located in Cordova, Alaska.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions The Institute shall conduct research and carry out educational and demonstration projects designed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Advisory board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scientific and technical committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Scientific and technical committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Director The Institute shall be administered by a Director appointed by the Advisory Board. The Prince William Sound Science and Technology Institute and the Scientific and Technical Committee may each submit independent recommendations for the Advisory Board’s consideration for appointment as Director. The Director may hire such staff and incur such expenses on behalf of the Institute as are authorized by the Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Evaluation The Secretary of Commerce may conduct an ongoing evaluation of the activities of the Institute to ensure that funds received by the Institute are used in a manner consistent with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Audit The Comptroller General of the United States, and any of his or her duly authorized representatives, shall have access, for purposes of audit and examination, to any books, documents, papers, and records of the Institute and its administering agency that are pertinent to the funds received and expended by the Institute and its administering agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Status of employees Employees of the Institute shall not, by reason of such employment, be considered to be employees of the Federal Government for any purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination The authorization in section 2736(b) of this title providing funding for the Institute shall terminate 1 year after the date on which the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, determines that oil and gas exploration, development, and production in the State of Alaska have ceased.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Use of funds No funds made available to carry out this section may be used to initiate litigation. No funds made available to carry out this section may be used for the acquisition of real property (including buildings) or construction of any building. No more than 20 percent of funds made available to carry out this section may be used to lease necessary facilities and to administer the Institute. The Advisory Board may compensate its Federal representatives for their reasonable travel costs. None of the funds authorized by this section shall be used for any purpose other than the functions specified in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>