<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2761" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2761/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2761/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2761"><akn:num>2761</akn:num><akn:heading>Oil pollution research and development program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2761. Oil pollution research and development program(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “Chair” means the Chairperson of the Interagency Committee designated under subsection (c)(2);

(2) the term “Commandant” means the Commandant of the Coast Guard;

(3) the term “institution of higher education” means an institution of higher education, as defined in section 1001(a) of title 20;

(4) the term “Interagency Committee” means the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research established under subsection (b);

(5) the term “Under Secretary” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere; and

(6) the term “Vice Chair” means the Vice Chairperson of the Interagency Committee designated under subsection (c)(3).


(b) Establishment of Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research(1) EstablishmentThere is established an Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research.


(2) PurposeThe Interagency Committee shall coordinate a comprehensive program of oil pollution research, technology development, and demonstration among the Federal agencies, in cooperation and coordination with industry, 4-year institutions of higher education and research institutions, State governments, and other nations, as appropriate, and shall foster cost-effective research mechanisms, including the joint funding of research.



(c) Membership(1) CompositionThe Interagency Committee shall be composed of—(A) at least 1 representative of the Coast Guard;

(B) at least 1 representative of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;

(C) at least 1 representative of the Environmental Protection Agency;

(D) at least 1 representative of the Department of the Interior;

(E) at least 1 representative of the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement;

(F) at least 1 representative of the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management;

(G) at least 1 representative of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;

(H) at least 1 representat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2761_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2761_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2761_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2761_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of the Interagency Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties of the Interagency Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2761_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oil pollution research and development program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Oil pollution research and development program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2761_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>International cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) International cooperation In accordance with the research plan submitted under subsection (d), the Interagency Committee shall coordinate and cooperate with other nations and foreign research entities in conducting oil pollution research, development, and demonstration activities, including controlled field tests of oil discharges.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2761_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biennial reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Biennial reports The Chair shall submit to Congress every 2 years on October 30 a report on the activities carried out under this section in the preceding 2 fiscal years, and on activities proposed to be carried out under this section in the current 2 fiscal year period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2761_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding Not to exceed $22,000,000 of amounts in the Fund shall be available annually to carry out this section except for subsection (e)(8). Of such sums— All activities authorized in this section, including subsection (e)(8), are subject to appropriations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>