<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2803"><akn:num>2803</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive Coastal Water Quality Monitoring Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2803. Comprehensive Coastal Water Quality Monitoring Program(a) Authority; joint implementation(1) The Administrator and the Under Secretary, in conjunction with other Federal, State, and local authorities, shall jointly develop and implement a program for the long-term collection, assimilation, and analysis of scientific data designed to measure the environmental quality of the Nation’s coastal ecosystems pursuant to this section. Monitoring conducted pursuant to this section shall be coordinated with relevant monitoring programs conducted by the Administrator, Under Secretary, and other Federal, State, and local authorities.

(2) Primary leadership for the monitoring program activities conducted by the Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to this section shall be located at the Environmental Research Laboratory in Narragansett, Rhode Island.


(b) Program elementsThe Comprehensive Coastal Water Quality Monitoring Program shall include, but not be limited to—(1) identification and analysis of the status of environmental quality in the Nation’s coastal ecosystems, including but not limited to, assessment of—(A) ambient water quality, including contaminant levels in relation to criteria and standards issued pursuant to title III or 11 So in original. Probably should be “of”. the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. 1311 et seq.);

(B) benthic environmental quality, including analysis of contaminant levels in sediments in relation to criteria and standards issued pursuant to title III of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. 1311 et seq.); and

(C) health and quality of living resources.22 So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.


(2) identification of sources of environmental degradation affecting the Nation’s coastal ecosystems;

(3) assessment of the impact of governmental programs and management strategies and measures designed to abate or prevent the environmental degradation of the Nation’s coastal ecosystems;

(4)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority; joint implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority; joint implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program elements The Comprehensive Coastal Water Quality Monitoring Program shall include, but not be limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring guidelines and protocols</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Monitoring guidelines and protocols</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intensive coastal water quality monitoring programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Intensive coastal water quality monitoring programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive Implementation Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Comprehensive Implementation Strategy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>