<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2902"><akn:num>2902</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2902. Definitions
In this chapter, the following definitions apply:(1) CouncilThe term “Council” means the Estuary Habitat Restoration Council established by section 2904 of this title.


(2) EstuaryThe term “estuary” means a part of a river or stream or other body of water that has an unimpaired connection with the open sea and where the sea water is measurably diluted with fresh water derived from land drainage. The term also includes near coastal waters and wetlands of the Great Lakes that are similar in form and function to estuaries, including the area located in the Great Lakes biogeographic region and designated as a National Estuarine Research Reserve under the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.) as of November 7, 2000.


(3) Estuary habitatThe term “estuary habitat” means the physical, biological, and chemical elements associated with an estuary, including the complex of physical and hydrologic features and living organisms within the estuary and associated ecosystems.


(4) Estuary habitat restoration activity(A) In generalThe term “estuary habitat restoration activity” means an activity that results in improving degraded estuaries or estuary habitat or creating estuary habitat (including both physical and functional restoration), with the goal of attaining a self-sustaining system integrated into the surrounding landscape.


(B) Included activitiesThe term “estuary habitat restoration activity” includes—(i) the reestablishment of chemical, physical, hydrologic, and biological features and components associated with an estuary;

(ii) except as provided in subparagraph (C), the cleanup of pollution for the benefit of estuary habitat;

(iii) the control of nonnative and invasive species in the estuary;

(iv) the reintroduction of species native to the estuary, including through such means as planting or promoting natural succession;

(v) the construction of reefs to promote fish and shellfish production and to provide estuary habit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Council The term “Council” means the Estuary Habitat Restoration Council established by section 2904 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estuary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Estuary The term “estuary” means a part of a river or stream or other body of water that has an unimpaired connection with the open sea and where the sea water is measurably diluted with fresh water derived from land drainage. The term also includes near coastal waters and wetlands of the Great Lakes that are similar in form and function to estuaries, including the area located in the Great Lakes biogeographic region and designated as a National Estuarine Research Reserve under the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.) as of November 7, 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estuary habitat</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Estuary habitat The term “estuary habitat” means the physical, biological, and chemical elements associated with an estuary, including the complex of physical and hydrologic features and living organisms within the estuary and associated ecosystems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estuary habitat restoration activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Estuary habitat restoration activity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estuary habitat restoration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Estuary habitat restoration project The term “estuary habitat restoration project” means a project to carry out an estuary habitat restoration activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estuary habitat restoration plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Estuary habitat restoration plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given such term by section 5304 of title 25.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Non-Federal interest The term “non-Federal interest” means a State, a political subdivision of a State, an Indian tribe, a regional or interstate agency, or, as provided in section 2903(f)(2) of this title, a nongovernmental organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Army.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) State The term “State” means the States of Alabama, Alaska, California, Connecticut, Delaware, Florida, Georgia, Hawaii, Illinois, Indiana, Louisiana, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Michigan, Minnesota, Mississippi, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, North Carolina, Ohio, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, South Carolina, Texas, Virginia, Washington, and Wisconsin, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and Guam.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>