<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/2905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2905"><akn:num>2905</akn:num><akn:heading>Estuary habitat restoration strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2905. Estuary habitat restoration strategy(a) In generalNot later than 1 year after November 7, 2000, the Council, 11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. shall develop an estuary habitat restoration strategy designed to ensure a comprehensive approach to maximize benefits derived from estuary habitat restoration projects and to foster the coordination of Federal and non-Federal activities related to restoration of estuary habitat.


(b) GoalThe goal of the strategy shall be the restoration of 1,000,000 acres of estuary habitat by the year 2010.


(c) Integration of estuary habitat restoration plans, programs, and partnershipsIn developing the estuary habitat restoration strategy, the Council shall—(1) conduct a review of estuary management or habitat restoration plans and Federal programs established under other laws that authorize funding for estuary habitat restoration activities; and

(2) ensure that the estuary habitat restoration strategy is developed in a manner that is consistent with the estuary management or habitat restoration plans.


(d) Elements of the strategyThe estuary habitat restoration strategy shall include proposals, methods, and guidance on—(1) maximizing the incentives for the creation of new public-private partnerships to carry out estuary habitat restoration projects and the use of Federal resources to encourage increased private sector involvement in estuary habitat restoration activities;

(2) ensuring that the estuary habitat restoration strategy will be implemented in a manner that is consistent with the estuary management or habitat restoration plans;

(3) promoting estuary habitat restoration projects to—(A) provide healthy ecosystems in order to support—(i) wildlife, including endangered and threatened species, migratory birds, and resident species of an estuary watershed; and

(ii) fish and shellfish, including commercial and recreational fisheries;


(B) improve surface and ground water quality and quantity, and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 1 year after November 7, 2000, the Council, 11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. shall develop an estuary habitat restoration strategy designed to ensure a comprehensive approach to maximize benefits derived from estuary habitat restoration projects and to foster the coordination of Federal and non-Federal activities related to restoration of estuary habitat.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Goal The goal of the strategy shall be the restoration of 1,000,000 acres of estuary habitat by the year 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration of estuary habitat restoration plans, programs, and partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Integration of estuary habitat restoration plans, programs, and partnerships In developing the estuary habitat restoration strategy, the Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of the strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Elements of the strategy The estuary habitat restoration strategy shall include proposals, methods, and guidance on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public review and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Public review and comment Before the Council adopts a final or revised estuary habitat restoration strategy, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a draft of the estuary habitat restoration strategy and provide an opportunity for public review and comment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Periodic revision Using data and information developed through project monitoring and management, and other relevant information, the Council may periodically review and update, as necessary, the estuary habitat restoration strategy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>