<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3008" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3008/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3008/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3008"><akn:num>3008</akn:num><akn:heading>Aviation accession training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3008. Aviation accession training programs(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.


(2) Member of the programThe term “member of the program” means a student who is enrolled in the program.


(3) ProgramThe term “program” means an aviation accession training program of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration established pursuant to subsection (b).



(b) Aviation accession training programs(1) Establishment authorizedThe Administrator, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, shall establish and maintain one or more aviation accession training programs for the commissioned officer corps of the Administration at institutions described in paragraph (2).


(2) Institutions describedAn institution described in this paragraph is an educational institution—(A) that requests to enter into an agreement with the Administrator providing for the establishment of the program at the institution;

(B) that has, as a part of its curriculum, a four-year baccalaureate program of professional flight and piloting instruction that is accredited by the Aviation Accreditation Board International;

(C) that is located in a geographic area that—(i) experiences a wide variation in climate-related activity, including frequent high winds, convective activity (including tornadoes), periods of low visibility, heat, and snow and ice episodes, to provide opportunities for pilots to demonstrate skill in all weather conditions compatible with future encounters during their service in the commissioned officer corps of the Administration; and

(ii) has a climate that can accommodate both primary and advanced flight training activity at least 75 percent of the year; and


(D) at which the Administrator determines that—(i) there will be at least one student enrolled in the program; and

(ii) the provisions of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3008_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3008_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aviation accession training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Aviation accession training programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3008_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3008_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance for qualified members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Financial assistance for qualified members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3008_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment of unearned portion of financial assistance when conditions of payment not met</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repayment of unearned portion of financial assistance when conditions of payment not met</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>