<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3021"><akn:num>3021</akn:num><akn:heading>Original appointments and reappointments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3021. Original appointments and reappointments(a) Original appointments(1) Grades(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), an original appointment of an officer may be made in such grades as may be appropriate for—(i) the qualification, experience, and length of service of the appointee; and

(ii) the commissioned officer corps of the Administration.


(B) Appointment of officer candidates(i) Limitation on gradeAn original appointment of an officer candidate, upon graduation from the basic officer training program of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, may not be made in any other grade than ensign.


(ii) RankOfficer candidates receiving appointments as ensigns upon graduation from the basic officer training program shall take rank according to their proficiency as shown by the order of their merit at date of graduation.




(2) Source of appointmentsAn original appointment may be made from among the following:(A) Graduates of the basic officer training program of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration.

(B) Subject to the approval of the Secretary of Defense, graduates of the military service academies of the United States who otherwise meet the academic standards for enrollment in the training program described in subparagraph (A).

(C) Graduates of the State maritime academies who—(i) otherwise meet the academic standards for enrollment in the training program described in subparagraph (A);

(ii) completed at least three years of regimented training while at a State maritime academy; and

(iii) obtained an unlimited tonnage or unlimited horsepower Merchant Mariner Credential from the United States Coast Guard.


(D) Licensed officers of the United States merchant marine who have served two or more years aboard a vessel of the United States in the capacity of a licensed officer, who otherwise meet the academic standards for enrollment in the training program described in subparagraph (A).


(3) DefinitionsIn this subs</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Original appointments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Original appointments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reappointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reappointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualifications An appointment under subsection (a) or (b) may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of precedence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Order of precedence Appointees under this section shall take precedence in the grade to which appointed in accordance with the dates of their commissions as commissioned officers in such grade. The order of precedence of appointees whose dates of commission are the same shall be determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inter-service transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Inter-service transfers For inter-service transfers (as described in Department of Defense Directive 1300.4 (dated December 27, 2006)) the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>