<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3031" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3031/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3031/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3031"><akn:num>3031</akn:num><akn:heading>Pay and allowances; date of acceptance of promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3031. Pay and allowances; date of acceptance of promotion(a) Acceptance and date of promotionAn officer of the commissioned corps who is promoted to a higher grade—(1) is deemed for all purposes to have accepted the promotion upon the date the promotion is made by the President, unless the officer expressly declines the promotion; and

(2) shall receive the pay and allowances of the higher grade from that date unless the officer is entitled under another provision of law to receive the pay and allowances of the higher grade from an earlier date.


(b) Oath of officeAn officer who subscribed to the oath of office required by section 3331 of title 5 shall not be required to renew such oath or to take a new oath upon promotion to a higher grade, if the service of the officer after the taking of such oath is continuous.


(Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 231, Dec. 19, 2002, 116 Stat. 3087.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Provisions similar to this section are contained in section 854a–2 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3031_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance and date of promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Acceptance and date of promotion An officer of the commissioned corps who is promoted to a higher grade—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3031_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oath of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Oath of office An officer who subscribed to the oath of office required by section 3331 of title 5 shall not be required to renew such oath or to take a new oath upon promotion to a higher grade, if the service of the officer after the taking of such oath is continuous.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>