<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3079" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3079/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3079/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3079"><akn:num>3079</akn:num><akn:heading>Student pre-commissioning education assistance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3079. Student pre-commissioning education assistance program(a) Authority to provide financial assistanceFor the purpose of maintaining adequate numbers of officers of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration on active duty, the Secretary may provide financial assistance to a person described in subsection (b) for expenses of the person while the person is pursuing on a full-time basis at an accredited educational institution (as determined by the Secretary of Education) a program of education approved by the Secretary that leads to—(1) a baccalaureate degree in not more than five academic years; or

(2) a postbaccalaureate degree.


(b) Eligible persons(1) In generalA person is eligible to obtain financial assistance under subsection (a) if the person—(A) is enrolled on a full-time basis in a program of education referred to in subsection (a) at any educational institution described in such subsection;

(B) meets all of the requirements for acceptance into the commissioned officer corps of the Administration except for the completion of a baccalaureate degree; and

(C) enters into a written agreement with the Secretary described in paragraph (2).


(2) AgreementA written agreement referred to in paragraph (1)(C) is an agreement between the person and the Secretary in which the person—(A) agrees to accept an appointment as an officer, if tendered; and

(B) upon completion of the person’s educational program, agrees to serve on active duty, immediately after appointment, for—(i) up to three years if the person received less than three years of assistance; and

(ii) up to five years if the person received at least three years of assistance.




(c) Qualifying expensesExpenses for which financial assistance may be provided under subsection (a) are the following:(1) Tuition and fees charged by the educational institution involved.

(2) The cost of educational materials.

(3) In the case of a program of education leading to a baccalaureate degree, laborator</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to provide financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to provide financial assistance For the purpose of maintaining adequate numbers of officers of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration on active duty, the Secretary may provide financial assistance to a person described in subsection (b) for expenses of the person while the person is pursuing on a full-time basis at an accredited educational institution (as determined by the Secretary of Education) a program of education approved by the Secretary that leads to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualifying expenses Expenses for which financial assistance may be provided under subsection (a) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on amount The Secretary shall prescribe the amount of financial assistance provided to a person under subsection (a), which may not exceed the amount specified in section 2173(e)(2) of title 10, for each year of obligated service that a person agrees to serve in an agreement described in subsection (b)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duration of assistance Financial assistance may be provided to a person under subsection (a) for not more than five consecutive academic years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsistence allowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Subsistence allowance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial clothing allowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Initial clothing allowance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Termination of financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Secretary may prescribe such regulations and orders as the Secretary considers appropriate to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concurrent completion of service obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Concurrent completion of service obligations A service obligation under this section may be completed concurrently with a service obligation under section 3006 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>