<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3079b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3079b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3079b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3079b"><akn:num>3079b</akn:num><akn:heading>Shore leave for professional mariners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3079b. Shore leave for professional mariners(a) In generalThe Under Secretary may prescribe regulations relating to shore leave for professional mariners without regard to the requirements of section 6305 of title 5.


(b) RequirementsThe regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall—(1) require that a professional mariner serving aboard an ocean-going vessel be granted a leave of absence of 4 days per pay period; and

(2) provide that a professional mariner serving in a temporary promotion position aboard a vessel may be paid the difference between such mariner’s temporary and permanent rates of pay for leave accrued while serving in the temporary promotion position.


(c) Professional mariner definedIn this section, the term “professional mariner” means an individual employed on a vessel of the Administration who has the necessary expertise to serve in the engineering, deck, steward, electronic technician, or survey department.


(Pub. L. 107–372, title II, § 269B, as added Pub. L. 117–263, div. K, title CXVII, § 11706(a), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 4157.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Under Secretary may prescribe regulations relating to shore leave for professional mariners without regard to the requirements of section 6305 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3079b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Professional mariner defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Professional mariner defined In this section, the term “professional mariner” means an individual employed on a vessel of the Administration who has the necessary expertise to serve in the engineering, deck, steward, electronic technician, or survey department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>