<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3302"><akn:num>3302</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee on Levee Safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3302. Committee on Levee Safety(a) EstablishmentThere is established a committee to be known as the “Committee on Levee Safety”.


(b) MembershipThe committee shall be composed of 16 members as follows:(1) Nonvoting members.—The following 2 nonvoting members:(A) The Secretary (or a designee of the Secretary).

(B) The Administrator (or a designee of the Administrator).


(2) The following 14 voting members appointed by the Secretary:(A) Eight representatives of State levee safety agencies, one from each of the eight civil works divisions of the Corps of Engineers.

(B) Two representatives of the private sector who have expertise in levee safety.

(C) Two representatives of local and regional governmental agencies who have expertise in levee safety.

(D) Two representatives of Indian tribes who have expertise in levee safety.



(c) Administration(1) Terms of voting members(A) In generalA voting member of the committee shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, except that, of the members first appointed—(i) 5 shall be appointed for a term of 1 year;

(ii) 5 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and

(iii) 4 shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.


(B) ReappointmentA voting member of the committee may be reappointed to the committee, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.


(C) VacanciesA vacancy on the committee shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.



(2) Chairperson(A) In generalThe voting members of the committee shall appoint a chairperson from among the voting members of the committee.


(B) TermThe chairperson shall serve a term of not more than 2 years.




(d) Standing committees(1) In generalThe committee may establish standing committees comprised of volunteers from all levels of government and the private sector, to advise the committee regarding specific levee safety issues, including participating programs, technical issues, public education and awareness, and safety and the environment.


(2) Membershi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established a committee to be known as the “Committee on Levee Safety”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The committee shall be composed of 16 members as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standing committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Standing committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duties and powers The committee—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Task force coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Task force coordination The committee shall, to the maximum extent practicable, coordinate the activities of the committee with the Federal Interagency Floodplain Management Task Force.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Applicability of chapter 10 of title 5 Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>