<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3303a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3303a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3303a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3303a"><akn:num>3303a</akn:num><akn:heading>Levee safety initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3303a. Levee safety initiative(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, shall carry out a levee safety initiative.


(b) ManagementThe Secretary shall appoint—(1) an administrator of the levee safety initiative; and

(2) such staff as are necessary to implement the initiative.


(c) Levee safety guidelines(1) EstablishmentNot later than 1 year after December 16, 2016, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator and in coordination with State, regional, local, and tribal governments and organizations with expertise in levee safety, shall establish a set of voluntary, comprehensive, national levee safety guidelines that—(A) are available for common, uniform use by all Federal, State, regional, local, and tribal agencies;

(B) incorporate policies, procedures, standards, and criteria for a range of levee types, canal structures, and related facilities and features; and

(C) provide for adaptation to local, regional, or watershed conditions.


(2) RequirementThe policies, procedures, standards, and criteria under paragraph (1)(B) shall be developed taking into consideration the levee hazard potential classification system established under subsection (d).


(3) IncorporationThe guidelines shall address, to the maximum extent practicable—(A) the activities and practices carried out by State, regional, local, and tribal governments and the private sector to safely build, regulate, operate, and maintain levees; and

(B) Federal activities that facilitate State, regional, or tribal efforts to develop and implement effective State, regional, or tribal programs for the safety of levees, including levee inspection, levee rehabilitation, locally developed floodplain management, and public education and training programs.


(4) Consideration by Federal agenciesTo the maximum extent practicable, all Federal agencies shall consider the levee safety guidelines in carrying out activities relating to the management of levees.


(5) Public com</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, shall carry out a levee safety initiative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management The Secretary shall appoint—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Levee safety guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Levee safety guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazard potential classification system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hazard potential classification system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance and materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance and materials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public education and awareness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public education and awareness</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>State, regional, and tribal levee safety program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) State, regional, and tribal levee safety program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Levee rehabilitation assistance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Levee rehabilitation assistance program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effect of section Nothing in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>