<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3303b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3303b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3303b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3303b"><akn:num>3303b</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3303b. Reports(a) State of levees(1) In generalNot later than 1 year after December 16, 2016, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary in coordination with the committee, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report describing the state of levees in the United States and the effectiveness of the levee safety initiative, including—(A) progress achieved in implementing the levee safety initiative;

(B) State, regional, and tribal participation in the levee safety initiative;

(C) recommendations to improve coordination of levee safety, floodplain management, and environmental protection concerns, including—(i) identifying and evaluating opportunities to coordinate public safety, floodplain management, and environmental protection activities relating to levees; and

(ii) evaluating opportunities to coordinate environmental permitting processes for operation and maintenance activities at existing levee projects in compliance with all applicable laws; and


(D) any recommendations for legislation and other congressional actions necessary to ensure national levee safety.


(2) InclusionEach report under paragraph (1) shall include a report of the committee that describes the independent recommendations of the committee for the implementation of the levee safety initiative.



(b) National dam and levee safety programNot later than 3 years after June 10, 2014, to the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary and the Administrator, in coordination with the committee, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that includes recommendations regarding the advisability and feasibility of, and potential approaches for, establishing a joint national dam and levee safety program.


(c) Alignment of Federal programs relating to leveesNot later than 2 years after December 16, 2016, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on opportunities for alignment of Federal programs to provide incentives to State, regi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State of levees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State of levees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National dam and levee safety program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National dam and levee safety program Not later than 3 years after June 10, 2014, to the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary and the Administrator, in coordination with the committee, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that includes recommendations regarding the advisability and feasibility of, and potential approaches for, establishing a joint national dam and levee safety program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alignment of Federal programs relating to levees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Alignment of Federal programs relating to levees Not later than 2 years after December 16, 2016, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on opportunities for alignment of Federal programs to provide incentives to State, regional, tribal, and local governments and individuals and entities—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3303b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for certain levee engineering projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Liability for certain levee engineering projects Not later than 1 year after December 16, 2016, the Secretary shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that includes recommendations that identify and address any legal liability associated with levee engineering projects that prevent—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>