<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3307"><akn:num>3307</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of Corps of Engineers levees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3307. Assessment of Corps of Engineers levees(a) In generalThe Secretary shall periodically conduct assessments of federally authorized levees under the jurisdiction of the Corps of Engineers, to evaluate the potential Federal interest in the modification (including realignment or incorporation of natural features and nature-based features, as such terms are defined in section 2289a(a) of this title) of levee systems to meet one or more of the following objectives:(1) Increasing the flood risk reduction benefits of such systems.

(2) Achieving greater flood resiliency.

(3) Restoring hydrological and ecological connections with adjacent floodplains that achieve greater environmental benefits without undermining flood risk reduction or flood resiliency for levee-protected communities.


(b) Levees operated by non-Federal interestsThe Secretary shall carry out an assessment under subsection (a) for a federally authorized levee system operated by a non-Federal interest only if the non-Federal interest—(1) requests the assessment; and

(2) agrees to provide 50 percent of the cost of the assessment.


(c) Assessments(1) ConsiderationsIn conducting an assessment under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider and identify, with respect to each levee system—(A) an estimate of the number of structures and population at risk and protected by the levee system that would be adversely impacted if the levee system fails or water levels exceed the height of any levee segment within the levee system (which may be the applicable estimate included in the levee database established under section 3303 of this title, if available);

(B) the number of times the non-Federal interest has received emergency flood-fighting or repair assistance under section 701n of this title for the levee system, and the total expenditures on postflood repairs over the life of the levee system;

(C) the functionality of the levee system with regard to higher precipitation levels, including due to chan</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall periodically conduct assessments of federally authorized levees under the jurisdiction of the Corps of Engineers, to evaluate the potential Federal interest in the modification (including realignment or incorporation of natural features and nature-based features, as such terms are defined in section 2289a(a) of this title) of levee systems to meet one or more of the following objectives:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Levees operated by non-Federal interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Levees operated by non-Federal interests The Secretary shall carry out an assessment under subsection (a) for a federally authorized levee system operated by a non-Federal interest only if the non-Federal interest—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flood plain management services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Flood plain management services In conducting an assessment under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider information on floods and flood damages compiled under section 709a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Incorporation of information The Secretary shall include in the levee database established under section 3303 of this title the information included in each report submitted under subsection (e), and make such information publicly available (including on a publicly available website).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Levee system defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Levee system defined In this section, the term “levee system” has the meaning given that term in section 3301(9) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>