<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3407" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3407/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3407/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3407"><akn:num>3407</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3407. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) CharacterizationThe terms “characterization”, “characterize”, and “characterizing” mean activities that provide comprehensive data and interpretations for a specific area of interest of the sea floor, sub-bottom, water column, or hydrologic features, such as water masses and currents, in direct support of specific research, environmental protection, resource management, policymaking, or applied mission objectives.


(2) ExplorationThe term 11 So in original. Probably should be “terms” and “mean”. “exploration”, “explore”, and “exploring” means 1 activities that provide—(A) a multidisciplinary view of an unknown or poorly understood area of the sea floor, sub-bottom, or water column; and

(B) an initial assessment of the physical, chemical, geological, biological, archaeological, or other characteristics of such an area.


(3) MappingThe terms “map” and “mapping” mean activities that provide comprehensive data and information needed to understand sea floor characteristics, including depth, topography, bottom type, sediment composition and distribution, underlying geologic structure, and benthic flora and fauna.


(Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12007, as added Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10305(h), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 3974.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3407_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Characterization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Characterization The terms “characterization”, “characterize”, and “characterizing” mean activities that provide comprehensive data and interpretations for a specific area of interest of the sea floor, sub-bottom, water column, or hydrologic features, such as water masses and currents, in direct support of specific research, environmental protection, resource management, policymaking, or applied mission objectives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3407_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exploration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Exploration The term 11 So in original. Probably should be “terms” and “mean”. “exploration”, “explore”, and “exploring” means 1 activities that provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3407_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mapping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Mapping The terms “map” and “mapping” mean activities that provide comprehensive data and information needed to understand sea floor characteristics, including depth, topography, bottom type, sediment composition and distribution, underlying geologic structure, and benthic flora and fauna.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>