<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3408" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3408/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3408/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3408"><akn:num>3408</akn:num><akn:heading>National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3408. National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council(a) EstablishmentThe President shall establish a council, to be known as the “National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council” (in this section referred to as the “Council”).


(b) PurposeThe Council shall—(1) update national priorities for ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization; and

(2) coordinate and facilitate activities to advance those priorities.


(c) ReportingThe Council shall report to the Ocean Science and Technology Subcommittee of the Ocean Policy Committee established under section 8932(c) of title 10.


(d) MembershipThe Council shall be composed of senior-level representatives from the appropriate Federal agencies.


(e) Co-ChairsThe Council shall be co-chaired by—(1) two senior-level representatives from the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and

(2) one senior-level representative from the Department of the Interior.


(f) DutiesThe Council shall—(1) set national ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization priorities and strategies;

(2) cultivate and facilitate transparent and sustained partnerships among Federal and State agencies, Indian Tribes, private industry, academia, and nongovernmental organizations to conduct ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization activities and related technology development;

(3) coordinate improved processes for data compilation, management, access, synthesis, and visualization with respect to ocean mapping, exploration, and characterization, with a focus on building on existing ocean data management systems and with appropriate safeguards on the public accessibility of data to protect national security equities, as appropriate;

(4) encourage education, workforce training, and public engagement activities that—(A) advance interdisciplinary principles that contribute to ocean mapping, exploration, research, and characterization;

(B) improve public engagement with and understanding of ocea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The President shall establish a council, to be known as the “National Ocean Mapping, Exploration, and Characterization Council” (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting The Council shall report to the Ocean Science and Technology Subcommittee of the Ocean Policy Committee established under section 8932(c) of title 10.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Membership The Council shall be composed of senior-level representatives from the appropriate Federal agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Co-Chairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Co-Chairs The Council shall be co-chaired by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Duties The Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Working Group on Ocean Exploration and Characterization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Interagency Working Group on Ocean Exploration and Characterization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Oversight The Council shall oversee—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3408_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Briefings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Briefings Not later than 1 year after December 23, 2022, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Council shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>