<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3504a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3504a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3504a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3504a"><akn:num>3504a</akn:num><akn:heading>Ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding opportunity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3504a. Ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding opportunity(a) In generalNot later than one year after the date of the enactment of the National Ocean Exploration Act,11 See References in Text note below. the Administrator shall develop an integrated ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding match opportunity, to be known as the “Brennan Ocean Mapping Fund” in memory of Rear Admiral Richard T. Brennan, within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with Federal, State, Tribal, local, nonprofit, private industry, or academic partners in order to increase the coordinated acquisition, processing, stewardship, and archival of new ocean and coastal mapping data in United States waters.


(b) RulesThe Administrator shall develop administrative and procedural rules for the ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding match opportunity developed under subsection (a), to include—(1) specific and detailed criteria that must be addressed by an applicant, such as geographic overlap with preestablished priorities, number and type of project partners, benefit to the applicant, coordination with other funding opportunities, and benefit to the public;

(2) determination of the appropriate funding match amounts and mechanisms to use, such as grants, agreements, or contracts; and

(3) other funding award criteria as are necessary or appropriate to ensure that evaluations of proposals and decisions to award funding under this section are based on objective standards applied fairly and equitably to those proposals.


(c) Geospatial services and contract vehiclesThe ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding match opportunity developed under subsection (a) shall leverage Federal expertise and capacities for geospatial services and Federal geospatial contract vehicles using the private sector for acquisition efficiencies.


(Pub. L. 111–11, title XII, § 12206, as added Pub. L. 117–263, div. J, title CIII, § 10307(e)(2), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 3978.)

Editorial Notes

Referen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3504a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the National Ocean Exploration Act,11 See References in Text note below. the Administrator shall develop an integrated ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding match opportunity, to be known as the “Brennan Ocean Mapping Fund” in memory of Rear Admiral Richard T. Brennan, within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration with Federal, State, Tribal, local, nonprofit, private industry, or academic partners in order to increase the coordinated acquisition, processing, stewardship, and archival of new ocean and coastal mapping data in United States waters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3504a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rules The Administrator shall develop administrative and procedural rules for the ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding match opportunity developed under subsection (a), to include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3504a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geospatial services and contract vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Geospatial services and contract vehicles The ocean and coastal mapping Federal funding match opportunity developed under subsection (a) shall leverage Federal expertise and capacities for geospatial services and Federal geospatial contract vehicles using the private sector for acquisition efficiencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>