<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3822" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3822/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3822/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3822"><akn:num>3822</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3822. Declaration(a) RequirementsOn entry into force of the Convention for the United States, a vessel of at least 24 meters in length, but less than 400 gross tons engaged on an international voyage (except fixed or floating platforms, FSUs, and FPSOs) must carry a declaration described in subsection (b) that is signed by the owner or owner’s authorized agent. That declaration shall be accompanied by appropriate documentation, such as a paint receipt or a contractor invoice, or contain an appropriate endorsement.


(b) Content of declarationThe declaration must contain a clear statement that the antifouling system on the vessel complies with the Convention. The Secretary may prescribe the form and other requirements of the declaration.


(Pub. L. 111–281, title X, § 1022, Oct. 15, 2010, 124 Stat. 3026.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3822_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements On entry into force of the Convention for the United States, a vessel of at least 24 meters in length, but less than 400 gross tons engaged on an international voyage (except fixed or floating platforms, FSUs, and FPSOs) must carry a declaration described in subsection (b) that is signed by the owner or owner’s authorized agent. That declaration shall be accompanied by appropriate documentation, such as a paint receipt or a contractor invoice, or contain an appropriate endorsement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3822_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content of declaration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Content of declaration The declaration must contain a clear statement that the antifouling system on the vessel complies with the Convention. The Secretary may prescribe the form and other requirements of the declaration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>