<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3852" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3852/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3852/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3852"><akn:num>3852</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3852. Civil enforcement(a) Civil penalty(1) In generalAny person who is found by the Secretary or the Administrator, as appropriate, after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, to have—(A) violated the Convention, this chapter, or any regulation prescribed under this chapter, is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $37,500 for each violation; or

(B) made a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation in any matter in which a statement or representation is required to be made to the Secretary under the Convention, this chapter, or any regulations prescribed under this chapter, is liable to the United States for a civil penalty of not more than $50,000 for each such statement or representation.


(2) Relationship to other lawThis subsection shall not limit or affect the authority of the Government under section 1001 of title 18.



(b) Assessment of penaltyThe amount of the civil penalty shall be assessed by the Secretary or Administrator, as appropriate, by written notice.


(c) Limitation for recreational vesselA civil penalty imposed under subsection (a) against the owner or operator of a recreational vessel, as that term is defined in section 2101 of title 46, for a violation of the Convention, this chapter, or any regulation prescribed under this chapter involving that recreational vessel, may not exceed $5,000 for each violation.


(d) Determination of penaltyFor purposes of penalties under this section, each day of a continuing violation constitutes a separate violation. In determining the amount of the penalty, the Secretary or Administrator shall take into account the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the prohibited acts committed and, with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of prior offenses, the economic impact of the penalty on the violator, the economic benefit to the violator and other matters as justice may require.


(e) RewardAn amount equal to not mo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3852_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Civil penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3852_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assessment of penalty The amount of the civil penalty shall be assessed by the Secretary or Administrator, as appropriate, by written notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3852_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation for recreational vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation for recreational vessel A civil penalty imposed under subsection (a) against the owner or operator of a recreational vessel, as that term is defined in section 2101 of title 46, for a violation of the Convention, this chapter, or any regulation prescribed under this chapter involving that recreational vessel, may not exceed $5,000 for each violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3852_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Determination of penalty For purposes of penalties under this section, each day of a continuing violation constitutes a separate violation. In determining the amount of the penalty, the Secretary or Administrator shall take into account the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the prohibited acts committed and, with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of prior offenses, the economic impact of the penalty on the violator, the economic benefit to the violator and other matters as justice may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3852_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reward</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reward An amount equal to not more than one-half of any civil penalty assessed by the Secretary or Administrator under this section may, subject to the availability of appropriations, be paid by the Secretary or Administrator, respectively, to any person who provided information that led to the assessment or imposition of the penalty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3852_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral to Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Referral to Attorney General If any person fails to pay a civil penalty assessed under this section after it has become final, or comply with an order issued under this chapter, the Secretary or Administrator, as appropriate, may refer the matter to the Attorney General of the United States for collection in any appropriate district court of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3852_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise, modification, or remission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compromise, modification, or remission Before referring any civil penalty that is subject to assessment or has been assessed under this section to the Attorney General, the Secretary, or Administrator, as appropriate, may compromise, modify, or remit, with or without conditions, the civil penalty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3852_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonpayment penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Nonpayment penalty Any person who fails to pay on a timely basis a civil penalty assessed under this section shall also be liable to the United States for interest on the penalty at an annual rate equal to 11 percent compounded quarterly, attorney fees and costs for collection proceedings, and a quarterly nonpayment penalty for each quarter during which such failure to pay persists. That nonpayment penalty shall be in an amount equal to 20 percent of the aggregate amount of that person’s penalties and nonpayment penalties that are unpaid as of the beginning of that quarter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>