<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/3907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3907"><akn:num>3907</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of eligibility and project selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3907. Determination of eligibility and project selection(a) Eligibility requirementsTo be eligible to receive financial assistance under this chapter, a project shall meet the following criteria, as determined by the Secretary or Administrator, as applicable:(1) Creditworthiness(A) In generalThe project and obligor shall be creditworthy, which shall be determined by the Secretary or the Administrator, as applicable.


(B) ConsiderationsIn determining the creditworthiness of a project and obligor, the Secretary or the Administrator, as applicable, shall take into consideration relevant factors, including—(i) the terms, conditions, financial structure, and security features of the proposed financing;

(ii) the dedicated revenue sources that will secure or fund the project obligations;

(iii) the financial assumptions upon which the project is based; and

(iv) the financial soundness and credit history of the obligor.


(C) Security featuresThe Secretary or the Administrator, as applicable, shall ensure that any financing for the project has appropriate security features, such as a rate covenant, supporting the project obligations to ensure repayment.


(D) Rating opinion letters(i) Preliminary rating opinion letterThe Secretary or the Administrator, as applicable, shall require each project applicant to provide, at the time of application, a preliminary rating opinion letter from at least 1 rating agency indicating that the senior obligations of the project (which may be the Federal credit instrument) have the potential to achieve an investment-grade rating.


(ii) Final rating opinion lettersThe Secretary or the Administrator, as applicable, shall require each project applicant to provide, prior to final acceptance and financing of the project, a final rating opinion letter from at least 1 rating agency indicating that the senior obligations of the project have an investment-grade rating.



(E) Special rule for certain combined projectsThe Administrator shall deve</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligibility requirements To be eligible to receive financial assistance under this chapter, a project shall meet the following criteria, as determined by the Secretary or Administrator, as applicable:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal requirements Nothing in this section supersedes the applicability of other requirements of Federal law (including regulations).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>