<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4002" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4002/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4002/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4002"><akn:num>4002</akn:num><akn:heading>National harmful algal bloom and hypoxia program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4002. National harmful algal bloom and hypoxia program(a) EstablishmentNot later than 1 year after June 30, 2014, the Under Secretary, acting through the Task Force, shall maintain and enhance a national harmful algal bloom and hypoxia program, including—(1) a statement of objectives, including understanding, detecting, predicting, controlling, mitigating, and responding to marine and freshwater harmful algal bloom and hypoxia events; and

(2) the comprehensive research plan and action strategy under section 4003 of this title.


(b) Periodic revisionThe Task Force shall periodically review and revise the Program, as necessary.


(c) Task Force functionsThe Task Force shall—(1) coordinate interagency review of the objectives and activities of the Program;

(2) expedite the interagency review process by ensuring timely review and dispersal of required reports and assessments under this chapter;

(3) support the implementation of the Action Strategy, including the coordination and integration of the research of all Federal programs, including ocean and Great Lakes science and management programs and centers, that address the chemical, biological, and physical components of marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;

(4) support the development of institutional mechanisms and financial instruments to further the objectives and activities of the Program;

(5) review the Program’s distribution of Federal funding to address the objectives and activities of the Program;

(6) promote the development of new technologies for predicting, monitoring, and mitigating harmful algal bloom and hypoxia conditions; and

(7) establish such interagency working groups as it considers necessary.


(d) Lead Federal agencyExcept as provided in subsection (h), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall have primary responsibility for administering the Program.


(e) Program dutiesIn administering the Program, the Under Secretary shall—(1) promote the Program, in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4002_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Not later than 1 year after June 30, 2014, the Under Secretary, acting through the Task Force, shall maintain and enhance a national harmful algal bloom and hypoxia program, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4002_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Periodic revision The Task Force shall periodically review and revise the Program, as necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4002_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Task Force functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Task Force functions The Task Force shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4002_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lead Federal agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Lead Federal agency Except as provided in subsection (h), the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall have primary responsibility for administering the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4002_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Program duties In administering the Program, the Under Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4002_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration activities The Under Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4002_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cooperative efforts The Under Secretary shall work cooperatively and avoid duplication of effort with other offices, centers, and programs within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, other agencies on the Task Force, and States, tribes, and nongovernmental organizations concerned with marine and freshwater issues to coordinate harmful algal bloom and hypoxia (and related) activities and research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4002_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Freshwater</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Freshwater With respect to the freshwater aspects of the Program, the Administrator, through the Task Force, shall carry out the duties otherwise assigned to the Under Secretary under this section, except the activities described in subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4002_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System The collection of monitoring and observation data under this chapter shall comply with all data standards and protocols developed pursuant to the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009 (33 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.). Such data shall be made available through the system established under that Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>