<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4003" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4003/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4003/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4003"><akn:num>4003</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive research plan and action strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4003. Comprehensive research plan and action strategy(a) In generalNot later than 1 year after June 30, 2014, the Under Secretary, through the Task Force, shall develop and submit to Congress a comprehensive research plan and action strategy to address marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia. The Action Strategy shall identify—(1) the specific activities to be carried out by the Program and the timeline for carrying out those activities;

(2) the roles and responsibilities of each Federal agency in the Task Force in carrying out the activities under paragraph (1); and

(3) the appropriate regions and subregions requiring specific research and activities to address harmful algal blooms and hypoxia.


(b) Regional focusThe regional and subregional parts of the Action Strategy shall identify—(1) regional priorities for ecological, economic, and social research on issues related to the impacts of harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;

(2) research, development, and demonstration activities needed to develop and advance technologies and techniques for minimizing the occurrence of harmful algal blooms and hypoxia and improving capabilities to detect, predict, monitor, control, mitigate, respond to, and remediate harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;

(3) ways to reduce the duration and intensity of harmful algal blooms and hypoxia, including deployment of response technologies in a timely manner;

(4) research and methods to address human health dimensions of harmful algal blooms and hypoxia;

(5) mechanisms, including the potential costs and benefits of those mechanisms, to protect ecosystems that may be or have been affected by harmful algal bloom and hypoxia events;

(6) mechanisms by which data, information, and products may be transferred between the Program and the State, tribal, and local governments and research entities;

(7) communication and information dissemination methods that State, tribal, and local governments may undertake to educate and inform </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 1 year after June 30, 2014, the Under Secretary, through the Task Force, shall develop and submit to Congress a comprehensive research plan and action strategy to address marine and freshwater harmful algal blooms and hypoxia. The Action Strategy shall identify—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional focus</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regional focus The regional and subregional parts of the Action Strategy shall identify—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilizing available studies and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Utilizing available studies and information In developing the Action Strategy, the Under Secretary shall utilize existing research, assessments, reports, and program activities, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of the Action Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Development of the Action Strategy In developing the Action Strategy, the Under Secretary shall, as appropriate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Federal Register The Under Secretary shall publish the Action Strategy in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Periodic revision The Under Secretary, in coordination and consultation with the individuals and entities under subsection (d), shall periodically review and revise the Action Strategy prepared under this section, as necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>