<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4008" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4008/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4008/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4008"><akn:num>4008</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4008. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Action StrategyThe term “Action Strategy” means the comprehensive research plan and action strategy established under section 4003 of this title.


(2) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.


(3) Harmful algal bloomThe term “harmful algal bloom” means marine and freshwater phytoplankton that proliferate to high concentrations, resulting in nuisance conditions or harmful impacts on marine and aquatic ecosystems, coastal communities, and human health through the production of toxic compounds or other biological, chemical, and physical impacts of the algae outbreak.


(4) HypoxiaThe term “hypoxia” means a condition where low dissolved oxygen in aquatic systems causes stress or death to resident organisms.


(5) ProgramThe term “Program” means the national harmful algal bloom and hypoxia program established under section 4002 of this title.


(6) StateThe term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, any other territory or possession of the United States, and any Indian tribe.


(7) Task ForceThe term “Task Force” means the Inter-Agency Task Force on Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia under section 4001(a) of this title.


(8) Under SecretaryThe term “Under Secretary” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.


(9) United States coastal watersThe term “United States coastal waters” includes the Great Lakes.


(Pub. L. 105–383, title VI, § 609, formerly § 608, as added Pub. L. 113–124, § 10(a), June 30, 2014, 128 Stat. 1385; renumbered § 609, Pub. L. 117–144, § 2(a)(1), June 16, 2022, 136 Stat. 1266.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 609 of Pub. L. 105–383 was renumbered section 610 and is classified to section 4009 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4008_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Action Strategy The term “Action Strategy” means the comprehensive research plan and action strategy established under section 4003 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4008_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Administrator The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4008_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Harmful algal bloom</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Harmful algal bloom The term “harmful algal bloom” means marine and freshwater phytoplankton that proliferate to high concentrations, resulting in nuisance conditions or harmful impacts on marine and aquatic ecosystems, coastal communities, and human health through the production of toxic compounds or other biological, chemical, and physical impacts of the algae outbreak.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4008_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hypoxia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Hypoxia The term “hypoxia” means a condition where low dissolved oxygen in aquatic systems causes stress or death to resident organisms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4008_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Program The term “Program” means the national harmful algal bloom and hypoxia program established under section 4002 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4008_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) State The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, any other territory or possession of the United States, and any Indian tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4008_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Task Force The term “Task Force” means the Inter-Agency Task Force on Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia under section 4001(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4008_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Under Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Under Secretary The term “Under Secretary” means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4008_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States coastal waters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) United States coastal waters The term “United States coastal waters” includes the Great Lakes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>