<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4218" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4218/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4218/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4218"><akn:num>4218</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4218. Authorization of appropriations(a) Authorization of appropriations(1) In generalThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Commerce to carry out this subchapter $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2024.


(2) Use of appropriated fundsSubject to paragraph (3), amounts made available under paragraph (1) shall be provided to the Foundation to match contributions (whether in currency, services, or property) made to the Foundation, or to a recipient of a grant provided by the Foundation, by private persons and State and local government agencies.


(3) Prohibition on use for administrative expenses(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), no Federal funds made available under paragraph (1) may be used by the Foundation for administrative expenses of the Foundation, including for salaries, travel and transportation expenses, and other overhead expenses.


(B) ExceptionThe Secretary may allow the use of Federal funds made available under paragraph (1) to pay for salaries during the 18-month period beginning on December 18, 2020.




(b) Additional authorization(1) In generalIn addition to the amounts made available under subsection (a), the Foundation may accept Federal funds from a Federal agency under any other Federal law for use by the Foundation to further the assessment, prevention, reduction, and removal of marine debris in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter.


(2) Use of funds accepted from Federal agenciesFederal funds provided to the Foundation under paragraph (1) shall be used by the Foundation for matching, in whole or in part, contributions (whether in currency, services, or property) made to the Foundation by private persons and State and local government agencies.



(c) Prohibition on use of grant amounts for litigation and lobbying expensesAmounts provided as a grant by the Foundation shall not be used for—(1) any expense related to litigation consistent with Federal-wide cost principles;</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4218_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4218_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4218_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of grant amounts for litigation and lobbying expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition on use of grant amounts for litigation and lobbying expenses Amounts provided as a grant by the Foundation shall not be used for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>