<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4233" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4233/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/4233/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4233"><akn:num>4233</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement with the Marine Debris Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4233. Agreement with the Marine Debris Foundation(a) In generalThe Secretary may offer to enter into an agreement, which may include a grant or cooperative agreement, under which the Marine Debris Foundation established under title I 11 See References in Text note below. may administer the prize competition.


(b) RequirementsAn agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall comply with the following requirements:(1) DutiesThe Marine Debris Foundation shall—(A) advertise the prize competition;

(B) solicit prize competition participants;

(C) administer funds relating to the prize competition;

(D) receive Federal and non-Federal funds—(i) to administer the prize competition; and

(ii) to award a cash prize;


(E) carry out activities to generate contributions of non-Federal funds to offset, in whole or in part—(i) the administrative costs of the prize competition; and

(ii) the costs of a cash prize;


(F) in the design and award of the prize, consult, as appropriate with experts from—(i) Federal agencies with jurisdiction over the prevention of marine debris or the promotion of innovative materials;

(ii) State agencies with jurisdiction over the prevention of marine debris or the promotion of innovative materials;

(iii) State, regional, or local conservation or post-consumer materials management organizations, the mission of which relates to the prevention of marine debris or the promotion of innovative materials;

(iv) conservation groups, technology companies, research institutions, scientists (including those with expertise in marine environments) institutions of higher education, industry, or individual stakeholders with an interest in the prevention of marine debris or the promotion of innovative materials;

(v) experts in the area of standards development regarding the degradation, breakdown, or recycling of polymers; and

(vi) other relevant experts of the Board’s choosing;


(G) in consultation with, and subject to final approval by, the Secretary, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4233_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may offer to enter into an agreement, which may include a grant or cooperative agreement, under which the Marine Debris Foundation established under title I 11 See References in Text note below. may administer the prize competition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4233_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements An agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall comply with the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>