<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/426l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/426l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/426l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_426l"><akn:num>426l</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of Lake Ontario</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 426l. Protection of Lake Ontario(a) Plan for shoreline protection and beach erosion control; report to CongressThe Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is directed to develop a plan for shoreline protection and beach erosion control along Lake Ontario, and report on such plan to the Congress as soon as practicable. Such report shall include recommendations on measures of protection and proposals for equitable cost sharing, together with recommendations for regulating the level of Lake Ontario to assure maximum protection of the natural environment and to hold shoreline damage to a minimum.


(b) Minimization of damage and erosion to Lake Ontario shorelineUntil the Congress receives and acts upon the report required under subsection (a) of this section, all Federal agencies having responsibilities affecting the level of Lake Ontario shall, consistent with existing authority, make every effort to discharge such responsibilities in a manner so as to minimize damage and erosion to the shoreline of Lake Ontario.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000.


(d) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Lake Ontario Protection Act of 1976.”


(Pub. L. 94–587, § 180, Oct. 22, 1976, 90 Stat. 2939.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan for shoreline protection and beach erosion control; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Plan for shoreline protection and beach erosion control; report to Congress The Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is directed to develop a plan for shoreline protection and beach erosion control along Lake Ontario, and report on such plan to the Congress as soon as practicable. Such report shall include recommendations on measures of protection and proposals for equitable cost sharing, together with recommendations for regulating the level of Lake Ontario to assure maximum protection of the natural environment and to hold shoreline damage to a minimum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimization of damage and erosion to Lake Ontario shoreline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Minimization of damage and erosion to Lake Ontario shoreline Until the Congress receives and acts upon the report required under subsection (a) of this section, all Federal agencies having responsibilities affecting the level of Lake Ontario shall, consistent with existing authority, make every effort to discharge such responsibilities in a manner so as to minimize damage and erosion to the shoreline of Lake Ontario.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426l_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Short title This section may be cited as the “Lake Ontario Protection Act of 1976.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>