<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/426o–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/426o–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/426o–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_426o_2"><akn:num>426o–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Great Lakes navigation and protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 426o–2. Great Lakes navigation and protection(a) Great Lakes navigationUsing available funds, the Secretary shall expedite the operation and maintenance, including dredging, of the navigation features of the Great Lakes and Connecting Channels for the purpose of supporting commercial navigation to authorized project depths.


(b) Great Lakes pilot projectUsing available funds, the Director of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, in coordination with the Secretary, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, and the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, shall carry out a pilot project, on an emergency basis, to control and prevent further spreading of viral hemorrhagic septicemia in the Great Lakes and Connecting Channels.


(c) Great Lakes and Connecting Channels definedIn this section, the term “Great Lakes and Connecting Channels” includes Lakes Superior, Huron, Michigan, Erie, and Ontario, all connecting waters between and among such lakes used for commercial navigation, any navigation features in such lakes or waters that are a Federal operation or maintenance responsibility, and areas of the Saint Lawrence River that are operated or maintained by the Federal Government for commercial navigation.


(Pub. L. 110–114, title V, § 5014, Nov. 8, 2007, 121 Stat. 1195.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

“Secretary” Defined
Secretary means the Secretary of the Army, see section 2 of Pub. L. 110–114, set out as a note under section 2201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426o_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Great Lakes navigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Great Lakes navigation Using available funds, the Secretary shall expedite the operation and maintenance, including dredging, of the navigation features of the Great Lakes and Connecting Channels for the purpose of supporting commercial navigation to authorized project depths.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426o_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Great Lakes pilot project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Great Lakes pilot project Using available funds, the Director of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, in coordination with the Secretary, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, and the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, shall carry out a pilot project, on an emergency basis, to control and prevent further spreading of viral hemorrhagic septicemia in the Great Lakes and Connecting Channels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_426o_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Great Lakes and Connecting Channels defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Great Lakes and Connecting Channels defined In this section, the term “Great Lakes and Connecting Channels” includes Lakes Superior, Huron, Michigan, Erie, and Ontario, all connecting waters between and among such lakes used for commercial navigation, any navigation features in such lakes or waters that are a Federal operation or maintenance responsibility, and areas of the Saint Lawrence River that are operated or maintained by the Federal Government for commercial navigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>