<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_467a"><akn:num>467a</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection of dams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 467a. Inspection of dams(a) In generalAs soon as practicable, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall carry out a national program of inspection of dams for the purpose of protecting human life and property. All dams in the United States shall be inspected by the Secretary except (1) dams under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Reclamation, the Tennessee Valley Authority, or the International Boundary and Water Commission, (2) dams which have been constructed pursuant to licenses issued under the authority of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.], (3) dams which have been inspected within the twelve-month period immediately prior to August 8, 1972, by a State agency and which the Governor of such State requests be excluded from inspection, and (4) dams which the Secretary of the Army determines do not pose any threat to human life or property. The Secretary may inspect dams which have been licensed under the Federal Power Act upon request of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and dams under the jurisdiction of the International Boundary and Water Commission upon request of such Commission.


(b) State participationOn request of a State dam safety agency, with respect to any dam the failure of which would affect the State, the head of a Federal agency shall—(1) provide information to the State dam safety agency on the construction, operation, maintenance, condition, or provisions for emergency operations of the dam; or

(2) allow any official of the State dam safety agency to participate in the Federal inspection of the dam.


(Pub. L. 92–367, § 3, formerly § 2, Aug. 8, 1972, 86 Stat. 506; Pub. L. 95–91, title IV, § 402(a)(1)(A), Aug. 4, 1977, 91 Stat. 583; renumbered § 3 and amended Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(3), (5), Oct. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 3685, 3687; Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3001(b), June 10, 2014, 128 Stat. 1282.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Power Act, referred to in subsec. (a),</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general As soon as practicable, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall carry out a national program of inspection of dams for the purpose of protecting human life and property. All dams in the United States shall be inspected by the Secretary except (1) dams under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Reclamation, the Tennessee Valley Authority, or the International Boundary and Water Commission, (2) dams which have been constructed pursuant to licenses issued under the authority of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.], (3) dams which have been inspected within the twelve-month period immediately prior to August 8, 1972, by a State agency and which the Governor of such State requests be excluded from inspection, and (4) dams which the Secretary of the Army determines do not pose any threat to human life or property. The Secretary may inspect dams which have been licensed under the Federal Power Act upon request of the Federal Energy Regulat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State participation On request of a State dam safety agency, with respect to any dam the failure of which would affect the State, the head of a Federal agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>