<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_467d"><akn:num>467d</akn:num><akn:heading>National inventory of dams and low-head dams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 467d. National inventory of dams and low-head dams(a) In generalThe Secretary of the Army shall maintain and update information on the inventory of dams and low-head dams in the United States.


(b) DamsThe inventory maintained under subsection (a) shall include any available information assessing each dam based on inspections completed by a Federal agency, a State dam safety agency, or a Tribal government.


(c) Low-head damsThe inventory maintained under subsection (a) shall include—(1) the location, ownership, description, current use, condition, height, and length of each low-head dam;

(2) any information on public safety conditions at each low-head dam; and

(3) any other relevant information concerning low-head dams.


(d) DataIn carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—(1) coordinate with Federal and State agencies, Tribal governments, and other relevant entities; and

(2) use data provided to the Secretary by those agencies and entities.


(e) Public availabilityThe Secretary shall make the inventory maintained under subsection (a) publicly available (including on a publicly available website), including—(1) public safety information on the dangers of low-head dams; and

(2) a directory of financial and technical assistance resources available to reduce safety hazards and fish passage barriers at low-head dams.


(f) ClarificationNothing in this section provides authority to the Secretary to carry out an activity, with respect to a low-head dam, that is not explicitly authorized under this section.


(g) Low-head dam definedIn this section, the term “low-head dam” means a river-wide artificial barrier that generally spans a stream channel, blocking the waterway and creating a backup of water behind the barrier, with a drop off over the wall of not less than 6 inches and not more than 25 feet.


(Pub. L. 92–367, § 6, as added Pub. L. 104–303, title II, § 215(c)(8), Oct. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 3687; amended Pub. L. 109–460, § 1(b), Dec. 22, 2006, 120 Sta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of the Army shall maintain and update information on the inventory of dams and low-head dams in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Dams The inventory maintained under subsection (a) shall include any available information assessing each dam based on inspections completed by a Federal agency, a State dam safety agency, or a Tribal government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-head dams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Low-head dams The inventory maintained under subsection (a) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Data In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Public availability The Secretary shall make the inventory maintained under subsection (a) publicly available (including on a publicly available website), including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Clarification Nothing in this section provides authority to the Secretary to carry out an activity, with respect to a low-head dam, that is not explicitly authorized under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-head dam defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Low-head dam defined In this section, the term “low-head dam” means a river-wide artificial barrier that generally spans a stream channel, blocking the waterway and creating a backup of water behind the barrier, with a drop off over the wall of not less than 6 inches and not more than 25 feet.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>