<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467f–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467f–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467f–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_467f_2"><akn:num>467f–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation of high hazard potential dams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 467f–2. Rehabilitation of high hazard potential dams(a) Establishment of programThe Administrator shall establish, within FEMA, a program to provide technical, planning, design, and construction assistance in the form of grants to States with dam safety programs for rehabilitation of eligible high hazard potential dams.


(b) Eligible activitiesA grant awarded under this section to a State may be used by the State to award grants to eligible subrecipients for—(1) repair;

(2) removal; or

(3) any other structural or nonstructural measures to rehabilitate an eligible high hazard potential dam.


(c) Award of grants(1) Application(A) In generalA State interested in receiving a grant under this section may submit to the Administrator an application for the grant.


(B) RequirementsAn application submitted to the Administrator under this section shall be submitted at such time, be in such form, and contain such information as the Administrator may prescribe by regulation.



(2) Grant(A) In generalThe Administrator may make a grant in accordance with this section for rehabilitation of eligible high hazard potential dams to a State that submits an application for the grant in accordance with the regulations prescribed by the Administrator.


(B) Grant agreementThe Administrator shall enter into a grant agreement with the State to establish the terms of the grant and the projects for which the grant is awarded, including the amount of the grant.


(C) Grant assuranceAs part of a grant agreement under subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall require that each eligible subrecipient to which the State awards a grant under this section provides an assurance from the dam owner, with respect to the dam to be rehabilitated, that the dam owner will carry out a plan for maintenance of the dam during the expected life of the dam.


(D) LimitationA State may not award a grant to an eligible subrecipient under this section that exceeds, for any 1 dam, the lesser of—(i) 12.5 percen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program The Administrator shall establish, within FEMA, a program to provide technical, planning, design, and construction assistance in the form of grants to States with dam safety programs for rehabilitation of eligible high hazard potential dams.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible activities A grant awarded under this section to a State may be used by the State to award grants to eligible subrecipients for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Award of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Floodplain management plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Floodplain management plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Priority system The Administrator, in consultation with the Board, shall develop a risk-based priority system for use in identifying eligible high hazard potential dams for which grants may be made under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of funds None of the funds provided in the form of a grant or otherwise made available under this section shall be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractual requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Contractual requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467f_2_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>