<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/467j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_467j"><akn:num>467j</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 467j. Authorization of appropriations(a) National dam safety program(1) Annual amountsThere are authorized to be appropriated to FEMA to carry out sections 467e, 467f, and 467h of this title (in addition to any amounts made available for similar purposes included in any other Act and amounts made available under subsections (b) through (e)), $9,200,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028, to remain available until expended.


(2) Allocation(A) In generalSubject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), for each fiscal year, amounts made available under this subsection to carry out section 467f of this title shall be allocated among the States as follows:(i) One-third among States that qualify for assistance under section 467f(e) of this title.

(ii) Two-thirds among States that qualify for assistance under section 467f(e) of this title, to each such State in proportion to—(I) the number of dams in the State that are listed as State-regulated dams on the inventory of dams and low-head dams maintained under section 467d of this title; as compared to

(II) the number of dams in all States that are listed as State-regulated dams on the inventory of dams and low-head dams maintained under section 467d of this title.



(B) Maximum amount of allocationThe amount of funds allocated to a State under this paragraph for a fiscal year may not exceed the amount that is equal to 4 times the amount of funds committed by the State to implement dam safety activities for that fiscal year.


(C) DeterminationThe Administrator and the Board shall determine the amount allocated to States.




(b) National inventory of dams and low-head damsThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 467d of this title $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.


(c) Public awarenessThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 467g–2 of this title $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.


(d) ResearchThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National dam safety program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National dam safety program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National inventory of dams and low-head dams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National inventory of dams and low-head dams There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 467d of this title $500,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public awareness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public awareness There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 467g–2 of this title $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Research There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 467g of this title $1,450,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028, to remain until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dam safety training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Dam safety training There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 467g–1 of this title $750,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467j_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Staff There is authorized to be appropriated to FEMA for the employment of such additional staff personnel as are necessary to carry out sections 467f through 467g–1 of this title $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_467j_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on use of amounts Amounts made available under this subchapter may not be used to construct or repair any Federal or non-Federal dam.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>