<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/535d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/535d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/535d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_535d"><akn:num>535d</akn:num><akn:heading>Permitting for international bridges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 535d. Permitting for international bridges(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible applicantThe term “eligible applicant” means an entity that has submitted an application for a Presidential permit during the period beginning on December 1, 2020, and ending on December 31, 2024, for any of the following:(A) 1 or more international bridges in Webb County, Texas.

(B) An international bridge in Cameron County, Texas.

(C) An international bridge in Maverick County, Texas.


(2) Presidential permit(A) In generalThe term “Presidential permit” means—(i) an approval by the President to construct, maintain, and operate an international bridge under section 535b of this title; or

(ii) an approval by the President to construct, maintain, and operate an international bridge pursuant to a process described in Executive Order 13867 (84 Fed. Reg. 15491; relating to Issuance of Permits With Respect to Facilities and Land Transportation Crossings at the International Boundaries of the United States) (or any successor Executive Order).


(B) InclusionThe term “Presidential permit” includes an amendment to an approval described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A).



(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of State.



(b) ApplicationAn eligible applicant for a Presidential permit to construct, maintain, and operate an international bridge shall submit an application for the permit to the Secretary.


(c) Recommendation(1) In generalNot later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary receives an application under subsection (b), the Secretary shall make a recommendation to the President—(A) to grant the Presidential permit; or

(B) to deny the Presidential permit.


(2) ConsiderationThe basis for a recommendation under paragraph (1) shall be whether the international bridge is in the foreign policy interests of the United States.



(d) Presidential action(1) In generalThe President shall grant or deny the Presidential permit for an application und</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application An eligible applicant for a Presidential permit to construct, maintain, and operate an international bridge shall submit an application for the permit to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recommendation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Presidential action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Document requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Document requirements Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall not require an eligible applicant for a Presidential permit—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rules of construction Nothing in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>