<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/556" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/556/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/556/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_556"><akn:num>556</akn:num><akn:heading>Printing reports generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 556. Printing reports generally
The Secretary of the Army shall cause the manuscript of the annual report of the Chief of Engineers and subordinate engineers, relating to the improvement of rivers and harbors, and the report of the Mississippi River Commission to be placed in the hands of the Director of the Government Publishing Office on or before the 15th day of October in each year, and the Director of the Government Publishing Office shall cause said reports to be printed with an accurate and comprehensive index thereof, on or before the first Monday in December in each year, for the use of Congress.
All reports on examinations and surveys which may be prepared during the recess of Congress shall, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Army, be printed by the Director of the Government Publishing Office as documents of the following session of Congress.
(Aug. 11, 1888, ch. 860, § 8, 25 Stat. 424; June 13, 1902, ch. 1079, § 1, 32 Stat. 367; Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 144, § 3, 37 Stat. 826; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 205(a), 61 Stat. 501; Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(d), Dec. 16, 2014, 128 Stat. 2537.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The first paragraph of this section is from act Aug. 11, 1888, popularly known as the “Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act”.
The Mississippi River Commission was created by act June 28, 1879, set out as sections 641, 642, 644, 646, and 647 of this title.
The words “and Missouri” which appeared in the original text after “Mississippi” were superseded by the abolition of the Missouri River Commission by act June 13, 1902, ch. 1079, § 1, 32 Stat. 367.
The second paragraph of this section is from the last paragraph of section 3 of act Mar. 4, 1913, which superseded a similar provision of act July 25, 1912, ch. 253, 37 Stat. 231. Other parts of said section 3 are set out in section 545 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
“Director of the Government Publishing Office” substituted for “P</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>