<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/561a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/561a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/561a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_561a"><akn:num>561a</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions from local interests; reduction to meet lowered cost</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 561a. Contributions from local interests; reduction to meet lowered cost
When the authorization of a project of river and harbor improvement requires that local interests shall contribute a specific sum of money toward its cost, the Secretary of the Army, upon the recommendation of the Chief of Engineers, may reduce the sum to be contributed to an amount which shall be in the same ratio to the amount of the required contribution as the actual cost of the work to which said contribution is applicable bears to its original estimated cost as set forth in the project document.
(Mar. 3, 1933, ch. 216, 47 Stat. 1545; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 205(a), 61 Stat. 501.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
A prior provision that the reduction authorized by this section was not to apply to contributions made prior to Mar. 3, 1933, was omitted as obsolete.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by section 205(a) of act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, 61 Stat. 501. Section 205(a) of act July 26, 1947, was repealed by section 53 of act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 641. Section 1 of act Aug. 10, 1956, enacted “Title 10, Armed Forces” which in sections 3010 to 3013 continued Department of the Army under administrative supervision of Secretary of the Army.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>