<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/562" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/562/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/562/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_562"><akn:num>562</akn:num><akn:heading>Channel depths and dimensions defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 562. Channel depths and dimensions defined
In the preparation of projects under this and subsequent river and harbor acts and after the project becomes operational, unless otherwise expressed, the channel depths referred to shall be understood to signify the depth at mean lower low water, as defined by the Department of Commerce for nautical charts and tidal predictions, in tidal waters tributary to the Atlantic and Gulf coasts and at mean lower low water, as defined by the Department of Commerce for nautical charts and tidal predictions, in tidal waters tributary to the Pacific coast and the mean depth for a continuous period of fifteen days of the lowest water, as defined by the Department of Commerce for nautical charts and tidal predictions, in the navigation season of any year in rivers and nontidal channels, and and 11 So in original. after the project becomes operational the channel dimensions specified shall be understood to admit of such increase at the entrances, bends, sidings, and turning places as may be necessary to allow of the free movement of boats.
(Mar. 4, 1915, ch. 142, § 5, 38 Stat. 1053; Pub. L. 102–580, title II, § 224, Oct. 31, 1992, 106 Stat. 4837.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section is from act Mar. 4, 1915, popularly known as the “Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1915”.

Prior ProvisionsSection superseded act Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 144, § 9, 37 Stat. 827, which read as follows: “In the preparation of projects under this and subsequent river and harbor acts, unless otherwise expressed, the channel depths referred to shall be understood to signify the depth at mean lower low water in tidal waters, and the mean depth during the month of lowest water in the navigation season in rivers and nontidal channels, and the channel dimensions specified shall be understood to admit of such increase at the entrances, bends, sidings, and turning places as may be necessary to allow of the free movement of boats.”


Amendments1992—Pub. L. 102–580 ins</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>