<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/578b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/578b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/578b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_578b"><akn:num>578b</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 578b. Disposition of projects(a) In generalIn carrying out a disposition study for a project of the Corps of Engineers, or a separable element of such a project, including a disposition study under section 549a of this title, the Secretary shall consider modifications that would improve the overall quality of the environment in the public interest, including removal of the project or separable element of a project.


(b) Disposition study transparencyThe Secretary shall carry out disposition studies described in subsection (a) in a transparent manner, including by—(1) providing opportunities for public input; and

(2) publishing the final disposition studies.


(c) Removal of infrastructureFor disposition studies described in subsection (a) in which the Secretary determines that a Federal interest no longer exists, and makes a recommendation of removal of the project or separable element of a project, the Secretary is authorized, using existing authorities, to pursue removal of the project or separable element of a project in partnership with other Federal agencies and non-Federal entities with appropriate capabilities to undertake infrastructure removal.


(Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1168, Oct. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 3798.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

“Secretary” Defined
Secretary means the Secretary of the Army, see section 102 of Pub. L. 115–270, set out as a note under section 2201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_578b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In carrying out a disposition study for a project of the Corps of Engineers, or a separable element of such a project, including a disposition study under section 549a of this title, the Secretary shall consider modifications that would improve the overall quality of the environment in the public interest, including removal of the project or separable element of a project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_578b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition study transparency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disposition study transparency The Secretary shall carry out disposition studies described in subsection (a) in a transparent manner, including by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_578b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal of infrastructure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Removal of infrastructure For disposition studies described in subsection (a) in which the Secretary determines that a Federal interest no longer exists, and makes a recommendation of removal of the project or separable element of a project, the Secretary is authorized, using existing authorities, to pursue removal of the project or separable element of a project in partnership with other Federal agencies and non-Federal entities with appropriate capabilities to undertake infrastructure removal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>