<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/579g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/579g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/579g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_579g"><akn:num>579g</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 579g. Annual reports(1) In generalNot later than 10 days after the date on which the budget of the President for each fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Appropriations of the Senate a report on the status of each covered report.


(2) ElementsThe Secretary shall include in the report required under paragraph (1) the following information:(A) A summary of the status of each covered report, including if each such report has been initiated.

(B) The amount of funds that—(i) have been made available to carry out each such report; and

(ii) the Secretary requires to complete each such report.


(C) A detailed assessment of how the Secretary intends to complete each covered report, including an anticipated timeline for completion.


(3) Publicly availableThe Secretary shall make each report required under paragraph (1) publicly available on the website of the Corps of Engineers.


(4) Notification of committeesThe Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Environment and Public Works of the Senate on an annual basis a draft of each covered report.


(5) Definition of covered reportIn this subsection, the term “covered report”—(A) means any report or study required to be submitted by the Secretary under this Act or any Act providing authorizations for water resources development projects enacted after January 4, 2025, to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate that has not been so submitted; and

(B) does not include a feasibility study (as such term is defined in section 2215(d) of this title.


(Pub. L. 118–272, div. A, title I, § 1150(b), Jan. 4, 20</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579g_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) In general Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget of the President for each fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Appropriations of the Senate a report on the status of each covered report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579g_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Elements The Secretary shall include in the report required under paragraph (1) the following information:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579g_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publicly available</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Publicly available The Secretary shall make each report required under paragraph (1) publicly available on the website of the Corps of Engineers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579g_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Notification of committees The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Environment and Public Works of the Senate on an annual basis a draft of each covered report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_579g_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of covered report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Definition of covered report In this subsection, the term “covered report”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>