<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/598c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/598c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/598c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_598c"><akn:num>598c</akn:num><akn:heading>Easements for hurricane and storm damage reduction projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 598c. Easements for hurricane and storm damage reduction projects(a) In generalWith respect to a project for hurricane and storm damage reduction for which the Secretary is requiring a perpetual easement, the Secretary shall, upon request by the non-Federal interest for the project, certify real estate availability and proceed to construction of such project with a nonperpetual easement if—(1) such certification and construction are in compliance with the terms of the report of the Chief of Engineers for the project and the applicable project partnership agreement; and

(2) the Secretary provides the non-Federal interest with formal notice that, in the event in which the nonperpetual easement expires and is not extended, the Secretary will be unable to—(A) fulfill the Federal responsibility with respect to the project or carry out any required nourishment of the project under the existing project authorization;

(B) carry out repair and rehabilitation of the project under section 701n of this title; and

(C) provide any other relevant Federal assistance with respect to the project.



(b) DisclosureFor any project for hurricane storm damage risk reduction, or a proposal to modify such a project, that is authorized after January 4, 2025, for which a perpetual easement is required for Federal participation in the project, the Secretary shall include in the report of the Chief of Engineers for the project a disclosure of such requirement.


(c) ManagementTo the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall, at the request of the non-Federal interest for a project for hurricane storm damage risk reduction, identify and accept the minimum real estate interests necessary to carry out the project, in accordance with section 598b of this title.


(d) Hurricane and storm damage reduction project implementation(1) In generalDuring the 2-year period beginning on January 4, 2025, notwithstanding any requirement of the Secretary for a covered project to comply with the memor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_598c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general With respect to a project for hurricane and storm damage reduction for which the Secretary is requiring a perpetual easement, the Secretary shall, upon request by the non-Federal interest for the project, certify real estate availability and proceed to construction of such project with a nonperpetual easement if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_598c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosure For any project for hurricane storm damage risk reduction, or a proposal to modify such a project, that is authorized after January 4, 2025, for which a perpetual easement is required for Federal participation in the project, the Secretary shall include in the report of the Chief of Engineers for the project a disclosure of such requirement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_598c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Management To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall, at the request of the non-Federal interest for a project for hurricane storm damage risk reduction, identify and accept the minimum real estate interests necessary to carry out the project, in accordance with section 598b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_598c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hurricane and storm damage reduction project implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hurricane and storm damage reduction project implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_598c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Savings clause Nothing in this section may be construed to affect the requirements of section 2213(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>