<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/59ff" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/59ff/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/59ff/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_59ff"><akn:num>59ff</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of nonnavigability for portions of Pelican Island, Texas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 59ff. Declaration of nonnavigability for portions of Pelican Island, Texas(a) Descriptions of nonnavigable areasSubject to the provisions of subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section, those portions of Pelican Island, Texas, which are not submerged and which are within the following property descriptions, are declared to be nonnavigable waters of the United States:(1) to (5) Omitted.


(b) ExceptionsNotwithstanding the declaration under subsection (a), the following portions of Pelican Island, Texas, within those lands described in subsection (a) shall remain navigable waters of the United States:(1) to (3) Omitted.


(c) Requirement that areas be improvedThe declaration under subsection (a) shall apply only to those parts of the areas described in subsection (a) of this section and not described in subsection (b) of this section which are or will be bulkheaded and filled or otherwise occupied by permanent structures or other permanent physical improvements, including marina facilities. All such work is subject to applicable Federal statutes and regulations, including sections 401 and 403 of this title, section 1344 of this title and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.].


(d) ExpirationIf, 20 years from December 19, 1991, any area or part thereof described in subsection (a) of this section and not described in subsection (b) of this section is not bulkheaded or filled or occupied by permanent structures or other permanent physical improvements, including marina facilities, in accordance with the requirements set out in subsection (c) of this section, or if work is not commenced within five years after issuance of any permits required to be obtained under subsection (c), then the declaration of nonnavigability for such area or part thereof shall expire.


(Pub. L. 102–241, § 52, Dec. 19, 1991, 105 Stat. 2228.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, referred to in subsec. (c), is Pub.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59ff_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Descriptions of nonnavigable areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Descriptions of nonnavigable areas Subject to the provisions of subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section, those portions of Pelican Island, Texas, which are not submerged and which are within the following property descriptions, are declared to be nonnavigable waters of the United States:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59ff_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions Notwithstanding the declaration under subsection (a), the following portions of Pelican Island, Texas, within those lands described in subsection (a) shall remain navigable waters of the United States:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59ff_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement that areas be improved</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirement that areas be improved The declaration under subsection (a) shall apply only to those parts of the areas described in subsection (a) of this section and not described in subsection (b) of this section which are or will be bulkheaded and filled or otherwise occupied by permanent structures or other permanent physical improvements, including marina facilities. All such work is subject to applicable Federal statutes and regulations, including sections 401 and 403 of this title, section 1344 of this title and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59ff_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expiration If, 20 years from December 19, 1991, any area or part thereof described in subsection (a) of this section and not described in subsection (b) of this section is not bulkheaded or filled or occupied by permanent structures or other permanent physical improvements, including marina facilities, in accordance with the requirements set out in subsection (c) of this section, or if work is not commenced within five years after issuance of any permits required to be obtained under subsection (c), then the declaration of nonnavigability for such area or part thereof shall expire.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>