<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/59ii" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/59ii/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/59ii/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_59ii"><akn:num>59ii</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of nonnavigability of a portion of the canal known as the James River and Kanawha Canal </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 59ii. Declaration of nonnavigability of a portion of the canal known as the James River and Kanawha Canal in Richmond, Virginia(a) Canal declared nonnavigableThe portion of the canal known as the James River and Kanawha Canal in Richmond, Virginia, located between the Great Ship Lock on the east and the limits of the City of Richmond on the west is hereby declared to be a nonnavigable waterway of the United States for purposes of subtitle II of title 46.


(b) Ensuring public safetyThe Secretary of Transportation shall provide such technical advice, information, and assistance as the City of Richmond, Virginia, or its designee may request to insure that the vessels operating on the waters declared nonnavigable by subsection (a) are built, maintained, and operated in a manner consistent with protecting public safety.


(c) Termination of declaration(1) In generalThe Secretary of Transportation may terminate the effectiveness of the declaration made by subsection (a) by publishing a determination that vessels operating on the waters declared nonnavigable by subsection (a) have not been built, maintained, and operated in a manner consistent with protecting public safety.


(2) Public inputBefore making a determination under this subsection, the Secretary of Transportation shall—(A) consult with appropriate State and local government officials regarding whether such a determination is necessary to protect public safety and will serve the public interest; and

(B) provide to persons who might be adversely affected by the determination the opportunity for comment and a hearing on whether such action is necessary to protect public safety and will serve the public interest.



(Pub. L. 106–32, § 2, June 1, 1999, 113 Stat. 115.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
FindingsPub. L. 106–32, § 1, June 1, 1999, 113 Stat. 115, provided that: 
“The Congress finds the following:
“(1) The canal known as the James River and Kanawha Canal played an important part in the economi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59ii_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Canal declared nonnavigable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Canal declared nonnavigable The portion of the canal known as the James River and Kanawha Canal in Richmond, Virginia, located between the Great Ship Lock on the east and the limits of the City of Richmond on the west is hereby declared to be a nonnavigable waterway of the United States for purposes of subtitle II of title 46.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59ii_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ensuring public safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Ensuring public safety The Secretary of Transportation shall provide such technical advice, information, and assistance as the City of Richmond, Virginia, or its designee may request to insure that the vessels operating on the waters declared nonnavigable by subsection (a) are built, maintained, and operated in a manner consistent with protecting public safety.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59ii_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of declaration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Termination of declaration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>