<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/59y" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/59y/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/59y/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_59y"><akn:num>59y</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of nonnavigability for portions of Coney Island Creek and Gravesend Bay, New York</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 59y. Declaration of nonnavigability for portions of Coney Island Creek and Gravesend Bay, New York(a) Area to be declared non-navigable; public interestUnless the Secretary finds, after consultation with local and regional public officials (including local and regional public planning organizations), that the proposed projects to be undertaken within the boundaries in the portions of Coney Island Creek and Gravesend Bay, New York, described below, are not in the public interest then, subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, those portions of such Creek and Bay, bounded and described as follows, are declared to be non-navigable waters of the United States:
Beginning at the corner formed by the intersection of the Westerly Line of Cropsey Avenue, and the Northernmost United States Pierhead Line of Coney Island Creek.
Running thence south 12 degrees 41 minutes 03 seconds E and along the westerly line of Cropsey Avenue, 98.72 feet to the northerly channel line as shown on Corps of Engineers Map Numbered F. 150 and on Survey by Rogers and Giollorenzo Numbered 13959 dated October 31, 1986.
Running thence in a westerly direction and along the said northerly channel line the following bearings and distances:
South 48 degrees 59 minutes 27 seconds west, 118.77 feet; south 37 degrees 07 minutes 01 seconds west, 232.00 feet; south 23 degrees 17 minutes 10 seconds west, 430.03 feet; south 31 degrees 25 minutes 46 seconds west, 210.95 feet; south 79 degrees 22 minutes 49 seconds west, 244.18 feet; north 55 degrees 00 minutes 29 seconds west, 183.10 feet; north 41 degrees 47 minutes 04 seconds west, 315.16 feet;
North 41 degrees 17 minutes 43 seconds west, 492.47 feet to the said Pierhead Line; thence north 73 degrees 58 minutes 40 seconds west and along said pierhead line, 2,665.25 feet to the intersection of the United States bulkhead line;
Thence north 0 degree 19 minutes 35 seconds west and along the United States Bulkhead line 1,138.50 feet to the intersection o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59y_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area to be declared non-navigable; public interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Area to be declared non-navigable; public interest Unless the Secretary finds, after consultation with local and regional public officials (including local and regional public planning organizations), that the proposed projects to be undertaken within the boundaries in the portions of Coney Island Creek and Gravesend Bay, New York, described below, are not in the public interest then, subject to subsections (b) and (c) of this section, those portions of such Creek and Bay, bounded and described as follows, are declared to be non-navigable waters of the United States:
Beginning at the corner formed by the intersection of the Westerly Line of Cropsey Avenue, and the Northernmost United States Pierhead Line of Coney Island Creek.
Running thence south 12 degrees 41 minutes 03 seconds E and along the westerly line of Cropsey Avenue, 98.72 feet to the northerly channel line as shown on Corps of Engineers Map Numbered F. 150 and on Survey by Rogers and Giollorenzo Numbered 13959 dated Oct</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59y_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limits on applicability; regulatory requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limits on applicability; regulatory requirements The declaration under subsection (a) shall apply only to those parts of the areas described in subsection (a) of this section which are or will be bulkheaded and filled or otherwise occupied by permanent structures, including marina facilities. All such work is subject to all applicable Federal statutes and regulations, including, but not necessarily limited to, sections 401 and 403 of this title, section 1344 of this title, and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_59y_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expiration date If, 20 years from November 17, 1988, any area or part thereof described in subsection (a) of this section is not bulkheaded or filled or occupied by permanent structures, including marina facilities, in accordance with the requirements set out in subsection (b) of this section, or if work in connection with any activity permitted in subsection (b) is not commenced within 5 years after issuance of such permits, then the declaration of non-navigability for such area or part thereof shall expire.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>