<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_602"><akn:num>602</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of channel of South Pass of Mississippi River</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 602. Maintenance of channel of South Pass of Mississippi River
Upon the termination of the contract entered into with the late James B. Eads for the maintenance of the channel through the South Pass of the Mississippi River, the Secretary of the Army is directed to take charge of said channel, including the jetties, and all auxiliary works connected therewith, and thereafter to maintain with the utmost efficiency said South Pass Channel; and for that purpose he is authorized to draw his warrants from time to time on the Treasurer of the United States, until otherwise provided for by law, for such sums of money as may be necessary, not to exceed in the aggregate for any one year $100,000. For that purpose any available Government dredge may be used.
For the purpose of securing the uninterrupted examinations and surveys of the South Pass of the Mississippi River, the Secretary of the Army, upon the application of the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to draw his warrant or requisition from time to time upon the Secretary of the Treasury for such sums as may be necessary to do such work, not to exceed in the aggregate for each year the sum of $10,000.
(Aug. 11, 1888, ch. 860, §§ 1, 4, 25 Stat. 422, 424; June 6, 1900, ch. 790, § 3, 31 Stat. 584; June 13, 1902, ch. 1079, § 1, 32 Stat. 340; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 205(a), 61 Stat. 501; Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1076, § 1(15), 68 Stat. 967.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Except for the last sentence, the first paragraph of this section was from a part of section 3 of act June 6, 1900. The omitted portion of the original text authorized the Secretary of War, in his discretion, to terminate the contract with James B. Eads and provided that the Secretary of War should take charge of the channel “in case of the termination of said contract, by virtue of the provisions hereof or by expiration of said contract.”
The last sentence of the first paragraph of this section was from a provision of section 1 of act June 13, 1902</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>