<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701b–12" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701b–12/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701b–12/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_701b_12"><akn:num>701b–12</akn:num><akn:heading>Floodplain management requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 701b–12. Floodplain management requirements(a) Compliance with floodplain management and insurance programsBefore construction of any project for local flood protection, or any project for hurricane or storm damage reduction, that involves Federal assistance from the Secretary, the non-Federal interest shall agree to participate in and comply with applicable Federal floodplain management and flood insurance programs.


(b) Floodplain management plansWithin 1 year after the date of signing a project cooperation agreement for construction of a project to which subsection (a) applies, the non-Federal interest shall prepare a floodplain management plan designed to reduce the impacts of future flood events in the project area. Such plan shall be implemented by the non-Federal interest not later than 1 year after completion of construction of the project.


(c) Guidelines(1) In generalThe Secretary shall develop guidelines for preparation of floodplain management plans by non-Federal interests under subsection (b).


(2) Required elementsThe guidelines developed under paragraph (1) shall—(A) address potential measures, practices, and policies to be undertaken by non-Federal interests to to 11 So in original. reduce loss of life, injuries, damages to property and facilities, public expenditures, and other adverse impacts associated with flooding and to preserve and enhance natural floodplain values; and

(B) address those measures to be undertaken by non-Federal interests to preserve the level of flood protection provided by a project to which subsection (a) applies.


(3) Limitation on statutory constructionNothing in this subsection shall be construed to confer any regulatory authority upon the Secretary or the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.



(d) Technical supportThe Secretary may provide technical support to a non-Federal interest for a project to which subsection (a) applies for the development and implementation of plans prepared under s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_701b_12_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with floodplain management and insurance programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compliance with floodplain management and insurance programs Before construction of any project for local flood protection, or any project for hurricane or storm damage reduction, that involves Federal assistance from the Secretary, the non-Federal interest shall agree to participate in and comply with applicable Federal floodplain management and flood insurance programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_701b_12_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Floodplain management plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Floodplain management plans Within 1 year after the date of signing a project cooperation agreement for construction of a project to which subsection (a) applies, the non-Federal interest shall prepare a floodplain management plan designed to reduce the impacts of future flood events in the project area. Such plan shall be implemented by the non-Federal interest not later than 1 year after completion of construction of the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_701b_12_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_701b_12_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical support The Secretary may provide technical support to a non-Federal interest for a project to which subsection (a) applies for the development and implementation of plans prepared under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>