<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701b–16" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701b–16/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701b–16/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_701b_16"><akn:num>701b–16</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of flood risk reduction projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 701b–16. Management of flood risk reduction projects(a) In generalIf 2 or more flood control projects are located within the same geographic area, the Secretary shall, at the request of the non-Federal interests for the affected projects, consider those projects as a single program for budgetary or project management purposes, if the Secretary determines that doing so would not be incompatible with the authorized project purposes.


(b) Cost share(1) In generalIf any work on a project to which subsection (a) applies is required solely because of impacts to that project from a navigation project, the cost of carrying out that work shall be shared in accordance with the cost-sharing requirements for the navigation project.


(2) Use of amountsWork described in paragraph (1) may be carried out using amounts made available under subsection (a).



(Pub. L. 113–121, title III, § 3012, June 10, 2014, 128 Stat. 1284.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

“Secretary” Defined
Secretary means the Secretary of the Army, see section 2 of Pub. L. 113–121, set out as a note under section 2201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_701b_16_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If 2 or more flood control projects are located within the same geographic area, the Secretary shall, at the request of the non-Federal interests for the affected projects, consider those projects as a single program for budgetary or project management purposes, if the Secretary determines that doing so would not be incompatible with the authorized project purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_701b_16_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cost share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>