<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701n–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701n–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701n–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_701n_3"><akn:num>701n–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent measures to reduce emergency flood fighting needs for communities subject to repetitive fl</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 701n–3. Permanent measures to reduce emergency flood fighting needs for communities subject to repetitive flooding(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Affected communityThe term “affected community” means a legally constituted public body (as that term is used in section 1962d–5b(b) of title 42)—(A) with jurisdiction over an area that has been subject to flooding in two or more events in any 10-year period; and

(B) that has received emergency flood-fighting assistance, including construction of temporary barriers by the Secretary, under section 701n of this title with respect to such flood events.


(2) Natural feature; nature-based featureThe terms “natural feature” and “nature-based feature” have the meanings given those terms in section 2289a of this title.



(b) Program(1) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to carry out a program to study, design, and construct water resources development projects through measures involving, among other things, strengthening, raising, extending, realigning, or otherwise modifying existing flood control works, designing new works, and incorporating natural features, nature-based features, or nonstructural features, as appropriate to provide flood and coastal storm risk management to affected communities.


(2) ConsiderationsIn carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practical, review and, where appropriate, incorporate natural features or nature-based features, or a combination of such features and nonstructural features, that avoid or reduce at least 50 percent of flood or storm damages in one or more of the alternatives included in the final alternatives evaluated.


(3) Construction(A) In generalThe Secretary may carry out a project described in paragraph (1) without further congressional authorization if—(i) the Secretary determines that the project—(I) is advisable to reduce the risk of flooding for an affected community; and

(II) produces benefits that are in excess of the estimated cost</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_701n_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_701n_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>