<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/701t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_701t"><akn:num>701t</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency fund for flood damage; amount; commitments to be fulfilled by local interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 701t. Emergency fund for flood damage; amount; commitments to be fulfilled by local interests
The sum of $25,000,000 is authorized to be appropriated as an emergency fund to be expended under the direction of the Secretary of the Army and the supervision of the Chief of Engineers for the repair, restoration, and strengthening of levees and other flood control works which have been threatened or destroyed by recent floods, or which may be threatened or destroyed by later floods, including the raising, extending, or other modification of such works as may be necessary in the discretion of the Chief of Engineers for the adequate functioning of the works for flood control: Provided, That local interests shall provide without cost to the United States all lands, easements, and rights of way necessary for the work and shall maintain and operate all the works after completion in a manner satisfactory to the Chief of Engineers: Provided further, That pending the appropriation of said sum, the Secretary of the Army may allot from existing flood-control appropriations such sums as may be necessary for the immediate prosecution of the work authorized by this section, such appropriations to be reimbursed from said emergency fund when appropriated: And provided further, That funds allotted under this authority shall not be diverted from the unobligated funds from the appropriation “Flood control, general”, made available in War Department Civil Functions Appropriation Acts for specific purposes.
(June 30, 1948, ch. 771, title II, § 208, 62 Stat. 1182.)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>