<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/702o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/702o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/702o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_702o"><akn:num>702o</akn:num><akn:heading>Mississippi River and Tributaries Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 702o. Mississippi River and Tributaries Project(a) In generalAfter any flood event requiring operation or activation of any floodway or backwater feature within the Mississippi River and Tributaries Project through natural overtopping of a Federal levee or artificial crevassing of a Federal levee to relieve pressure on the levees elsewhere in the system, the Secretary shall expeditiously reset and restore the damaged floodway’s levees.


(b) ConsultationIn carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for consultation with affected communities.


(c) Mississippi River and Tributaries ProjectThe term “Mississippi River and Tributaries Project” means the Mississippi River and Tributaries project authorized by the Act of May 15, 1928 (Chap. 569; 45 Stat. 534).


(Pub. L. 115–270, title I, § 1128, Oct. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 3780.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe act of May 15, 1928, referred to in subsec. (c), is act May 15, 1928, ch. 569, 45 Stat. 534, which enacted sections 702a, 702b to 702d, 702e to 702g, 702h, 702i, 702j, 702k, 702l, 702m, and 704 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

“Secretary” Defined
Secretary means the Secretary of the Army, see section 102 of Pub. L. 115–270, set out as a note under section 2201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_702o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general After any flood event requiring operation or activation of any floodway or backwater feature within the Mississippi River and Tributaries Project through natural overtopping of a Federal levee or artificial crevassing of a Federal levee to relieve pressure on the levees elsewhere in the system, the Secretary shall expeditiously reset and restore the damaged floodway’s levees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_702o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for consultation with affected communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_702o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mississippi River and Tributaries Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mississippi River and Tributaries Project The term “Mississippi River and Tributaries Project” means the Mississippi River and Tributaries project authorized by the Act of May 15, 1928 (Chap. 569; 45 Stat. 534).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>