<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/853o–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/853o–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/853o–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_853o_1"><akn:num>853o–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit of service as deck officer or junior engineer and certain other active service for retirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 853o–1. Credit of service as deck officer or junior engineer and certain other active service for retirement and retirement pay
Active service in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as a deck officer or junior engineer and active service counted on June 30, 1922, for longevity pay, shall be credited to commissioned officers as active commissioned service for purposes of retirement and retirement pay.
(Pub. L. 87–649, § 9(c), Sept. 7, 1962, 76 Stat. 496; 1965 Reorg. Plan No. 2, eff. July 13, 1965, 30 F.R. 8819, 79 Stat. 1318; 1970 Reorg. Plan No. 4, eff. Oct. 3, 1970, 35 F.R. 15627, 84 Stat. 2090.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 302 of Title 37 prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 37, Pay and Allowances of the Uniformed Services, by Pub. L. 87–649, § 1, Sept. 7, 1962, 76 Stat. 451.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Nov. 1, 1962, see section 15 of Pub. L. 87–649, set out as a note preceding section 101 of Title 37, Pay and Allowances of the Uniformed Services.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Coast and Geodetic Survey consolidated with Weather Bureau to form a new agency in Department of Commerce to be known as Environmental Science Services Administration, and commissioned officers of Survey transferred to ESSA, by Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1965, eff. July 13, 1965, 30 F.R. 8819, 79 Stat. 1318, set out as a note under section 851 of this title. The Reorg. Plan also transferred to Secretary of Commerce all functions of Coast and Geodetic Survey and Director of Survey. Subsequently, Environmental Science Services Administration abolished, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration established, and Commissioned Officer Corps of ESSA redesignated Commissioned Officer Corps of NOAA by Reorg. Plan No. 4 of 1970, eff. Oct. 3, 1970, 35 F.R. 15627, 84 Stat. 2090, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees. For further de</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>