<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/857–17" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/857–17/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/857–17/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_857_17"><akn:num>857–17</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency cooperation and assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 857–17. Interagency cooperation and assistance(a) LiaisonThe head of each department or agency of the Federal Government concerned with marine and atmospheric matters shall designate a senior policy official to participate as observer in the work of the Committee and offer necessary assistance.


(b) Agency assistanceThe Committee is authorized to request from the head of any department, agency, or independent instrumentality of the Federal Government any information and assistance it deems necessary to carry out the functions assigned under sections 857–13 to 857–18 of this title. The head of each such department, agency, or instrumentality is authorized to cooperate with the Committee, and, to the extent permitted by law, to furnish such information and assistance to the Committee upon request made by the Chairman, without reimbursement for such services and assistance.


(c) Administrative assistanceThe Secretary of Commerce shall make available to the Committee such staff, information, personnel, and administrative services and assistance as may reasonably be required to carry out the provisions of sections 857–13 to 857–18 of this title.


(Pub. L. 95–63, § 6, July 5, 1977, 91 Stat. 266.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those contained in this section, which required the designation of senior policy officials as observers, directed the Secretary of Commerce to provide administrative assistance, and authorized requests for assistance from Federal agencies by the Federal Advisory Committee on Oceans and Atmosphere as originally established on Aug. 16, 1971, were contained in sections 857–8 and 857–11 of this title prior to repeal by section 7(a) of Pub. L. 95–63.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Termination of Advisory CommitteesAdvisory committees established after Jan. 5, 1973, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a committee establi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_857_17_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liaison</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liaison The head of each department or agency of the Federal Government concerned with marine and atmospheric matters shall designate a senior policy official to participate as observer in the work of the Committee and offer necessary assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_857_17_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agency assistance The Committee is authorized to request from the head of any department, agency, or independent instrumentality of the Federal Government any information and assistance it deems necessary to carry out the functions assigned under sections 857–13 to 857–18 of this title. The head of each such department, agency, or instrumentality is authorized to cooperate with the Committee, and, to the extent permitted by law, to furnish such information and assistance to the Committee upon request made by the Chairman, without reimbursement for such services and assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_857_17_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative assistance The Secretary of Commerce shall make available to the Committee such staff, information, personnel, and administrative services and assistance as may reasonably be required to carry out the provisions of sections 857–13 to 857–18 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>