<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/857–19" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/857–19/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/857–19/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_857_19"><akn:num>857–19</akn:num><akn:heading>Biennial report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 857–19. Biennial report
Beginning in September, 2001, the President shall transmit to the Congress biennially a report that includes a detailed listing of all existing Federal programs related to ocean and coastal activities, including a description of each program, the current funding for the program, linkages to other Federal programs, and a projection of the funding level for the program for each of the next 5 fiscal years beginning after the report is submitted.
(Pub. L. 106–256, § 5, Aug. 7, 2000, 114 Stat. 648.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
National Ocean PolicyPub. L. 106–256, Aug. 7, 2000, 114 Stat. 644, as amended by Pub. L. 107–206, title I, § 206, Aug. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 833; Pub. L. 107–372, title III, § 306, Dec. 19, 2002, 116 Stat. 3096; Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(200), Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4328, provided that:
“SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.“This Act may be cited as the ‘Oceans Act of 2000’.


“SEC. 2. PURPOSE AND OBJECTIVES.“The purpose of this Act is to establish a commission to make recommendations for coordinated and comprehensive national ocean policy that will promote—“(1) the protection of life and property against natural and manmade hazards;

“(2) responsible stewardship, including use, of fishery resources and other ocean and coastal resources;

“(3) the protection of the marine environment and prevention of marine pollution;

“(4) the enhancement of marine-related commerce and transportation, the resolution of conflicts among users of the marine environment, and the engagement of the private sector in innovative approaches for sustainable use of living marine resources and responsible use of non-living marine resources;

“(5) the expansion of human knowledge of the marine environment including the role of the oceans in climate and global environmental change and the advancement of education and training in fields related to ocean and coastal activities;

“(6) the continued investment in and development and improvement of the capabi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>