<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/891b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/891b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/891b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_891b"><akn:num>891b</akn:num><akn:heading>Fleet replacement and modernization Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 891b. Fleet replacement and modernization Plan(a) In generalTo carry out the program authorized in section 891a of this title, the Secretary shall develop and submit to Congress a replacement and modernization Plan for the NOAA fleet covering the years authorized under section 891h of this title.


(b) TimingThe Plan required in subsection (a) shall be submitted to Congress within 30 days of October 29, 1992, and updated on an annual basis.


(c) Plan elementsThe Plan required in subsection (a) shall include the following—(1) the number of vessels proposed to be modernized or replaced, the schedule for their modernization or replacement, and anticipated funding requirements;

(2) the number of vessels proposed to be constructed, leased, or chartered;

(3) the number of vessels, or days at sea, that can be obtained by using the vessels of the UNOLS;

(4) the number of vessels that will be made available to NOAA by the Secretary of the Navy, or any other federal 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. official, and the terms and conditions for their availability;

(5) the proposed acquisition of modern scientific instrumentation for the NOAA fleet, including acoustic systems, data transmission positioning and communication systems, physical, chemical, and meteorological oceanographic systems, and data acquisition and processing systems; and

(6) the appropriate role of the NOAA Corps in operating and maintaining the NOAA fleet.


(d) Contracting limitationThe Secretary may not enter into any contract for the construction, lease, or service life extension of a vessel of the NOAA fleet before the date of the submission to Congress of the Plan required in subsection (a).


(Pub. L. 102–567, title VI, § 604, Oct. 29, 1992, 106 Stat. 4300.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Fishery Survey Vessel AcquisitionPub. L. 106–450, title III, Nov. 7, 2000, 114 Stat. 1945, provided that:
“SEC. 301. SHORT TITLE.“This title may be cited as the ‘Fisheries Survey Ve</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_891b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To carry out the program authorized in section 891a of this title, the Secretary shall develop and submit to Congress a replacement and modernization Plan for the NOAA fleet covering the years authorized under section 891h of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_891b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Timing The Plan required in subsection (a) shall be submitted to Congress within 30 days of October 29, 1992, and updated on an annual basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_891b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Plan elements The Plan required in subsection (a) shall include the following—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_891b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contracting limitation The Secretary may not enter into any contract for the construction, lease, or service life extension of a vessel of the NOAA fleet before the date of the submission to Congress of the Plan required in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>