<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/894" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/894/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/894/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_894"><akn:num>894</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions to address sexual harassment at National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 894. Actions to address sexual harassment at National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration(a) Required policyNot later than 1 year after December 23, 2016, the Secretary of Commerce shall, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, develop a policy on the prevention of and response to sexual harassment involving employees of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, members of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, and individuals who work with or conduct business on behalf of the Administration.


(b) Matters to be specified in policyThe policy developed under subsection (a) shall include—(1) establishment of a program to promote awareness of the incidence of sexual harassment;

(2) clear procedures an individual should follow in the case of an occurrence of sexual harassment, including—(A) a specification of the person or persons to whom an alleged occurrence of sexual harassment should be reported by an individual and options for confidential reporting, including—(i) options and contact information for after-hours contact; and

(ii) a procedure for obtaining assistance and reporting sexual harassment while working in a remote scientific field camp, at sea, or in another field status; and


(B) a specification of any other person whom the victim should contact;


(3) establishment of a mechanism by which—(A) questions regarding sexual harassment can be confidentially asked and confidentially answered; and

(B) incidents of sexual harassment can be reported on a restricted or unrestricted basis; and


(4) a prohibition on retaliation and consequences for retaliatory actions.


(c) Consultation and assistanceIn developing the policy required by subsection (a), the Secretary may consult or receive assistance from such State, local, and national organizations and subject matter experts as the Secretary considers appropriate.


(d) Availability of policyThe Secretary shall ensure that the policy developed under subsectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_894_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required policy Not later than 1 year after December 23, 2016, the Secretary of Commerce shall, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, develop a policy on the prevention of and response to sexual harassment involving employees of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, members of the commissioned officer corps of the Administration, and individuals who work with or conduct business on behalf of the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_894_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters to be specified in policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Matters to be specified in policy The policy developed under subsection (a) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_894_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation and assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation and assistance In developing the policy required by subsection (a), the Secretary may consult or receive assistance from such State, local, and national organizations and subject matter experts as the Secretary considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_894_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of policy The Secretary shall ensure that the policy developed under subsection (a) is available to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_894_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geographic distribution of equal employment opportunity personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Geographic distribution of equal employment opportunity personnel The Secretary shall designate out of existing staff at least 1 employee of the Administration who is tasked with handling matters relating to equal employment opportunity or sexual harassment at each marine and aviation center of the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_894_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quarterly reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Quarterly reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>