<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_902"><akn:num>902</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 902. Definitions
When used in this chapter—(1) The term “person” means individual, partnership, corporation, or association.

(2) The term “injury” means accidental injury or death arising out of and in the course of employment, and such occupational disease or infection as arises naturally out of such employment or as naturally or unavoidably results from such accidental injury, and includes an injury caused by the willful act of a third person directed against an employee because of his employment.

(3) The term “employee” means any person engaged in maritime employment, including any longshoreman or other person engaged in longshoring operations, and any harbor-worker including a ship repairman, shipbuilder, and ship-breaker, but such term does not include—(A) individuals employed exclusively to perform office clerical, secretarial, security, or data processing work;

(B) individuals employed by a club, camp, recreational operation, restaurant, museum, or retail outlet;

(C) individuals employed by a marina and who are not engaged in construction, replacement, or expansion of such marina (except for routine maintenance);

(D) individuals who (i) are employed by suppliers, transporters, or vendors, (ii) are temporarily doing business on the premises of an employer described in paragraph (4), and (iii) are not engaged in work normally performed by employees of that employer under this chapter;

(E) aquaculture workers;

(F) individuals employed to build any recreational vessel under sixty-five feet in length, or individuals employed to repair any recreational vessel, or to dismantle any part of a recreational vessel in connection with the repair of such vessel;

(G) a master or member of a crew of any vessel; or

(H) any person engaged by a master to load or unload or repair any small vessel under eighteen tons net;


if individuals described in clauses (A) through (F) are subject to coverage under a State workers’ compensation law.

(4) The term “employer” means</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “person” means individual, partnership, corporation, or association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “injury” means accidental injury or death arising out of and in the course of employment, and such occupational disease or infection as arises naturally out of such employment or as naturally or unavoidably results from such accidental injury, and includes an injury caused by the willful act of a third person directed against an employee because of his employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “employee” means any person engaged in maritime employment, including any longshoreman or other person engaged in longshoring operations, and any harbor-worker including a ship repairman, shipbuilder, and ship-breaker, but such term does not include— if individuals described in clauses (A) through (F) are subject to coverage under a State workers’ compensation law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “employer” means an employer any of whose employees are employed in maritime employment, in whole or in part, upon the navigable waters of the United States (including any adjoining pier, wharf, dry dock, terminal, building way, marine railway, or other adjoining area customarily used by an employer in loading, unloading, repairing, or building a vessel).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “carrier” means any person or fund authorized under section 932 of this title to insure under this chapter and includes self-insurers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “deputy commissioner” means the deputy commissioner having jurisdiction in respect of an injury or death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “State” includes a Territory and the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “United States” when used in a geographical sense means the several States and Territories and the District of Columbia, including the territorial waters thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) “Disability” means incapacity because of injury to earn the wages which the employee was receiving at the time of injury in the same or any other employment; but such term shall mean permanent impairment, determined (to the extent covered thereby) under the guides to the evaluation of permanent impairment promulgated and modified from time to time by the American Medical Association, in the case of an individual whose claim is described in section 910(d)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>