<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_903"><akn:num>903</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 903. Coverage(a) Disability or death; injuries occurring upon navigable waters of United StatesExcept as otherwise provided in this section, compensation shall be payable under this chapter in respect of disability or death of an employee, but only if the disability or death results from an injury occurring upon the navigable waters of the United States (including any adjoining pier, wharf, dry dock, terminal, building way, marine railway, or other adjoining area customarily used by an employer in loading, unloading, repairing, dismantling, or building a vessel).


(b) Governmental officers and employeesNo compensation shall be payable in respect of the disability or death of an officer or employee of the United States, or any agency thereof, or of any State or foreign government, or any subdivision thereof.


(c) Intoxication; willful intention to killNo compensation shall be payable if the injury was occasioned solely by the intoxication of the employee or by the willful intention of the employee to injure or kill himself or another.


(d) Small vessels(1) No compensation shall be payable to an employee employed at a facility of an employer if, as certified by the Secretary, the facility is engaged in the business of building, repairing, or dismantling exclusively small vessels (as defined in paragraph (3) of this subsection), unless the injury occurs while upon the navigable waters of the United States or while upon any adjoining pier, wharf, dock, facility over land for launching vessels, or facility over land for hauling, lifting, or drydocking vessels.

(2) Notwithstanding paragraph (1), compensation shall be payable to an employee—(A) who is employed at a facility which is used in the business of building, repairing, or dismantling small vessels if such facility receives Federal maritime subsidies; or

(B) if the employee is not subject to coverage under a State workers’ compensation law.


(3) For purposes of this subsection, a small vessel means—(A) a com</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disability or death; injuries occurring upon navigable waters of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disability or death; injuries occurring upon navigable waters of United States Except as otherwise provided in this section, compensation shall be payable under this chapter in respect of disability or death of an employee, but only if the disability or death results from an injury occurring upon the navigable waters of the United States (including any adjoining pier, wharf, dry dock, terminal, building way, marine railway, or other adjoining area customarily used by an employer in loading, unloading, repairing, dismantling, or building a vessel).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governmental officers and employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Governmental officers and employees No compensation shall be payable in respect of the disability or death of an officer or employee of the United States, or any agency thereof, or of any State or foreign government, or any subdivision thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intoxication; willful intention to kill</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Intoxication; willful intention to kill No compensation shall be payable if the injury was occasioned solely by the intoxication of the employee or by the willful intention of the employee to injure or kill himself or another.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Small vessels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for benefits paid under other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Credit for benefits paid under other laws Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any amounts paid to an employee for the same injury, disability, or death for which benefits are claimed under this chapter pursuant to any other workers’ compensation law or section 30104 of title 46 shall be credited against any liability imposed by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>