<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_907"><akn:num>907</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical services and supplies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 907. Medical services and supplies(a) General requirementThe employer shall furnish such medical, surgical, and other attendance or treatment, nurse and hospital service, medicine, crutches, and apparatus, for such period as the nature of the injury or the process of recovery may require.


(b) Physician selection; administrative supervision; change of physicians and hospitalsThe employee shall have the right to choose an attending physician authorized by the Secretary to provide medical care under this chapter as hereinafter provided. If, due to the nature of the injury, the employee is unable to select his physician and the nature of the injury requires immediate medical treatment and care, the employer shall select a physician for him. The Secretary shall actively supervise the medical care rendered to injured employees, shall require periodic reports as to the medical care being rendered to injured employees, shall have authority to determine the necessity, character, and sufficiency of any medical aid furnished or to be furnished, and may, on his own initiative or at the request of the employer, order a change of physicians or hospitals when in his judgment such change is desirable or necessary in the interest of the employee or where the charges exceed those prevailing within the community for the same or similar services or exceed the provider’s customary charges. Change of physicians at the request of employees shall be permitted in accordance with regulations of the Secretary.


(c) Physicians and health care providers not authorized to render medical care or provide medical services(1)(A) The Secretary shall annually prepare a list of physicians and health care providers in each compensation district who are not authorized to render medical care or provide medical services under this chapter. The names of physicians and health care providers contained on the list required under this subparagraph shall be made available to employees and employers in each </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General requirement The employer shall furnish such medical, surgical, and other attendance or treatment, nurse and hospital service, medicine, crutches, and apparatus, for such period as the nature of the injury or the process of recovery may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physician selection; administrative supervision; change of physicians and hospitals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Physician selection; administrative supervision; change of physicians and hospitals The employee shall have the right to choose an attending physician authorized by the Secretary to provide medical care under this chapter as hereinafter provided. If, due to the nature of the injury, the employee is unable to select his physician and the nature of the injury requires immediate medical treatment and care, the employer shall select a physician for him. The Secretary shall actively supervise the medical care rendered to injured employees, shall require periodic reports as to the medical care being rendered to injured employees, shall have authority to determine the necessity, character, and sufficiency of any medical aid furnished or to be furnished, and may, on his own initiative or at the request of the employer, order a change of physicians or hospitals when in his judgment such change is desirable or necessary in the interest of the employee or where the charges exceed those prevai</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physicians and health care providers not authorized to render medical care or provide medical services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Physicians and health care providers not authorized to render medical care or provide medical services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request of treatment or services prerequisite to recovery of expenses; formal report of injury and treatment; suspension of compensation for refusal of treatment or examination; justification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Request of treatment or services prerequisite to recovery of expenses; formal report of injury and treatment; suspension of compensation for refusal of treatment or examination; justification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physical examination; medical questions; report of physical impairment; review or reexamination; costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Physical examination; medical questions; report of physical impairment; review or reexamination; costs In the event that medical questions are raised in any case, the Secretary shall have the power to cause the employee to be examined by a physician employed or selected by the Secretary and to obtain from such physician a report containing his estimate of the employee’s physical impairment and such other information as may be appropriate. Any party who is dissatisfied with such report may request a review or reexamination of the employee by one or more different physicians employed or selected by the Secretary. The Secretary shall order such review or reexamination unless he finds that it is clearly unwarranted. Such review or reexamination shall be completed within two weeks from the date ordered unless the Secretary finds that because of extraordinary circumstances a longer period is required. The Secretary shall have the power in his discretion to charge the cost of examination </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Place of examination; exclusion of physicians other than examining physician of Secretary; good cause for conclusions of other physicians respecting impairment; examination by employer’s physician; suspension of proceedings and compensation for refusal of examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Place of examination; exclusion of physicians other than examining physician of Secretary; good cause for conclusions of other physicians respecting impairment; examination by employer’s physician; suspension of proceedings and compensation for refusal of examination An employee shall submit to a physical examination under subsection (e) at such place as the Secretary may require. The place, or places, shall be designated by the Secretary and shall be reasonably convenient for the employee. No physician selected by the employer, carrier, or employee shall be present at or participate in any manner in such examination, nor shall conclusions of such physicians as to the nature or extent of impairment or the cause of impairment be available to the examining physician unless otherwise ordered, for good cause, by the Secretary. Such employer or carrier shall, upon request, be entitled to have the employee examined immediately thereafter and upon the same premises by a qualified physicia</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and charges for examinations, treatment, or service; limitation; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fees and charges for examinations, treatment, or service; limitation; regulations All fees and other charges for medical examinations, treatment, or service shall be limited to such charges as prevail in the community for such treatment, and shall be subject to regulation by the Secretary. The Secretary shall issue regulations limiting the nature and extent of medical expenses chargeable against the employer without authorization by the employer or the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Third party liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Third party liability The liability of an employer for medical treatment as herein provided shall not be affected by the fact that his employee was injured through the fault or negligence of a third party not in the same employ, or that suit has been brought against such third party. The employer shall, however, have a cause of action against such third party to recover any amounts paid by him for such medical treatment in like manner as provided in section 933(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physicians’ ineligibility for subsection (e) physical examinations and reviews because of workmen’s compensation claim employment or fee acceptance or participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Physicians’ ineligibility for subsection (e) physical examinations and reviews because of workmen’s compensation claim employment or fee acceptance or participation Unless the parties to the claim agree, the Secretary shall not employ or select any physician for the purpose of making examinations or reviews under subsection (e) of this section who, during such employment, or during the period of two years prior to such employment, has been employed by, or accepted or participated in any fee relating to a workmen’s compensation claim from any insurance carrier or any self-insurer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure; judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Procedure; judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>