<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/908" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/908/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/908/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_908"><akn:num>908</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation for disability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 908. Compensation for disability
Compensation for disability shall be paid to the employee as follows:(a) Permanent total disability: In case of total disability adjudged to be permanent 66⅔ per centum of the average weekly wages shall be paid to the employee during the continuance of such total disability. Loss of both hands, or both arms, or both feet, or both legs, or both eyes, or of any two thereof shall, in the absence of conclusive proof to the contrary, constitute permanent total disability. In all other cases permanent total disability shall be determined in accordance with the facts.

(b) Temporary total disability: In case of disability total in character but temporary in quality 66⅔ per centum of the average weekly wages shall be paid to the employee during the continuance thereof.

(c) Permanent partial disability: In case of disability partial in character but permanent in quality the compensation shall be 66⅔ per centum of the average weekly wages, which shall be in addition to compensation for temporary total disability or temporary partial disability paid in accordance with subsection (b) or subsection (e) of this section, respectively, and shall be paid to the employee, as follows:(1) Arm lost, three hundred and twelve weeks’ compensation.

(2) Leg lost, two hundred and eighty-eight weeks’ compensation.

(3) Hand lost, two hundred and forty-four weeks’ compensation.

(4) Foot lost, two hundred and five weeks’ compensation.

(5) Eye lost, one hundred and sixty weeks’ compensation.

(6) Thumb lost, seventy-five weeks’ compensation.

(7) First finger lost, forty-six weeks’ compensation.

(8) Great toe lost, thirty-eight weeks’ compensation.

(9) Second finger lost, thirty weeks’ compensation.

(10) Third finger lost, twenty-five weeks’ compensation.

(11) Toe other than great toe lost, sixteen weeks’ compensation.

(12) Fourth finger lost, fifteen weeks’ compensation.

(13) Loss of hearing:(A) Compensation for loss of hearing in one ear, fifty-two w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Permanent total disability: In case of total disability adjudged to be permanent 66⅔ per centum of the average weekly wages shall be paid to the employee during the continuance of such total disability. Loss of both hands, or both arms, or both feet, or both legs, or both eyes, or of any two thereof shall, in the absence of conclusive proof to the contrary, constitute permanent total disability. In all other cases permanent total disability shall be determined in accordance with the facts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Temporary total disability: In case of disability total in character but temporary in quality 66⅔ per centum of the average weekly wages shall be paid to the employee during the continuance thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Permanent partial disability: In case of disability partial in character but permanent in quality the compensation shall be 66⅔ per centum of the average weekly wages, which shall be in addition to compensation for temporary total disability or temporary partial disability paid in accordance with subsection (b) or subsection (e) of this section, respectively, and shall be paid to the employee, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Temporary partial disability: In case of temporary partial disability resulting in decrease of earning capacity the compensation shall be two-thirds of the difference between the injured employee’s average weekly wages before the injury and his wage-earning capacity after the injury in the same or another employment, to be paid during the continuance of such disability, but shall not be paid for a period exceeding five years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Injury increasing disability:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Maintenance for employees undergoing vocational rehabilitation: An employee who as a result of injury is or may be expected to be totally or partially incapacitated for a remunerative occupation and who, under the direction of the Secretary as provided by section 939(c) of this title, is being rendered fit to engage in a remunerative occupation, shall receive additional compensation necessary for his maintenance, but such additional compensation shall not exceed $25 a week. The expense shall be paid out of the special fund established in section 944 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The wage-earning capacity of an injured employee in cases of partial disability under subsection (c)(21) of this section or under subsection (e) of this section shall be determined by his actual earnings if such actual earnings fairly and reasonably represent his wage-earning capacity: Provided, however, That if the employee has no actual earnings or his actual earnings do not fairly and reasonably represent his wage-earning capacity, the deputy commissioner may, in the interest of justice, fix such wage-earning capacity as shall be reasonable, having due regard to the nature of his injury, the degree of physical impairment, his usual employment, and any other factors or circumstances in the case which may affect his capacity to earn wages in his disabled condition, including the effect of disability as it may naturally extend into the future.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_908_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>