<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/944" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/944/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/33/944/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_944"><akn:num>944</akn:num><akn:heading>Special fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 944. Special fund(a) Establishment; administration; custody, trustThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a special fund. Such fund shall be administered by the Secretary. The Treasurer of the United States shall be the custodian of such fund, and all moneys and securities in such fund shall be held in trust by such Treasurer and shall not be money or property of the United States.


(b) Disbursements; bond of custodianThe Treasurer is authorized to disburse moneys from such fund only upon order of the Secretary. He shall be required to give bond in an amount to be fixed and with securities to be approved by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Comptroller General of the United States conditioned upon the faithful performance of his duty as custodian of such fund.


(c) Payments into fundPayments into such fund shall be made as follows:(1) Whenever the Secretary determines that there is no person entitled under this chapter to compensation for the death of an employee which would otherwise be compensable under this chapter, the appropriate employer shall pay $5,000 as compensation for the death of such an employee.

(2) At the beginning of each calendar year the Secretary shall estimate the probable expenses of the fund during that calendar year and the amount of payments required (and the schedule therefor) to maintain adequate reserves in the fund. Each carrier and self-insurer shall make payments into the fund on a prorated assessment by the Secretary determined by—(A) computing the ratio (expressed as a percent) of (i) the carrier’s or self-insured’s workers’ compensation payments under this chapter during the preceding calendar year, to (ii) the total of such payments by all carriers and self-insureds under this chapter during such year;

(B) computing the ratio (expressed as a percent) of (i) the payments under section 908(f) of this title during the preceding calendar year which are attributable to the carrier or self-insured, to (ii) the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; administration; custody, trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; administration; custody, trust There is established in the Treasury of the United States a special fund. Such fund shall be administered by the Secretary. The Treasurer of the United States shall be the custodian of such fund, and all moneys and securities in such fund shall be held in trust by such Treasurer and shall not be money or property of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbursements; bond of custodian</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disbursements; bond of custodian The Treasurer is authorized to disburse moneys from such fund only upon order of the Secretary. He shall be required to give bond in an amount to be fixed and with securities to be approved by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Comptroller General of the United States conditioned upon the faithful performance of his duty as custodian of such fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments into fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments into fund Payments into such fund shall be made as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations; records, availability; recordkeeping; provisions of sections 49 and 50 of title 15 applicable to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Investigations; records, availability; recordkeeping; provisions of sections 49 and 50 of title 15 applicable to Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Depositories; investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Depositories; investments The Treasurer of the United States shall deposit any moneys paid into such fund into such depository banks as the Secretary may designate and may invest any portion of the funds which, in the opinion of the Secretary, is not needed for current requirements, in bonds or notes of the United States or of any Federal land bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation of liability Neither the United States nor the Secretary shall be liable in respect of payments authorized under section 908 of this title in an amount greater than the money or property deposited in or belonging to such fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit by Comptroller General; finality of payment determinations; credits of disbursing officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Audit by Comptroller General; finality of payment determinations; credits of disbursing officers The Comptroller General of the United States shall audit the account for such fund, but the action of the Secretary in making payments from such fund shall be final and not subject to review, and the Comptroller General is authorized and directed to allow credit in the accounts of any disbursing officer of the Secretary for payments made from such fund authorized by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions for civil penalties and unpaid assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Civil actions for civil penalties and unpaid assessments All civil penalties and unpaid assessments provided for in this chapter shall be collected by civil suit brought by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeds available for certain payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Proceeds available for certain payments The proceeds of this fund shall be available for payments:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_944_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Audit to Congress The fund shall be audited annually and the results of such audit shall be included in the annual report required by section 942 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>