<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1124" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1124/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1124/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1124"><akn:num>1124</akn:num><akn:heading>Tests of innovative procurement methods and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1124. Tests of innovative procurement methods and procedures(a) In General.—The Administrator may develop innovative procurement methods and procedures to be tested by selected executive agencies. In developing a program to test innovative procurement methods and procedures under this subsection, the Administrator shall consult with the heads of executive agencies to—(1) ascertain the need for and specify the objectives of the program;

(2) develop the guidelines and procedures for carrying out the program and the criteria to be used in measuring the success of the program;

(3) evaluate the potential costs and benefits which may be derived from the innovative procurement methods and procedures tested under the program;

(4) select the appropriate executive agencies or components of executive agencies to carry out the program;

(5) specify the categories and types of products or services to be procured under the program; and

(6) develop the methods to be used to analyze the results of the program.


(b) Approval of Executive Agencies Required.—A program to test innovative procurement methods and procedures may not be carried out unless approved by the heads of the executive agencies selected to carry out the program.

(c) Request for Waiver of Law.—If the Administrator determines that it is necessary to waive the application of a provision of law to carry out a proposed program to test innovative procurement methods and procedures under subsection (a), the Administrator shall transmit notice of the proposed program to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and request that the Committees take the necessary action to provide that the provision of law does not apply with respect to the proposed program. The notification to Congress shall include—(1) a description of the proposed program (including the scope and purpose of the proposed program);

(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1124_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator may develop innovative procurement methods and procedures to be tested by selected executive agencies. In developing a program to test innovative procurement methods and procedures under this subsection, the Administrator shall consult with the heads of executive agencies to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1124_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of Executive Agencies Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A program to test innovative procurement methods and procedures may not be carried out unless approved by the heads of the executive agencies selected to carry out the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1124_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for Waiver of Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) If the Administrator determines that it is necessary to waive the application of a provision of law to carry out a proposed program to test innovative procurement methods and procedures under subsection (a), the Administrator shall transmit notice of the proposed program to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and request that the Committees take the necessary action to provide that the provision of law does not apply with respect to the proposed program. The notification to Congress shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>