<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1323"><akn:num>1323</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions and authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1323. Functions and authorities(a) In General.—The Council shall perform functions that include the following:(1) Identifying and recommending development by the National Institute of Standards and Technology of supply chain risk management standards, guidelines, and practices for executive agencies to use when assessing and developing mitigation strategies to address supply chain risks, particularly in the acquisition and use of covered articles under section 1326(a) of this title.

(2) Identifying or developing criteria for sharing information with executive agencies, other Federal entities, and non-Federal entities with respect to supply chain risk, including information related to the exercise of authorities provided under this section and sections 1326 and 4713 of this title. At a minimum, such criteria shall address—(A) the content to be shared;

(B) the circumstances under which sharing is mandated or voluntary; and

(C) the circumstances under which it is appropriate for an executive agency to rely on information made available through such sharing in exercising the responsibilities and authorities provided under this section and section 4713 of this title.


(3) Identifying an appropriate executive agency to—(A) accept information submitted by executive agencies based on the criteria established under paragraph (2);

(B) facilitate the sharing of information received under subparagraph (A) to support supply chain risk analyses under section 1326 of this title, recommendations under this section, and covered procurement actions under section 4713 of this title;

(C) share with the Council information regarding covered procurement actions by executive agencies taken under section 4713 of this title; and

(D) inform the Council of orders issued under this section.


(4) Identifying, as appropriate, executive agencies to provide—(A) shared services, such as support for making risk assessments, validation of products that may be suitable for acquisition, and m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Council shall perform functions that include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Office and Committees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Council may establish a program office and any committees, working groups, or other constituent bodies the Council deems appropriate, in its sole and unreviewable discretion, to carry out its functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for Exclusion or Removal Orders.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Request Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Council may request such information from executive agencies as is necessary for the Council to carry out its functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Councils.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Council shall consult and coordinate, as appropriate, with other relevant councils and interagency committees, including the Chief Information Officers Council, the Chief Acquisition Officers Council, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council, and the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, with respect to supply chain risks posed by the acquisition and use of covered articles.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>