<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1502"><akn:num>1502</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost accounting standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1502. Cost accounting standards(a) Authority.—(1) Cost accounting standards board.—The Cost Accounting Standards Board has exclusive authority to prescribe, amend, and rescind cost accounting standards, and interpretations of the standards, designed to achieve uniformity and consistency in the cost accounting standards governing measurement, assignment, and allocation of costs to contracts with the Federal Government.

(2) Administrator for federal procurement policy.—The Administrator, after consultation with the Board, shall prescribe rules and procedures governing actions of the Board under this chapter. The rules and procedures shall require that any action to prescribe, amend, or rescind a standard or interpretation be approved by majority vote of the Board.


(b) Mandatory Use of Standards.—(1) Subcontract.—(A) Definition.—In this paragraph, the term “subcontract” includes a transfer of commercial products or commercial services between divisions, subsidiaries, or affiliates of a contractor or subcontractor.

(B) When standards are to be used.—Cost accounting standards prescribed under this chapter are mandatory for use by all executive agencies and by contractors and subcontractors in estimating, accumulating, and reporting costs in connection with the pricing and administration of, and settlement of disputes concerning, all negotiated prime contract and subcontract procurements with the Federal Government in excess of the amount set forth in section 3702(a)(1)(A) of title 10 as the amount is adjusted in accordance with applicable requirements of law.

(C) Nonapplication of standards.—Subparagraph (B) does not apply to—(i) a contract or subcontract for the acquisition of a commercial product or commercial service;

(ii) a contract or subcontract where the price negotiated is based on a price set by law or regulation;

(iii) a firm, fixed-price contract or subcontract awarded on the basis of adequate price competition without submission of certified cost or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory Use of Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Board Action for Prescribing Standards and Interpretations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Before prescribing cost accounting standards and interpretations, the Board shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Dates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rules, regulations, cost accounting standards, and modifications thereof prescribed or amended under this chapter shall have the full force and effect of law, and shall become effective within 120 days after publication in the Federal Register in final form, unless the Board determines that a longer period is necessary. The Board shall determine implementation dates for contractors and subcontractors. The dates may not be later than the beginning of the second fiscal year of the contractor or subcontractor after the standard becomes effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accompanying Material.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rules, regulations, cost accounting standards, and modifications thereof prescribed or amended under this chapter shall be accompanied by prefatory comments and by illustrations, if necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementing Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Board shall prescribe regulations for the implementation of cost accounting standards prescribed or interpreted under this section. The regulations shall be incorporated into the Federal Acquisition Regulation and shall require contractors and subcontractors as a condition of contracting with the Federal Government to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of Certain Sections of Title 5.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Functions exercised under this chapter are not subject to sections 551, 553 to 559, and 701 to 706 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>