<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1704"><akn:num>1704</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning and policy-making for acquisition workforce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1704. Planning and policy-making for acquisition workforce(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Associate Administrator.—The term “Associate Administrator” means the Associate Administrator for Acquisition Workforce Programs as designated by the Administrator pursuant to subsection (b).

(2) Chief Acquisition Officer.—The term “Chief Acquisition Officer” means a Chief Acquisition Officer for an executive agency appointed pursuant to section 1702 of this title.


(b) Associate Administrator for Acquisition Workforce Programs.—The Administrator shall designate a member of the Senior Executive Service as the Associate Administrator for Acquisition Workforce Programs. The Associate Administrator shall be chosen on the basis of demonstrated knowledge and expertise in acquisition, human capital, and management. The Associate Administrator shall be located in the Office of Federal Procurement Policy. The Associate Administrator shall be responsible for—(1) supervising the acquisition workforce training fund established under section 1703(i) of this title;

(2) developing, in coordination with Chief Acquisition Officers and Chief Human Capital Officers, a strategic human capital plan for the acquisition workforce of the Federal Government;

(3) reviewing and providing input to individual agency acquisition workforce succession plans;

(4) recommending to the Administrator and other senior government officials appropriate programs, policies, and practices to increase the quantity and quality of the Federal acquisition workforce;

(5) implementing workforce programs under subsections (f) through (l) of section 1703 of this title; and

(6) carrying out other functions that the Administrator may assign.


(c) Acquisition and Contracting Training Programs Within Executive Agencies.—(1) Chief Acquisition Officer authorities and responsibilities.—Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the head of an executive agency, the Chief Acquisition Officer for that agency shal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Associate Administrator for Acquisition Workforce Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator shall designate a member of the Senior Executive Service as the Associate Administrator for Acquisition Workforce Programs. The Associate Administrator shall be chosen on the basis of demonstrated knowledge and expertise in acquisition, human capital, and management. The Associate Administrator shall be located in the Office of Federal Procurement Policy. The Associate Administrator shall be responsible for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition and Contracting Training Programs Within Executive Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government-wide Policies and Evaluation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Administrator shall issue policies to promote the development of performance standards for training and uniform implementation of this section by executive agencies, with due regard for differences in program requirements among agencies that may be appropriate and warranted in view of the agency mission. The Administrator shall evaluate the implementation of the provisions of subsection (c) by executive agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on Acquisition and Contracting Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administrator shall ensure that the heads of executive agencies collect and maintain standardized information on the acquisition and contracting workforce related to the implementation of subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition Workforce Human Capital Succession Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition Workforce Development Strategic Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training in the Acquisition of Architect and Engineering Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Administrator shall ensure that a sufficient number of Federal employees are trained in the acquisition of architect and engineering services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of Recruitment and Retention Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Administrator, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall encourage executive agencies to use existing authorities, including direct hire authority and tuition assistance programs, to recruit and retain acquisition personnel and consider recruiting acquisition personnel who may be retiring from the private sector, consistent with existing laws and regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>