<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1707" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1707/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1707/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1707"><akn:num>1707</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of proposed regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1707. Publication of proposed regulations(a) Covered Policies, Regulations, Procedures, and Forms.—(1) Required comment period.—Except as provided in subsection (d), a procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form (including an amendment or modification thereto) may not take effect until 60 days after it is published for public comment in the Federal Register pursuant to subsection (b) if it—(A) relates to the expenditure of appropriated funds; and

(B)(i) has a significant effect beyond the internal operating procedures of the agency issuing the policy, regulation, procedure, or form; or

(ii) has a significant cost or administrative impact on contractors or offerors.



(2) Exception.—A policy, regulation, procedure, or form may take effect earlier than 60 days after the publication date when there are compelling circumstances for the earlier effective date, but the effective date may not be less than 30 days after the publication date.


(b) Publication in Federal Register and Comment Period.—Subject to subsection (c), the head of the agency shall have published in the Federal Register a notice of the proposed procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form and provide for a public comment period for receiving and considering the views of all interested parties on the proposal. The length of the comment period may not be less than 30 days.

(c) Contents of Notice.—Notice of a proposed procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form prepared for publication in the Federal Register shall include—(1) the text of the proposal or, if it is impracticable to publish the full text of the proposal, a summary of the proposal and a statement specifying the name, address, and telephone number of the officer or employee of the executive agency from whom the full text may be obtained; and

(2) a request for interested parties to submit comments on the proposal and the name and address of the officer or employee of the Federal Government designated to receive the c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1707_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Policies, Regulations, Procedures, and Forms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1707_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication in Federal Register and Comment Period.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to subsection (c), the head of the agency shall have published in the Federal Register a notice of the proposed procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form and provide for a public comment period for receiving and considering the views of all interested parties on the proposal. The length of the comment period may not be less than 30 days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1707_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of Notice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice of a proposed procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form prepared for publication in the Federal Register shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1707_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The requirements of subsections (a) and (b) may be waived by the officer authorized to issue a procurement policy, regulation, procedure, or form if urgent and compelling circumstances make compliance with the requirements impracticable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1707_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effectiveness of Policy, Regulation, Procedure, or Form.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>