<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/1903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1903"><akn:num>1903</akn:num><akn:heading>Special emergency procurement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1903. Special emergency procurement authority(a) Applicability.—The authorities provided in subsections (b) and (c) apply with respect to a procurement of property or services by or for an executive agency that the head of the executive agency determines are to be used—(1) in support of a contingency operation (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10);

(2) to facilitate the defense against or recovery from cyber, nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological attack against the United States;

(3) in support of a request from the Secretary of State or the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to facilitate the provision of international disaster assistance pursuant to chapter 9 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2292 et seq.); or

(4) in support of an emergency or major disaster (as those terms are defined in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5122)).


(b) Increased Thresholds and Limitation.—For a procurement to which this section applies under subsection (a)—(1) the amount specified in section 1902(a), (d), and (e) of this title shall be deemed to be—(A) $15,000 in the case of a contract to be awarded and performed, or purchase to be made, in the United States; and

(B) $25,000 in the case of a contract to be awarded and performed, or purchase to be made, outside the United States;


(2) the term “simplified acquisition threshold” means—(A) $750,000 in the case of a contract to be awarded and performed, or purchase to be made, in the United States; and

(B) $1,500,000 in the case of a contract to be awarded and performed, or purchase to be made, outside the United States; and


(3) the $5,000,000 limitation in sections 1901(a)(2) and 3305(a)(2) of this title and section 3205(a)(2) of title 10 is deemed to be $10,000,000.


(c) Authority To Treat Property or Service as Commercial Product or Commercial Service.—(1) In general.—The head of an exec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The authorities provided in subsections (b) and (c) apply with respect to a procurement of property or services by or for an executive agency that the head of the executive agency determines are to be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased Thresholds and Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For a procurement to which this section applies under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Treat Property or Service as Commercial Product or Commercial Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>