<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/2301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/2301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/2301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2301"><akn:num>2301</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of electronic commerce in Federal procurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2301. Use of electronic commerce in Federal procurement(a) Definition.—For the purposes of this section, the term “electronic commerce” means electronic techniques for accomplishing business transactions, including electronic mail or messaging, World Wide Web technology, electronic bulletin boards, purchase cards, electronic funds transfers, and electronic data interchange.

(b) Establishment, Maintenance, and Use of Electronic Commerce Procedures and Processes.—The head of each executive agency, after consulting with the Administrator, shall establish, maintain, and use, to the maximum extent that is practicable and cost-effective, procedures and processes that employ electronic commerce in the conduct and administration of the procurement system of the agency.

(c) Applicable Standards.—In conducting electronic commerce, the head of an executive agency shall apply nationally and internationally recognized standards that broaden interoperability and ease the electronic interchange of information.

(d) Requirements of Systems, Technologies, Procedures, and Processes.—The head of each executive agency shall ensure that systems, technologies, procedures, and processes established pursuant to this section—(1) are implemented with uniformity throughout the agency, to the extent practicable;

(2) are implemented only after granting due consideration to the use or partial use, as appropriate, of existing electronic commerce and electronic data interchange systems and infrastructures such as the Federal acquisition computer network architecture known as FACNET;

(3) facilitate access to Federal Government procurement opportunities, including opportunities for small business concerns, socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns, and business concerns owned predominantly by women; and

(4) ensure that any notice of agency requirements or agency solicitation for contract opportunities is provided in a form that allows convenient and universal user access</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2301_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purposes of this section, the term “electronic commerce” means electronic techniques for accomplishing business transactions, including electronic mail or messaging, World Wide Web technology, electronic bulletin boards, purchase cards, electronic funds transfers, and electronic data interchange.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2301_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment, Maintenance, and Use of Electronic Commerce Procedures and Processes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The head of each executive agency, after consulting with the Administrator, shall establish, maintain, and use, to the maximum extent that is practicable and cost-effective, procedures and processes that employ electronic commerce in the conduct and administration of the procurement system of the agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2301_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In conducting electronic commerce, the head of an executive agency shall apply nationally and internationally recognized standards that broaden interoperability and ease the electronic interchange of information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2301_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements of Systems, Technologies, Procedures, and Processes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The head of each executive agency shall ensure that systems, technologies, procedures, and processes established pursuant to this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2301_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In carrying out the requirements of this section, the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2301_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability to Department of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the term “executive agency” does not include the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>