<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3309" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3309/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3309/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3309"><akn:num>3309</akn:num><akn:heading>Design-build selection procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3309. Design-build selection procedures(a) Authorization.—Unless the traditional acquisition approach of design-bid-build established under sections 1101 to 1104 of title 40 or another acquisition procedure authorized by law is used, the head of an executive agency shall use the two-phase selection procedures authorized in this section for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when a determination is made under subsection (b) that the procedures are appropriate for use.

(b) Criteria for Use.—A contracting officer shall make a determination whether two-phase selection procedures are appropriate for use for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when—(1) the contracting officer anticipates that 3 or more offers will be received for the contract;

(2) design work must be performed before an offeror can develop a price or cost proposal for the contract;

(3) the offeror will incur a substantial amount of expense in preparing the offer; and

(4) the contracting officer has considered information such as the following:(A) The extent to which the project requirements have been adequately defined.

(B) The time constraints for delivery of the project.

(C) The capability and experience of potential contractors.

(D) The suitability of the project for use of the two-phase selection procedures.

(E) The capability of the agency to manage the two-phase selection process.

(F) Other criteria established by the agency.



(c) Procedures Described.—Two-phase selection procedures consist of the following:(1) Development of scope of work statement.—The agency develops, either in-house or by contract, a scope of work statement for inclusion in the solicitation that defines the project and provides prospective offerors with sufficient information regarding the Federal Government’s requirements (which may include criteria and preliminary design, budget parameters, an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3309_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unless the traditional acquisition approach of design-bid-build established under sections 1101 to 1104 of title 40 or another acquisition procedure authorized by law is used, the head of an executive agency shall use the two-phase selection procedures authorized in this section for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when a determination is made under subsection (b) that the procedures are appropriate for use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3309_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A contracting officer shall make a determination whether two-phase selection procedures are appropriate for use for entering into a contract for the design and construction of a public building, facility, or work when—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3309_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures Described.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Two-phase selection procedures consist of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3309_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation To State Number of Offerors To Be Selected for Phase-Two Requests for Competitive Proposals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A solicitation issued pursuant to the procedures described in subsection (c) shall state the maximum number of offerors that are to be selected to submit competitive proposals pursuant to subsection (c)(4). The maximum number specified in the solicitation shall not exceed 5 unless the agency determines with respect to an individual solicitation that a specified number greater than 5 is in the Federal Government’s interest and is consistent with the purposes and objectives of the two-phase selection process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3309_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for Guidance and Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Federal Acquisition Regulation shall include guidance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>