<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3311"><akn:num>3311</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualification requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3311. Qualification requirement(a) Definition.—In this section, the term “qualification requirement” means a requirement for testing or other quality assurance demonstration that must be completed by an offeror before award of a contract.

(b) Actions Before Enforcing Qualification Requirement.—Except as provided in subsection (c), the head of an agency, before enforcing any qualification requirement, shall—(1) prepare a written justification stating the necessity for establishing the qualification requirement and specify why the qualification requirement must be demonstrated before contract award;

(2) specify in writing and make available to a potential offeror on request all requirements that a prospective offeror, or its product, must satisfy to become qualified, with those requirements to be limited to those least restrictive to meet the purposes necessitating the establishment of the qualification requirement;

(3) specify an estimate of the cost of testing and evaluation likely to be incurred by a potential offeror to become qualified;

(4) ensure that a potential offeror is provided, on request, a prompt opportunity to demonstrate at its own expense (except as provided in subsection (d)) its ability to meet the standards specified for qualification using—(A) qualified personnel and facilities—(i) of the agency concerned;

(ii) of another agency obtained through interagency agreement; or

(iii) under contract; or


(B) other methods approved by the agency (including use of approved testing and evaluation services not provided under contract to the agency);


(5) if testing and evaluation services are provided under contract to the agency for the purposes of paragraph (4), provide to the extent possible that those services be provided by a contractor that—(A) is not expected to benefit from an absence of additional qualified sources; and

(B) is required in the contract to adhere to any restriction on technical data asserted by the potential offeror seeking </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the term “qualification requirement” means a requirement for testing or other quality assurance demonstration that must be completed by an offeror before award of a contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions Before Enforcing Qualification Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as provided in subsection (c), the head of an agency, before enforcing any qualification requirement, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability, Waiver Authority, and Referral of Offers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3311_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fewer Than 2 Actual Manufacturers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3311_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination and Revalidation of Qualification Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Within 7 years after the establishment of a qualification requirement, the need for the requirement shall be examined and the standards of the requirement revalidated in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b). This subsection does not apply in the case of a qualification requirement for which a waiver is in effect under subsection (c)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3311_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>When Enforcement of Qualification Requirement Not Allowed.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Except in an emergency as determined by the head of the agency, after the head of the agency determines not to enforce a qualification requirement for a solicitation, the agency may not enforce the requirement unless the agency complies with the requirements of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>