<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3312" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3312/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3312/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3312"><akn:num>3312</akn:num><akn:heading>Database on price trends of items and services under Federal contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3312. Database on price trends of items and services under Federal contracts(a) Database Required.—The Administrator shall establish and maintain a database of information on price trends for items and services under contracts with the Federal Government. The information in the database shall be designed to assist Federal acquisition officials in the following:(1) Monitoring developments in price trends for items and services under contracts with the Federal Government.

(2) Conducting price or cost analyses for items and services under offers for contracts with the Federal Government, or otherwise conducting determinations of the reasonableness of prices for items and services under such offers, and addressing unjustified escalation in prices being paid by the Federal Government for items and services under contracts with the Federal Government.


(b) Use.—(1) The database under subsection (a) shall be available to executive agencies in the evaluation of offers for contracts with the Federal Government for items and services.

(2) The Secretary of Defense may satisfy the requirements of this section by complying with the requirements of section 892 11 See References in Text note below. of the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 (10 U.S.C. 2306a note).


(Added Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 851(a)(1), Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 1855.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 892 of the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011, referred to in subsec. (b)(2), is section 892 of Pub. L. 111–383, which was formerly set out as a note under section 2306a of Title 10, Armed Forces, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1073(f), Nov. 25, 2015, 129 Stat. 996.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Use of Elements of Department of Defense Pilot ProjectPub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 851(b), Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 1855, provided that: “In establishing the database required by sectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3312_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Database Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator shall establish and maintain a database of information on price trends for items and services under contracts with the Federal Government. The information in the database shall be designed to assist Federal acquisition officials in the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3312_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>