<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3701"><akn:num>3701</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis of award and rejection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3701. Basis of award and rejection(a) Award.—An executive agency shall evaluate sealed bids and competitive proposals, and award a contract, based solely on the factors specified in the solicitation.

(b) Rejection.—All sealed bids or competitive proposals received in response to a solicitation may be rejected if the agency head determines that rejection is in the public interest.

(Pub. L. 111–350, § 3, Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 3770.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


3701(a)41:253b(a).June 30, 1949, ch. 288, title III, § 303B(a), (b), as added Pub. L. 98–369, title VII, § 2711(a)(2), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 1179; Pub. L. 103–355, title I, § 1061(c)(1), Oct. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 3267.
3701(b)41:253b(b).



Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Use of Lowest Price Technically Acceptable Source Selection ProcessPub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 880, Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1909, as amended by Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 806(a)(2), Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 1485; Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VIII, § 822, Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 1983, provided that:
“(a) Statement of Policy.—It shall be the policy of the United States Government to avoid using lowest price technically acceptable source selection criteria in circumstances that would deny the Government the benefits of cost and technical tradeoffs in the source selection process.

“(b) Revision of Federal Acquisition Regulation.—Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [Aug. 13, 2018], the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be revised to require that, for solicitations issued on or after the date that is 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, lowest price technically acceptable source selection criteria are used only in situations in which—“(1) an executive agency is able to comprehensively and clearly describe the minimum requirements expressed in terms of performance objectives, measure</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3701_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An executive agency shall evaluate sealed bids and competitive proposals, and award a contract, based solely on the factors specified in the solicitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3701_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rejection.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) All sealed bids or competitive proposals received in response to a solicitation may be rejected if the agency head determines that rejection is in the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>