<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3704"><akn:num>3704</akn:num><akn:heading>Post-award debriefings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3704. Post-award debriefings(a) Request for Debriefing.—When a contract is awarded by the head of an executive agency on the basis of competitive proposals, an unsuccessful offeror, on written request received by the agency within 3 days after the date on which the unsuccessful offeror receives the notification of the contract award, shall be debriefed and furnished the basis for the selection decision and contract award.

(b) When Debriefing To Be Conducted.—The executive agency shall debrief the offeror within, to the maximum extent practicable, 5 days after receipt of the request by the executive agency.

(c) Information To Be Provided.—The debriefing shall include, at a minimum—(1) the executive agency’s evaluation of the significant weak or deficient factors in the offeror’s offer;

(2) the overall evaluated cost and technical rating of the offer of the contractor awarded the contract and the overall evaluated cost and technical rating of the offer of the debriefed offeror;

(3) the overall ranking of all offers;

(4) a summary of the rationale for the award;

(5) in the case of a proposal that includes a commercial product that is an end item under the contract, the make and model of the item being provided in accordance with the offer of the contractor awarded the contract; and

(6) reasonable responses to relevant questions posed by the debriefed offeror as to whether source selection procedures set forth in the solicitation, applicable regulations, and other applicable authorities were followed by the executive agency.


(d) Information Not To Be Included.—The debriefing may not include point-by-point comparisons of the debriefed offeror’s offer with other offers and may not disclose any information that is exempt from disclosure under section 552(b) of title 5.

(e) Inclusion of Statement in Solicitation.—Each solicitation for competitive proposals shall include a statement that information described in subsection (c) may be disclosed in post-award debri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for Debriefing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) When a contract is awarded by the head of an executive agency on the basis of competitive proposals, an unsuccessful offeror, on written request received by the agency within 3 days after the date on which the unsuccessful offeror receives the notification of the contract award, shall be debriefed and furnished the basis for the selection decision and contract award.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>When Debriefing To Be Conducted.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The executive agency shall debrief the offeror within, to the maximum extent practicable, 5 days after receipt of the request by the executive agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information To Be Provided.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The debriefing shall include, at a minimum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Not To Be Included.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The debriefing may not include point-by-point comparisons of the debriefed offeror’s offer with other offers and may not disclose any information that is exempt from disclosure under section 552(b) of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of Statement in Solicitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Each solicitation for competitive proposals shall include a statement that information described in subsection (c) may be disclosed in post-award debriefings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>After Successful Protest.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) If, within one year after the date of the contract award and as a result of a successful procurement protest, the executive agency seeks to fulfill the requirement under the protested contract either on the basis of a new solicitation of offers or on the basis of new best and final offers requested for that contract, the head of the executive agency shall make available to all offerors—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Summary To Be Included in File.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The contracting officer shall include a summary of the debriefing in the contract file.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>