<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/3904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3904"><akn:num>3904</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract authority for severable services contracts and multiyear contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3904. Contract authority for severable services contracts and multiyear contracts(a) Comptroller General.—The Comptroller General may use available funds to enter into contracts for the procurement of severable services for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year and to enter into multiyear contracts for the acquisition of property and nonaudit-related services to the same extent as executive agencies under sections 3902 and 3903 of this title.

(b) Library of Congress.—The Library of Congress may use available funds to enter into contracts for the lease or procurement of severable services for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year and to enter into multiyear contracts for the acquisition of property and services pursuant to sections 3902 and 3903 of this title.

(c) Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.—The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives may enter into—(1) contracts for the procurement of severable services for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year to the same extent as the head of an executive agency under the authority of section 3902 of this title; and

(2) multiyear contracts for the acquisitions of property and nonaudit-related services to the same extent as executive agencies under the authority of section 3903 of this title.


(d) Congressional Budget Office.—The Congressional Budget Office may use available funds to enter into contracts for the procurement of severable services for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year and may enter into multiyear contracts for the acquisition of property and services to the same extent as executive agencies under the authority of sections 3902 and 3903 of this title.

(e) Secretary and Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.—Subject to regulations prescribed by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Secr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3904_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comptroller General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Comptroller General may use available funds to enter into contracts for the procurement of severable services for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year and to enter into multiyear contracts for the acquisition of property and nonaudit-related services to the same extent as executive agencies under sections 3902 and 3903 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3904_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Library of Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Library of Congress may use available funds to enter into contracts for the lease or procurement of severable services for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year and to enter into multiyear contracts for the acquisition of property and services pursuant to sections 3902 and 3903 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3904_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives may enter into—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3904_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Budget Office.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Congressional Budget Office may use available funds to enter into contracts for the procurement of severable services for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in the next fiscal year and may enter into multiyear contracts for the acquisition of property and services to the same extent as executive agencies under the authority of sections 3902 and 3903 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3904_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary and Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subject to regulations prescribed by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Secretary and the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate may enter into—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3904_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capitol Police.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The United States Capitol Police may enter into—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3904_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Architect of the Capitol.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Architect of the Capitol may enter into—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3904_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution may enter into—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>