<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/4705" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/4705/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/4705/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4705"><akn:num>4705</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of contractor employees from reprisal for disclosure of certain information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4705. Protection of contractor employees from reprisal for disclosure of certain information(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Contract.—The term “contract” means a contract awarded by the head of an executive agency.

(2) Contractor.—The term “contractor” means a person awarded a contract with an executive agency.

(3) Inspector general.—The term “Inspector General” means an Inspector General appointed under chapter 4 of title 5.


(b) Prohibition of Reprisals.—An employee of a contractor may not be discharged, demoted, or otherwise discriminated against as a reprisal for disclosing to a Member of Congress or an authorized official of an executive agency or the Department of Justice information relating to a substantial violation of law related to a contract (including the competition for, or negotiation of, a contract).

(c) Investigation of Complaints.—An individual who believes that the individual has been subjected to a reprisal prohibited by subsection (b) may submit a complaint to the Inspector General of the executive agency. Unless the Inspector General determines that the complaint is frivolous, the Inspector General shall investigate the complaint and, on completion of the investigation, submit a report of the findings of the investigation to the individual, the contractor concerned, and the head of the agency. If the executive agency does not have an Inspector General, the duties of the Inspector General under this section shall be performed by an official designated by the head of the executive agency.

(d) Remedy and Enforcement Authority.—(1) Actions contractor may be ordered to take.—If the head of an executive agency determines that a contractor has subjected an individual to a reprisal prohibited by subsection (b), the head of the executive agency may take one or more of the following actions:(A) Abatement.—Order the contractor to take affirmative action to abate the reprisal.

(B) Reinstatement.—Order the contractor to reinstate the individual</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4705_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4705_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of Reprisals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An employee of a contractor may not be discharged, demoted, or otherwise discriminated against as a reprisal for disclosing to a Member of Congress or an authorized official of an executive agency or the Department of Justice information relating to a substantial violation of law related to a contract (including the competition for, or negotiation of, a contract).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4705_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation of Complaints.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An individual who believes that the individual has been subjected to a reprisal prohibited by subsection (b) may submit a complaint to the Inspector General of the executive agency. Unless the Inspector General determines that the complaint is frivolous, the Inspector General shall investigate the complaint and, on completion of the investigation, submit a report of the findings of the investigation to the individual, the contractor concerned, and the head of the agency. If the executive agency does not have an Inspector General, the duties of the Inspector General under this section shall be performed by an official designated by the head of the executive agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4705_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedy and Enforcement Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4705_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of Section.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) This section does not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4705_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Four-year Suspension of Effectiveness While Pilot Program Is in Effect.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) While section 4712 11 See References in Text note below. of this title is in effect, this section shall not be in effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>