<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/4712" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/4712/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/4712/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4712"><akn:num>4712</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancement of contractor protection from reprisal for disclosure of certain information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4712. Enhancement of contractor protection from reprisal for disclosure of certain information(a) Prohibition of Reprisals.—(1) In general.—An employee of a contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor may not be discharged, demoted, or otherwise discriminated against as a reprisal for disclosing to a person or body described in paragraph (2) information that the employee reasonably believes is evidence of gross mismanagement of a Federal contract or grant, a gross waste of Federal funds, an abuse of authority relating to a Federal contract or grant, a substantial and specific danger to public health or safety, or a violation of law, rule, or regulation related to a Federal contract (including the competition for or negotiation of a contract) or grant.

(2) Persons and bodies covered.—The persons and bodies described in this paragraph are the persons and bodies as follows:(A) A Member of Congress or a representative of a committee of Congress.

(B) An Inspector General.

(C) The Government Accountability Office.

(D) A Federal employee responsible for contract or grant oversight or management at the relevant agency.

(E) An authorized official of the Department of Justice or other law enforcement agency.

(F) A court or grand jury.

(G) A management official or other employee of the contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor who has the responsibility to investigate, discover, or address misconduct.


(3) Rules of construction.—For the purposes of paragraph (1)—(A) an employee who initiates or provides evidence of contractor, subcontractor, grantee, subgrantee, or personal services contractor misconduct in any judicial or administrative proceeding relating to waste, fraud, or abuse on a Federal contract or grant shall be deemed to have made a disclosure covered by such paragraph; and

(B) a reprisal described in paragraph (1) is prohibited even if it is undertaken at the request of an executiv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4712_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of Reprisals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4712_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation of Complaints.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4712_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedy and Enforcement Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4712_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The head of each executive agency shall ensure that contractors, subcontractors, grantees, subgrantees, and personal services contractors of the agency inform their employees in writing of the rights and remedies provided under this section, in the predominant native language of the workforce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4712_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize the discharge of, demotion of, or discrimination against an employee for a disclosure other than a disclosure protected by subsection (a) or to modify or derogate from a right or remedy otherwise available to the employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4712_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4712_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4712_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Nothing in this section, or the amendments made by this section,11 So in original. shall be construed to provide any rights to disclose classified information not otherwise provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>