<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/6506" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/6506/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/6506/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6506"><akn:num>6506</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6506. Administrative provisions(a) In General.—The Secretary shall administer this chapter.

(b) Regulations.—The Secretary may make, amend, and rescind regulations as necessary to carry out this chapter.

(c) Use of Government Officers and Employees.—The Secretary shall use Federal officers and employees and, with a State’s consent, State and local officers and employees as the Secretary finds necessary to assist in the administration of this chapter.

(d) Appointments.—The Secretary shall appoint an administrative officer and attorneys, experts, and other employees from time to time as the Secretary finds necessary for the administration of this chapter. The appointments are subject to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 and other law applicable to the employment and compensation of officers and employees of the Federal Government.

(e) Investigations.—The Secretary, or an authorized representative of the Secretary, may make investigations and findings as provided in this chapter and may, in any part of the United States, prosecute an inquiry necessary to carry out this chapter.

(Pub. L. 111–350, § 3, Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 3809.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


650641:38.June 30, 1936, ch. 881, § 4, 49 Stat. 2038.


In subsection (b), the word “rules” is omitted as included in “regulations”.
In subsection (c), the words “and to prescribe rules and regulations with respect thereto” are omitted as unnecessary because of subsection (b).
In subsection (d), the words “without regard to the provisions of the civil-service laws”, which appear in section 4 of the Walsh-Healey Act (June 30, 1936, ch. 881, 49 Stat. 2038), are omitted as obsolete because of Executive Order 8743, April 23, 1941 (5 U.S.C. 3301 note), issued by the President pursuant to the Act of November 26, 1940, ch. 919, title I, § 1, 54 Stat. 1211. The words “the Classification Act of 1923”, which appear in sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall administer this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may make, amend, and rescind regulations as necessary to carry out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Government Officers and Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall use Federal officers and employees and, with a State’s consent, State and local officers and employees as the Secretary finds necessary to assist in the administration of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall appoint an administrative officer and attorneys, experts, and other employees from time to time as the Secretary finds necessary for the administration of this chapter. The appointments are subject to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 and other law applicable to the employment and compensation of officers and employees of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary, or an authorized representative of the Secretary, may make investigations and findings as provided in this chapter and may, in any part of the United States, prosecute an inquiry necessary to carry out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>