<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/6508" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/6508/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/6508/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6508"><akn:num>6508</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to make exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6508. Authority to make exceptions(a) Duty of the Secretary To Make Exceptions.—When the head of an agency of the United States makes a written finding that the inclusion of representations or stipulations under section 6502 of this title in a proposal or contract will seriously impair the conduct of Federal Government business, the Secretary shall make exceptions, in specific cases or otherwise, when justice or the public interest will be served.

(b) Authority of the Secretary To Modify Existing Contracts.—When an agency of the United States and a contractor jointly recommend, the Secretary may modify the terms of an existing contract with respect to minimum wages and maximum hours of labor as the Secretary finds necessary and proper in the public interest or to prevent injustice and undue hardship.

(c) Authority of the Secretary To Allow Limitations, Variations, Tolerances, and Exemptions.—The Secretary may provide reasonable limitations and may prescribe regulations to allow reasonable variations, tolerances, and exemptions in the application of this chapter to contractors, including with respect to minimum wages and maximum hours of labor.

(d) Rate of Pay for Overtime.—When the Secretary permits an increase in the maximum hours of labor stipulated in a contract, the Secretary shall set a rate of pay for overtime. The overtime rate must be at least one and one-half times the basic hourly rate.

(e) Authority of the President To Suspend.—The President may suspend any of the representations and stipulations contained in section 6502 of this title whenever, in the President’s judgment, suspension is in the public interest.

(Pub. L. 111–350, § 3, Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 3810.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


6508(a)41:40 (1st sentence).June 30, 1936, ch. 881, § 6, 49 Stat. 2038; June 28, 1940, ch. 440, title I, § 13, 54 Stat. 681.
6508(b)41:40 (2d sentence).
6508(c)41:40 (3d sentence).
6508</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6508_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of the Secretary To Make Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) When the head of an agency of the United States makes a written finding that the inclusion of representations or stipulations under section 6502 of this title in a proposal or contract will seriously impair the conduct of Federal Government business, the Secretary shall make exceptions, in specific cases or otherwise, when justice or the public interest will be served.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6508_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the Secretary To Modify Existing Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) When an agency of the United States and a contractor jointly recommend, the Secretary may modify the terms of an existing contract with respect to minimum wages and maximum hours of labor as the Secretary finds necessary and proper in the public interest or to prevent injustice and undue hardship.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6508_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the Secretary To Allow Limitations, Variations, Tolerances, and Exemptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may provide reasonable limitations and may prescribe regulations to allow reasonable variations, tolerances, and exemptions in the application of this chapter to contractors, including with respect to minimum wages and maximum hours of labor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6508_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate of Pay for Overtime.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) When the Secretary permits an increase in the maximum hours of labor stipulated in a contract, the Secretary shall set a rate of pay for overtime. The overtime rate must be at least one and one-half times the basic hourly rate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6508_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the President To Suspend.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The President may suspend any of the representations and stipulations contained in section 6502 of this title whenever, in the President’s judgment, suspension is in the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>