<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/6510" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/6510/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/6510/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6510"><akn:num>6510</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturers and regular dealers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6510. Manufacturers and regular dealers(a) Prescribing Standards.—The Secretary may prescribe, in regulations, standards for determining whether a contractor is a manufacturer or regular dealer with respect to materials, supplies, articles, or equipment to be manufactured or furnished under, or used in the performance of, a contract entered into by an agency of the United States.

(b) Judicial Review.—An interested person has the right of judicial review of any legal question relating to interpretation of the terms “regular dealer” and “manufacturer” as defined pursuant to subsection (a).

(Pub. L. 111–350, § 3, Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 3811.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


651041:43b.June 30, 1936, ch. 881, § 11, as added Pub. L. 103–355, title VII, § 7201(4), Oct. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 3378; Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(f)(1)(A), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 675.


In subsection (a), the words “an agency of the United States” are substituted for “any executive department, independent establishment, or other agency or instrumentality of the United States, or by the District of Columbia, or by any corporation all the stock of which is beneficially owned by the United States” because of the definition in section 6501 of the revised title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6510_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prescribing Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary may prescribe, in regulations, standards for determining whether a contractor is a manufacturer or regular dealer with respect to materials, supplies, articles, or equipment to be manufactured or furnished under, or used in the performance of, a contract entered into by an agency of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6510_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An interested person has the right of judicial review of any legal question relating to interpretation of the terms “regular dealer” and “manufacturer” as defined pursuant to subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>