<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/7103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/7103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/41/7103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7103"><akn:num>7103</akn:num><akn:heading>Decision by contracting officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7103. Decision by contracting officer(a) Claims Generally.—(1) Submission of contractor’s claims to contracting officer.—Each claim by a contractor against the Federal Government relating to a contract shall be submitted to the contracting officer for a decision.

(2) Contractor’s claims in writing.—Each claim by a contractor against the Federal Government relating to a contract shall be in writing.

(3) Contracting officer to decide federal government’s claims.—Each claim by the Federal Government against a contractor relating to a contract shall be the subject of a written decision by the contracting officer.

(4) Time for submitting claims.—(A) In general.—Each claim by a contractor against the Federal Government relating to a contract and each claim by the Federal Government against a contractor relating to a contract shall be submitted within 6 years after the accrual of the claim.

(B) Exception.—Subparagraph (A) of this paragraph does not apply to a claim by the Federal Government against a contractor that is based on a claim by the contractor involving fraud.


(5) Applicability.—The authority of this subsection and subsections (c)(1), (d), and (e) does not extend to a claim or dispute for penalties or forfeitures prescribed by statute or regulation that another Federal agency is specifically authorized to administer, settle, or determine.


(b) Certification of Claims.—(1) Requirement generally.—For claims of more than $100,000 made by a contractor, the contractor shall certify that—(A) the claim is made in good faith;

(B) the supporting data are accurate and complete to the best of the contractor’s knowledge and belief;

(C) the amount requested accurately reflects the contract adjustment for which the contractor believes the Federal Government is liable; and

(D) the certifier is authorized to certify the claim on behalf of the contractor.


(2) Who may execute certification.—The certification required by paragraph (1) may be executed by an individual </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claims Generally.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of Claims.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fraudulent Claims.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of Decision.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The contracting officer shall issue a decision in writing and shall mail or otherwise furnish a copy of the decision to the contractor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of Decision.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The contracting officer’s decision shall state the reasons for the decision reached and shall inform the contractor of the contractor’s rights as provided in this chapter. Specific findings of fact are not required. If made, specific findings of fact are not binding in any subsequent proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Issuance of Decision.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of Decision Unless Appealed.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The contracting officer’s decision on a claim is final and conclusive and is not subject to review by any forum, tribunal, or Federal Government agency, unless an appeal or action is timely commenced as authorized by this chapter. This chapter does not prohibit an executive agency from including a clause in a Federal Government contract requiring that, pending final decision of an appeal, action, or final settlement, a contractor shall proceed diligently with performance of the contract in accordance with the contracting officer’s decision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative Means of Dispute Resolution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>