<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1308" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1308/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1308/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1308"><akn:num>1308</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on importation of dog and cat fur products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1308. Prohibition on importation of dog and cat fur products(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Cat furThe term “cat fur” means the pelt or skin of any animal of the species Felis catus.


(2) Interstate commerceThe term “interstate commerce” means the transportation for sale, trade, or use between any State, territory, or possession of the United States, or the District of Columbia, and any place outside thereof.


(3) Customs lawsThe term “customs laws of the United States” means any other law or regulation enforced or administered by the United States Customs Service.


(4) Designated authorityThe term “designated authority” means the Secretary of the Treasury, with respect to the prohibitions under subsection (b)(1)(A), and the President (or the President’s designee), with respect to the prohibitions under subsection (b)(1)(B).


(5) Dog furThe term “dog fur” means the pelt or skin of any animal of the species Canis familiaris.


(6) Dog or cat fur productThe term “dog or cat fur product” means any item of merchandise which consists, or is composed in whole or in part, of any dog fur, cat fur, or both.


(7) PersonThe term “person” includes any individual, partnership, corporation, association, organization, business trust, government entity, or other entity subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.


(8) United StatesThe term “United States” means the customs territory of the United States, as defined in general note 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.



(b) Prohibitions(1) In generalIt shall be unlawful for any person to—(A) import into, or export from, the United States any dog or cat fur product; or

(B) introduce into interstate commerce, manufacture for introduction into interstate commerce, sell, trade, or advertise in interstate commerce, offer to sell, or transport or distribute in interstate commerce in the United States, any dog or cat fur product.


(2) ExceptionThis subsection shall not apply to the importation, expor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1308_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1308_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1308_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Penalties and enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1308_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of names of certain violators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publication of names of certain violators The designated authorities shall, at least once each year, publish in the Federal Register a list of the names of any producer, manufacturer, supplier, seller, importer, or exporter, whether or not located within the customs territory of the United States or subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, against whom a final administrative determination with respect to the assessment of a civil penalty for a knowing and intentional or a grossly negligent violation has been made under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>