<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1312" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1312/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1312/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1312"><akn:num>1312</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonded smelting and refining warehouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1312. Bonded smelting and refining warehouses(a) Bond; charges against bondAny plant engaged in smelting or refining, or both, of metal-bearing materials as defined in this section may, upon the giving of satisfactory bond, be designated a bonded smelting or refining warehouse. Metal-bearing materials may be entered into a bonded smelting or refining warehouse without the payment of duties thereon and there smelted or refined, or both, together with metal-bearing materials of domestic or foreign origin. Upon arrival of imported metal-bearing materials at the warehouse they shall be sampled according to commercial methods and assayed, both under customs supervision. The bond shall be charged with a sum equal in amount to the duties which would be payable on such metal-bearing materials in their condition as imported if entered for consumption, and the bond charge shall be adjusted to reflect changes in the applicable rate of duty occurring while the imported materials are still covered by the bond.


(b) Cancellation of charges against bondThe several charges against such bond may be canceled in whole or in part—(1) upon the exportation from the bonded warehouses which treated the metal-bearing materials, or from any other bonded smelting or refining warehouse, of a quantity of the same kind of metal contained in any product of smelting or refining of metal-bearing materials equal to the dutiable quantity contained in the imported metal-bearing materials less wastage provided for in subsection (c); except that—(A) in the case of a withdrawal for exportation of such a product to a USMCA country, as defined in section 4502 of this title, if any of the imported metal-bearing materials are goods subject to USMCA drawback, as defined in section 4534(a) of this title, the duties on the materials shall be paid, and the charges against the bond canceled, before the 61st day after the date of exportation; but upon the presentation, before such 61st day, of satisfactory evid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond; charges against bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Bond; charges against bond Any plant engaged in smelting or refining, or both, of metal-bearing materials as defined in this section may, upon the giving of satisfactory bond, be designated a bonded smelting or refining warehouse. Metal-bearing materials may be entered into a bonded smelting or refining warehouse without the payment of duties thereon and there smelted or refined, or both, together with metal-bearing materials of domestic or foreign origin. Upon arrival of imported metal-bearing materials at the warehouse they shall be sampled according to commercial methods and assayed, both under customs supervision. The bond shall be charged with a sum equal in amount to the duties which would be payable on such metal-bearing materials in their condition as imported if entered for consumption, and the bond charge shall be adjusted to reflect changes in the applicable rate of duty occurring while the imported materials are still covered by the bond.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation of charges against bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cancellation of charges against bond The several charges against such bond may be canceled in whole or in part— If Canada ceases to be a USMCA country and the suspension of the operation of the United States-Canada Free-Trade Agreement thereafter terminates, no charges against such bond may be canceled in whole or part upon an exportation to Canada under paragraph (1) or (4) during the period such Agreement is in operation except to the extent that the metal-bearing materials were of Canadian origin as determined in accordance with section 202 of the United States-Canada Free-Trade Agreement Implementation Act of 1988.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance on bond for wastage of metals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allowance on bond for wastage of metals For purposes of paragraphs (1), (3), (4), and (5) of subsection (b), due allowances shall be made for wastage of metals other than copper, lead, and zinc, as ascertained from time to time by the Secretary of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for exportation of product other than refined metal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Credit for exportation of product other than refined metal Upon the exportation of a product of smelting or refining other than refined metal the bond shall be credited with a quantity of metal equivalent to the quantity of metal contained in the product exported less the proportionate part of the deductions allowed for losses in determination of the bond charge being cancelled that would not ordinarily be sustained in production of the specific product exported as ascertained from time to time by the Secretary of the Treasury; except that— If Canada ceases to be a USMCA country and the suspension of the operation of the United States-Canada Free-Trade Agreement thereafter terminates, no bond shall be credited under this subsection with respect to an exportation of a product to Canada during the period such Agreement is in operation except to the extent that the product is a drawback eligible good under section 204(a) of the United States-Canada Free-Trade Agreement Implementation </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>General bond for two or more warehouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) General bond for two or more warehouses Two or more smelting or refining warehouses may be included under one general bond and the quantities of each kind of metal subject to duty on hand at all of such warehouses may be aggregated to satisfy the bond obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision and cost of labor under this section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Supervision and cost of labor under this section Labor performed and services rendered pursuant to this section shall be under the supervision of an officer of the customs, to be appointed by the Secretary of the Treasury and at the expense of the manufacturer. The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>