<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1313"><akn:num>1313</akn:num><akn:heading>Drawback and refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1313. Drawback and refunds(a) Articles made from imported merchandiseUpon the exportation or destruction under customs supervision of articles manufactured or produced in the United States with the use of imported merchandise, provided that those articles have not been used prior to such exportation or destruction, an amount calculated pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury under subsection (l) shall be refunded as drawback, except that duties shall not be so refunded upon the exportation or destruction of flour or by-products produced from imported wheat. Where two or more products result from the manipulation of imported merchandise, the drawback shall be distributed to the several products in accordance with their relative values at the time of separation.


(b) Substitution for drawback purposes(1) In generalIf imported duty-paid merchandise or merchandise classifiable under the same 8-digit HTS subheading number as such imported merchandise is used in the manufacture or production of articles within a period not to exceed 5 years from the date of importation of such imported merchandise, there shall be allowed upon the exportation, or destruction under customs supervision, of any such articles, notwithstanding the fact that none of the imported merchandise may actually have been used in the manufacture or production of the exported or destroyed articles, an amount calculated pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury under subsection (l), but only if those articles have not been used prior to such exportation or destruction.


(2) Requirements relating to transfer of merchandise(A) Manufacturers and producersDrawback shall be allowed under paragraph (1) with respect to an article manufactured or produced using imported merchandise or other merchandise classifiable under the same 8-digit HTS subheading number as such imported merchandise only if the manufacturer or producer of the article received such impo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Articles made from imported merchandise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Articles made from imported merchandise Upon the exportation or destruction under customs supervision of articles manufactured or produced in the United States with the use of imported merchandise, provided that those articles have not been used prior to such exportation or destruction, an amount calculated pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury under subsection (l) shall be refunded as drawback, except that duties shall not be so refunded upon the exportation or destruction of flour or by-products produced from imported wheat. Where two or more products result from the manipulation of imported merchandise, the drawback shall be distributed to the several products in accordance with their relative values at the time of separation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substitution for drawback purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Substitution for drawback purposes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Merchandise not conforming to sample or specifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Merchandise not conforming to sample or specifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flavoring extracts; medicinal or toilet preparations; bottled distilled spirits and wines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Flavoring extracts; medicinal or toilet preparations; bottled distilled spirits and wines Upon the exportation of flavoring extracts, medicinal or toilet preparations (including perfumery) manufactured or produced in the United States in part from domestic alcohol on which an internal-revenue tax has been paid, there shall be allowed a drawback equal in amount to the tax found to have been paid on the alcohol so used.
Upon the exportation of bottled distilled spirits and wines manufactured or produced in the United States on which an internal-revenue tax has been paid or determined, there shall be allowed, under regulations to be prescribed by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, a drawback equal in amount to the tax found to have been paid or determined on such bottled distilled spirits and wines. In the case of distilled spirits, the preceding sentence shall not apply unless the claim for drawback is filed by the bottler or pac</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imported salt for curing fish</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Imported salt for curing fish Imported salt in bond may be used in curing fish taken by vessels licensed to engage in the fisheries, and in curing fish on the shores of the navigable waters of the United States, whether such fish are taken by licensed or unlicensed vessels, and upon proof that the salt has been used for either of such purposes, the duties on the same shall be remitted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exportation of meats cured with imported salt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exportation of meats cured with imported salt Upon the exportation of meats, whether packed or smoked, which have been cured in the United States with imported salt, there shall be refunded, upon satisfactory proof that such meats have been cured with imported salt, the duties paid on the salt so used in curing such exported meats, in amounts not less than $100.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Materials for construction and equipment of vessels built for foreigners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Materials for construction and equipment of vessels built for foreigners The provisions of this section shall apply to materials imported and used in the construction and equipment of vessels built for foreign account and ownership, or for the government of any foreign country, notwithstanding that such vessels may not within the strict meaning of the term be articles exported.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jet aircraft engines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Jet aircraft engines Upon the exportation of jet aircraft engines manufactured or produced abroad that have been overhauled, repaired, rebuilt, or reconditioned in the United States with the use of imported merchandise, including parts, there shall be refunded, upon satisfactory proof that such imported merchandise has been so used, the duties which have been paid thereon, in amounts not less than $100.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proof of exportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Proof of exportation A person claiming drawback under this section based on the exportation of an article shall provide proof of the exportation of the article. Such proof of exportation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1313_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unused merchandise drawback</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Unused merchandise drawback</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>