<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1330" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1330/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1330/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1330"><akn:num>1330</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1330. Organization of Commission(a) MembershipThe United States International Trade Commission (referred to in this subtitle as the “Commission”) shall be composed of six commissioners who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. No person shall be eligible for appointment as a commissioner unless he is a citizen of the United States, and, in the judgment of the President, is possessed of qualifications requisite for developing expert knowledge of international trade problems and efficiency in administering the duties and functions of the Commission. A person who has served as a commissioner for more than 5 years (excluding service as a commissioner before January 3, 1975) shall not be eligible for reappointment as a commissioner. Not more than three of the commissioners shall be members of the same political party, and in making appointments members of different political parties shall be appointed alternately as nearly as may be practicable.


(b) Terms of officeThe terms of office of the commissioners holding office on January 3, 1975, which (but for this sentence) would expire on June 16, 1975, June 16, 1976, June 16, 1977, June 16, 1978, June 16, 1979, and June 16, 1980, shall expire on December 16, 1976, June 16, 1978, December 16, 1979, June 16, 1981, December 16, 1982, and June 16, 1984, respectively. The term of office of each commissioner appointed after such date shall expire 9 years from the date of the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed, except that—(1) any commissioner appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term, and

(2) any commissioner may continue to serve as a commissioner after an expiration of his term of office until his successor is appointed and qualified.


(c) Chairman and vice chairman; quorum(1) The chairman and the vice chairman of the Commissio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1330_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Membership The United States International Trade Commission (referred to in this subtitle as the “Commission”) shall be composed of six commissioners who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. No person shall be eligible for appointment as a commissioner unless he is a citizen of the United States, and, in the judgment of the President, is possessed of qualifications requisite for developing expert knowledge of international trade problems and efficiency in administering the duties and functions of the Commission. A person who has served as a commissioner for more than 5 years (excluding service as a commissioner before January 3, 1975) shall not be eligible for reappointment as a commissioner. Not more than three of the commissioners shall be members of the same political party, and in making appointments members of different political parties shall be appointed alternately as nearly as may be practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1330_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms of office The terms of office of the commissioners holding office on January 3, 1975, which (but for this sentence) would expire on June 16, 1975, June 16, 1976, June 16, 1977, June 16, 1978, June 16, 1979, and June 16, 1980, shall expire on December 16, 1976, June 16, 1978, December 16, 1979, June 16, 1981, December 16, 1982, and June 16, 1984, respectively. The term of office of each commissioner appointed after such date shall expire 9 years from the date of the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1330_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman and vice chairman; quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chairman and vice chairman; quorum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1330_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of divided vote in certain cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect of divided vote in certain cases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1330_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1330_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Commission under Paperwork Reduction Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of Commission under Paperwork Reduction Act The Commission shall be considered to be an independent regulatory agency for purposes of chapter 35 of title 44.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>