<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1331" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1331/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1331/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1331"><akn:num>1331</akn:num><akn:heading>General powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1331. General powers(a) Administration(1)(A) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the chairman of the Commission shall—(i) appoint and fix the compensation of such employees of the Commission as he deems necessary (other than the personal staff of each commissioner), including the secretary,

(ii) procure the services of experts and consultants in accordance with the provisions of section 3109 of title 5, and

(iii) exercise and be responsible for all other administrative functions of the Commission.


(B) The chairman of the Commission may accept, hold, administer, and utilize gifts, devises, and bequests of property, both real and personal, for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Commission.

(C) Any decision by the chairman under subparagraph (A) or (B) shall be subject to disapproval by a majority vote of all the commissioners in office.


(2) Subject to approval by a majority vote of all the commissioners in office, the chairman may—(A) terminate the employment of any supervisory employee of the Commission whose duties involve substantial personal responsibility for Commission matters and who is compensated at a rate equal to, or in excess of, the rate for grade GS–15 of the General Schedule in section 5332 of title 5, and

(B) formulate the annual budget of the Commission.


(3) No member of the Commission, in making public statements with respect to any policy matter for which the Commission has responsibility, shall represent himself as speaking for the Commission, or his views as being the views of the Commission, with respect to such matter except to the extent that the Commission has adopted the policy being expressed.


(b) Application of civil service lawExcept for employees excepted under civil service rules, all employees of the commission shall be appointed from lists of eligibles to be supplied by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and in accordance with the civil service law.


(c) ExpensesAll of the expenses of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of civil service law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of civil service law Except for employees excepted under civil service rules, all employees of the commission shall be appointed from lists of eligibles to be supplied by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management and in accordance with the civil service law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expenses All of the expenses of the commission, including all necessary expenses for transportation incurred by the commissioners or by their employees under their orders in making any investigation or upon official business in any other places than at their respective headquarters, shall be allowed and paid on the presentation of itemized vouchers therefor approved by the chairman (except that in the case of a commissioner, or the personal staff of any commissioner, such vouchers may be approved by that commissioner).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal office at Washington</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Principal office at Washington The principal office of the commission shall be in the city of Washington, but it may meet and exercise all its powers at any other place. The commission may, by one or more of its members, or by such agents as it may designate, prosecute any inquiry necessary to its duties in any part of the United States or in any foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office at New York</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Office at New York The commission is authorized to establish and maintain an office at the port of New York for the purpose of directing or carrying on any investigation, receiving and compiling statistics, selecting, describing, and filing samples of articles, and performing any of the duties or exercising any of the powers imposed upon it by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1331_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Official seal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Official seal The commission is authorized to adopt an official seal, which shall be judicially noticed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>