<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1332" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1332/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1332/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1332"><akn:num>1332</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1332. Investigations(a) Investigations and reportsIt shall be the duty of the commission to investigate the administration and fiscal and industrial effects of the customs laws of this country, the relations between the rates of duty on raw materials and finished or partly finished products, the effects of ad valorem and specific duties and of compound specific and ad valorem duties, all questions relative to the arrangement of schedules and classification of articles in the several schedules of the customs law, and, in general, to investigate the operation of customs laws, including their relation to the Federal revenues, their effect upon the industries and labor of the country, and to submit reports of its investigations as hereafter provided.


(b) Investigations of tariff relationsThe commission shall have power to investigate the tariff relations between the United States and foreign countries, commercial treaties, preferential provisions, economic alliances, the effect of export bounties and preferential transportation rates, the volume of importations compared with domestic production and consumption, and conditions, causes, and effects relating to competition of foreign industries with those of the United States, including dumping and cost of production.


(c) Investigation of Paris Economy PactThe commission shall have power to investigate the Paris Economy Pact and similar organizations and arrangements in Europe.


(d) Information for President and CongressIn order that the President and the Congress may secure information and assistance, it shall be the duty of the commission to—(1) Ascertain conversion costs and costs of production in the principal growing, producing, or manufacturing centers of the United States of articles of the United States, whenever in the opinion of the commission it is practicable;

(2) Ascertain conversion costs and costs of production in the principal growing, producing, or manufacturing centers of foreign countries of arti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1332_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Investigations and reports It shall be the duty of the commission to investigate the administration and fiscal and industrial effects of the customs laws of this country, the relations between the rates of duty on raw materials and finished or partly finished products, the effects of ad valorem and specific duties and of compound specific and ad valorem duties, all questions relative to the arrangement of schedules and classification of articles in the several schedules of the customs law, and, in general, to investigate the operation of customs laws, including their relation to the Federal revenues, their effect upon the industries and labor of the country, and to submit reports of its investigations as hereafter provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1332_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations of tariff relations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investigations of tariff relations The commission shall have power to investigate the tariff relations between the United States and foreign countries, commercial treaties, preferential provisions, economic alliances, the effect of export bounties and preferential transportation rates, the volume of importations compared with domestic production and consumption, and conditions, causes, and effects relating to competition of foreign industries with those of the United States, including dumping and cost of production.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1332_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation of Paris Economy Pact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Investigation of Paris Economy Pact The commission shall have power to investigate the Paris Economy Pact and similar organizations and arrangements in Europe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1332_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information for President and Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information for President and Congress In order that the President and the Congress may secure information and assistance, it shall be the duty of the commission to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1332_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions When used in this subdivision and in subdivision (d)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1332_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1332_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to President and Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports to President and Congress The commission shall put at the disposal of the President of the United States, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Finance of the Senate, whenever requested, all information at its command, and shall make such investigations and reports as may be requested by the President or by either of said committees or by either branch of the Congress. However, the Commission may not release information which the Commission considers to be confidential business information unless the party submitting the confidential business information had notice, at the time of submission, that such information would be released by the Commission, or such party subsequently consents to the release of the information. The Commission shall report to Congress on the first Monday of December of each year after June 17, 1930, a statement of the methods adopted and all expenses incurred, a summary of all reports made during the y</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>