<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1336" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1336/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1336/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1336"><akn:num>1336</akn:num><akn:heading>Equalization of costs of production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1336. Equalization of costs of production(a) Change of classification or dutiesIn order to put into force and effect the policy of Congress by this chapter intended, the commission (1) upon request of the President, or (2) upon resolution of either or both Houses of Congress, or (3) upon its own motion, or (4) when in the judgment of the commission there is good and sufficient reason therefor, upon application of any interested party, shall investigate the differences in the costs of production of any domestic article and of any like or similar foreign article. In the course of the investigation the commission shall hold hearings and give reasonable public notice thereof, and shall afford reasonable opportunity for parties interested to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard at such hearings. The commission shall report to the President the results of the investigation and its findings with respect to such differences in costs of production. If the commission finds it shown by the investigation that the duties expressly fixed by statute do not equalize the differences in the costs of production of the domestic article and the like or similar foreign article when produced in the principal competing country, the commission shall specify in its report such increases or decreases in rates of duty expressly fixed by statute (including any necessary change in classification) as it finds shown by the investigation to be necessary to equalize such differences. In no case shall the total increase or decrease of such rates of duty exceed 50 per centum of the rates expressly fixed by statute.


(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 96–39, title II, § 202(a)(2)(A), July 26, 1979, 93 Stat. 202

(c) Proclamation by the PresidentThe President shall by proclamation approve the rates of duty and changes in classification specified in any report of the commission under this section, if in his judgment such rates of duty and changes are shown by such investigation of the commission to be </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change of classification or duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Change of classification or duties In order to put into force and effect the policy of Congress by this chapter intended, the commission (1) upon request of the President, or (2) upon resolution of either or both Houses of Congress, or (3) upon its own motion, or (4) when in the judgment of the commission there is good and sufficient reason therefor, upon application of any interested party, shall investigate the differences in the costs of production of any domestic article and of any like or similar foreign article. In the course of the investigation the commission shall hold hearings and give reasonable public notice thereof, and shall afford reasonable opportunity for parties interested to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard at such hearings. The commission shall report to the President the results of the investigation and its findings with respect to such differences in costs of production. If the commission finds it shown by the investigation that the duties expr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 96–39, title II, § 202(a)(2)(A), July 26, 1979, 93 Stat. 202</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proclamation by the President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Proclamation by the President The President shall by proclamation approve the rates of duty and changes in classification specified in any report of the commission under this section, if in his judgment such rates of duty and changes are shown by such investigation of the commission to be necessary to equalize such differences in costs of production.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of rates and changes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date of rates and changes Commencing thirty days after the date of any presidential proclamation of approval the increased or decreased rates of duty and changes in classification specified in the report of the commission shall take effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ascertainment of differences in costs of production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Ascertainment of differences in costs of production In ascertaining under this section the differences in costs of production, the commission shall take into consideration, in so far as it finds it practicable:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of changes in duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Modification of changes in duty Any increased or decreased rate of duty or change in classification which has taken effect as above provided may be modified or terminated in the same manner and subject to the same conditions and limitations (including time of taking effect) as is provided in this section in the case of original increases, decreases, or changes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against transfers from the free list to the dutiable list or from the dutiable list to the free list</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prohibition against transfers from the free list to the dutiable list or from the dutiable list to the free list Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize a transfer of an article from the dutiable list to the free list or from the free list to the dutiable list, nor a change in form of duty. Whenever it is provided in any paragraph of Subtitle I of this chapter, or in any amendatory act, that the duty or duties shall not exceed a specified ad valorem rate upon the articles provided for in such paragraph, no rate determined under the provisions of this section upon such articles shall exceed the maximum ad valorem rate so specified.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions For the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations of President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rules and regulations of President The President is authorized to make all needful rules and regulations for carrying out his functions under the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1336_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 96–39, title II, § 202(a)(2)(D), July 26, 1979, 93 Stat. 202</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>