<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1337" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1337/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1337/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1337"><akn:num>1337</akn:num><akn:heading>Unfair practices in import trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1337. Unfair practices in import trade(a) Unlawful activities; covered industries; definitions(1) Subject to paragraph (2), the following are unlawful, and when found by the Commission to exist shall be dealt with, in addition to any other provision of law, as provided in this section:(A) Unfair methods of competition and unfair acts in the importation of articles (other than articles provided for in subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (E)) into the United States, or in the sale of such articles by the owner, importer, or consignee, the threat or effect of which is—(i) to destroy or substantially injure an industry in the United States;

(ii) to prevent the establishment of such an industry; or

(iii) to restrain or monopolize trade and commerce in the United States.


(B) The importation into the United States, the sale for importation, or the sale within the United States after importation by the owner, importer, or consignee, of articles that—(i) infringe a valid and enforceable United States patent or a valid and enforceable United States copyright registered under title 17; or

(ii) are made, produced, processed, or mined under, or by means of, a process covered by the claims of a valid and enforceable United States patent.


(C) The importation into the United States, the sale for importation, or the sale within the United States after importation by the owner, importer, or consignee, of articles that infringe a valid and enforceable United States trademark registered under the Trademark Act of 1946 [15 U.S.C. 1051 et seq.].

(D) The importation into the United States, the sale for importation, or the sale within the United States after importation by the owner, importer, or consignee, of a semiconductor chip product in a manner that constitutes infringement of a mask work registered under chapter 9 of title 17.

(E) The importation into the United States, the sale for importation, or the sale within the United States after importation by the owner, importer, o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful activities; covered industries; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unlawful activities; covered industries; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation of violations by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investigation of violations by Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations; review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determinations; review The Commission shall determine, with respect to each investigation conducted by it under this section, whether or not there is a violation of this section, except that the Commission may, by issuing a consent order or on the basis of an agreement between the private parties to the investigation, including an agreement to present the matter for arbitration, terminate any such investigation, in whole or in part, without making such a determination. Each determination under subsection (d) or (e) shall be made on the record after notice and opportunity for a hearing in conformity with the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5. All legal and equitable defenses may be presented in all cases. A respondent may raise any counterclaim in a manner prescribed by the Commission. Immediately after a counterclaim is received by the Commission, the respondent raising such counterclaim shall file a notice of removal with a United States district court in which v</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of articles from entry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exclusion of articles from entry</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of articles from entry during investigation except under bond; procedures applicable; preliminary relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusion of articles from entry during investigation except under bond; procedures applicable; preliminary relief</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cease and desist orders; civil penalty for violation of orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cease and desist orders; civil penalty for violation of orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion from entry or cease and desist order; conditions and procedures applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exclusion from entry or cease and desist order; conditions and procedures applicable</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions for abuse of discovery and abuse of process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Sanctions for abuse of discovery and abuse of process The Commission may by rule prescribe sanctions for abuse of discovery and abuse of process to the extent authorized by Rule 11 and Rule 37 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeiture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Forfeiture</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1337_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral to President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Referral to President</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>