<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1351"><akn:num>1351</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign trade agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1351. Foreign trade agreements(a) Authority of President; modification and decrease of duties; altering import restrictions(1) For the purpose of expanding foreign markets for the products of the United States (as a means of assisting in establishing and maintaining a better relationship among various branches of American agriculture, industry, mining, and commerce) by regulating the admission of foreign goods into the United States in accordance with the characteristics and needs of various branches of American production so that foreign markets will be made available to those branches of American production which require and are capable of developing such outlets by affording corresponding market opportunities for foreign products in the United States, the President, whenever he finds as a fact that any existing duties or other import restrictions of the United States or any foreign country are unduly burdening and restricting the foreign trade of the United States and that the purpose above declared will be promoted by the means hereinafter specified, is authorized from time to time—(A) To enter into foreign trade agreements with foreign governments or instrumentalities thereof: Provided, That the enactment of the Trade Agreements Extension Act of 1955 shall not be construed to determine or indicate the approval or disapproval by the Congress of the executive agreement known as the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade.

(B) To proclaim such modifications of existing duties and other import restrictions, or such additional import restrictions, or such continuance, and for such minimum periods, of existing customs or excise treatment of any article covered by foreign trade agreements, as are required or appropriate to carry out any foreign trade agreement that the President has entered into hereunder.


(2) No proclamation pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection shall be made—(A) Increasing by more than 50 per centum any rate of duty existing on July 1,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1351_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of President; modification and decrease of duties; altering import restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of President; modification and decrease of duties; altering import restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1351_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cuba; preferential customs treatment; decrease of rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cuba; preferential customs treatment; decrease of rates Nothing in this section or the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 [19 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.] shall be construed to prevent the application, with respect to rates of duty established under this section or the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 pursuant to agreements with countries other than Cuba, of the provisions of the treaty of commercial reciprocity concluded between the United States and the Republic of Cuba on December 11, 1902, or to preclude giving effect to an agreement with Cuba concluded under this section or the Trade Expansion Act of 1962, modifying the existing preferential customs treatment of any article the growth, produce, or manufacture of Cuba. Nothing in this chapter or the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 shall be construed to preclude the application to any product of Cuba (including products preferentially free of duty) of a rate of duty not higher than the rate applicable to the like products of other foreign countries (ex</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1351_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1351_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate basis for additional increases or decreases; restoration of terminated treaties forbidden</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rate basis for additional increases or decreases; restoration of terminated treaties forbidden</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1351_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 87–794, title II, § 257(b), Oct. 11, 1962, 76 Stat. 882</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1351_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and advice from industry, agriculture, and labor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Information and advice from industry, agriculture, and labor It is declared to be the sense of the Congress that the President, during the course of negotiating any foreign trade agreement under this section, should seek information and advice with respect to such agreement from representatives of industry, agriculture, and labor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>