<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1401a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1401a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1401a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1401a"><akn:num>1401a</akn:num><akn:heading>Value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1401a. Value(a) Generally(1) Except as otherwise specifically provided for in this chapter, imported merchandise shall be appraised, for the purposes of this chapter, on the basis of the following:(A) The transaction value provided for under subsection (b).

(B) The transaction value of identical merchandise provided for under subsection (c), if the value referred to in subparagraph (A) cannot be determined, or can be determined but cannot be used by reason of subsection (b)(2).

(C) The transaction value of similar merchandise provided for under subsection (c), if the value referred to in subparagraph (B) cannot be determined.

(D) The deductive value provided for under subsection (d), if the value referred to in subparagraph (C) cannot be determined and if the importer does not request alternative valuation under paragraph (2).

(E) The computed value provided for under subsection (e), if the value referred to in subparagraph (D) cannot be determined.

(F) The value provided for under subsection (f), if the value referred to in subparagraph (E) cannot be determined.


(2) If the value referred to in paragraph (1)(C) cannot be determined with respect to imported merchandise, the merchandise shall be appraised on the basis of the computed value provided for under paragraph (1)(E), rather than the deductive value provided for under paragraph (1)(D), if the importer makes a request to that effect to the customs officer concerned within such time as the Secretary shall prescribe. If the computed value of the merchandise cannot subsequently be determined, the merchandise may not be appraised on the basis of the value referred to in paragraph (1)(F) unless the deductive value of the merchandise cannot be determined under paragraph (1)(D).

(3) Upon written request therefor by the importer of merchandise, and subject to provisions of law regarding the disclosure of information, the customs officer concerned shall provide the importer with a written explanation of how th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Generally</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transaction value of imported merchandise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transaction value of imported merchandise</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transaction value of identical merchandise and similar merchandise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transaction value of identical merchandise and similar merchandise</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductive value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deductive value</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computed value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Computed value</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value if other values cannot be determined or used</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Value if other values cannot be determined or used</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>