<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1401"><akn:num>1401</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1401. Miscellaneous
When used in this subtitle or in part I of subtitle II—(a) VesselThe word “vessel” includes every description of water craft or other contrivance used, or capable of being used, as a means of transportation in water, but does not include aircraft.


(b) VehicleThe word “vehicle” includes every description of carriage or other contrivance used, or capable of being used, as a means of transportation on land, but does not include aircraft.


(c) MerchandiseThe word “merchandise” means goods, wares, and chattels of every description, and includes merchandise the importation of which is prohibited, and monetary instruments as defined in section 5312 of title 31.


(d) PersonThe word “person” includes partnerships, associations, and corporations.


(e) MasterThe word “master” means the person having the command of the vessel.


(f) DayThe word “day” means the time from eight o’clock antemeridian to five o’clock postmeridian.


(g) NightThe word “night” means the time from five o’clock postmeridian to eight o’clock antemeridian.


(h) United StatesThe term “United States” includes all Territories and possessions of the United States except the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Wake Island, Midway Islands, Kingman Reef, Johnston Island, and the island of Guam.


(i) Officer of the customs; customs officerThe terms “officer of the customs” and “customs officer” mean any officer of the United States Customs Service of the Treasury Department (also hereinafter referred to as the “Customs Service”) or any commissioned, warrant, or petty officer of the Coast Guard, or any agent or other person, including foreign law enforcement officers, authorized by law or designated by the Secretary of the Treasury to perform any duties of an officer of the Customs Service.


(j) Customs watersThe term “customs waters” means, in the case of a foreign vessel subject to a treaty or other arrangement between a foreign government and the United States enabling or permitting th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Vessel The word “vessel” includes every description of water craft or other contrivance used, or capable of being used, as a means of transportation in water, but does not include aircraft.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vehicle</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Vehicle The word “vehicle” includes every description of carriage or other contrivance used, or capable of being used, as a means of transportation on land, but does not include aircraft.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Merchandise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Merchandise The word “merchandise” means goods, wares, and chattels of every description, and includes merchandise the importation of which is prohibited, and monetary instruments as defined in section 5312 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Person The word “person” includes partnerships, associations, and corporations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Master</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Master The word “master” means the person having the command of the vessel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Day</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Day The word “day” means the time from eight o’clock antemeridian to five o’clock postmeridian.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Night</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Night The word “night” means the time from five o’clock postmeridian to eight o’clock antemeridian.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) United States The term “United States” includes all Territories and possessions of the United States except the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Wake Island, Midway Islands, Kingman Reef, Johnston Island, and the island of Guam.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officer of the customs; customs officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Officer of the customs; customs officer The terms “officer of the customs” and “customs officer” mean any officer of the United States Customs Service of the Treasury Department (also hereinafter referred to as the “Customs Service”) or any commissioned, warrant, or petty officer of the Coast Guard, or any agent or other person, including foreign law enforcement officers, authorized by law or designated by the Secretary of the Treasury to perform any duties of an officer of the Customs Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customs waters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Customs waters The term “customs waters” means, in the case of a foreign vessel subject to a treaty or other arrangement between a foreign government and the United States enabling or permitting the authorities of the United States to board, examine, search, seize, or otherwise to enforce upon such vessel upon the high seas the laws of the United States, the waters within such distance of the coast of the United States as the said authorities are or may be so enabled or permitted by such treaty or arrangement and, in the case of every other vessel, the waters within four leagues of the coast of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>