<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1414" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1414/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1414/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1414"><akn:num>1414</akn:num><akn:heading>Remote location filing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1414. Remote location filing(a) Core entry information(1) In generalA Program participant may file electronically an entry of merchandise with the Customs Service from a location other than the district designated in the entry for examination (hereafter in this section referred to as a “remote location”) if—(A) the Customs Service is satisfied that the participant has the capabilities referred to in paragraph (2)(A) regarding such method of filing; and

(B) the participant elects to file from the remote location.


(2) Requirements(A) In generalIn order to qualify for filing from a remote location, a Program participant must have the capability to provide, on an entry-by-entry basis, for the following:(i) The electronic entry of merchandise.

(ii) The electronic entry summary of required information.

(iii) The electronic transmission of invoice information (when required by the Customs Service).

(iv) The electronic payment of duties, fees, and taxes.

(v) Such other electronic capabilities within the existing or planned components of the Program as the Secretary shall by regulation require.


(B) Restriction on exemption from requirementsThe Customs Service may not permit any exemption or waiver from the requirements established by this section for participation in remote entry filing.



(3) Conditions on filing under this sectionThe Secretary may prohibit a Program participant from participating in remote location filing, and may remove a Program participant from participation in remote location filing, if the participant—(i) fails to meet all the compliance requirements and operational standards of remote location filing; or

(ii) fails to adhere to all applicable laws and regulations.


(4) Alternative filingAny Program participant that is eligible to file entry information electronically from a remote location but chooses not to do so in the case of any entry must file any paper documentation for the entry at the designated location referred to in subsectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Core entry information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Core entry information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional entry information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional entry information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Post-entry summary information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Post-entry summary information A Program participant that is eligible to file electronically entry information under subsection (a) and additional information under subsection (b) from a remote location may file at any remote location designated by the Customs Service any information required by the Customs Service after entry summary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1414_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>