<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1431a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1431a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1431a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1431a"><akn:num>1431a</akn:num><akn:heading>Documentation of waterborne cargo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1431a. Documentation of waterborne cargo(a) ApplicabilityThis section shall apply to all cargo to be exported that is moved by a vessel carrier from a port in the United States.


(b) Documentation required(1) No shipper of cargo subject to this section (including an ocean transportation intermediary that is a non-vessel-operating common carrier (as defined in section 3(17)(B) of the Shipping Act of 1984 (46 U.S.C. App. 1702(17)(B) 11 See References in Text note below.) 22 So in original. Probably should be “1702(17)(B))))”. may tender or cause to be tendered to a vessel carrier cargo subject to this section for loading on a vessel in a United States port, unless such cargo is properly documented pursuant to this subsection.

(2) For the purposes of this subsection, cargo shall be considered properly documented if the shipper submits to the vessel carrier or its agent a complete set of shipping documents no later than 24 hours after the cargo is delivered to the marine terminal operator, but under no circumstances later than 24 hours prior to departure of the vessel.

(3) A complete set of shipping documents shall include—(A) for shipments for which a shipper’s export declaration is required, a copy of the export declaration or, if the shipper files such declarations electronically in the Automated Export System, the complete bill of lading, and the master or equivalent shipping instructions, including the Internal Transaction Number (ITN); or

(B) for shipments for which a shipper’s export declaration is not required, a shipper’s export declaration exemption statement and such other documents or information as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe.


(4) The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe the time, manner, and form by which shippers shall transmit documents or information required under this subsection to the Customs Service.


(c) Loading undocumented cargo prohibited(1) No marine terminal operator (as defined in section 3(14) of the Shipping Act of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability This section shall apply to all cargo to be exported that is moved by a vessel carrier from a port in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documentation required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Documentation required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loading undocumented cargo prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Loading undocumented cargo prohibited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting of undocumented cargo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting of undocumented cargo</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assessment of penalties Whoever is found to have violated subsection (b) of this section shall be liable to the United States for civil penalties in a monetary amount up to the value of the cargo, or the actual cost of the transportation, whichever is greater.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seizure of undocumented cargo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Seizure of undocumented cargo</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect on other provisions Nothing in this section shall be construed, interpreted, or applied to relieve or excuse any party from compliance with any obligation or requirement arising under any other law, regulation, or order with regard to the documentation or carriage of cargo.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>