<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1431" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1431/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1431/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1431"><akn:num>1431</akn:num><akn:heading>Manifests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1431. Manifests(a) In generalEvery vessel required to make entry under section 1434 of this title or obtain clearance under section 60105 of title 46 shall have a manifest that complies with the requirements prescribed under subsection (d).


(b) Production of manifestAny manifest required by the Customs Service shall be signed, produced, delivered or electronically transmitted by the master or person in charge of the vessel, aircraft, or vehicle, or by any other authorized agent of the owner or operator of the vessel, aircraft, or vehicle in accordance with the requirements prescribed under subsection (d). A manifest may be supplemented by bill of lading data supplied by the issuer of such bill. If any irregularity of omission or commission occurs in any way in respect to any manifest or bill of lading data, the owner or operator of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle, or any party responsible for such irregularity, shall be liable for any fine or penalty prescribed by law with respect to such irregularity. The Customs Service may take appropriate action against any of the parties.


(c) Public disclosure of certain manifest information(1) Except as provided in subparagraph (2), the following information, when contained in a vessel vessel 11 So in original. or aircraft manifest, shall be available for public disclosure:(A) The name and address of each importer or consignee and the name and address of the shipper to such importer or consignee, unless the importer or consignee has made a biennial certification, in accordance with procedures adopted by the Secretary of the Treasury, claiming confidential treatment of such information.

(B) The general character of the cargo.

(C) The number of packages and gross weight.

(D) The name of the vessel, aircraft, or carrier.

(E) The seaport or airport of loading.

(F) The seaport or airport of discharge.

(G) The country of origin of the shipment.

(H) The trademarks appearing on the goods or packages.


(2)(A) The informat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Every vessel required to make entry under section 1434 of this title or obtain clearance under section 60105 of title 46 shall have a manifest that complies with the requirements prescribed under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Production of manifest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Production of manifest Any manifest required by the Customs Service shall be signed, produced, delivered or electronically transmitted by the master or person in charge of the vessel, aircraft, or vehicle, or by any other authorized agent of the owner or operator of the vessel, aircraft, or vehicle in accordance with the requirements prescribed under subsection (d). A manifest may be supplemented by bill of lading data supplied by the issuer of such bill. If any irregularity of omission or commission occurs in any way in respect to any manifest or bill of lading data, the owner or operator of the vessel, aircraft or vehicle, or any party responsible for such irregularity, shall be liable for any fine or penalty prescribed by law with respect to such irregularity. The Customs Service may take appropriate action against any of the parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public disclosure of certain manifest information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public disclosure of certain manifest information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1431_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>