<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1449" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1449/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1449/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1449"><akn:num>1449</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlading at port of entry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1449. Unlading at port of entry
Except as provided in sections 1442 and 1447 of this title (relating to residue cargo and to bulk cargo respectively), merchandise and baggage imported in any vessel by sea shall be unladen at the port of entry to which such vessel is destined, unless (1) such vessel is compelled by any cause to put into another port of entry, and the Customs Service issues a permit for the unlading of such merchandise or baggage at such port, or (2) the Secretary of the Treasury, because of an emergency existing at the port of destination, authorizes such vessel to proceed to another port of entry. Merchandise and baggage so unladen may be entered in the same manner as other imported merchandise or baggage and may be treated as unclaimed merchandise or baggage and stored at the expense and risk of the owner thereof, or may be reladen without entry upon the vessel from which it was unladen for transportation to its destination.
(June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title IV, § 449, 46 Stat. 714; Pub. L. 91–271, title III, § 301(b), June 2, 1970, 84 Stat. 287; Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 649(b), Dec. 8, 1993, 107 Stat. 2208.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 449, 42 Stat. 954. That section was superseded by section 449 of act June 17, 1930, comprising this section, and repealed by section 651(a)(1) of the 1930 act.
Provisions concerning protests and reports by vessels compelled by distress of weather or other necessity to put into a port of the United States; permits for the unlading thereof; the storage of the goods; the disposal of perishable goods; variances between the report, and the delivery of the cargo, and the reloading of such vessels, and a special provision for Spanish vessels arriving in distress, were contained in R.S. §§ 2891–2895. Provisions for report and entry of vessels prevented by ice from getting to the port or place at which her cargo was</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>