<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1459" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1459/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1459/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1459"><akn:num>1459</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements for individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1459. Reporting requirements for individuals(a) Individuals arriving other than by conveyanceExcept as otherwise authorized by the Secretary, individuals arriving in the United States other than by vessel, vehicle, or aircraft shall—(1) enter the United States only at a border crossing point designated by the Secretary; and

(2) immediately—(A) report the arrival, and

(B) present themselves, and all articles accompanying them for inspection;


to the customs officer at the customs facility designated for that crossing point.


(b) Individuals arriving by reported conveyanceExcept as otherwise authorized by the Secretary, passengers and crew members aboard a conveyance the arrival in the United States of which was made or reported in accordance with section 1433 or 1644 of this title or section 1644a(b)(1) or (c)(1) of this title, or in accordance with applicable regulations, shall remain aboard the conveyance until authorized to depart the conveyance by the appropriate customs officer. Upon departing the conveyance, the passengers and crew members shall immediately report to the designated customs facility with all articles accompanying them.


(c) Individuals arriving by unreported conveyanceExcept as otherwise authorized by the Secretary, individuals aboard a conveyance the arrival in the United States of which was not made or reported in accordance with the laws or regulations referred to in subsection (b) of this section shall immediately notify a customs officer and report their arrival, together with appropriate information concerning the conveyance on or in which they arrived, and present their property for customs examination and inspection.


(d) Departure from designated customs facilitiesExcept as otherwise authorized by the Secretary, any person required to report to a designated customs facility under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this section may not depart that facility until authorized to do so by the appropriate customs officer.


(e) Unlawful a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1459_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals arriving other than by conveyance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Individuals arriving other than by conveyance Except as otherwise authorized by the Secretary, individuals arriving in the United States other than by vessel, vehicle, or aircraft shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1459_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals arriving by reported conveyance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Individuals arriving by reported conveyance Except as otherwise authorized by the Secretary, passengers and crew members aboard a conveyance the arrival in the United States of which was made or reported in accordance with section 1433 or 1644 of this title or section 1644a(b)(1) or (c)(1) of this title, or in accordance with applicable regulations, shall remain aboard the conveyance until authorized to depart the conveyance by the appropriate customs officer. Upon departing the conveyance, the passengers and crew members shall immediately report to the designated customs facility with all articles accompanying them.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1459_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals arriving by unreported conveyance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Individuals arriving by unreported conveyance Except as otherwise authorized by the Secretary, individuals aboard a conveyance the arrival in the United States of which was not made or reported in accordance with the laws or regulations referred to in subsection (b) of this section shall immediately notify a customs officer and report their arrival, together with appropriate information concerning the conveyance on or in which they arrived, and present their property for customs examination and inspection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1459_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Departure from designated customs facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Departure from designated customs facilities Except as otherwise authorized by the Secretary, any person required to report to a designated customs facility under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this section may not depart that facility until authorized to do so by the appropriate customs officer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1459_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Unlawful acts It is unlawful—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1459_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Civil penalty Any individual who violates any provision of subsection (e) of this section is liable for a civil penalty of $5,000 for the first violation, and $10,000 for each subsequent violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1459_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Criminal penalty In addition to being liable for a civil penalty under subsection (f) of this section, any individual who intentionally violates any provision of subsection (e) of this section is, upon conviction, liable for a fine of not more than $5,000, or imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>