<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1466" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1466/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1466/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1466"><akn:num>1466</akn:num><akn:heading>Equipment and repairs of vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1466. Equipment and repairs of vessels(a) Vessels subject to duty; penaltiesThe equipments, or any part thereof, including boats, purchased for, or the repair parts or materials to be used, or the expenses of repairs made in a foreign country upon a vessel documented under the laws of the United States to engage in the foreign or coasting trade, or a vessel intended to be employed in such trade, shall, on the first arrival of such vessel in any port of the United States, be liable to entry and the payment of an ad valorem duty of 50 per centum on the cost thereof in such foreign country. If the owner or master willfully or knowingly neglects or fails to report, make entry, and pay duties as herein required, or if he makes any false statement in respect of such purchases or repairs without reasonable cause to believe the truth of such statements, or aids or procures the making of any false statement as to any matter material thereto without reasonable cause to believe the truth of such statement, such vessel, or a monetary amount up to the value thereof as determined by the Secretary, to be recovered from the owner, shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture. For the purposes of this section, compensation paid to members of the regular crew of such vessel in connection with the installation of any such equipments or any part thereof, or the making of repairs, in a foreign country, shall not be included in the cost of such equipment or part thereof, or of such repairs.


(b) NoticeIf the appropriate customs officer has reasonable cause to believe a violation has occurred and determines that further proceedings are warranted, he shall issue to the person concerned a written notice of his intention to issue a penalty claim. Such notice shall—(1) describe the circumstances of the alleged violation;

(2) specify all laws and regulations allegedly violated;

(3) disclose all the material facts which establish the alleged violation;

(4) state the estimated loss of lawful</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1466_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels subject to duty; penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Vessels subject to duty; penalties The equipments, or any part thereof, including boats, purchased for, or the repair parts or materials to be used, or the expenses of repairs made in a foreign country upon a vessel documented under the laws of the United States to engage in the foreign or coasting trade, or a vessel intended to be employed in such trade, shall, on the first arrival of such vessel in any port of the United States, be liable to entry and the payment of an ad valorem duty of 50 per centum on the cost thereof in such foreign country. If the owner or master willfully or knowingly neglects or fails to report, make entry, and pay duties as herein required, or if he makes any false statement in respect of such purchases or repairs without reasonable cause to believe the truth of such statements, or aids or procures the making of any false statement as to any matter material thereto without reasonable cause to believe the truth of such statement, such vessel, or a monetary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1466_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice If the appropriate customs officer has reasonable cause to believe a violation has occurred and determines that further proceedings are warranted, he shall issue to the person concerned a written notice of his intention to issue a penalty claim. Such notice shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1466_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Violation After considering representations, if any, made by the person concerned pursuant to the notice issued under subsection (b), the appropriate customs officer shall determine whether any violation of subsection (a), as alleged in the notice, has occurred. If such officer determines that there was no violation, he shall promptly notify, in writing, the person to whom the notice was sent. If such officer determines that there was a violation, he shall issue a written penalty claim to such person. The written penalty claim shall specify all changes in the information provided under paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1466_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remission for necessary repairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Remission for necessary repairs If the owner or master of such vessel furnishes good and sufficient evidence that— then the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to remit or refund such duties, and such vessel shall not be liable to forfeiture, and no license or enrollment and license, or renewal of either, shall hereafter be issued to any such vessel until the collector to whom application is made for the same shall be satisfied, from the oath of the owner or master, that all such equipments or parts thereof or materials and repairs made within the year immediately preceding such application have been duly accounted for under the provisions of this section, and the duties accruing thereon duly paid; and if such owner or master shall refuse to take such oath, or take it falsely, the vessel shall be seized and forfeited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1466_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions for arrivals two or more years after last departure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusions for arrivals two or more years after last departure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1466_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil aircraft exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Civil aircraft exception The duty imposed under subsection (a) shall not apply to the cost of equipments, or any part thereof, purchased, of repair parts or materials used, or of repairs made in a foreign country with respect to a United States civil aircraft, within the meaning of general note 3(c)(iv) of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1466_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fish net and netting purchases and repairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fish net and netting purchases and repairs The duty imposed by subsection (a) shall not apply to entries on and after October 1, 1979, and before January 1, 1982, of— for any United States documented tuna purse seine vessel of greater than 500 tons carrying capacity or any United States tuna purse seine vessel required to carry a certificate of inclusion under the general permit issued to the American Tunaboat Association pursuant to section 1374 of title 16.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1466_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign repair of vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Foreign repair of vessels The duty imposed by subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to— Declaration and entry shall not be required with respect to the installation, equipment, parts, and materials described in paragraph (4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>