<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1504"><akn:num>1504</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1504. Limitation on liquidation(a) Liquidation(1) Entries for consumptionUnless an entry of merchandise for consumption is extended under subsection (b) of this section or suspended as required by statute or court order, except as provided in section 1675(a)(3) of this title, an entry of merchandise for consumption not liquidated within 1 year from—(A) the date of entry of such merchandise,

(B) the date of the final withdrawal of all such merchandise covered by a warehouse entry,

(C) the date of withdrawal from warehouse of such merchandise for consumption if, pursuant to regulations issued under section 1505(a) of this title, duties may be deposited after the filing of any entry or withdrawal from warehouse,

(D) if a reconciliation is filed, or should have been filed, the date of the filing under section 1484 of this title or the date the reconciliation should have been filed, whichever is earlier; or

(E) 11 See 2004 Amendment notes below. if a reconfigured entry is filed under an import activity summary statement, the date the import activity summary statement is filed or should have been filed, whichever is earlier;


shall be deemed liquidated at the rate of duty, value, quantity, and amount of duties asserted by the importer of record. Notwithstanding section 1500(e) of this title, notice of liquidation need not be given of an entry deemed liquidated.

(2) Entries or claims for drawback(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B) or (C), unless an entry or claim for drawback is extended under subsection (b) or suspended as required by statute or court order, an entry or claim for drawback not liquidated within 1 year from the date of entry or claim shall be deemed liquidated at the drawback amount asserted by the claimant or claim. Notwithstanding section 1500(e) of this title, notice of liquidation need not be given of an entry deemed liquidated.


(B) Unliquidated importsAn entry or claim for drawback whose designated or identified import entrie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liquidation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Extension The Secretary of the Treasury may extend the period in which to liquidate an entry if— The Secretary shall give notice of an extension under this subsection to the importer of record or drawback claimant, as the case may be, and the surety of such importer of record or drawback claimant. Notice shall be in such form and manner (which may include electronic transmittal) as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe. Any entry the liquidation of which is extended under this subsection shall be treated as having been liquidated at the rate of duty, value, quantity, and amount of duty asserted by the importer of record, or the drawback amount asserted by the drawback claimant, at the expiration of 4 years from the applicable date specified in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of suspension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice of suspension If the liquidation of any entry is suspended, the Secretary shall by regulation require that notice of the suspension be provided, in such manner as the Secretary considers appropriate, to the importer of record or drawback claimant, as the case may be, and to any authorized agent and surety of such importer of record or drawback claimant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal of suspension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Removal of suspension Except as provided in section 1675(a)(3) of this title, when a suspension required by statute or court order is removed, the Customs Service shall liquidate the entry, unless liquidation is extended under subsection (b), within 6 months after receiving notice of the removal from the Department of Commerce, other agency, or a court with jurisdiction over the entry. Any entry (other than an entry with respect to which liquidation has been extended under subsection (b)) not liquidated by the Customs Service within 6 months after receiving such notice shall be treated as having been liquidated at the rate of duty, value, quantity, and amount of duty asserted by the importer of record or (in the case of a drawback entry or claim) at the drawback amount asserted by the drawback claimant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>