<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1509" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1509/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1509/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1509"><akn:num>1509</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of books and witnesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1509. Examination of books and witnesses(a) AuthorityIn any investigation or inquiry conducted for the purpose of ascertaining the correctness of any entry, for determining the liability of any person for duty, fees and taxes due or duties, fees and taxes which may be due the United States, for determining liability for fines and penalties, or for insuring compliance with the laws of the United States administered by the United States Customs Service, the Secretary (but no delegate of the Secretary below the rank of district director or special agent in charge) may—(1) examine, or cause to be examined, upon reasonable notice, any record (which for purposes of this section, includes, but is not limited to, any statement, declaration, document, or electronically generated or machine readable data) described in the notice with reasonable specificity, which may be relevant to such investigation or inquiry, except that—(A) if such record is required by law or regulation for the entry of the merchandise (whether or not the Customs Service required its presentation at the time of entry) it shall be provided to the Customs Service within a reasonable time after demand for its production is made, taking into consideration the number, type, and age of the item demanded; and

(B) if a person of whom demand is made under subparagraph (A) fails to comply with the demand, the person may be subject to penalty under subsection (g);


(2) summon, upon reasonable notice—(A) the person who—(i) imported, or knowingly caused to be imported, merchandise into the customs territory of the United States, or a vehicle producer whose good is subject to a claim of preferential tariff treatment under the USMCA (as defined in section 4502 of this title),

(ii) exported merchandise, or knowingly caused merchandise to be exported, to a USMCA country (as defined in section 4502 of this title) or to Canada during such time as the United States-Canada Free-Trade Agreement is in force with respect t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1509_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority In any investigation or inquiry conducted for the purpose of ascertaining the correctness of any entry, for determining the liability of any person for duty, fees and taxes due or duties, fees and taxes which may be due the United States, for determining liability for fines and penalties, or for insuring compliance with the laws of the United States administered by the United States Customs Service, the Secretary (but no delegate of the Secretary below the rank of district director or special agent in charge) may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1509_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory audit procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulatory audit procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1509_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of summons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Service of summons A summons issued pursuant to this section may be served by any person designated in the summons to serve it. Service upon a natural person may be made by personal delivery of the summons to him. Service may be made upon a domestic or foreign corporation or upon a partnership or other unincorporated association which is subject to suit under a common name, by delivering the summons to an officer, or managing or general agent, or to any other agent authorized by appointment or by law to receive service of process. The certificate of service signed by the person serving the summons is prima facie evidence of the facts it states on the hearing of an application for the enforcement of the summons. When the summons requires the production of records, such records shall be described in the summons with reasonable specificity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1509_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special procedures for third-party summonses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special procedures for third-party summonses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1509_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of records and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) List of records and information The Customs Service shall identify and publish a list of the records or entry information that is required to be maintained and produced under subsection (a)(1)(A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1509_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping compliance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Recordkeeping compliance program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1509_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>