<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1516" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1516/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1516/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1516"><akn:num>1516</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitions by domestic interested parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1516. Petitions by domestic interested parties(a) Request for classification and rate of duty; petition(1) The Secretary shall, upon written request by an interested party furnish the classification and the rate of duty imposed upon designated imported merchandise of a class or kind manufactured, produced, or sold at wholesale by such interested party. If the interested party believes that the appraised value, the classification, or rate of duty is not correct, it may file a petition with the Secretary setting forth—(A) a description of the merchandise,

(B) the appraised value, the classification, or the rate of duty that it believes proper, and

(C) the reasons for its belief.


(2) As used in this section, the term “interested party” means a person who is—(A) a manufacturer, producer, or wholesaler in the United States;

(B) a certified union or recognized union or group of workers which is representative of an industry engaged in the manufacture, production, or wholesale in the United States; or

(C) a trade or business association a majority of whose members are manufacturers, producers, or wholesalers in the United States,


of goods of the same class or kind as the designated imported merchandise. Such term includes an association, a majority of whose members is composed of persons described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).

(3) Any producer of a raw agricultural product who is considered under section 1677(4)(E) of this title to be part of the industry producing a processed agricultural product of the same class or kind as the designated imported merchandise shall, for purposes of this section, be treated as an interested party producing such processed agricultural product.


(b) Determination on petitionIf, after receipt and consideration of a petition filed by such an interested party, the Secretary determines that the appraised value, the classification, or rate of duty is not correct, he shall determine the proper appraised value, classification, or r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for classification and rate of duty; petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Request for classification and rate of duty; petition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination on petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination on petition If, after receipt and consideration of a petition filed by such an interested party, the Secretary determines that the appraised value, the classification, or rate of duty is not correct, he shall determine the proper appraised value, classification, or rate of duty and shall notify the petitioner of his determination. All such merchandise entered for consumption or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption more than thirty days after the date such notice to the petitioner is published in the weekly Customs Bulletin shall be appraised, classified, or assessed as to the rate of duty in accordance with the Secretary’s determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contest by petitioner of appraised value, classification, or rate of duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contest by petitioner of appraised value, classification, or rate of duty If the Secretary determines that the appraised value, classification, or rate of duty with respect to which a petition was filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section is correct, he shall notify the petitioner. If dissatisfied with the determination of the Secretary, the petitioner may file with the Secretary, not later than thirty days after the date of the notification, notice that it desires to contest the appraised value, classification, or rate of duty. Upon receipt of notice from the petitioner, the Secretary shall cause publication to be made of his determination as to the proper appraised value, classification, or rate of duty and of the petitioner’s desire to contest, and shall thereafter furnish the petitioner with such information as to the entries and consignees of such merchandise, entered after the publication of the determination of the Secretary, at such ports of entry designated by the p</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal, classification, and liquidation of entries of merchandise covered by published decisions of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Appraisal, classification, and liquidation of entries of merchandise covered by published decisions of Secretary Notwithstanding the filing of an action pursuant to chapter 169 of title 28, merchandise of the character covered by the published decision of the Secretary (when entered for consumption or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption on or before the date of publication of a decision of the United States Court of International Trade or of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, not in harmony with the published decision of the Secretary) shall be appraised or classified, or both, and the entries liquidated, in accordance with the decision of the Secretary and, except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the final liquidations of these entries shall be conclusive upon all parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consignee or his agent as party in interest before the Court of International Trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consignee or his agent as party in interest before the Court of International Trade The consignee or his agent shall have the right to appear and to be heard as a party in interest before the United States Court of International Trade.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisement, classification, and assessment of duty of merchandise covered by published decision of Secretary in accordance with final judicial decision of Court of International Trade or Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit sustaining cause of action in whole or in part; suspension of liquidation of entries; publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appraisement, classification, and assessment of duty of merchandise covered by published decision of Secretary in accordance with final judicial decision of Court of International Trade or Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit sustaining cause of action in whole or in part; suspension of liquidation of entries; publication If the cause of action is sustained in whole or in part by a decision of the United States Court of International Trade or of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, merchandise of the character covered by the published decision of the Secretary, which is entered for consumption or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption after the date of publication in the Federal Register by the Secretary or the administering authority of a notice of the court decision, shall be subject to appraisement, classification, and assessment of duty in accordance with the final judicial decision in the action, and the liquidation of entries covering the merchand</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations implementing required procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations implementing required procedures Regulations shall be prescribed by the Secretary to implement the procedures required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>