<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1516a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1516a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1516a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1516a"><akn:num>1516a</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review in countervailing duty and antidumping duty proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1516a. Judicial review in countervailing duty and antidumping duty proceedings(a) Review of determination(1) Review of certain determinationsWithin 30 days after the date of publication in the Federal Register of—(A) a determination by the administering authority, under 1671a(c) 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”. or 1673a(c) of this title, not to initiate an investigation,

(B) a determination by the Commission, under section 1675(b) of this title, not to review a determination based upon changed circumstances,

(C) a negative determination by the Commission, under section 1671b(a) or 1673b(a) of this title, as to whether there is reasonable indication of material injury, threat of material injury, or material retardation, or

(D) a final determination by the administering authority or the Commission under section 1675(c)(3) of this title,


an interested party who is a party to the proceeding in connection with which the matter arises may commence an action in the United States Court of International Trade by filing concurrently a summons and complaint, each with the content and in the form, manner, and style prescribed by the rules of that court, contesting any factual findings or legal conclusions upon which the determination is based.

(2) Review of determinations on record(A) In generalWithin thirty days after—(i) the date of publication in the Federal Register of—(I) notice of any determination described in clause (ii), (iii), (iv), (v), or (viii) of subparagraph (B),

(II) an antidumping or countervailing duty order based upon any determination described in clause (i) of subparagraph (B), or

(III) notice of the implementation of any determination described in clause (vii) of subparagraph (B), or


(ii) the date of mailing of a determination described in clause (vi) of subparagraph (B),


an interested party who is a party to the proceeding in connection with which the matter arises may commence an action in the United States Court</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Review of determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards of review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards of review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation of entries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Liquidation of entries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Standing Any interested party who was a party to the proceeding under section 1303 22 See References in Text note below. of this title or subtitle IV of this chapter shall have the right to appear and be heard as a party in interest before the United States Court of International Trade. The party filing the action shall notify all such interested parties of the filing of an action under this section, in the form, manner, style, and within the time prescribed by rules of the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation in accordance with final decision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Liquidation in accordance with final decision If the cause of action is sustained in whole or in part by a decision of the United States Court of International Trade or of the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit— shall be liquidated in accordance with the final court decision in the action. Such notice of the court decision shall be published within ten days from the date of the issuance of the court decision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1516a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of countervailing duty and antidumping duty determinations involving free trade area country merchandise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Review of countervailing duty and antidumping duty determinations involving free trade area country merchandise</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>