<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1517" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1517/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1517/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1517"><akn:num>1517</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for investigating claims of evasion of antidumping and countervailing duty orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1517. Procedures for investigating claims of evasion of antidumping and countervailing duty orders(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Administering authorityThe term “administering authority” has the meaning given that term in section 1677(1) of this title.


(2) CommissionerThe term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.


(3) Covered merchandiseThe term “covered merchandise” means merchandise that is subject to—(A) an antidumping duty order issued under section 1673e of this title; or

(B) a countervailing duty order issued under section 1671e of this title.


(4) Enter; entryThe terms “enter” and “entry” refer to the entry, or withdrawal from warehouse for consumption, of merchandise into the customs territory of the United States.


(5) Evasion(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “evasion” refers to entering covered merchandise into the customs territory of the United States by means of any document or electronically transmitted data or information, written or oral statement, or act that is material and false, or any omission that is material, and that results in any cash deposit or other security or any amount of applicable antidumping or countervailing duties being reduced or not being applied with respect to the merchandise.


(B) Exception for clerical error(i) In generalExcept as provided in clause (ii), the term “evasion” does not include entering covered merchandise into the customs territory of the United States by means of—(I) a document or electronically transmitted data or information, written or oral statement, or act that is false as a result of a clerical error; or

(II) an omission that results from a clerical error.


(ii) Patterns of negligent conductIf the Commissioner determines that a person has entered covered merchandise into the customs territory of the United States by means of a clerical error referred to in subclause (I) or (II) of clause (i) and that the clerical error is</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1517_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1517_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investigations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1517_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1517_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect of determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1517_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interim measures Not later than 90 calendar days after initiating an investigation under subsection (b) with respect to covered merchandise, the Commissioner shall decide based on the investigation if there is a reasonable suspicion that such covered merchandise was entered into the customs territory of the United States through evasion and, if the Commissioner decides there is such a reasonable suspicion, the Commissioner shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1517_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1517_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1517_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction with respect to other civil and criminal proceedings and investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction with respect to other civil and criminal proceedings and investigations No determination under subsection (c), review under subsection (f), or action taken by the Commissioner pursuant to this section shall preclude any individual or entity from proceeding, or otherwise affect or limit the authority of any individual or entity to proceed, with any civil, criminal, or administrative investigation or proceeding pursuant to any other provision of Federal or State law, including sections 1592 of this title and 1595a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>