<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1557" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1557/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1557/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1557"><akn:num>1557</akn:num><akn:heading>Entry for warehouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1557. Entry for warehouse(a) Withdrawal of merchandise; time; payment of charges(1) Any merchandise subject to duty (including international travel merchandise), with the exception of perishable articles and explosive substances other than firecrackers, may be entered for warehousing and be deposited in a bonded warehouse at the expense and risk of the owner 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. purchaser, importer, or consignee. Such merchandise may be withdrawn, at any time within 5 years from the date of importation, or such longer period of time as the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection may at its discretion permit upon proper request being filed and good cause shown, for consumption upon payment of the duties and charges accruing thereon at the rate of duty imposed by law upon such merchandise at the date of withdrawal; or may be withdrawn for exportation or for transportation and exportation to a foreign country, or for shipment or for transportation and shipment to the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Wake Island, Midway Islands, Kingman Reef, Johnston Island, or the island of Guam, without the payment of duties thereon, or for transportation and rewarehousing at another port or elsewhere, or for transfer to another bonded warehouse at the same port; except that—(A) the total period of time for which such merchandise may remain in bonded warehouse shall not exceed 5 years from the date of importation or such longer period of time as the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection may at its discretion permit upon proper request being filed and good cause shown; and

(B) turbine fuel may be withdrawn for use under section 1309 of this title without the payment of duty if an amount equal to the quantity of fuel withdrawn is shown to be used within 30 days after the day of withdrawal, but duties (together with interest payable from the date of the withdrawal at the rate of interest established under section 6621 of title 26) shall be depos</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1557_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of merchandise; time; payment of charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Withdrawal of merchandise; time; payment of charges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1557_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transferal of right of withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transferal of right of withdrawal The right to withdraw any merchandise entered in accordance with subsection (a) of this section for the purposes specified in such subsection may be transferred upon compliance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury and upon the filing by the transferee of a bond in such amount and containing such conditions as the Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe. The bond shall include an obligation to pay, with respect to the merchandise the subject of the transfer, all unpaid regular, increased, and additional duties, all unpaid taxes imposed upon or by reason of importation, and all unpaid charges and exactions. Such transfers shall be irrevocable, shall relieve the transferor from all customs liability with respect to obligations assumed by the transferee under the bond herein provided for, and shall confer upon the transferee all rights to the privileges provided for in this section and in sections 1562 and 1563 of this title w</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1557_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Destruction of merchandise at request of con­signee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Destruction of merchandise at request of con­signee Merchandise entered under bond, under any provision of law, may, upon payment of all charges other than duty on the merchandise, be destroyed, at the request and at the expense of the consignee, within the bonded period under customs supervision, in lieu of exportation, and upon such destruction the entry of such merchandise shall be liquidated without payment of duty and any duties collected shall be refunded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1557_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal before payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Withdrawal before payment Merchandise may be withdrawn for consumption without the payment of the duty thereon if the importer of record or transferee is permitted to pay duty at a later time pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary under section 1505 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>