<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1583" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1583/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1583/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1583"><akn:num>1583</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of outbound mail</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1583. Examination of outbound mail(a) Examination(1) In generalFor purposes of ensuring compliance with the Customs laws of the United States and other laws enforced by the Customs Service, including the provisions of law described in paragraph (2), a Customs officer may, subject to the provisions of this section, stop and search at the border, without a search warrant, mail of domestic origin transmitted for export by the United States Postal Service and foreign mail transiting the United States that is being imported or exported by the United States Postal Service.


(2) Provisions of law describedThe provisions of law described in this paragraph are the following:(A) Section 5316 of title 31 (relating to reports on exporting and importing monetary instruments).

(B) Sections 1461, 1463, 1465, and 1466, and chapter 110 of title 18 (relating to obscenity and child pornography).

(C) Section 953 of title 21 (relating to exportation of controlled substances).

(D) The Export Administration Act of 1979 (50 U.S.C. App. 2401 et seq.).11 See References in Text note below.

(E) Section 2778 of title 22.

(F) The International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.).



(b) Search of mail not sealed against inspection and other mailMail not sealed against inspection under the postal laws and regulations of the United States, mail which bears a Customs declaration, and mail with respect to which the sender or addressee has consented in writing to search, may be searched by a Customs officer.


(c) Search of mail sealed against inspection weighing in excess of 16 ounces(1) In generalMail weighing in excess of 16 ounces sealed against inspection under the postal laws and regulations of the United States may be searched by a Customs officer, subject to paragraph (2), if there is reasonable cause to suspect that such mail contains one or more of the following:(A) Monetary instruments, as defined in section 1956 of title 18.

(B) A weapon of mass destruction, as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1583_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Examination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1583_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Search of mail not sealed against inspection and other mail</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Search of mail not sealed against inspection and other mail Mail not sealed against inspection under the postal laws and regulations of the United States, mail which bears a Customs declaration, and mail with respect to which the sender or addressee has consented in writing to search, may be searched by a Customs officer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1583_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Search of mail sealed against inspection weighing in excess of 16 ounces</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Search of mail sealed against inspection weighing in excess of 16 ounces</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1583_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Search of mail sealed against inspection weighing 16 ounces or less</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Search of mail sealed against inspection weighing 16 ounces or less Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to mail weighing 16 ounces or less sealed against inspection under the postal laws and regulations of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>