<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1590" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1590/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1590/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1590"><akn:num>1590</akn:num><akn:heading>Aviation smuggling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1590. Aviation smuggling(a) In generalIt is unlawful for the pilot of any aircraft to transport, or for any individual on board any aircraft to possess, merchandise knowing, or intending, that the merchandise will be introduced into the United States contrary to law.


(b) Sea transfersIt is unlawful for any person to transfer merchandise between an aircraft and a vessel on the high seas or in the customs waters of the United States if such person has not been authorized by the Secretary to make such transfer and—(1) either—(A) the aircraft is owned by a citizen of the United States or is registered in the United States, or

(B) the vessel is a vessel of the United States (within the meaning of section 1703(b) of this title), or


(2) regardless of the nationality of the vessel or aircraft, such transfer is made under circumstances indicating the intent to make it possible for such merchandise, or any part thereof, to be introduced into the United States unlawfully.


(c) Civil penaltiesAny person who violates any provision of this section is liable for a civil penalty equal to twice the value of the merchandise involved in the violation, but not less than $10,000. The value of any controlled substance included in the merchandise shall be determined in accordance with section 1497(b) of this title.


(d) Criminal penaltiesIn addition to being liable for a civil penalty under subsection (c), any person who intentionally commits, or attempts or conspires to commit, a violation of any provision of this section is, upon conviction—(1) liable for a fine of not more than $10,000 or imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both, if none of the merchandise involved was a controlled substance; or

(2) liable for a fine of not more than $250,000 or imprisonment for not more than 20 years, or both, if any of the merchandise involved was a controlled substance.


(e) Seizure and forfeiture(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), a vessel or aircraft used in connection with,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1590_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general It is unlawful for the pilot of any aircraft to transport, or for any individual on board any aircraft to possess, merchandise knowing, or intending, that the merchandise will be introduced into the United States contrary to law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1590_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sea transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sea transfers It is unlawful for any person to transfer merchandise between an aircraft and a vessel on the high seas or in the customs waters of the United States if such person has not been authorized by the Secretary to make such transfer and—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1590_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Civil penalties Any person who violates any provision of this section is liable for a civil penalty equal to twice the value of the merchandise involved in the violation, but not less than $10,000. The value of any controlled substance included in the merchandise shall be determined in accordance with section 1497(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1590_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criminal penalties In addition to being liable for a civil penalty under subsection (c), any person who intentionally commits, or attempts or conspires to commit, a violation of any provision of this section is, upon conviction—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1590_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seizure and forfeiture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Seizure and forfeiture</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1590_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Merchandise” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Merchandise” defined As used in this section, the term “merchandise” means only merchandise the importation of which into the United States is prohibited or restricted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1590_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definition of aircraft In this section, the term “aircraft”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1590_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intent of transfer of merchandise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Intent of transfer of merchandise For purposes of imposing civil penalties under this section, any of the following acts, when performed within 250 miles of the territorial sea of the United States, shall be prima facie evidence that the transportation or possession of merchandise was unlawful and shall be presumed to constitute circumstances indicating that the purpose of the transfer is to make it possible for such merchandise, or any part thereof, to be introduced into the United States unlawfully, and for purposes of subsection (e) or section 1595a of this title, shall be prima facie evidence that an aircraft or vessel was used in connection with, or to aid or facilitate, a violation of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>