<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1593a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1593a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1593a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1593a"><akn:num>1593a</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for false drawback claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1593a. Penalties for false drawback claims(a) Prohibition(1) General ruleNo person, by fraud, or negligence—(A) may seek, induce or affect, or attempt to seek, induce, or affect, the payment or credit to that person or others of any drawback claim by means of—(i) any document, written or oral statement, or electronically transmitted data or information, or act which is material and false, or

(ii) any omission which is material; or


(B) may aid or abet any other person to violate subparagraph (A).


(2) ExceptionClerical errors or mistakes of fact are not violations of paragraph (1) unless they are part of a pattern of negligent conduct. The mere nonintentional repetition by an electronic system of an initial clerical error does not constitute a pattern of negligent conduct.



(b) Procedures(1) Prepenalty notice(A) In generalIf the Customs Service has reasonable cause to believe that there has been a violation of subsection (a) and determines that further proceedings are warranted, the Customs Service shall issue to the person concerned a written notice of intent to issue a claim for a monetary penalty. Such notice shall—(i) identify the drawback claim;

(ii) set forth the details relating to the seeking, inducing, or affecting, or the attempted seeking, inducing, or affecting, or the aiding or procuring of, the drawback claim;

(iii) specify all laws and regulations allegedly violated;

(iv) disclose all the material facts which establish the alleged violation;

(v) state whether the alleged violation occurred as a result of fraud or negligence;

(vi) state the estimated actual or potential loss of revenue due to the drawback claim, and, taking into account all circumstances, the amount of the proposed monetary penalty; and

(vii) inform such person that he shall have a reasonable opportunity to make representations, both oral and written, as to why a claim for a monetary penalty should not be issued in the amount stated.


(B) ExceptionsThe Customs Service may</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1593a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1593a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1593a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maximum penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1593a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deprivation of lawful revenue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deprivation of lawful revenue Notwithstanding section 1514 of this title, if the United States has been deprived of lawful duties and taxes resulting from a violation of subsection (a), the Customs Service shall require that such duties and taxes be restored whether or not a monetary penalty is assessed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1593a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drawback compliance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Drawback compliance program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1593a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternatives to penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Alternatives to penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1593a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repetitive violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Repetitive violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1593a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulation The Secretary shall promulgate regulations and guidelines to implement this section. Such regulations shall specify that for purposes of subsections (c) and (g), a repeat negligent violation involving the same issue shall be treated as a repetitive violation for a maximum period of 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1593a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court of International Trade proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Court of International Trade proceedings Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in any proceeding commenced by the United States in the Court of International Trade for the recovery of any monetary penalty claimed under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>