<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1617" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1617/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1617/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1617"><akn:num>1617</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise of Government claims by Secretary of the Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1617. Compromise of Government claims by Secretary of the Treasury
Upon a report by a customs officer, United States attorney, or any special attorney, having charge of any claim arising under the customs laws, showing the facts upon which such claim is based, the probabilities of a recovery and the terms upon which the same may be compromised, the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to compromise such claim, if such action shall be recommended by the General Counsel for the Department of the Treasury.
(June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title IV, § 617, 46 Stat. 757; May 10, 1934, ch. 277, § 512(b), 48 Stat. 759; June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1, 62 Stat. 869; Pub. L. 91–271, title III, § 301(gg), June 2, 1970, 84 Stat. 291.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in act Sept. 21, 1922, ch. 356, title IV, § 617, 42 Stat. 987. That section was superseded by section 617 of act June 17, 1930, comprising this section, and repealed by section 651(a)(1) of the 1930 act.

Amendments1970—Pub. L. 91–271 substituted reference to customs officer for reference to collector and struck out reference to customs agents.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Act June 25, 1948, eff. Sept. 1, 1948, substituted “United States attorney” for “district attorney”. See section 541 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, and Historical and Revision Note thereunder.

Effective Date of 1970 AmendmentFor effective date of amendment by Pub. L. 91–271, see section 203 of Pub. L. 91–271, set out as a note under section 1500 of this title.


Transfer of Functions
Act May 10, 1934, ch. 277, § 512(b), 48 Stat. 759, abolished offices of General Counsel and Assistant General Counsel for Bureau of Internal Revenue, and office of Solicitor and Assistant Solicitor of the Treasury and transferred powers, duties, and functions thereof to General Counsel for Department of the Treasury.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>