<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1619" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1619/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1619/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1619"><akn:num>1619</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of compensation to informers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1619. Award of compensation to informers(a) In generalIf—(1) any person who is not an employee or officer of the United States—(A) detects and seizes any vessel, vehicle, aircraft, merchandise, or baggage subject to seizure and forfeiture under the customs laws or the navigation laws and reports such detection and seizure to a customs officer, or

(B) furnishes to a United States attorney, the Secretary of the Treasury, or any customs officer original information concerning—(i) any fraud upon the customs revenue, or

(ii) any violation of the customs laws or the navigation laws which is being, or has been, perpetrated or contemplated by any other person; and



(2) such detection and seizure or such information leads to a recovery of—(A) any duties withheld, or

(B) any fine, penalty, or forfeiture of property incurred;



the Secretary may award and pay such person an amount that does not exceed 25 percent of the net amount so recovered.

(b) Forfeited property not soldIf—(1) any vessel, vehicle, aircraft, merchandise, or baggage is forfeited to the United States and is thereafter, in lieu of sale—(A) destroyed under the customs or navigation laws, or

(B) delivered to any governmental agency for official use, and


(2) any person would be eligible to receive an award under subsection (a) but for the lack of sale of such forfeited property,


the Secretary may award and pay such person an amount that does not exceed 25 percent of the appraised value of such forfeited property.

(c) Dollar limitationThe amount awarded and paid to any person under this section may not exceed $250,000 for any case.


(d) Source of paymentUnless otherwise provided by law, any amount paid under this section shall be paid out of appropriations available for the collection of the customs revenue.


(e) Recovery of bail bondFor purposes of this section, an amount recovered under a bail bond shall be deemed a recovery of a fine incurred.


(June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title IV, § 619, 46 Stat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1619_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If— the Secretary may award and pay such person an amount that does not exceed 25 percent of the net amount so recovered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1619_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeited property not sold</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Forfeited property not sold If— the Secretary may award and pay such person an amount that does not exceed 25 percent of the appraised value of such forfeited property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1619_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dollar limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dollar limitation The amount awarded and paid to any person under this section may not exceed $250,000 for any case.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1619_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Source of payment Unless otherwise provided by law, any amount paid under this section shall be paid out of appropriations available for the collection of the customs revenue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1619_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of bail bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recovery of bail bond For purposes of this section, an amount recovered under a bail bond shall be deemed a recovery of a fine incurred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>