<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1631"><akn:num>1631</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of private collection agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1631. Use of private collection agencies(a) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate, shall enter into contracts and incur obligations with one or more persons for collection services to recover indebtedness arising under the customs laws and owed the United States Government, but only after the Customs Service has exhausted all administrative efforts, including all claims against applicable surety bonds, to collect the indebtedness.


(b) Contract requirementsAny contract entered into under subsection (a) shall provide that—(1) the Secretary retains the authority to resolve a dispute, compromise a claim, end collection action, and refer a matter to the Attorney General to bring a civil action; and

(2) the person is subject to—(A) section 552a of title 5 to the extent provided in subsection (m) of such section; and

(B) laws and regulations of the United States Government and State governments related to debt collection practices.



(c) Payment of costsThe debtor shall be assessed and pay any and all costs associated with collection efforts pursuant to this section. Notwithstanding section 3302(b) of title 31, any sum so collected shall be used to pay the costs of debt collection services.


(June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title IV, § 631, as added Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 671, Dec. 8, 1993, 107 Stat. 2217; amended Pub. L. 104–295, § 3(a)(9), Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3516; Pub. L. 106–36, title I, § 1001(b)(5)(A), June 25, 1999, 113 Stat. 132.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1999—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 106–36 amended directory language of Pub. L. 104–295. See 1996 Amendment note below.
1996—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 104–295, as amended by Pub. L. 106–36, added subsec. (c).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1996 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 104–295 applicable as of Dec. 8, 1993, see section 3(b) of Pub. L. 104–295, set out as a note under section 1321 o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate, shall enter into contracts and incur obligations with one or more persons for collection services to recover indebtedness arising under the customs laws and owed the United States Government, but only after the Customs Service has exhausted all administrative efforts, including all claims against applicable surety bonds, to collect the indebtedness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contract requirements Any contract entered into under subsection (a) shall provide that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of costs The debtor shall be assessed and pay any and all costs associated with collection efforts pursuant to this section. Notwithstanding section 3302(b) of title 31, any sum so collected shall be used to pay the costs of debt collection services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>