<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1641" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1641/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1641/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1641"><akn:num>1641</akn:num><akn:heading>Customs brokers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1641. Customs brokers(a) DefinitionsAs used in this section:(1) The term “customs broker” means any person granted a customs broker’s license by the Secretary under subsection (b).

(2) The term “customs business” means those activities involving transactions with U.S. Customs and Border Protection concerning the entry and admissibility of merchandise, its classification and valuation, the payment of duties, taxes, or other charges assessed or collected by U.S. Customs and Border Protection upon merchandise by reason of its importation, or the refund, rebate, or drawback thereof. It also includes the preparation of documents or forms in any format and the electronic transmission of documents, invoices, bills, or parts thereof, intended to be filed with U.S. Customs and Border Protection in furtherance of such activities, whether or not signed or filed by the preparer, or activities relating to such preparation, but does not include the mere electronic transmission of data received for transmission to Customs.

(3) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Treasury.


(b) Customs broker’s licenses(1) In generalNo person may conduct customs business (other than solely on behalf of that person) unless that person holds a valid customs broker’s license issued by the Secretary under paragraph (2) or (3).


(2) Licenses for individualsThe Secretary may grant an individual a customs broker’s license only if that individual is a citizen of the United States. Before granting the license, the Secretary may require an applicant to show any facts deemed necessary to establish that the applicant is of good moral character and qualified to render valuable service to others in the conduct of customs business. In assessing the qualifications of an applicant, the Secretary may conduct an examination to determine the applicant’s knowledge of customs and related laws, regulations and procedures, bookkeeping, accounting, and all other appropriate matters.


(3) Licenses for cor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customs broker’s licenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Customs broker’s licenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customs broker’s permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Customs broker’s permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disciplinary proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disciplinary proceedings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial appeal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Judicial appeal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations by the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations by the Secretary The Secretary may prescribe such rules and regulations relating to the customs business of customs brokers as the Secretary considers necessary to protect importers and the revenue of the United States, and to carry out the provisions of this section, including rules and regulations governing the licensing of or issuance of permits to customs brokers, the keeping of books, accounts, and records by customs brokers, and documents and correspondence, and the furnishing by customs brokers of any other information relating to their customs business to any duly accredited officer or employee of U.S. Customs and Border Protection. The Secretary may not prohibit customs brokers from limiting their liability to other persons in the conduct of customs business. For purposes of this subsection or any other provision of this chapter pertaining to recordkeeping, all data required to be retained by a customs broker may be kept on microfilm, optical disc, magnetic tap</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Triennial reports by customs brokers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Triennial reports by customs brokers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Fees and charges The Secretary may prescribe reasonable fees and charges to defray the costs of U.S. Customs and Border Protection in carrying out the provisions of this section, including, but not limited to, a fee for licenses issued under subsection (b) and fees for any test administered by him or under his direction; except that no separate fees shall be imposed to defray the costs of an individual audit or of individual disciplinary proceedings of any nature.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1641_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of importers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Identification of importers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>