<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1645" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1645/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1645/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1645"><akn:num>1645</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation and interment of remains of deceased employees in foreign countries; travel or shippi</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1645. Transportation and interment of remains of deceased employees in foreign countries; travel or shipping expenses incurred on foreign ships(a) Transfers in foreign countriesThe expense of transporting the remains of customs officers and employees who die while in or in transit to foreign countries in the discharge of their official duties, to their former homes in this country for interment, and the ordinary and necessary expenses for such interment, at their posts of duty or at home, are authorized to be paid upon the written order of the Secretary of the Treasury. The expenses authorized by this subdivision shall be paid from the appropriation for the collection of the revenue from customs.


(b) Transportation on foreign shipsNotwithstanding the provisions of section 601 of the Merchant Marine Act, 1928, or of any other law, any allowance, within the limitations prescribed by law, for travel or shipping expenses incurred on a foreign ship by any officer or employee of the Bureau of Customs or the Customs Service, shall be credited if the Secretary of the Treasury certifies to the Comptroller General that transportation on such foreign ship was necessary to protect the revenue.


(June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title IV, § 645(a), (c), 46 Stat. 761; Aug. 2, 1946, ch. 744, § 2, 60 Stat. 807.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 601 of the Merchant Marine Act, 1928, referred to in subsec. (b), was classified to section 891r of former Title 46, Shipping, and was repealed by the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 (approved June 29, 1936, ch. 858, § 903(c), 49 Stat. 2016), but was reenacted in substance by section 901 of that Act, which was classified to section 1241 of the former Appendix to Title 46, Shipping. Section 901 of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 was subsequently repealed and restated in sections 55302, 55303, and 55305 of Title 46, Shipping, by Pub. L. 109–304, §§ 8(c), 19, Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1586, 1710. For disposition of sections of the former Appendix </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1645_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers in foreign countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfers in foreign countries The expense of transporting the remains of customs officers and employees who die while in or in transit to foreign countries in the discharge of their official duties, to their former homes in this country for interment, and the ordinary and necessary expenses for such interment, at their posts of duty or at home, are authorized to be paid upon the written order of the Secretary of the Treasury. The expenses authorized by this subdivision shall be paid from the appropriation for the collection of the revenue from customs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1645_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation on foreign ships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transportation on foreign ships Notwithstanding the provisions of section 601 of the Merchant Marine Act, 1928, or of any other law, any allowance, within the limitations prescribed by law, for travel or shipping expenses incurred on a foreign ship by any officer or employee of the Bureau of Customs or the Customs Service, shall be credited if the Secretary of the Treasury certifies to the Comptroller General that transportation on such foreign ship was necessary to protect the revenue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>