<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1673c"><akn:num>1673c</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination or suspension of investigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1673c. Termination or suspension of investigation(a) Termination of investigation upon withdrawal of petition(1) In general(A) Withdrawal of petitionExcept as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), an investigation under this part may be terminated by either the administering authority or the Commission, after notice to all parties to the investigation, upon withdrawal of the petition by the petitioner or by the administering authority if the investigation was initiated under section 1673a(a) of this title.


(B) Refiling of petitionIf, within 3 months after the withdrawal of a petition under subparagraph (A), a new petition is filed seeking the imposition of duties on both the subject merchandise of the withdrawn petition and the subject merchandise from another country, the administering authority and the Commission may use in the investigation initiated pursuant to the new petition any records compiled in an investigation conducted pursuant to the withdrawn petition. This subparagraph applies only with respect to the first withdrawal of a petition.



(2) Special rules for quantitative restriction agreements(A) In generalSubject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), the administering authority may not terminate an investigation under paragraph (1) by accepting an understanding or other kind of agreement to limit the volume of imports into the United States of the subject merchandise unless the administering authority is satisfied that termination on the basis of that agreement is in the public interest.


(B) Public interest factorsIn making a decision under subparagraph (A) regarding the public interest the administering authority shall take into account—(i) whether, based upon the relative impact on consumer prices and the availability of supplies of the merchandise, the agreement would have a greater adverse impact on United States consumers than the imposition of antidumping duties;

(ii) the relative impact on the international economic interests of the United States</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of investigation upon withdrawal of petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Termination of investigation upon withdrawal of petition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements to eliminate completely sales at less than fair value or to cease exports of merchandise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agreements to eliminate completely sales at less than fair value or to cease exports of merchandise The administering authority may suspend an investigation if the exporters of the subject merchandise who account for substantially all of the imports of that merchandise agree—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements eliminating injurious effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreements eliminating injurious effect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional rules and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional rules and conditions The administering authority may not accept an agreement under subsection (b) or (c) unless— Where practicable, the administering authority shall provide to the exporters who would have been subject to the agreement the reasons for not accepting the agreement and, to the extent possible, an opportunity to submit comments thereon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of investigation procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Suspension of investigation procedure Before an investigation may be suspended under subsection (b) or (c) the administering authority shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effects of suspension of investigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effects of suspension of investigation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation to be continued upon request</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Investigation to be continued upon request If the administering authority, within 20 days after the date of publication of the notice of suspension of an investigation, receives a request for the continuation of the investigation from— then the administering authority and the Commission shall continue the investigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of suspension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Review of suspension</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violation of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Violation of agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination not to take agreement into account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Determination not to take agreement into account In making a final determination under section 1673d of this title, or in conducting a review under section 1675 of this title, in a case in which the administering authority has terminated a suspension of investigation under subsection (i)(1), or continued an investigation under subsection (g), the Commission and the administering authority shall consider all of the subject merchandise without regard to the effect of any agreement under subsection (b) or (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>