<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1673d"><akn:num>1673d</akn:num><akn:heading>Final determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1673d. Final determinations(a) Final determination by administering authority(1) General ruleWithin 75 days after the date of its preliminary determination under section 1673b(b) of this title, the administering authority shall make a final determination of whether the subject merchandise is being, or is likely to be, sold in the United States at less than its fair value.


(2) Extension of period for determinationThe administering authority may postpone making the final determination under paragraph (1) until not later than the 135th day after the date on which it published notice of its preliminary determination under section 1673b(b) of this title if a request in writing for such a postponement is made by—(A) exporters who account for a significant proportion of exports of the merchandise which is the subject of the investigation, in a proceeding in which the preliminary determination by the administering authority under section 1673b(b) of this title was affirmative, or

(B) the petitioner, in a proceeding in which the preliminary determination by the administering authority under section 1673b(b) of this title was negative.


(3) Critical circumstances determinationsIf the final determination of the administering authority is affirmative, then that determination, in any investigation in which the presence of critical circumstances has been alleged under section 1673b(e) of this title, shall also contain a finding of whether—(A)(i) there is a history of dumping and material injury by reason of dumped imports in the United States or elsewhere of the subject merchandise, or

(ii) the person by whom, or for whose account, the merchandise was imported knew or should have known that the exporter was selling the subject merchandise at less than its fair value and that there would be material injury by reason of such sales, and


(B) there have been massive imports of the subject merchandise over a relatively short period.


Such findings may be affirmative even thou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final determination by administering authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Final determination by administering authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final determination by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Final determination by Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of final determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effect of final determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of notice of determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publication of notice of determinations Whenever the administering authority or the Commission makes a determination under this section, it shall notify the petitioner, other parties to the investigation, and the other agency of its determination and of the facts and conclusions of law upon which the determination is based, and it shall publish notice of its determination in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Correction of ministerial errors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Correction of ministerial errors The administering authority shall establish procedures for the correction of ministerial errors in final determinations within a reasonable time after the determinations are issued under this section. Such procedures shall ensure opportunity for interested parties to present their views regarding any such errors. As used in this subsection, the term “ministerial error” includes errors in addition, subtraction, or other arithmetic function, clerical errors resulting from inaccurate copying, duplication, or the like, and any other type of unintentional error which the administering authority considers ministerial.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>