<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1673"><akn:num>1673</akn:num><akn:heading>Antidumping duties imposed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1673. Antidumping duties imposed
If—(1) the administering authority determines that a class or kind of foreign merchandise is being, or is likely to be, sold in the United States at less than its fair value, and

(2) the Commission determines that—(A) an industry in the United States—(i) is materially injured, or

(ii) is threatened with material injury, or


(B) the establishment of an industry in the United States is materially retarded,


by reason of imports of that merchandise or by reason of sales (or the likelihood of sales) of that merchandise for importation,


then there shall be imposed upon such merchandise an antidumping duty, in addition to any other duty imposed, in an amount equal to the amount by which the normal value exceeds the export price (or the constructed export price) for the merchandise. For purposes of this section and section 1673d(b)(1) of this title, a reference to the sale of foreign merchandise includes the entering into of any leasing arrangement regarding the merchandise that is equivalent to the sale of the merchandise.
(June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title VII, § 731, as added Pub. L. 96–39, title I, § 101, July 26, 1979, 93 Stat. 162; amended Pub. L. 98–573, title VI, § 602(b), Oct. 30, 1984, 98 Stat. 3024; Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 233(a)(1)(A), (2)(A)(i), Dec. 8, 1994, 108 Stat. 4898.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–465 substituted “normal value exceeds the export price (or the constructed export price)” for “foreign market value exceeds the United States price” in concluding provisions.
1984—Pub. L. 98–573 inserted “or by reason of sales (or the likelihood of sales) of that merchandise for importation” after “by reason of imports of that merchandise” in par. (2), and inserted sentence at end providing that for purposes of this section and section 1673d(b)(1) of this title, a reference to the sale of foreign merchandise includes the entering into of any leasing arrangement regarding the merchandise that is equivalen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) the administering authority determines that a class or kind of foreign merchandise is being, or is likely to be, sold in the United States at less than its fair value, and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) the Commission determines that— by reason of imports of that merchandise or by reason of sales (or the likelihood of sales) of that merchandise for importation,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>