<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1673h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1673h"><akn:num>1673h</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of product categories for short life cycle merchandise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1673h. Establishment of product categories for short life cycle merchandise(a) Establishment of product categories(1) Petitions(A) In generalAn eligible domestic entity may file a petition with the Commission requesting that a product category be established with respect to short life cycle merchandise at any time after the merchandise becomes the subject of 2 or more affirmative dumping determinations.


(B) ContentsA petition filed under subparagraph (A) shall—(i) identify the short life cycle merchandise that is the subject of the affirmative dumping determinations,

(ii) specify the short life cycle merchandise that the petitioner seeks to have included in the same product category as the merchandise that is subject to the affirmative dumping determinations,

(iii) specify any short life cycle merchandise the petitioner particularly seeks to have excluded from the product category,

(iv) provide reasons for the inclusions and exclusions specified under clauses (ii) and (iii), and

(v) identify such merchandise in terms of the designations used in the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.



(2) Determinations on sufficiency of petitionUpon receiving a petition under paragraph (1), the Commission shall—(A) request the administering authority to confirm promptly the affirmative determinations on which the petition is based, and

(B) upon receipt of such confirmation, determine whether the merchandise covered by the confirmed affirmative determinations is short life cycle merchandise and whether the petitioner is an eligible domestic entity.


(3) Notice; hearingsIf the determinations under paragraph (2)(B) are affirmative, the Commission shall—(A) publish notice in the Federal Register that the petition has been received, and

(B) provide opportunity for the presentation of views regarding the establishment of the requested product category, including a public hearing if requested by any interested person.


(4) Determinations(A) In generalBy no later</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of product categories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of product categories</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1673h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transitional rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transitional rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>