<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1675b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1675b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1675b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1675b"><akn:num>1675b</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for injury investigations for certain section 1303 or section 1671(c) countervailing d</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1675b. Special rules for injury investigations for certain section 1303 or section 1671(c) countervailing duty orders and investigations(a) In general(1) Investigation by the commission upon requestIn the case of a countervailing duty order described in paragraph (2), which—(A) applies to merchandise that is the product of a Subsidies Agreement country, and

(B)(i) is in effect on the date on which such country becomes a Subsidies Agreement country, or

(ii) is issued on a date that is after the date described in clause (i) pursuant to a court order in an action brought under section 1516a of this title,



the Commission, upon receipt of a request from an interested party described in section 1677(9)(C), (D), (E), (F), or (G) of this title for an injury investigation with respect to such order, shall initiate an investigation and shall determine whether an industry in the United States is likely to be materially injured by reason of imports of the subject merchandise if the order is revoked.

(2) Description of countervailing duty ordersA countervailing duty order described in this paragraph is an order issued under section 1303 11 See References in Text note below. of this title or section 1671(c) of this title with respect to which the requirement of an affirmative determination of material injury was not applicable at the time such order was issued.


(3) Requirements of request for investigationA request for an investigation under this subsection shall be submitted—(A) in the case of an order described in paragraph (1)(B)(i), within 6 months after the date on which the country described in paragraph (1)(A) becomes a Subsidies Agreement country, or

(B) in the case of an order described in paragraph (1)(B)(ii), within 6 months after the date the order is issued.


(4) Suspension of liquidationWith respect to entries of subject merchandise made on or after—(A) in the case of an order described in paragraph (1)(B)(i), the date on which the country described in p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation procedure and schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investigation procedure and schedule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pending and suspended countervailing duty investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Pending and suspended countervailing duty investigations If, on the date on which a country becomes a Subsidies Agreement country, there is a countervailing duty investigation in progress or suspended under section 1303 1 of this title or section 1671(c) of this title that applies to merchandise which is a product of that country and with respect to which the requirement of an affirmative determination of material injury was not applicable at the time the investigation was initiated, the Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publication in Federal Register The administering authority or the Commission, as the case may be, shall publish in the Federal Register a notice of the initiation of any investigation, and a notice of any determination or revocation, made pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for simultaneous expedited review under section 1675(c)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Request for simultaneous expedited review under section 1675(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>