<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1675" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1675/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1675/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1675"><akn:num>1675</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative review of determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1675. Administrative review of determinations(a) Periodic review of amount of duty(1) In generalAt least once during each 12-month period beginning on the anniversary of the date of publication of a countervailing duty order under this subtitle or under section 1303 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, an antidumping duty order under this subtitle or a finding under the Antidumping Act, 1921, or a notice of the suspension of an investigation, the administering authority, if a request for such a review has been received and after publication of notice of such review in the Federal Register, shall—(A) review and determine the amount of any net countervailable subsidy,

(B) review, and determine (in accordance with paragraph (2)), the amount of any antidumping duty, and

(C) review the current status of, and compliance with, any agreement by reason of which an investigation was suspended, and review the amount of any net countervailable subsidy or dumping margin involved in the agreement,


and shall publish in the Federal Register the results of such review, together with notice of any duty to be assessed, estimated duty to be deposited, or investigation to be resumed.

(2) Determination of antidumping duties(A) In generalFor the purpose of paragraph (1)(B), the administering authority shall determine—(i) the normal value and export price (or constructed export price) of each entry of the subject merchandise, and

(ii) the dumping margin for each such entry.


(B) Determination of antidumping or countervailing duties for new exporters and producers(i) In generalIf the administering authority receives a request from an exporter or producer of the subject merchandise establishing that—(I) such exporter or producer did not export the merchandise that was the subject of an antidumping duty or countervailing duty order to the United States (or, in the case of a regional industry, did not export the subject merchandise for sale in the region concerned) dur</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review of amount of duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Periodic review of amount of duty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reviews based on changed circumstances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reviews based on changed circumstances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Five-year review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Five-year review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation of order or finding; termination of suspended investigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Revocation of order or finding; termination of suspended investigation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Hearings Whenever the administering authority or the Commission conducts a review under this section, it shall, upon the request of an interested party, hold a hearing in accordance with section 1677c(b) of this title in connection with that review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination that basis for suspension no longer exists</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Determination that basis for suspension no longer exists If the determination of the Commission under subsection (b)(2)(B) is negative, the suspension agreement shall be treated as not accepted, beginning on the date of publication of the Commission’s determination, and the administering authority and the Commission shall proceed, under section 1671c(i) or 1673c(i) of this title, as if the suspension agreement had been violated on that date, except that no duty under any order subsequently issued shall be assessed on merchandise entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption before that date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reviews to implement results of subsidies enforcement proceeding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reviews to implement results of subsidies enforcement proceeding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1675_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Correction of ministerial errors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Correction of ministerial errors The administering authority shall establish procedures for the correction of ministerial errors in final determinations within a reasonable time after the determinations are issued under this section. Such procedures shall ensure opportunity for interested parties to present their views regarding any such errors. As used in this subsection, the term “ministerial error” includes errors in addition, subtraction, or other arithmetic function, clerical errors resulting from inaccurate copying, duplication, or the like, and any other type of unintentional error which the administering authority considers ministerial.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>