<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1676" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1676/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1676/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1676"><akn:num>1676</akn:num><akn:heading>Required consultations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1676. Required consultations(a) Agreements in response to countervailable subsidiesWithin 90 days after the administering authority accepts a quantitative restriction agreement under section 1671c(a)(2) or (c)(3) of this title, the President shall enter into consultations with the government that is party to the agreement for purposes of—(1) eliminating the countervailable subsidy completely, or

(2) reducing the net countervailable subsidy to a level that eliminates completely the injurious effect of exports to the United States of the merchandise.


(b) Modification of agreements on basis of consultationsAt the direction of the President, the administering authority shall modify a quantitative restriction agreement as a result of consultations entered into under subsection (a).


(c) Special rule regarding agreements under section 1671c(c)(3) of this titleThis subpart shall cease to apply to a quantitative restriction agreement described in section 1671c(c)(3) of this title at such time as that agreement ceases to have force and effect under section 1671c(f) of this title or violation is found under section 1671c(i) of this title.


(June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title VII, § 761, as added Pub. L. 98–573, title VI, § 611(a)(4), Oct. 30, 1984, 98 Stat. 3031; amended Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 270(a)(1)(I), (b)(1)(C), (2), Dec. 8, 1994, 108 Stat. 4917.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 103–465, § 270(b)(1)(C), (2), inserted “countervailable” before “subsidies” in heading.
Subsec. (a)(1), (2). Pub. L. 103–465, § 270(a)(1)(I), inserted “countervailable” before “subsidy”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1994 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 103–465 effective, except as otherwise provided, on the date on which the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States (Jan. 1, 1995), and applicable with respect to investigations, reviews, and inquiries initiated and petitions filed under specified provisions of this </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1676_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements in response to countervailable subsidies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Agreements in response to countervailable subsidies Within 90 days after the administering authority accepts a quantitative restriction agreement under section 1671c(a)(2) or (c)(3) of this title, the President shall enter into consultations with the government that is party to the agreement for purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1676_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of agreements on basis of consultations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Modification of agreements on basis of consultations At the direction of the President, the administering authority shall modify a quantitative restriction agreement as a result of consultations entered into under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1676_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule regarding agreements under section 1671c(c)(3) of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule regarding agreements under This subpart shall cease to apply to a quantitative restriction agreement described in section 1671c(c)(3) of this title at such time as that agreement ceases to have force and effect under section 1671c(f) of this title or violation is found under section 1671c(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>