<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1677"><akn:num>1677</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions; special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1677. Definitions; special rules
For purposes of this subtitle—(1) Administering authorityThe term “administering authority” means the Secretary of Commerce, or any other officer of the United States to whom the responsibility for carrying out the duties of the administering authority under this subtitle are transferred by law.


(2) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the United States International Trade Commission.


(3) CountryThe term “country” means a foreign country, a political subdivision, dependent territory, or possession of a foreign country, and, except for the purpose of antidumping proceedings, may include an association of 2 or more foreign countries, political subdivisions, dependent territories, or possessions of countries into a customs union outside the United States.


(4) Industry(A) In generalThe term “industry” means the producers as a whole of a domestic like product, or those producers whose collective output of a domestic like product constitutes a major proportion of the total domestic production of the product.


(B) Related parties(i) If a producer of a domestic like product and an exporter or importer of the subject merchandise are related parties, or if a producer of the domestic like product is also an importer of the subject merchandise, the producer may, in appropriate circumstances, be excluded from the industry.

(ii) For purposes of clause (i), a producer and an exporter or importer shall be considered to be related parties, if—(I) the producer directly or indirectly controls the exporter or importer,

(II) the exporter or importer directly or indirectly controls the producer,

(III) a third party directly or indirectly controls the producer and the exporter or importer, or

(IV) the producer and the exporter or importer directly or indirectly control a third party and there is reason to believe that the relationship causes the producer to act differently than a nonrelated producer.


For purposes of this subparagraph, a par</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administering authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Administering authority The term “administering authority” means the Secretary of Commerce, or any other officer of the United States to whom the responsibility for carrying out the duties of the administering authority under this subtitle are transferred by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Commission The term “Commission” means the United States International Trade Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Country The term “country” means a foreign country, a political subdivision, dependent territory, or possession of a foreign country, and, except for the purpose of antidumping proceedings, may include an association of 2 or more foreign countries, political subdivisions, dependent territories, or possessions of countries into a customs union outside the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Industry</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Countervailable subsidy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Countervailable subsidy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_5A"><akn:num>(5A)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specificity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5A) Specificity For purposes of this paragraph and paragraph (5B), any reference to an enterprise or industry is a reference to a foreign enterprise or foreign industry and includes a group of such enterprises or industries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_5B"><akn:num>(5B)</akn:num><akn:heading>Categories of noncountervailable subsidies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5B) Categories of noncountervailable subsidies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net countervailable subsidy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Net countervailable subsidy For the purpose of determining the net countervailable subsidy, the administering authority may subtract from the gross countervailable subsidy the amount of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Material injury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Material injury</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsidies Agreement; Agreement on Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Subsidies Agreement; Agreement on Agriculture</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>