<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677f–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677f–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677f–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1677f_1"><akn:num>1677f–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Sampling and averaging; determination of weighted average dumping margin and countervailable subsidy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1677f–1. Sampling and averaging; determination of weighted average dumping margin and countervailable subsidy rate(a) In generalFor purposes of determining the export price (or constructed export price) under section 1677a of this title or the normal value under section 1677b of this title, and in carrying out reviews under section 1675 of this title, the administering authority may—(1) use averaging and statistically valid samples, if there is a significant volume of sales of the subject merchandise or a significant number or types of products, and

(2) decline to take into account adjustments which are insignificant in relation to the price or value of the merchandise.


(b) Selection of averages and samplesThe authority to select averages and statistically valid samples shall rest exclusively with the administering authority. The administering authority shall, to the greatest extent possible, consult with the exporters and producers regarding the method to be used to select exporters, producers, or types of products under this section.


(c) Determination of dumping margin(1) General ruleIn determining weighted average dumping margins under section 1673b(d), 1673d(c), or 1675(a) of this title, the administering authority shall determine the individual weighted average dumping margin for each known exporter and producer of the subject merchandise.


(2) ExceptionIf it is not practicable to make individual weighted average dumping margin determinations under paragraph (1) because of the large number of exporters or producers involved in the investigation or review, the administering authority may determine the weighted average dumping margins for a reasonable number of exporters or producers by limiting its examination to—(A) a sample of exporters, producers, or types of products that is statistically valid based on the information available to the administering authority at the time of selection, or

(B) exporters and producers accounting for the largest volume </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For purposes of determining the export price (or constructed export price) under section 1677a of this title or the normal value under section 1677b of this title, and in carrying out reviews under section 1675 of this title, the administering authority may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of averages and samples</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection of averages and samples The authority to select averages and statistically valid samples shall rest exclusively with the administering authority. The administering authority shall, to the greatest extent possible, consult with the exporters and producers regarding the method to be used to select exporters, producers, or types of products under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of dumping margin</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination of dumping margin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of less than fair value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Determination of less than fair value</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of countervailable subsidy rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Determination of countervailable subsidy rate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of antidumping duty in certain proceedings relating to imports from nonmarket economy countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Adjustment of antidumping duty in certain proceedings relating to imports from nonmarket economy countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>