<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1677f"><akn:num>1677f</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1677f. Access to information(a) Information generally made available(1) Public information functionThere shall be established a library of information relating to foreign subsidy practices and countervailing measures. Copies of material in the library shall be made available to the public upon payment of the costs of preparing such copies.


(2) Progress of investigation reportsThe administering authority and the Commission shall, from time to time upon request, inform the parties to an investigation of the progress of that investigation.


(3) Ex parte meetingsThe administering authority and the Commission shall maintain a record of any ex parte meeting between—(A) interested parties or other persons providing factual information in connection with a proceeding, and

(B) the person charged with making the determination, or any person charged with making a final recommendation to that person, in connection with that proceeding,


if information relating to that proceeding was presented or discussed at such meeting. The record of such an ex parte meeting shall include the identity of the persons present at the meeting, the date, time, and place of the meeting, and a summary of the matters discussed or submitted. The record of the ex parte meeting shall be included in the record of the proceeding.

(4) Summaries; non-proprietary submissionsThe administering authority and the Commission shall disclose—(A) any proprietary information received in the course of a proceeding if it is disclosed in a form which cannot be associated with, or otherwise be used to identify, operations of a particular person, and

(B) any information submitted in connection with a proceeding which is not designated as proprietary by the person submitting it.



(b) Proprietary information(1) Proprietary status maintained(A) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (a)(4)(A) and subsection (c), information submitted to the administering authority or the Commission which is designated as propr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information generally made available</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information generally made available</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proprietary information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Proprietary information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited disclosure of certain proprietary information under protective order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limited disclosure of certain proprietary information under protective order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Service Any party submitting written information, including business proprietary information, to the administering authority or the Commission during a proceeding shall, at the same time, serve the information upon all interested parties who are parties to the proceeding, if the information is covered by a protective order. The administering authority or the Commission shall not accept any such information that is not accompanied by a certificate of service and a copy of the protective order version of the document containing the information. Business proprietary information shall only be served upon interested parties who are parties to the proceeding that are subject to protective order; however, a nonconfidential summary thereof shall be served upon all other interested parties who are parties to the proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 231(d)(1), Dec. 8, 1994, 108 Stat. 4897</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of proprietary information under protective orders issued pursuant to the United States-Canada Agreement or the USMCA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosure of proprietary information under protective orders issued pursuant to the United States-Canada Agreement or the USMCA</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information relating to violations of protective orders and sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Information relating to violations of protective orders and sanctions The administering authority and the Commission may withhold from disclosure any correspondence, private letters of reprimand, settlement agreements, and documents and files compiled in relation to investigations and actions involving a violation or possible violation of a protective order issued under subsection (c) or (d), and such information shall be treated as information described in section 552(b)(3) of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity for comment by consumers and industrial users</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Opportunity for comment by consumers and industrial users The administering authority and the Commission shall provide an opportunity for industrial users of the subject merchandise and, if the merchandise is sold at the retail level, for representative consumer organizations, to submit relevant information to the administering authority concerning dumping or a countervailable subsidy, and to the Commission concerning material injury by reason of dumped or subsidized imports.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677f_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of determinations; requirements for final determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Publication of determinations; requirements for final determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>