<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1677_2"><akn:num>1677–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation of countervailable subsidies on certain processed agricultural products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1677–2. Calculation of countervailable subsidies on certain processed agricultural products
In the case of an agricultural product processed from a raw agricultural product in which—(1) the demand for the prior stage product is substantially dependent on the demand for the latter stage product, and

(2) the processing operation adds only limited value to the raw commodity,


countervailable subsidies found to be provided to either producers or processors of the product shall be deemed to be provided with respect to the manufacture, production, or exportation of the processed product.
(June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title VII, § 771B, as added Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1313(a), Aug. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 1185; amended Pub. L. 100–647, title IX, § 9001(a)(4), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3806; Pub. L. 103–465, title II, § 270(b)(1)(D), (2), Dec. 8, 1994, 108 Stat. 4917.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–465 inserted “countervailable” before “subsidies” in section catchline and concluding provisions.
1988—Pub. L. 100–647 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “In the case of an agricultural product processed from a raw agricultural product in which (1) the demand for the prior stage product is substantially dependent on the demand for the latter stage product, and (2) the processing operation adds only limited value to the raw commodity, subsidies found to be provided to either producers or processors of the product shall be deemed to be provided with respect to the manufacture, production, or exportation of the processed product.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1994 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 103–465 effective, except as otherwise provided, on the date on which the WTO Agreement enters into force with respect to the United States (Jan. 1, 1995), and applicable with respect to investigations, reviews, and inquiries initiated and petitions filed under specified provisions of this chapter after such date,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_2_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) the demand for the prior stage product is substantially dependent on the demand for the latter stage product, and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_2_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) the processing operation adds only limited value to the raw commodity,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>