<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1677–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1677_1"><akn:num>1677–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Upstream subsidies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1677–1. Upstream subsidies(a) “Upstream subsidy” definedThe term “upstream subsidy” means any countervailable subsidy, other than an export subsidy, that—(1) is paid or bestowed by an authority (as defined in section 1677(5) of this title) with respect to a product (hereafter in this section referred to as an “input product”) that is used in the same country as the authority in the manufacture or production of merchandise which is the subject of a countervailing duty proceeding;

(2) in the judgment of the administering authority bestows a competitive benefit on the merchandise; and

(3) has a significant effect on the cost of manufacturing or producing the merchandise.


In applying this subsection, an association of two or more foreign countries, political subdivisions, dependent territories, or possessions of foreign countries organized into a customs union outside the United States shall be treated as being one country if the countervailable subsidy is provided by the customs union.

(b) Determination of competitive benefit(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the administering authority shall decide that a competitive benefit has been bestowed when the price for the input product referred to in subsection (a)(1) for such use is lower than the price that the manufacturer or producer of merchandise which is the subject of a countervailing duty proceeding would otherwise pay for the product in obtaining it from another seller in an arms-length transaction.


(2) AdjustmentsIf the administering authority has determined in a previous proceeding that a countervailable subsidy is paid or bestowed on the input product that is used for comparison under paragraph (1), the administering authority may (A) where appropriate, adjust the price that the manufacturer or producer of merchandise which is the subject of such proceeding would otherwise pay for the product to reflect the effects of the countervailable subsidy, or (B) select in lieu of that price a pri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Upstream subsidy” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Upstream subsidy” defined The term “upstream subsidy” means any countervailable subsidy, other than an export subsidy, that— In applying this subsection, an association of two or more foreign countries, political subdivisions, dependent territories, or possessions of foreign countries organized into a customs union outside the United States shall be treated as being one country if the countervailable subsidy is provided by the customs union.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of competitive benefit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of competitive benefit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1677_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of amount of countervailable subsidy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inclusion of amount of countervailable subsidy If the administering authority decides, during the course of a countervailing duty proceeding that an upstream countervailable subsidy is being or has been paid or bestowed regarding the subject merchandise, the administering authority shall include in the amount of any countervailing duty imposed on the merchandise an amount equal to the amount of the competitive benefit referred to in subparagraph (1)(B),11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (a)(2) of this section,”. except that in no event shall the amount be greater than the amount of the countervailable subsidy determined with respect to the upstream product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>