<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1681a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1681a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1681a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1681a"><akn:num>1681a</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for entry of certain cigarettes and smokeless tobacco products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1681a. Requirements for entry of certain cigarettes and smokeless tobacco products(a) General ruleExcept as provided in subsection (b), cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products may be imported into the United States only if—(1) the original manufacturer of those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products has timely submitted, or has certified that it will timely submit, to the Secretary of Health and Human Services the lists of the ingredients added to the tobacco in the manufacture of such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products as described in section 1335a of title 15 or section 4403 of title 15, as the case may be;

(2) the precise warning statements in the precise format specified in section 1333 of title 15 or section 4402 of title 15, as the case may be, are permanently imprinted on both—(A) the primary packaging of all those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products; and

(B) any other pack, box, carton, or container of any kind in which those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products are to be offered for sale or otherwise distributed to consumers;


(3) the manufacturer or importer of those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products is in compliance with respect to those cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products being imported into the United States with a rotation plan approved by the Federal Trade Commission pursuant to section 1333(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 15 or section 4402(d) 1 of title 15, as the case may be;

(4) if such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products bear a United States trademark registered for such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products, the owner of such United States trademark registration for cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products (or a person authorized to act on behalf of such owner) has consented to the importation of such cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products into the United States; and

(5) the importer has submitted at the time of entry all of the certificates described in subsection (c).


(b) Exemp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as provided in subsection (b), cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products may be imported into the United States only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exemptions Cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products satisfying the conditions of any of the following paragraphs shall not be subject to the requirements of subsection (a): For purposes of this section, a trademark is registered in the United States if it is registered in the United States Patent and Trademark Office under the provisions of title I of the Act of July 5, 1946 [15 U.S.C. 1051 et seq.] (popularly known as the “Trademark Act of 1946”), and a copy of the certificate of registration of such mark has been filed with the Secretary. The Secretary shall make available to interested parties a current list of the marks so filed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customs certifications required for cigarette or smokeless tobacco product imports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Customs certifications required for cigarette or smokeless tobacco product imports The certificates that must be submitted by the importer of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products at the time of entry in order to comply with subsection (a)(5) are— The Secretary may provide by regulation for the submission of certifications under this section in electronic form if, prior to the entry of any cigarettes or smokeless tobacco products into the United States, the person required to provide such certifications submits to the Secretary a written statement, signed under penalties of perjury, verifying the accuracy and completeness of all information contained in such electronic submissions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1681a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State access to customs certifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State access to customs certifications A State, through its Attorney General, shall be entitled to obtain copies of any certification required under subsection (c) directly—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>