<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1751" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1751/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1751/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1751"><akn:num>1751</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of fairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1751. Designation of fairs(a) Notice to Secretary of the TreasuryWhen the Secretary of Commerce is satisfied that the public interest in promoting trade will be served by allowance of the privileges provided for in this chapter to any fair to be held in the United States, he shall so advise the Secretary of the Treasury, designating (1) the name of the fair, (2) the place where the fair will be held, (3) the date when the fair will open and the date when it will close, and (4) the name of the operator of the fair.


(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this chapter—(1) The term “fair” means any fair, exhibition, or exposition designated by the Secretary of Commerce pursuant to this section.

(2) The term “closing date” in the case of any fair means the date designated pursuant to subsection (a)(3) as the date when the fair will close, or (if earlier) the date on which such fair actually closes.


(c) RegulationsThe Secretary of Commerce may prescribe such regulations as he deems necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section.


(Pub. L. 86–14, § 2, Apr. 22, 1959, 73 Stat. 18.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short TitlePub. L. 86–14, § 1, Apr. 22, 1959, 73 Stat. 18, provided: “This Act [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Trade Fair Act of 1959’.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1751_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Secretary of the Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice to Secretary of the Treasury When the Secretary of Commerce is satisfied that the public interest in promoting trade will be served by allowance of the privileges provided for in this chapter to any fair to be held in the United States, he shall so advise the Secretary of the Treasury, designating (1) the name of the fair, (2) the place where the fair will be held, (3) the date when the fair will open and the date when it will close, and (4) the name of the operator of the fair.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1751_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1751_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations The Secretary of Commerce may prescribe such regulations as he deems necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>