<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1754" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1754/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1754/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1754"><akn:num>1754</akn:num><akn:heading>Marking, packaging, and labeling requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1754. Marking, packaging, and labeling requirements(a) Marking requirements of the customs lawsArticles entered under section 1752 of this title shall not be subject to any marking requirements of the customs laws, except that when any such article is entered for consumption under section 1753 of this title it shall not be released from customs custody until the marking requirements of the customs laws have been complied with.


(b) Packaging, marking, or labeling requirements of the internal-revenue laws or the Federal Alcohol Administration ActArticles entered under section 1752 of this title shall not be subject to the packaging, marking, or labeling requirements of the internal-revenue laws or of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act [27 U.S.C. 201 et seq.], except that any such article failing to comply with such requirements—(1) shall be conspicuously marked prior to exhibition “Not labeled or packaged as required by law—not for sale”, and

(2) when entered for consumption under section 1753 of this title, shall not be released from customs custody until such packaging, marking, and labeling requirements have been complied with.


The application of the permit requirements of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act and the occupational taxes prescribed by chapter 51 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be determined without regard to this chapter.

(Pub. L. 86–14, § 5, Apr. 22, 1959, 73 Stat. 19; Pub. L. 99–514, § 2, Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2095.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Alcohol Administration Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is act Aug. 29, 1935, ch. 814, 49 Stat. 977, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 201 et seq.) of chapter 8 of Title 27, Intoxicating Liquors. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 201 of Title 27 and Tables.
Chapter 51 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (b), is classified to section 5001 et seq. of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code.

Amendment</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1754_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marking requirements of the customs laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Marking requirements of the customs laws Articles entered under section 1752 of this title shall not be subject to any marking requirements of the customs laws, except that when any such article is entered for consumption under section 1753 of this title it shall not be released from customs custody until the marking requirements of the customs laws have been complied with.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1754_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Packaging, marking, or labeling requirements of the internal-revenue laws or the Federal Alcohol Administration Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Packaging, marking, or labeling requirements of the internal-revenue laws or the Federal Alcohol Administration Act Articles entered under section 1752 of this title shall not be subject to the packaging, marking, or labeling requirements of the internal-revenue laws or of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act [27 U.S.C. 201 et seq.], except that any such article failing to comply with such requirements— The application of the permit requirements of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act and the occupational taxes prescribed by chapter 51 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be determined without regard to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>