<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1862" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1862/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1862/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1862"><akn:num>1862</akn:num><akn:heading>Safeguarding national security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1862. Safeguarding national security(a) Prohibition on decrease or elimination of duties or other import restrictions if such reduction or elimination would threaten to impair national securityNo action shall be taken pursuant to section 1821(a) of this title or pursuant to section 1351 of this title to decrease or eliminate the duty or other import restrictions on any article if the President determines that such reduction or elimination would threaten to impair the national security.


(b) Investigations by Secretary of Commerce to determine effects on national security of imports of articles; consultation with Secretary of Defense and other officials; hearings; assessment of defense requirements; report to President; publication in Federal Register; promulgation of regulations(1)(A) Upon request of the head of any department or agency, upon application of an interested party, or upon his own motion, the Secretary of Commerce (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall immediately initiate an appropriate investigation to determine the effects on the national security of imports of the article which is the subject of such request, application, or motion.

(B) The Secretary shall immediately provide notice to the Secretary of Defense of any investigation initiated under this section.


(2)(A) In the course of any investigation conducted under this subsection, the Secretary shall—(i) consult with the Secretary of Defense regarding the methodological and policy questions raised in any investigation initiated under paragraph (1),

(ii) seek information and advice from, and consult with, appropriate officers of the United States, and

(iii) if it is appropriate and after reasonable notice, hold public hearings or otherwise afford interested parties an opportunity to present information and advice relevant to such investigation.


(B) Upon the request of the Secretary, the Secretary of Defense shall provide the Secretary an assessment of the defens</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on decrease or elimination of duties or other import restrictions if such reduction or elimination would threaten to impair national security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition on decrease or elimination of duties or other import restrictions if such reduction or elimination would threaten to impair national security No action shall be taken pursuant to section 1821(a) of this title or pursuant to section 1351 of this title to decrease or eliminate the duty or other import restrictions on any article if the President determines that such reduction or elimination would threaten to impair the national security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations by Secretary of Commerce to determine effects on national security of imports of articles; consultation with Secretary of Defense and other officials; hearings; assessment of defense requirements; report to President; publication in Federal Register; promulgation of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investigations by Secretary of Commerce to determine effects on national security of imports of articles; consultation with Secretary of Defense and other officials; hearings; assessment of defense requirements; report to President; publication in Federal Register; promulgation of regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of imports; determination by President; report to Congress; additional actions; publication in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adjustment of imports; determination by President; report to Congress; additional actions; publication in Federal Register</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. There are two subsecs. designated (d). Second subsec. (d) probably should be designated (e). Domestic production for national defense; impact of foreign competition on economic welfare of domestic industries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For the purposes of this section, the Secretary and the President shall, in the light of the requirements of national security and without excluding other relevant factors, give consideration to domestic production needed for projected national defense requirements, the capacity of domestic industries to meet such requirements, existing and anticipated availabilities of the human resources, products, raw materials, and other supplies and services essential to the national defense, the requirements of growth of such industries and such supplies and services including the investment, exploration, and development necessary to assure such growth, and the importation of goods in terms of their quantities, availabilities, character, and use as those affect such industries and the capacity of the United States to meet national security requirements. In the administration of this section, the Secretary and the President shall further recognize the close relation of the economic welfare of </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>1 Report by Secretary of Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional disapproval of Presidential adjustment of imports of petroleum or petroleum products; disapproval resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Congressional disapproval of Presidential adjustment of imports of petroleum or petroleum products; disapproval resolution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>