<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1918" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1918/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1918/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1918"><akn:num>1918</akn:num><akn:heading>Protective provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1918. Protective provisions(a) Maintenance of records by recipients of assistanceEach recipient of adjustment assistance under section 1913, 1914, or 1917 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, shall keep records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds, if any, of such adjustment assistance, and which will facilitate an effective audit. The recipient shall also keep such other records as the Secretary of Commerce may prescribe.


(b) Access to books, documents, papers, and records for purpose of audit and examinationThe Secretary of Commerce and the Comptroller General of the United States shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and rec­ords of the recipient pertaining to adjustment assistance under sections 1913, 1914, and 1917 1 of this title.


(c) Certification of names and fees of attorneys, agents, and other persons engaged for purpose of expediting applications for assistanceNo adjustment assistance shall be extended under section 1913, 1914, or 1917 1 of this title to any firm unless the owners, partners, or officers certify to the Secretary of Commerce—(1) the names of any attorneys, agents, and other persons engaged by or on behalf of the firm for the purpose of expediting applications for such adjustment assistance, and

(2) the fees paid or to be paid to any such person.


(d) Agreement with respect to employment of persons who occupied a position, or engaged in activities which the Secretary of Commerce determines involved discretionNo financial assistance shall be provided to any firm under section 1914 1 of this title unless the owners, partners, or officers shall execute an agreement binding them and the firm for a period of 2 years after such financial assistance is provided, to refrain from employing, tendering any office or employment to, or retaining for professional services any person who, on the date such assistance or any part thereof</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1918_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of records by recipients of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Maintenance of records by recipients of assistance Each recipient of adjustment assistance under section 1913, 1914, or 1917 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, shall keep records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds, if any, of such adjustment assistance, and which will facilitate an effective audit. The recipient shall also keep such other records as the Secretary of Commerce may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1918_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to books, documents, papers, and records for purpose of audit and examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Access to books, documents, papers, and records for purpose of audit and examination The Secretary of Commerce and the Comptroller General of the United States shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and rec­ords of the recipient pertaining to adjustment assistance under sections 1913, 1914, and 1917 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1918_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of names and fees of attorneys, agents, and other persons engaged for purpose of expediting applications for assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certification of names and fees of attorneys, agents, and other persons engaged for purpose of expediting applications for assistance No adjustment assistance shall be extended under section 1913, 1914, or 1917 1 of this title to any firm unless the owners, partners, or officers certify to the Secretary of Commerce—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1918_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement with respect to employment of persons who occupied a position, or engaged in activities which the Secretary of Commerce determines involved discretion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Agreement with respect to employment of persons who occupied a position, or engaged in activities which the Secretary of Commerce determines involved discretion No financial assistance shall be provided to any firm under section 1914 1 of this title unless the owners, partners, or officers shall execute an agreement binding them and the firm for a period of 2 years after such financial assistance is provided, to refrain from employing, tendering any office or employment to, or retaining for professional services any person who, on the date such assistance or any part thereof was provided, or within one year prior thereto, shall have served as an officer, attorney, agent, or employee occupying a position or engaging in activities which the Secretary of Commerce shall have determined involve discretion with respect to the provision of such financial assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>