<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1981" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1981/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/1981/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1981"><akn:num>1981</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1981. General authority(a) Proclamation of increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction; report to the Congress; adoption of resolution of approval; request for additional information(1) After receiving an affirmative finding of the United States International Trade Commission under section 1901(b) of this title with respect to an industry, the President may proclaim such increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction on the article causing or threatening to cause serious injury to such industry as he determines to be necessary to prevent or remedy serious injury to such industry.

(2) If the President does not, within 60 days after the date on which he receives such affirmative finding, proclaim the increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction on such article found and reported by the United States International Trade Commission pursuant to section 1901(e) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title—(A) he shall immediately submit a report to the House of Representatives and to the Senate stating why he has not proclaimed such increase or imposition, and

(B) such increase or imposition shall take effect (as provided in paragraph (3)) upon the adoption by both Houses of the Congress (within the 60-day period following the date on which the report referred to in subparagraph (A) is submitted to the House of Representatives and the Senate), by the yeas and nays by the affirmative vote of a majority of the authorized membership of each House, of a concurrent resolution stating in effect that the Senate and House of Representatives approve the increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction on the article found and reported by the United States International Trade Commission.


For purposes of subparagraph (B), in the computation of the 60-day period there shall be excluded the days on which either House is not in session because of adjournment of more than 3 days to a day </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1981_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proclamation of increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction; report to the Congress; adoption of resolution of approval; request for additional information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proclamation of increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction; report to the Congress; adoption of resolution of approval; request for additional information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1981_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum rate of increase</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Maximum rate of increase No proclamation pursuant to subsection (a) shall be made— For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “existing on July 1, 1934” has the meaning assigned to such term by paragraph (5) of section 1886 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1981_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction, termination, or extension of increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reduction, termination, or extension of increase in, or imposition of, any duty or other import restriction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1981_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of developments with respect to industries concerned; annual report to President; advice of probable economic effect; considerations; investigations; hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of developments with respect to industries concerned; annual report to President; advice of probable economic effect; considerations; investigations; hearings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1981_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conformity of trade agreements with this section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conformity of trade agreements with this section The President, as soon as practicable, shall take such action as he determines to be necessary to bring trade agreements entered into under section 1351 of this title into conformity with the provisions of this section. No trade agreement shall be entered into under section 1821(a) of this title unless such agreement permits action in conformity with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>