<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2071" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2071/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2071/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2071"><akn:num>2071</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Service; Commissioner; appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2071. Establishment of Service; Commissioner; appointment
There shall be in the Department of the Treasury a service to be known as the United States Customs Service, and a Commissioner of Customs.11 See Change of Name note below. The Commissioner of Customs,1 who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall—(1) be at the head of the United States Customs Service;

(2) carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury; and

(3) report to the Secretary of the Treasury through such other officials as may be designated by the Secretary.

(Mar. 3, 1927, ch. 348, § 1, 44 Stat. 1381; May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 8, 46 Stat. 430; Ex. Ord. No. 6639, § 1a, Mar. 10, 1934; Pub. L. 101–207, § 3(b)(1), Dec. 7, 1989, 103 Stat. 1833; Pub. L. 114–125, title VIII, § 802(d)(2), Feb. 24, 2016, 130 Stat. 210.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Provisions that fixed the compensation of the Commissioner have been omitted as the position is under the Executive Schedule, see section 5316 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.
Provisions that authorized appointment of the Commissioner “without regard to the civil service laws” were omitted as the appointment is subject to the civil service laws unless specifically excepted by such laws or by laws enacted subsequent to Executive Order No. 8743, Apr. 23, 1941, issued by the President pursuant to the act of Nov. 26, 1940, ch. 919, title I, § 1, 54 Stat. 1211, which covered most excepted positions into the classified (competitive) civil service. The Order is set out as a note under section 3301 of Title 5. The position is currently excepted from the civil service rules and regulations by Schedule C, see Part 213 of Title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations.
Section was formerly classified to section 281 of Title 5 prior to the general revision and codification of Title 5 by Pub. L. 89–554, § 1, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 378.
References to the Bureau of Prohibition and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2071_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) be at the head of the United States Customs Service;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2071_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2071_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) report to the Secretary of the Treasury through such other officials as may be designated by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>