<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2079" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2079/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2079/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2079"><akn:num>2079</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments in foreign countries; claims for reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2079. Payments in foreign countries; claims for reimbursement
The provisions of this Act shall not affect payments made for the United States Customs Service in foreign countries, nor the right of any customs officer or employee to claim reimbursement for personal funds expended in connection with the enforcement of the customs laws.
(Mar. 28, 1928, ch. 266, § 4, as added Aug. 7, 1939, ch. 566, § 1, 53 Stat. 1263; amended Pub. L. 91–513, title III, § 1102(n)(3), Oct. 27, 1970, 84 Stat. 1293.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in text, is act Mar. 28, 1928, ch. 266, 45 Stat. 374, which enacted sections 2077 to 2080 of this title and sections 529a and 529g of former Title 31, Money and Finance. Sections 529a and 529g of former Title 31, were repealed by sections 1101(a)(3) and 1101(a)(6), respectively, of Pub. L. 91–513, title III, Oct. 27, 1970, 84 Stat. 1291, 1292.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 529e of Title 31 prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by Pub. L. 97–258, § 1, Sept. 13, 1982, 96 Stat. 877.

Amendments1970—Pub. L. 91–513 struck out references to narcotics officers and narcotics laws.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1970 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 91–513 effective on first day of seventh calendar month that begins after the day immediately preceding the date of enactment of Pub. L. 91–513, which was approved on Oct. 27, 1970, see section 1105(a) of Pub. L. 91–513, set out as an Effective Date note under section 951 of Title 21, Food and Drugs.

Savings ProvisionProsecutions for any violation of law occurring, and civil seizures or forfeitures and injunctive proceedings commenced, prior to the effective date of amendment of this section by section 1102 of Pub. L. 91–513 not to be affected or abated by reason thereof, see section 1103 of Pub. L. 91–513, set out as a note under section 171 of Title 21, Food and Drugs.


Transfer of Functio</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>