<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2083" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2083/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2083/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2083"><akn:num>2083</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual national trade and customs law violation estimates and enforcement strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2083. Annual national trade and customs law violation estimates and enforcement strategy(a) Violation estimatesNot later than 30 days before the beginning of each fiscal year after fiscal year 1991, the Commissioner of Customs 11 See Change of Name note below. shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Committees”) a report that contains estimates of—(1) the number and extent of violations of the trade, customs, and illegal drug control laws listed under subsection (b) that will likely occur during the fiscal year; and

(2) the relative incidence of the violations estimated under paragraph (1) among the various ports of entry and customs regions within the customs territory.


(b) Applicable statutory provisionsThe Commissioner of Customs,1 after consultation with the Committees—(1) shall, within 60 days after August 20, 1990, prepare a list of those provisions of the trade, customs, and illegal drug control laws of the United States for which the United States Customs Service has enforcement responsibility and to which the reports required under subsection (a) will apply; and

(2) may from time-to-time amend the listing developed under paragraph (1).


(c) Enforcement strategyWithin 90 days after submitting a report under subsection (a) for any fiscal year, the Commissioner of Customs 1 shall—(1) develop a nationally uniform enforcement strategy for dealing during that year with the violations estimated in the report; and

(2) submit to the Committees a report setting forth the details of the strategy.


(d) Compliance programThe Commissioner of Customs 1 shall—(1) devise and implement a methodology for estimating the level of compliance with the laws administered by the Customs Service; and

(2) include as an additional part of the report required to be submitted under subsection (a) for each of fiscal years 1994, 1995, and 1996, an eval</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2083_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violation estimates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Violation estimates Not later than 30 days before the beginning of each fiscal year after fiscal year 1991, the Commissioner of Customs 11 See Change of Name note below. shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Committees”) a report that contains estimates of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2083_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable statutory provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicable statutory provisions The Commissioner of Customs,1 after consultation with the Committees—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2083_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement strategy Within 90 days after submitting a report under subsection (a) for any fiscal year, the Commissioner of Customs 1 shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2083_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compliance program The Commissioner of Customs 1 shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2083_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Confidentiality The contents of any report submitted to the Committees under subsection (a) or (c)(2) are confidential and disclosure of all or part of the contents is restricted to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>