<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2112"><akn:num>2112</akn:num><akn:heading>Barriers to and other distortions of trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2112. Barriers to and other distortions of trade(a) Congressional findings; directives; disavowal of prior approval of legislationThe Congress finds that barriers to (and other distortions of) international trade are reducing the growth of foreign markets for the products of United States agriculture, industry, mining, and commerce, diminishing the intended mutual benefits of reciprocal trade concessions, adversely affecting the United States economy, preventing fair and equitable access to supplies, and preventing the development of open and nondiscriminatory trade among nations. The President is urged to take all appropriate and feasible steps within his power (including the full exercise of the rights of the United States under international agreements) to harmonize, reduce, or eliminate such barriers to (and other distortions of) international trade. The President is further urged to utilize the authority granted by subsection (b) to negotiate trade agreements with other countries and instrumentalities providing on a basis of mutuality for the harmonization, reduction, or elimination of such barriers to (and other distortions of) international trade. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as prior approval of any legislation which may be necessary to implement an agreement concerning barriers to (or other distortions of) international trade.


(b) Presidential determinations prerequisite to entry into trade agreements; trade with Israel(1) Whenever the President determines that any barriers to (or other distortions of) international trade of any foreign country or the United States unduly burden and restrict the foreign trade of the United States or adversely affect the United States economy, or that the imposition of such barriers is likely to result in such a burden, restriction, or effect, and that the purposes of this chapter will be promoted thereby, the President, during the 13-year period beginning on January 3, 1975, may enter into trade agreeme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings; directives; disavowal of prior approval of legislation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings; directives; disavowal of prior approval of legislation The Congress finds that barriers to (and other distortions of) international trade are reducing the growth of foreign markets for the products of United States agriculture, industry, mining, and commerce, diminishing the intended mutual benefits of reciprocal trade concessions, adversely affecting the United States economy, preventing fair and equitable access to supplies, and preventing the development of open and nondiscriminatory trade among nations. The President is urged to take all appropriate and feasible steps within his power (including the full exercise of the rights of the United States under international agreements) to harmonize, reduce, or eliminate such barriers to (and other distortions of) international trade. The President is further urged to utilize the authority granted by subsection (b) to negotiate trade agreements with other countries and instrumentalities providing on a basis of m</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential determinations prerequisite to entry into trade agreements; trade with Israel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Presidential determinations prerequisite to entry into trade agreements; trade with Israel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential consultation with Congress prior to entry into trade agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Presidential consultation with Congress prior to entry into trade agreements Before the President enters into any trade agreement under this section providing for the harmonization, reduction, or elimination of a barrier to (or other distortion of) international trade, he shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and with each committee of the House and the Senate and each joint committee of the Congress which has jurisdiction over legislation involving subject matters which would be affected by such trade agreement. Such consultation shall include all matters relating to the implementation of such trade agreement as provided in subsections (d) and (e). If it is proposed to implement such trade agreement, together with one or more other trade agreements entered into under this section, in a single implementing bill, such consultation shall include the desirability and feasibility of such proposed impl</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2112_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Congress of agreements, drafts of implementing bills, and statements of proposed administrative action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Submission to Congress of agreements, drafts of implementing bills, and statements of proposed administrative action Whenever the President enters into a trade agreement under this section providing for the harmonization, reduction, or elimination of a barrier to (or other distortion of) international trade, he shall submit such agreement, together with a draft of an implementing bill (described in section 2191(b) of this title) and a statement of any administrative action proposed to implement such agreement, to the Congress as provided in subsection (e), and such agreement shall enter into force with respect to the United States only if the provisions of subsection (e) are complied with and the implementing bill submitted by the President is enacted into law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2112_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Steps prerequisite to entry into force of trade agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Steps prerequisite to entry into force of trade agreements Each trade agreement submitted to the Congress under this subsection shall enter into force with respect to the United States if (and only if)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2112_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations imposed upon foreign countries or instrumentalities receiving benefits under trade agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Obligations imposed upon foreign countries or instrumentalities receiving benefits under trade agreements To insure that a foreign country or instrumentality which receives benefits under a trade agreement entered into under this section is subject to the obligations imposed by such agreement, the President may recommend to Congress in the implementing bill and statement of administrative action submitted with respect to such agreement that the benefits and obligations of such agreement apply solely to the parties to such agreement, if such application is consistent with the terms of such agreement. The President may also recommend with respect to any such agreement that the benefits and obligations of such agreement not apply uniformly to all parties to such agreement, if such application is consistent with the terms of such agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2112_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>