<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2132" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2132/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2132/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2132"><akn:num>2132</akn:num><akn:heading>Balance-of-payments authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2132. Balance-of-payments authority(a) Presidential proclamations of temporary import surcharges and temporary limitations on imports through quotas in situations of fundamental international payments problemsWhenever fundamental international payments problems require special import measures to restrict imports—(1) to deal with large and serious United States balance-of-payments deficits.

(2) to prevent an imminent and significant depreciation of the dollar in foreign exchange markets, or

(3) to cooperate with other countries in correcting an international balance-of-payments disequilibrium,


the President shall proclaim, for a period not exceeding 150 days (unless such period is extended by Act of Congress)—
(A) a temporary import surcharge, not to exceed 15 percent ad valorem, in the form of duties (in addition to those already imposed, if any) on articles imported into the United States;

(B) temporary limitations through the use of quotas on the importation of articles into the United States; or

(C) both a temporary import surcharge described in subparagraph (A) and temporary limitations described in subparagraph (B).


The authority delegated under subparagraph (B) (and so much of subparagraph (C) as relates to subparagraph (B)) may be exercised (i) only if international trade or monetary agreements to which the United States is a party permit the imposition of quotas as a balance-of-payments measure, and (ii) only to the extent that the fundamental imbalance cannot be dealt with effectively by a surcharge proclaimed pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (C). Any temporary import surcharge proclaimed pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (C) shall be treated as a regular customs duty.

(b) Import restrictions not imposed when contrary to national interest of United StatesIf the President determines that the imposition of import restrictions under subsection (a) will be contrary to the national interest of the United States, then he may refrain from proclaiming such </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2132_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential proclamations of temporary import surcharges and temporary limitations on imports through quotas in situations of fundamental international payments problems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Presidential proclamations of temporary import surcharges and temporary limitations on imports through quotas in situations of fundamental international payments problems Whenever fundamental international payments problems require special import measures to restrict imports— the President shall proclaim, for a period not exceeding 150 days (unless such period is extended by Act of Congress)— The authority delegated under subparagraph (B) (and so much of subparagraph (C) as relates to subparagraph (B)) may be exercised (i) only if international trade or monetary agreements to which the United States is a party permit the imposition of quotas as a balance-of-payments measure, and (ii) only to the extent that the fundamental imbalance cannot be dealt with effectively by a surcharge proclaimed pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (C). Any temporary import surcharge proclaimed pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (C) shall be treated as a regular customs duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2132_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Import restrictions not imposed when contrary to national interest of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Import restrictions not imposed when contrary to national interest of United States If the President determines that the imposition of import restrictions under subsection (a) will be contrary to the national interest of the United States, then he may refrain from proclaiming such restrictions and he shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2132_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential proclamations liberalizing imports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Presidential proclamations liberalizing imports Whenever the President determines that fundamental international payments problems require special import measures to increase imports— the President is authorized to proclaim, for a period of 150 days (unless such period is extended by Act of Congress)— Import liberalizing actions proclaimed pursuant to this subsection shall be of broad and uniform application with respect to product coverage except that the President shall not proclaim measures under this subsection with respect to those articles where in his judgment such action will cause or contribute to material injury to firms or workers in any domestic industry, including agriculture, mining, fishing, or commerce, or to impairment of the national security, or will otherwise be contrary to the national interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2132_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscriminatory treatment of import restricting actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nondiscriminatory treatment of import restricting actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2132_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Broad and uniform application of import restricting actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Broad and uniform application of import restricting actions Import restricting actions proclaimed pursuant to subsection (a) shall be of broad and uniform application with respect to product coverage except where the President determines, consistently with the purposes of this section, that certain articles should not be subject to import restricting actions because of the needs of the United States economy. Such exceptions shall be limited to the unavailability of domestic supply at reasonable prices, the necessary importation of raw materials, avoiding serious dislocations in the supply of imported goods, and other similar factors. In addition, uniform exceptions may be made where import restricting actions will be unnecessary or ineffective in carrying out the purposes of this section, such as with respect to articles already subject to import restrictions, goods in transit, or goods under binding contract. Neither the authorization of import restricting actions nor the determin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2132_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quantitative limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Quantitative limitations Any quantitative limitation proclaimed pursuant to subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (a) on the quantity or value, or both, of an article—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2132_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension, modification, or termination of proclamations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Suspension, modification, or termination of proclamations The President may at any time, consistent with the provisions of this section, suspend, modify, or terminate, in whole or in part, any proclamation under this section either during the initial 150-day period of effectiveness or as extended by subsequent Act of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2132_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of tariff concessions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Termination of tariff concessions No provision of law authorizing the termination of tariff concessions shall be used to impose a surcharge on imports into the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>