<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2135" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2135/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2135/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2135"><akn:num>2135</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination and withdrawal authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2135. Termination and withdrawal authority(a) Grant of authority for termination or withdrawal at end of period specified in agreementEvery trade agreement entered into under this chapter shall be subject to termination, in whole or in part, or withdrawal, upon due notice, at the end of a period specified in the agreement. Such period shall be not more than 3 years from the date on which the agreement becomes effective. If the agreement is not terminated or withdrawn from at the end of the period so specified, it shall be subject to termination or withdrawal thereafter upon not more than 6 months’ notice.


(b) Authority to terminate proclamations at any timeThe President may at any time terminate, in whole or in part, any proclamation made under this chapter.


(c) Increased duties or other import restrictions following withdrawal, suspension, or modification of obligations with respect to trade of foreign countries or instrumentalitiesWhenever the United States, acting in pursuance of any of its rights or obligations under any trade agreement entered into pursuant to this chapter, section 1821 of this title, or section 1351 of this title, withdraws, suspends, or modifies any obligation with respect to the trade of any foreign country or instrumentality thereof, the President is authorized to proclaim increased duties or other import restrictions, to the extent, at such times, and for such periods as he deems necessary or appropriate, in order to exercise the rights or fulfill the obligations of the United States. No proclamation shall be made under this subsection increasing any existing duty to a rate more than 50 percent above the rate set forth in rate column numbered 2 of the Tariff Schedules of the United States, as in effect on January 1, 1975, or 20 percent ad valorem above the rate existing on January 1, 1975, whichever is higher.


(d) Retaliatory authorityWhenever any foreign country or instrumentality withdraws, suspends, or modifies the application o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2135_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant of authority for termination or withdrawal at end of period specified in agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant of authority for termination or withdrawal at end of period specified in agreement Every trade agreement entered into under this chapter shall be subject to termination, in whole or in part, or withdrawal, upon due notice, at the end of a period specified in the agreement. Such period shall be not more than 3 years from the date on which the agreement becomes effective. If the agreement is not terminated or withdrawn from at the end of the period so specified, it shall be subject to termination or withdrawal thereafter upon not more than 6 months’ notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2135_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to terminate proclamations at any time</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to terminate proclamations at any time The President may at any time terminate, in whole or in part, any proclamation made under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2135_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased duties or other import restrictions following withdrawal, suspension, or modification of obligations with respect to trade of foreign countries or instrumentalities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Increased duties or other import restrictions following withdrawal, suspension, or modification of obligations with respect to trade of foreign countries or instrumentalities Whenever the United States, acting in pursuance of any of its rights or obligations under any trade agreement entered into pursuant to this chapter, section 1821 of this title, or section 1351 of this title, withdraws, suspends, or modifies any obligation with respect to the trade of any foreign country or instrumentality thereof, the President is authorized to proclaim increased duties or other import restrictions, to the extent, at such times, and for such periods as he deems necessary or appropriate, in order to exercise the rights or fulfill the obligations of the United States. No proclamation shall be made under this subsection increasing any existing duty to a rate more than 50 percent above the rate set forth in rate column numbered 2 of the Tariff Schedules of the United States, as in effect on Januar</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2135_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retaliatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Retaliatory authority Whenever any foreign country or instrumentality withdraws, suspends, or modifies the application of trade agreement obligations of benefit to the United States without granting adequate compensation therefor, the President, in pursuance of rights granted to the United States under any trade agreement and to the extent necessary to protect United States economic interests (including United States balance of payments), may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2135_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation of duties or other import restrictions after termination of or withdrawal from agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Continuation of duties or other import restrictions after termination of or withdrawal from agreements Duties or other import restrictions required or appropriate to carry out any trade agreement entered into pursuant to this chapter, section 1821 of this title, or section 1351 of this title shall not be affected by any termination, in whole or in part, of such agreement or by the withdrawal of the United States from such agreement and shall remain in effect after the date of such termination or withdrawal for 1 year, unless the President by proclamation provides that such rates shall be restored to the level at which they would be but for the agreement. Within 60 days after the date of any such termination or withdrawal, the President shall transmit to the Congress his recommendations as to the appropriate rates of duty for all articles which were affected by the termination or withdrawal or would have been so affected but for the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2135_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public hearings Before taking any action pursuant to subsection (b), (c), or (d), the President shall provide for a public hearing during the course of which interested persons shall be given a reasonable opportunity to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard, unless he determines that such prior hearings will be contrary to the national interest because of the need for expeditious action, in which case he shall provide for a public hearing promptly after such action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>