<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2136" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2136/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2136/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2136"><akn:num>2136</akn:num><akn:heading>Reciprocal nondiscriminatory treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2136. Reciprocal nondiscriminatory treatment(a) Direct and indirect importsExcept as otherwise provided in this chapter or in any other provision of law, any duty or other import restriction or duty-free treatment proclaimed in carrying out any trade agreement under this subchapter shall apply to products of all foreign countries, whether imported directly or indirectly.


(b) Presidential determination of whether major industrial countries have made substantially equivalent concessions to the United StatesThe President shall determine, after the conclusion of all negotiations entered into under this chapter or at the end of the 5-year period beginning on January 3, 1975, whichever is earlier, whether any major industrial country has failed to make concessions under trade agreements entered into under this chapter which provide competitive opportunities for the commerce of the United States in such country substantially equivalent to the competitive opportunities, provided by concessions made by the United States under trade agreements entered into under this chapter, for the commerce of such country in the United States.


(c) Major industrial countriesFor purposes of this section, “major industrial country” means Canada, the European Economic Community, the individual member countries of such Community, Japan, and any other foreign country designated by the President for purposes of this subsection.


(Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 126, Jan. 3, 1975, 88 Stat. 1992; Pub. L. 105–362, title XIV, § 1401(b)(1), Nov. 10, 1998, 112 Stat. 3294.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 93–618, Jan. 3, 1975, 88 Stat. 1978, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under section 2101 of this title and Tables.

Amendments1998—Subsecs. (c), (d). Pub. L. 105–362 redesignated subsec. (d) as (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2136_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct and indirect imports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Direct and indirect imports Except as otherwise provided in this chapter or in any other provision of law, any duty or other import restriction or duty-free treatment proclaimed in carrying out any trade agreement under this subchapter shall apply to products of all foreign countries, whether imported directly or indirectly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2136_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential determination of whether major industrial countries have made substantially equivalent concessions to the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Presidential determination of whether major industrial countries have made substantially equivalent concessions to the United States The President shall determine, after the conclusion of all negotiations entered into under this chapter or at the end of the 5-year period beginning on January 3, 1975, whichever is earlier, whether any major industrial country has failed to make concessions under trade agreements entered into under this chapter which provide competitive opportunities for the commerce of the United States in such country substantially equivalent to the competitive opportunities, provided by concessions made by the United States under trade agreements entered into under this chapter, for the commerce of such country in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2136_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Major industrial countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Major industrial countries For purposes of this section, “major industrial country” means Canada, the European Economic Community, the individual member countries of such Community, Japan, and any other foreign country designated by the President for purposes of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>