<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2155" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2155/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2155/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2155"><akn:num>2155</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and advice from private and public sectors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2155. Information and advice from private and public sectors(a) In general(1) The President shall seek information and advice from representative elements of the private sector and the non-Federal governmental sector with respect to—(A) negotiating objectives and bargaining positions before entering into a trade agreement under this subchapter or section 4202 of this title;

(B) the operation of any trade agreement once entered into, including preparation for dispute settlement panel proceedings to which the United States is a party; and

(C) other matters arising in connection with the development, implementation, and administration of the trade policy of the United States, including those matters referred to in Reorganization Plan Number 3 of 1979 and Executive Order Numbered 12188, and the priorities for actions thereunder.


To the maximum extent feasible, such information and advice on negotiating objectives shall be sought and considered before the commencement of negotiations.

(2) The President shall consult with representative elements of the private sector and the non-Federal governmental sector on the overall current trade policy of the United States. The consultations shall include, but are not limited to, the following elements of such policy:(A) The principal multilateral and bilateral trade negotiating objectives and the progress being made toward their achievement.

(B) The implementation, operation, and effectiveness of recently concluded multilateral and bilateral trade agreements and resolution of trade disputes.

(C) The actions taken under the trade laws of the United States and the effectiveness of such actions in achieving trade policy objectives.

(D) Important developments in other areas of trade for which there must be developed a proper policy response.


(3) The President shall take the advice received through consultation under paragraph (2) into account in determining the importance which should be placed on each major objective and n</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committee for Trade Policy and Negotiations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advisory Committee for Trade Policy and Negotiations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General policy, sectoral, or functional advisory committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General policy, sectoral, or functional advisory committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy, technical, and other advice and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Policy, technical, and other advice and information Committees established under subsection (c) shall meet at the call of the United States Trade Representative and the Secretaries of Agriculture, Commerce, Labor, Defense, or other executive departments, as appropriate, to provide policy advice, technical advice and information, and advice on other factors relevant to the matters referred to in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meeting of advisory committees at conclusion of negotiations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Meeting of advisory committees at conclusion of negotiations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application of chapter 10 of title 5 The provisions of chapter 10 of title 5 apply—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade secrets and confidential information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Trade secrets and confidential information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory committee support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Advisory committee support The United States Trade Representative, and the Secretaries of Commerce, Labor, Defense, Agriculture, the Treasury, or other executive departments, as appropriate, shall provide such staff, information, personnel, and administrative services and assistance to advisory committees established under subsection (c) as such committees may reasonably require to carry out their activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with advisory committees; procedures; nonacceptance of committee advice or recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Consultation with advisory committees; procedures; nonacceptance of committee advice or recommendations It shall be the responsibility of the United States Trade Representative, in conjunction with the Secretaries of Commerce, Labor, Agriculture, the Treasury, or other executive departments, as appropriate, to adopt procedures for consultation with and obtaining information and advice from the advisory committees established under subsection (c) on a continuing and timely basis. Such consultation shall include the provision of information to each advisory committee as to— with respect to matters referred to in subsection (a). The United States Trade Representative shall not be bound by the advice or recommendations of such advisory committees, but shall inform the advisory committees of significant departures from such advice or recommendations made. In addition, in the course of consultations with the Congress under this subchapter, information on the advice and information provid</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private organizations or groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Private organizations or groups In addition to any advisory committee established under this section, the President shall provide adequate, timely and continuing opportunity for the submission on an informal basis (and, if such information is submitted under the provisions of subsection (g), on a confidential basis) by private organizations or groups, representing government, labor, industry, agriculture, small business, service industries, consumer interests, and others, of statistics, data and other trade information, as well as policy recommendations, pertinent to any matter referred to in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>