<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2171" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2171/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2171/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2171"><akn:num>2171</akn:num><akn:heading>Structure, functions, powers, and personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2171. Structure, functions, powers, and personnel(a) Establishment within Executive Office of the PresidentThere is established within the Executive Office of the President the Office of the United States Trade Representative (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Office”).


(b) United States Trade Representative; Deputy United States Trade Representatives(1) The Office shall be headed by the United States Trade Representative who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. As an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate, any nomination of the United States Trade Representative submitted to the Senate for confirmation, and referred to a committee, shall be referred to the Committee on Finance. The United States Trade Representative shall hold office at the pleasure of the President, shall be entitled to receive the same allowances as a chief of mission, and shall have the rank of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary.

(2) There shall be in the Office three Deputy United States Trade Representatives, one Chief Agricultural Negotiator, and one Chief Innovation and Intellectual Property Negotiator, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. As an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate, any nomination of a Deputy United States Trade Representative, the Chief Agricultural Negotiator, or the Chief Innovation and Intellectual Property Negotiator submitted to the Senate for its advice and consent, and referred to a committee, shall be referred to the Committee on Finance. Each Deputy United States Trade Representative, the Chief Agricultural Negotiator, and the Chief Innovation and Intellectual Property Negotiator shall hold office at the pleasure of the President and shall have the rank of Ambassador.

(3) There shall be in the Office one Chief Transparency Officer. The Chief Transparency Officer shall consult with Congress on transparency policy, co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2171_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment within Executive Office of the President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment within Executive Office of the President There is established within the Executive Office of the President the Office of the United States Trade Representative (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2171_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States Trade Representative; Deputy United States Trade Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) United States Trade Representative; Deputy United States Trade Representatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2171_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of United States Trade Representative and Deputy United States Trade Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties of United States Trade Representative and Deputy United States Trade Representatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2171_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unfair trade practices; additional duties of Representative; advisory committee; definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Unfair trade practices; additional duties of Representative; advisory committee; definition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2171_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of United States Trade Representative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Powers of United States Trade Representative The United States Trade Representative may, for the purpose of carrying out his functions under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2171_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of other Federal agencies The United States Trade Representative shall, to the extent he deems it necessary for the proper administration and execution of the trade agreements programs of the United States, draw upon the resources of, and consult with, Federal agencies in connection with the performance of his functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2171_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2171_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Center on Trade Implementation, Monitoring, and Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Interagency Center on Trade Implementation, Monitoring, and Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>