<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2193" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2193/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2193/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2193"><akn:num>2193</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolutions relating to extension of waiver authority under section 402 of the Trade Act of 1974</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2193. Resolutions relating to extension of waiver authority under section 402 of the Trade Act of 1974(a) Contents of resolutionFor purposes of this section, the term “resolution” means only a joint resolution of the two Houses of Congress, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the Congress does not approve the extension of the authority contained in section 402(c) of the Trade Act of 1974 recommended by the President to the Congress on ___ with respect to ___.”, with the first blank space being filled with the appropriate date, and the second blank space being filled with the names of those countries, if any, with respect to which such extension of authority is not approved, and with the clause beginning with “with respect to” being omitted if the extension of the authority is not approved with respect to any country.


(b) Application of rules of section 2192 of this title; exceptions(1) Except as provided in this section, the provisions of section 2192 of this title shall apply to resolutions described in subsection (a).

(2) In applying section 2192(c)(1) of this title, all calendar days shall be counted.

(3) That part of section 2192(d)(2) of this title which provides that no amendment is in order shall not apply to any amendment to a resolution which is limited to striking out or inserting the names of one or more countries or to striking out or inserting a with-respect-to clause. Debate in the House of Representatives on any amendment to a resolution shall be limited to not more than 1 hour which shall be equally divided between those favoring and those opposing the amendment. A motion in the House to further limit debate on an amendment to a resolution is not debatable.

(4) That part of section 2192(e)(4) of this title which provides that no amendment is in order shall not apply to any amendment to a resolution which is limited to striking out or inserting the names of one or more countries or to striking out or inserting a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2193_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contents of resolution For purposes of this section, the term “resolution” means only a joint resolution of the two Houses of Congress, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the Congress does not approve the extension of the authority contained in section 402(c) of the Trade Act of 1974 recommended by the President to the Congress on ___ with respect to ___.”, with the first blank space being filled with the appropriate date, and the second blank space being filled with the names of those countries, if any, with respect to which such extension of authority is not approved, and with the clause beginning with “with respect to” being omitted if the extension of the authority is not approved with respect to any country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2193_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of rules of section 2192 of this title; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of rules of</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2193_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of second resolution not in order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consideration of second resolution not in order It shall not be in order in either the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider a resolution with respect to a recommendation of the President under section 2432(d) of this title (other than a resolution described in subsection (a) received from the other House), if that House has adopted a resolution with respect to the same recommendation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2193_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures relating to conference reports in the Senate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Procedures relating to conference reports in the Senate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>