<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2212"><akn:num>2212</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmission of agreements to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2212. Transmission of agreements to Congress(a) Submission of copy and reasonsAs soon as practicable after a trade agreement entered into under section 2133 or 2134 of this title or under section 4202 of this title has entered into force with respect to the United States, the President shall, if he has not previously done so, transmit a copy of such trade agreement to each House of the Congress together with a statement, in the light of the advice of the International Trade Commission under section 2151(b) of this title, if any, and of other relevant considerations, of his reasons for entering into the agreement.


(b) Submission to each memberThe President shall transmit to each Member of the Congress a summary of the information required to be transmitted to each House under subsection (a). For purposes of this subsection, the term “Member” includes any Delegate or Resident Commissioner.


(Pub. L. 93–618, title I, § 162, Jan. 3, 1975, 88 Stat. 2008; Pub. L. 100–647, title IX, § 9001(a)(10), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3807; Pub. L. 107–210, div. B, title XXI, § 2110(a)(6), Aug. 6, 2002, 116 Stat. 1020; Pub. L. 114–26, title I, § 110(a)(7), June 29, 2015, 129 Stat. 358.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2015—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 114–26 substituted “section 4202 of this title” for “section 3803 of this title”.
2002—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 107–210 substituted “or under section 3803 of this title” for “or under section 2902 of this title”.
1988—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 100–647 struck out “part 1 of this subchapter or” after “entered into under”, and inserted “or under section 2902 of this title” after “2134 of this title”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1988 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 100–647 applicable as if such amendment took effect on Aug. 23, 1988, see section 9001(b) of Pub. L. 100–647, set out as an Effective and Termination Dates of 1988 Amendments note under section 58c of this title.

Executive Documents

Delegation of Authority
For delega</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of copy and reasons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission of copy and reasons As soon as practicable after a trade agreement entered into under section 2133 or 2134 of this title or under section 4202 of this title has entered into force with respect to the United States, the President shall, if he has not previously done so, transmit a copy of such trade agreement to each House of the Congress together with a statement, in the light of the advice of the International Trade Commission under section 2151(b) of this title, if any, and of other relevant considerations, of his reasons for entering into the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to each member</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submission to each member The President shall transmit to each Member of the Congress a summary of the information required to be transmitted to each House under subsection (a). For purposes of this subsection, the term “Member” includes any Delegate or Resident Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>