<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2253" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2253/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2253/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2253"><akn:num>2253</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by President after determination of import injury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2253. Action by President after determination of import injury(a) In general(1)(A) After receiving a report under section 2252(f) of this title containing an affirmative finding regarding serious injury, or the threat thereof, to a domestic industry, the President shall take all appropriate and feasible action within his power which the President determines will facilitate efforts by the domestic industry to make a positive adjustment to import competition and provide greater economic and social benefits than costs.

(B) The action taken by the President under subparagraph (A) shall be to such extent, and for such duration, subject to subsection (e)(1), that the President determines to be appropriate and feasible under such subparagraph.

(C) The interagency trade organization established under section 1872(a) of this title shall, with respect to each affirmative determination reported under section 2252(f) of this title, make a recommendation to the President as to what action the President should take under subparagraph (A).


(2) In determining what action to take under paragraph (1), the President shall take into account—(A) the recommendation and report of the Commission;

(B) the extent to which workers and firms in the domestic industry are—(i) benefitting from adjustment assistance and other manpower programs, and

(ii) engaged in worker retraining efforts;


(C) the efforts being made, or to be implemented, by the domestic industry (including the efforts included in any adjustment plan or commitment submitted to the Commission under section 2252(a) of this title) to make a positive adjustment to import competition;

(D) the probable effectiveness of the actions authorized under paragraph (3) to facilitate positive adjustment to import competition;

(E) the short- and long-term economic and social costs of the actions authorized under paragraph (3) relative to their short- and long-term economic and social benefits and other considerations relative to the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2253_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2253_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2253_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of action recommended by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Implementation of action recommended by Commission If the President reports under subsection (b)(1) or (2) that— the action recommended by the Commission shall take effect (as provided in subsection (d)(2)) upon the enactment of a joint resolution described in section 2192(a)(1)(A) of this title within the 90-day period beginning on the date on which the document referred to in subsection (b)(1) or (2) is transmitted to the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2253_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for taking effect of certain relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time for taking effect of certain relief</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2253_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations on actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2253_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certain agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2253_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>