<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2271" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2271/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2271/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2271"><akn:num>2271</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2271. Petitions(a) Filing of petitions; assistance; publication of notice(1) A petition for certification of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance for a group of workers under this part may be filed simultaneously with the Secretary and with the Governor of the State in which such workers’ firm or subdivision is located by any of the following:(A) The group of workers (including workers in an agricultural firm or subdivision of any agricultural firm).

(B) The certified or recognized union or other duly authorized representative of such workers.

(C) Employers of such workers, one-stop operators or one-stop partners (as defined in section 101 of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (29 U.S.C. 2801)),11 See References in Text note below. including State employment security agencies, or the State dislocated worker unit established under title I of such Act,1 on behalf of such workers.


(2) Upon receipt of a petition filed under paragraph (1), the Governor shall—(A) ensure that rapid response assistance and appropriate core and intensive services (as described in section 134 of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (29 U.S.C. 2864)) 1 authorized under other Federal laws are made available to the workers covered by the petition to the extent authorized under such laws; and

(B) assist the Secretary in the review of the petition by verifying such information and providing such other assistance as the Secretary may request.


(3) Upon receipt of the petition, the Secretary shall promptly publish notice in the Federal Register that the Secretary has received the petition and initiated an investigation.


(b) HearingIf the petitioner, or any other person found by the Secretary to have a substantial interest in the proceedings, submits not later than 10 days after the date of the Secretary’s publication under subsection (a) a request for a hearing, the Secretary shall provide for a public hearing and afford such interested persons an opportunity to be present, to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2271_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of petitions; assistance; publication of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Filing of petitions; assistance; publication of notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2271_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hearing If the petitioner, or any other person found by the Secretary to have a substantial interest in the proceedings, submits not later than 10 days after the date of the Secretary’s publication under subsection (a) a request for a hearing, the Secretary shall provide for a public hearing and afford such interested persons an opportunity to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>