<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2296" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2296/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2296/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2296"><akn:num>2296</akn:num><akn:heading>Training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2296. Training(a) Approval of training; limitation on expenditures; reasonable expectation of employment; payment of costs; approved training programs; nonduplication of payments from other sources; disapproval of certain programs; exhaustion of unemployment benefits; promulgation of regulations(1) If the Secretary determines that—(A) there is no suitable employment (which may include technical and professional employment) available for an adversely affected worker,

(B) the worker would benefit from appropriate training,

(C) there is a reasonable expectation of employment following completion of such training,

(D) training approved by the Secretary is reasonably available to the worker from either governmental agencies or private sources (which may include area career and technical education schools, as defined in section 2302 of title 20, and employers) 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma.

(E) the worker is qualified to undertake and complete such training, and

(F) such training is suitable for the worker and available at a reasonable cost,


the Secretary shall approve such training for the worker. Upon such approval, the worker shall be entitled to have payment of the costs of such training (subject to the limitations imposed by this section) paid on his behalf by the Secretary directly or through a voucher system. Insofar as possible, the Secretary shall provide or assure the provision of such training on the job, which shall include related education necessary for the acquisition of skills needed for a position within a particular occupation.

(2)(A) The total amount of payments that may be made under paragraph (1) for any fiscal year shall not exceed $220,000,000.

(B) If, during any fiscal year, the Secretary estimates that the amount of funds necessary to pay the costs of training approved under this section will exceed the amount of the limitation imposed under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall decide how the portion of such</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2296_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of training; limitation on expenditures; reasonable expectation of employment; payment of costs; approved training programs; nonduplication of payments from other sources; disapproval of certain programs; exhaustion of unemployment benefits; promulgation of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Approval of training; limitation on expenditures; reasonable expectation of employment; payment of costs; approved training programs; nonduplication of payments from other sources; disapproval of certain programs; exhaustion of unemployment benefits; promulgation of regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2296_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Supplemental assistance The Secretary may, where appropriate, authorize supplemental assistance necessary to defray reasonable transportation and subsistence expenses for separate maintenance when training is provided in facilities which are not within commuting distance of a worker’s regular place of residence. The Secretary may not authorize—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2296_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of costs of on-the-job training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of costs of on-the-job training The Secretary shall pay the costs of any on-the-job training of an adversely affected worker that is approved under subsection (a)(1) in equal monthly installments, but the Secretary may pay such costs, notwithstanding any other provision of this section, only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2296_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for unemployment insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility for unemployment insurance A worker may not be determined to be ineligible or disqualified for unemployment insurance or program benefits under this subpart because the individual is in training approved under subsection (a), because of leaving work which is not suitable employment to enter such training, or because of the application to any such week in training of provisions of State law or Federal unemployment insurance law relating to availability for work, active search for work, or refusal to accept work. The Secretary shall submit to the Congress a quarterly report regarding the amount of funds expended during the quarter concerned to provide training under subsection (a) and the anticipated demand for such funds for any remaining quarters in the fiscal year concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2296_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Suitable employment” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Suitable employment” defined For purposes of this section the term “suitable employment” means, with respect to a worker, work of a substantially equal or higher skill level than the worker’s past adversely affected employment, and wages for such work at not less than 80 percent of the worker’s average weekly wage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2296_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Customized training” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Customized training” defined For purposes of this section, the term “customized training” means training that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>