<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2318" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2318/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2318/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2318"><akn:num>2318</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration project for alternative trade adjustment assistance for older workers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2318. Demonstration project for alternative trade adjustment assistance for older workers(a) In general(1) EstablishmentNot later than 1 year after August 6, 2002, the Secretary shall establish an alternative trade adjustment assistance program for older workers that provides the benefits described in paragraph (2).


(2) Benefits(A) PaymentsA State shall use the funds provided to the State under section 2313 of this title to pay, for a period not to exceed 2 years, to a worker described in paragraph (3)(B), 50 percent of the difference between—(i) the wages received by the worker from reemployment; and

(ii) the wages received by the worker at the time of separation.


(B) Health insuranceA worker described in paragraph (3)(B) participating in the program established under paragraph (1) is eligible to receive, for a period not to exceed 2 years, a credit for health insurance costs under section 35 of title 26, as added by section 201 of the Trade Act of 2002.



(3) Eligibility(A) Firm eligibility(i) In generalThe Secretary shall provide the opportunity for a group of workers on whose behalf a petition is filed under section 2271 of this title to request that the group of workers be certified for the alternative trade adjustment assistance program under this section at the time the petition is filed.


(ii) CriteriaIn determining whether to certify a group of workers as eligible for the alternative trade adjustment assistance program, the Secretary shall consider the following criteria:(I) Whether a significant number of workers in the workers’ firm are 50 years of age or older.

(II) Whether the workers in the workers’ firm possess skills that are not easily transferable.

(III) The competitive conditions within the workers’ industry.


(iii) DeadlineThe Secretary shall determine whether the workers in the group are eligible for the alternative trade adjustment assistance program by the date specified in section 2273(a) of this title.



(B) Individual eligibili</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2318_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2318_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Termination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>