<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2341" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2341/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2341/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2341"><akn:num>2341</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitions and determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2341. Petitions and determinations(a) Filing of petition; receipt of petition; initiation of investigationA petition for a certification of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance under this part may be filed with the Secretary of Commerce (hereinafter in this part referred to as the “Secretary”) by a firm (including any agricultural firm) or its representative. Upon receipt of the petition, the Secretary shall promptly publish notice in the Federal Register that he has received the petition and initiated an investigation.


(b) Public hearingIf the petitioner, or any other person, organization, or group found by the Secretary to have a substantial interest in the proceedings, submits not later than 10 days after the date of the Secretary’s publication under subsection (a) a request for a hearing, the Secretary shall provide for a public hearing and afford such interested persons an opportunity to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard.


(c) Certification(1) The Secretary shall certify a firm (including any agricultural firm) as eligible to apply for adjustment assistance under this part if the Secretary determines—(A) that a significant number or proportion of the workers in such firm have become totally or partially separated, or are threatened to become totally or partially separated,

(B) that—(i) sales or production, or both, of such firm have decreased absolutely, or

(ii) sales or production, or both, of an article that accounted for not less than 25 percent of the total production or sales of the firm during the 12-month period preceding the most recent 12-month period for which data are available have decreased absolutely, and


(C) increases of imports of articles like or directly competitive with articles which are produced by such firm contributed importantly to such total or partial separation, or threat thereof, and to such decline in sales or production.


(2) For purposes of paragraph (1)(C)—(A) The term “contributed importantly” </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2341_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of petition; receipt of petition; initiation of investigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Filing of petition; receipt of petition; initiation of investigation A petition for a certification of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance under this part may be filed with the Secretary of Commerce (hereinafter in this part referred to as the “Secretary”) by a firm (including any agricultural firm) or its representative. Upon receipt of the petition, the Secretary shall promptly publish notice in the Federal Register that he has received the petition and initiated an investigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2341_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public hearing If the petitioner, or any other person, organization, or group found by the Secretary to have a substantial interest in the proceedings, submits not later than 10 days after the date of the Secretary’s publication under subsection (a) a request for a hearing, the Secretary shall provide for a public hearing and afford such interested persons an opportunity to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2341_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2341_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowable period for determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allowable period for determination A determination shall be made by the Secretary as soon as possible after the date on which the petition is filed under this section, but in any event not later than 60 days after that date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>