<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2342" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2342/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2342/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2342"><akn:num>2342</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of adjustment proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2342. Approval of adjustment proposals(a) Application for adjustment assistanceA firm certified under section 2341 of this title as eligible to apply for adjustment assistance may, at any time within 2 years after the date of such certification, file an application with the Secretary for adjustment assistance under this part. Such application shall include a proposal for the economic adjustment of such firm.


(b) Technical assistance(1) Adjustment assistance under this part consists of technical assistance. The Secretary shall approve a firm’s application for adjustment assistance only if the Secretary determines that the firm’s adjustment proposal—(A) is reasonably calculated to materially contribute to the economic adjustment of the firm,

(B) gives adequate consideration to the interests of the workers of such firm, and

(C) demonstrates that the firm will make all reasonable efforts to use its own resources for economic development.


(2) The Secretary shall make a determination as soon as possible after the date on which an application is filed under this section, but in no event later than 60 days after such date.


(c) Termination of certification of eligibilityWhenever the Secretary determines that any firm no longer requires assistance under this part, he shall terminate the certification of eligibility of such firm and promptly have notice of such termination published in the Federal Register. Such termination shall take effect on the termination date specified by the Secretary.


(Pub. L. 93–618, title II, § 252, Jan. 3, 1975, 88 Stat. 2030; Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13006(a)(1), (2), Apr. 7, 1986, 100 Stat. 304.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1986—Subsec. (b)(1). Pub. L. 99–272, § 13006(a)(1), amended par. (1) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (1) read as follows: “Adjustment assistance under this part consists of technical assistance and financial assistance, which may be furnished singly or in combination. The Secretary shall approve a firm’s app</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2342_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for adjustment assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application for adjustment assistance A firm certified under section 2341 of this title as eligible to apply for adjustment assistance may, at any time within 2 years after the date of such certification, file an application with the Secretary for adjustment assistance under this part. Such application shall include a proposal for the economic adjustment of such firm.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2342_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Technical assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2342_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of certification of eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Termination of certification of eligibility Whenever the Secretary determines that any firm no longer requires assistance under this part, he shall terminate the certification of eligibility of such firm and promptly have notice of such termination published in the Federal Register. Such termination shall take effect on the termination date specified by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>