<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2343" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2343/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2343/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2343"><akn:num>2343</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2343. Technical assistance(a) Discretion of Secretary; types of assistanceThe Secretary may provide a firm, on terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, with such technical assistance as in his judgment will carry out the purposes of this part with respect to the firm. The technical assistance furnished under this part may consist of one or more of the following:(1) Assistance to a firm in preparing its petition for certification of eligibility under section 2341 of this title.

(2) Assistance to a certified firm in developing a proposal for its economic adjustment.

(3) Assistance to a certified firm in the implementation of such a proposal.


(b) Utilization of existing agencies, private individuals, etc., in furnishing assistance; grants to intermediary organizations(1) The Secretary shall furnish technical assistance under this part through existing agencies and through private individuals, firms, or institutions (including private consulting services), or by grants to intermediary organizations (including Trade Adjustment Assistance Centers).

(2) In the case of assistance furnished through private individuals, firms, or institutions (including private consulting services), the Secretary may share the cost thereof (but not more than 75 percent of such cost for assistance described in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a) may be borne by the United States).

(3) The Secretary may make grants to intermediary organizations in order to defray up to 100 percent of administrative expenses incurred in providing such technical assistance to a firm.


(Pub. L. 93–618, title II, § 253, Jan. 3, 1975, 88 Stat. 2031; Pub. L. 97–35, title XXV, § 2521, Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 890; Pub. L. 99–272, title XIII, § 13006(a)(3), Apr. 7, 1986, 100 Stat. 304; Pub. L. 111–5, div. B, title I, § 1867(b), Feb. 17, 2009, 123 Stat. 400; Pub. L. 112–40, title II, § 201(b), (c), Oct. 21, 2011, 125 Stat. 403; Pub. L. 114–27, title IV, § 402(b), (c), June 29, 2015,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretion of Secretary; types of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Discretion of Secretary; types of assistance The Secretary may provide a firm, on terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, with such technical assistance as in his judgment will carry out the purposes of this part with respect to the firm. The technical assistance furnished under this part may consist of one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2343_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of existing agencies, private individuals, etc., in furnishing assistance; grants to intermediary organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Utilization of existing agencies, private individuals, etc., in furnishing assistance; grants to intermediary organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>