<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2371" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2371/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2371/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2371"><akn:num>2371</akn:num><akn:heading>Community College and Career Training Grant Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2371. Community College and Career Training Grant Program(a) Grants authorized(1) In generalBeginning August 1, 2009, the Secretary may award Community College and Career Training Grants to eligible institutions for the purpose of developing, offering, or improving educational or career training programs for workers eligible for training under section 2296 of this title.


(2) LimitationsAn eligible institution may not be awarded—(A) more than one grant under this section; or

(B) a grant under this section in excess of $1,000,000.



(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible institutionThe term “eligible institution” means an institution of higher education (as defined in section 1002 of title 20), but only with respect to a program offered by the institution that can be completed in not more than 2 years.


(2) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.



(c) Grant proposals(1) In generalAn eligible institution seeking to receive a grant under this section shall submit a grant proposal to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(2) GuidelinesNot later than June 1, 2009, the Secretary shall—(A) promulgate guidelines for the submission of grant proposals under this section; and

(B) publish and maintain such guidelines on the website of the Department of Labor.


(3) AssistanceThe Secretary shall offer assistance in preparing a grant proposal to any eligible institution that requests such assistance.


(4) General requirements for grant proposals(A) In generalA grant proposal submitted to the Secretary under this section shall include a detailed description of—(i) the specific project for which the grant proposal is submitted, including the manner in which the grant will be used to develop, offer, or improve an educational or career training program that is suited to workers eligible for training under section 2296 of this title;

(ii) the extent to which the project for which </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2371_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2371_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2371_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2371_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for award of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criteria for award of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2371_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual report Not later than December 15, 2009, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives a report—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>