<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2401a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2401a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2401a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2401a"><akn:num>2401a</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitions; group eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2401a. Petitions; group eligibility(a) In generalA petition for a certification of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance under this part may be filed with the Secretary by a group of agricultural commodity producers or by their duly authorized representative. Upon receipt of the petition, the Secretary shall promptly publish notice in the Federal Register that the Secretary has received the petition and initiated an investigation.


(b) HearingsIf the petitioner, or any other person found by the Secretary to have a substantial interest in the proceedings, submits not later than 10 days after the date of the Secretary’s publication under subsection (a) of this section a request for a hearing, the Secretary shall provide for a public hearing and afford such interested person an opportunity to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard.


(c) Group eligibility requirementsThe Secretary shall certify a group of agricultural commodity producers as eligible to apply for adjustment assistance under this part if the Secretary determines—(1) that the national average price for the agricultural commodity, or a class of goods within the agricultural commodity, produced by the group for the most recent marketing year for which the national average price is available is less than 80 percent of the average of the national average price for such agricultural commodity, or such class of goods, for the 5 marketing years preceding the most recent marketing year; and

(2) that increases in imports of articles like or directly competitive with the agricultural commodity, or class of goods within the agricultural commodity, produced by the group contributed importantly to the decline in price described in paragraph (1).


(d) Special rule for qualified subsequent yearsA group of agricultural commodity producers certified as eligible under section 2401b of this title shall be eligible to apply for assistance under this part in any qualified year after the year the group </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A petition for a certification of eligibility to apply for adjustment assistance under this part may be filed with the Secretary by a group of agricultural commodity producers or by their duly authorized representative. Upon receipt of the petition, the Secretary shall promptly publish notice in the Federal Register that the Secretary has received the petition and initiated an investigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hearings If the petitioner, or any other person found by the Secretary to have a substantial interest in the proceedings, submits not later than 10 days after the date of the Secretary’s publication under subsection (a) of this section a request for a hearing, the Secretary shall provide for a public hearing and afford such interested person an opportunity to be present, to produce evidence, and to be heard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Group eligibility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Group eligibility requirements The Secretary shall certify a group of agricultural commodity producers as eligible to apply for adjustment assistance under this part if the Secretary determines—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for qualified subsequent years</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rule for qualified subsequent years A group of agricultural commodity producers certified as eligible under section 2401b of this title shall be eligible to apply for assistance under this part in any qualified year after the year the group is first certified, if the Secretary determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of qualified year and commodity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Determination of qualified year and commodity In this part:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>