<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2401b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2401b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2401b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2401b"><akn:num>2401b</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations by Secretary of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2401b. Determinations by Secretary of Agriculture(a) In generalAs soon as practicable after the date on which a petition is filed under section 2401a of this title, but in any event not later than 40 days after that date, the Secretary shall determine whether the petitioning group meets the requirements of section 2401a(c) or (d) of this title, as the case may be, and shall, if the group meets the requirements, issue a certification of eligibility to apply for assistance under this part covering agricultural commodity producers in any group that meets the requirements. Each certification shall specify the date on which eligibility under this part begins.


(b) NoticeUpon making a determination on a petition, the Secretary shall promptly publish a summary of the determination in the Federal Register, together with the Secretary’s reasons for making the determination.


(c) Termination of certificationWhenever the Secretary determines, with respect to any certification of eligibility under this part, that the decline in price for the agricultural commodity covered by the certification is no longer attributable to the conditions described in section 2401a of this title, the Secretary shall terminate such certification and promptly cause notice of such termination to be published in the Federal Register, together with the Secretary’s reasons for making such determination.


(Pub. L. 93–618, title II, § 293, as added Pub. L. 107–210, div. A, title I, § 141(a), Aug. 6, 2002, 116 Stat. 948; amended Pub. L. 111–5, div. B, title I, §§ 1882(b), 1884, Feb. 17, 2009, 123 Stat. 416, 419; Pub. L. 112–40, title II, §§ 201(b), (c), 223(a)(1), Oct. 21, 2011, 125 Stat. 403, 412; Pub. L. 114–27, title IV, § 402(b), (c), June 29, 2015, 129 Stat. 374.)

Termination of AssistanceFor termination of assistance under this part after June 30, 2022, see Termination Date note below.

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section reflects the July 1, 2021, reversion to provisions in effect on Jan. 1, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general As soon as practicable after the date on which a petition is filed under section 2401a of this title, but in any event not later than 40 days after that date, the Secretary shall determine whether the petitioning group meets the requirements of section 2401a(c) or (d) of this title, as the case may be, and shall, if the group meets the requirements, issue a certification of eligibility to apply for assistance under this part covering agricultural commodity producers in any group that meets the requirements. Each certification shall specify the date on which eligibility under this part begins.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice Upon making a determination on a petition, the Secretary shall promptly publish a summary of the determination in the Federal Register, together with the Secretary’s reasons for making the determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Termination of certification Whenever the Secretary determines, with respect to any certification of eligibility under this part, that the decline in price for the agricultural commodity covered by the certification is no longer attributable to the conditions described in section 2401a of this title, the Secretary shall terminate such certification and promptly cause notice of such termination to be published in the Federal Register, together with the Secretary’s reasons for making such determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>