<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2503"><akn:num>2503</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of trade agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2503. Approval of trade agreements(a) Approval of agreements and statements of administrative actionIn accordance with the provisions of sections 2112 and 2191 of this title, the Congress approves the trade agreements described in subsection (c) submitted to the Congress on June 19, 1979, and the statements of administrative action proposed to implement such trade agreements submitted to the Congress on that date.


(b) Acceptance of agreements by the President(1) In generalThe President may accept for the United States the final legal instruments or texts embodying each of the trade agreements approved by the Congress under subsection (a). The President shall submit a copy of each final instrument or text to the Congress on the date such text or instrument is available, together with a notification of any changes in the instruments or texts, including their annexes, if any, as accepted and the texts of such agreements as submitted to the Congress under subsection (a). Such final legal instruments or texts shall be deemed to be the agreements submitted to and approved by the Congress under subsection (a) if such changes are—(A) only rectifications of a formal character or minor technical or clerical changes which do not affect the substance or meaning of the texts as submitted to the Congress on June 19, 1979, or

(B) changes in annexes to such agreements, and the President determines that the balance of United States rights and obligations under such agreements is maintained.


(2) Application of agreement between the United States and other countriesNo agreement accepted by the President under paragraph (1) shall apply between the United States and any other country unless the President determines that such country—(A) has accepted the obligations of the agreement with respect to the United States, and

(B) should not otherwise be denied the benefits of the agreement with respect to the United States because such country has not accorded adequate benefits, inclu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of agreements and statements of administrative action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Approval of agreements and statements of administrative action In accordance with the provisions of sections 2112 and 2191 of this title, the Congress approves the trade agreements described in subsection (c) submitted to the Congress on June 19, 1979, and the statements of administrative action proposed to implement such trade agreements submitted to the Congress on that date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of agreements by the President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acceptance of agreements by the President</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade agreements to which this Act applies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Trade agreements to which this Act applies The trade agreements to which subsection (a) applies are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>