<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2504"><akn:num>2504</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship of trade agreements to United States law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2504. Relationship of trade agreements to United States law(a) United States statutes to prevail in conflictNo provision of any trade agreement approved by the Congress under section 2503(a) of this title, nor the application of any such provision to any person or circumstance, which is in conflict with any statute of the United States shall be given effect under the laws of the United States.


(b) Implementing regulationsRegulations necessary or appropriate to carry out actions proposed in any statement of proposed administrative action submitted to the Congress under section 2112 of this title to implement each agreement approved under section 2503(a) of this title shall be issued within 1 year after the date of the entry into force of such agreement with respect to the United States.


(c) Changes in statutes to implement a requirement, amendment, or recommendation(1) Presidential determinationWhenever the President determines that it is necessary or appropriate to amend, repeal, or enact a statute of the United States in order to implement any requirement of, amendment to, or recommendation under such an agreement, he shall submit to the Congress a draft of a bill to accomplish the amendment, repeal, or enactment and a statement of any administrative action proposed to implement the requirement, amendment, or recommendation. Not less than 30 days before submitting such a bill, the President shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, and each committee of the House or Senate which has jurisdiction over legislation involving subject matters which would be affected by such amendment, repeal, or enactment. The consultation shall treat all matters relating to the implementation of such requirement, amendment, or recommendation, as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3).


(2) Conditions for taking effect under United States lawNo such amendment shall enter into force with respect to the U</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States statutes to prevail in conflict</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) United States statutes to prevail in conflict No provision of any trade agreement approved by the Congress under section 2503(a) of this title, nor the application of any such provision to any person or circumstance, which is in conflict with any statute of the United States shall be given effect under the laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementing regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Implementing regulations Regulations necessary or appropriate to carry out actions proposed in any statement of proposed administrative action submitted to the Congress under section 2112 of this title to implement each agreement approved under section 2503(a) of this title shall be issued within 1 year after the date of the entry into force of such agreement with respect to the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes in statutes to implement a requirement, amendment, or recommendation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Changes in statutes to implement a requirement, amendment, or recommendation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unspecified private remedies not created</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Unspecified private remedies not created Neither the entry into force with respect to the United States of any agreement approved under section 2503(a) of this title, nor the enactment of this Act, shall be construed as creating any private right of action or remedy for which provision is not explicitly made under this Act or under the laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>