<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2518" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2518/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2518/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2518"><akn:num>2518</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2518. Definitions
As used in this subchapter—(1) AgreementThe term “Agreement” means the Agreement on Government Procurement referred to in section 3511(d)(17) of this title, as submitted to the Congress, but including rectifications, modifications, and amendments which are accepted by the United States.


(2) Civil aircraftThe term “civil aircraft and related articles” means—(A) all aircraft other than aircraft to be purchased for use by the Department of Defense or the United States Coast Guard;

(B) the engines (and parts and components for incorporation therein) of such aircraft;

(C) any other parts, components, and subassemblies for incorporation in such aircraft; and

(D) any ground flight simulators, and parts and components thereof, for use with respect to such aircraft,


whether to be purchased for use as original or replacement equipment in the manufacture, repair, maintenance, rebuilding, modification, or conversion of such aircraft, and without regard to whether such aircraft or articles receive duty-free treatment pursuant to section 601(a)(2).

(3) Developed countriesThe term “developed countries” means countries so designated by the President.


(4) Eligible product(A) In generalThe term “eligible product” means, with respect to any foreign country or instrumentality that is—(i) a party to the Agreement, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under the Agreement for procurement by the United States;

(ii) Mexico, as a party to the USMCA (as defined in section 4502 of this title), a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under the USMCA for procurement by the United States;

(iii) a party to a free trade agreement that entered into force with respect to the United States after December 31, 2003, and before January 2, 2005, a product or service of that country or instrumentality which is covered under the free trade agreement for procurement by the United States;

(iv) a party to the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2518_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agreement The term “Agreement” means the Agreement on Government Procurement referred to in section 3511(d)(17) of this title, as submitted to the Congress, but including rectifications, modifications, and amendments which are accepted by the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2518_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Civil aircraft The term “civil aircraft and related articles” means— whether to be purchased for use as original or replacement equipment in the manufacture, repair, maintenance, rebuilding, modification, or conversion of such aircraft, and without regard to whether such aircraft or articles receive duty-free treatment pursuant to section 601(a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2518_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Developed countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Developed countries The term “developed countries” means countries so designated by the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2518_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Eligible product</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2518_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Instrumentality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Instrumentality The term “instrumentality” shall not be construed to include an agency or division of the government of a country, but may be construed to include such arrangements as the European Economic Community.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2518_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Least developed country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Least developed country The term “least developed country” means any country on the United Nations General Assembly list of least developed countries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2518_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Major industrial country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Major industrial country The term “major industrial country” means any such country as defined in section 2136 of this title and any instrumentality of such a country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>