<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2571" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2571/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2571/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2571"><akn:num>2571</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2571. Definitions
As used in this subchapter—(1) AgreementThe term “Agreement” means the Agreement on Technical Barriers to Trade referred to in section 3511(d)(5) of this title.


(2) Conformity assessment procedureThe term “conformity assessment procedure” means any procedure used, directly or indirectly, to determine that relevant requirements in technical regulations or standards are fulfilled.


(3) Federal agencyThe term “Federal agency” means any of the following within the meaning of chapter 2 of part I of title 5:(A) Any executive department.

(B) Any military department.

(C) Any Government corporation.

(D) Any Government-controlled corporation.

(E) Any independent establishment.


(4) International conformity assessment procedureThe term “international conformity assessment procedure” means a conformity assessment procedure that is adopted by an international standards organization.


(5) International standardThe term “international standard” means any standard that is promulgated by an international standards organization.


(6) International standards organizationThe term “international standards organization” means any organization—(A) the membership of which is open to representatives, whether public or private, of the United States and at least all Members; and

(B) that is engaged in international standards-related activities.


(7) International standards-related activityThe term “international standards-related activity” means the negotiation, development, or promulgation of, or any amendment or change to, an international standard, or an international conformity assessment procedure, or both.


(8) MemberThe term “Member” means a WTO member as defined in section 3501(10) of this title.


(9) Private personThe term “private person” means—(A) any individual who is a citizen or national of the United States; and

(B) any corporation, partnership, association, or other legal entity organized or existing under the law of any State, whether for pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agreement The term “Agreement” means the Agreement on Technical Barriers to Trade referred to in section 3511(d)(5) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conformity assessment procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Conformity assessment procedure The term “conformity assessment procedure” means any procedure used, directly or indirectly, to determine that relevant requirements in technical regulations or standards are fulfilled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Federal agency The term “Federal agency” means any of the following within the meaning of chapter 2 of part I of title 5:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>International conformity assessment procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) International conformity assessment procedure The term “international conformity assessment procedure” means a conformity assessment procedure that is adopted by an international standards organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>International standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) International standard The term “international standard” means any standard that is promulgated by an international standards organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>International standards organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) International standards organization The term “international standards organization” means any organization—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>International standards-related activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) International standards-related activity The term “international standards-related activity” means the negotiation, development, or promulgation of, or any amendment or change to, an international standard, or an international conformity assessment procedure, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Member</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Member The term “Member” means a WTO member as defined in section 3501(10) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Private person The term “private person” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2571_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Product The term “product” means any natural or manufactured item.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>