<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2575b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2575b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2575b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2575b"><akn:num>2575b</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpart definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2575b. Subpart definitions
Notwithstanding section 2571 of this title, for purposes of this subpart—(1) AnimalThe term “animal” includes fish, bees, and wild fauna.


(2) Approval procedureThe term “approval procedure” means any registration, notification, or other mandatory administrative procedure for—(A) approving the use of an additive for a stated purpose or under stated conditions, or

(B) establishing a tolerance for a stated purpose or under stated conditions for a contaminant,


in a food, beverage, or feedstuff prior to permitting the use of the additive or the marketing of a food, beverage, or feedstuff containing the additive or contaminant.

(3) ContaminantThe term “contaminant” includes pesticide and veterinary drug residues and extraneous matter.


(4) Control or inspection procedureThe term “control or inspection procedure” means any procedure used, directly or indirectly, to determine that a sanitary or phytosanitary measure is fulfilled, including sampling, testing, inspection, evaluation, verification, monitoring, auditing, assurance of conformity, accreditation, registration, certification, or other procedure involving the physical examination of a good, of the packaging of a good, or of the equipment or facilities directly related to production, marketing, or use of a good, but does not mean an approval procedure.


(5) PlantThe term “plant” includes wild flora.


(6) Risk assessmentThe term “risk assessment” means an evaluation of—(A) the potential for the introduction, establishment or spread of a pest or disease and associated biological and economic consequences; or

(B) the potential for adverse effects on human or animal life or health arising from the presence of an additive, contaminant, toxin or disease-causing organism in a food, beverage, or feedstuff.


(7) Sanitary or phytosanitary measure(A) In generalThe term “sanitary or phytosanitary measure” means a measure to—(i) protect animal or plant life or health in the United States fr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2575b_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Animal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Animal The term “animal” includes fish, bees, and wild fauna.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2575b_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Approval procedure The term “approval procedure” means any registration, notification, or other mandatory administrative procedure for— in a food, beverage, or feedstuff prior to permitting the use of the additive or the marketing of a food, beverage, or feedstuff containing the additive or contaminant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2575b_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contaminant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Contaminant The term “contaminant” includes pesticide and veterinary drug residues and extraneous matter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2575b_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control or inspection procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Control or inspection procedure The term “control or inspection procedure” means any procedure used, directly or indirectly, to determine that a sanitary or phytosanitary measure is fulfilled, including sampling, testing, inspection, evaluation, verification, monitoring, auditing, assurance of conformity, accreditation, registration, certification, or other procedure involving the physical examination of a good, of the packaging of a good, or of the equipment or facilities directly related to production, marketing, or use of a good, but does not mean an approval procedure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2575b_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Plant The term “plant” includes wild flora.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2575b_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Risk assessment The term “risk assessment” means an evaluation of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2575b_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanitary or phytosanitary measure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Sanitary or phytosanitary measure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>