<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2703a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2703a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2703a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2703a"><akn:num>2703a</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for Haiti</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2703a. Special rules for Haiti(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Initial applicable 1-year periodThe term “initial applicable 1-year period” means the 1-year period beginning on December 20, 2006.


(2) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.


(3) Core labor standardsThe term “core labor standards” means—(A) freedom of association;

(B) the effective recognition of the right to bargain collectively;

(C) the elimination of all forms of compulsory or forced labor;

(D) the effective abolition of child labor and a prohibition on the worst forms of child labor; and

(E) the elimination of discrimination in respect of employment and occupation.


(4) Enter; entryThe terms “enter” and “entry” refer to the entry, or withdrawal from warehouse for consumption, in the customs territory of the United States.


(5) Imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican RepublicArticles are “imported directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic” if—(A) the articles are shipped directly from Haiti or the Dominican Republic into the United States without passing through the territory of any intermediate country; or

(B) the articles are shipped from Haiti or the Dominican Republic into the United States through the territory of an intermediate country, and—(i) the articles in the shipment do not enter into the commerce of any intermediate country, and the invoices, bills of lading, and other shipping documents specify the United States as the final destination; or

(ii) the invoices and other documents do not specify the United States as the final destination, but the articles in the shipment—(I) remain under the control of the customs authority in the intermediate country;

(II) do not enter into the commerce of the intermediate country except for the purpose of a sale other than at retail; and

(III) have not been subjected to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apparel and other textile articles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Apparel and other textile articles</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703a_v"><akn:num>(v)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(v) Definitions In this paragraph:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for certain wire harness automotive components</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule for certain wire harness automotive components</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance improvement and compliance needs assessment and remediation program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance improvement and compliance needs assessment and remediation program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions regarding enforcement of circumvention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Conditions regarding enforcement of circumvention</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The President shall issue regulations to carry out this section not later than 180 days after December 20, 2006. The President shall consult with the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate in preparing such regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Termination Except as provided in subsection (b)(1), the duty-free treatment provided under this section shall remain in effect until September 30, 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>