<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2707" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2707/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2707/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2707"><akn:num>2707</akn:num><akn:heading>Center for the Study of Western Hemispheric Trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2707. Center for the Study of Western Hemispheric Trade(a) EstablishmentThe Commissioner of Customs, after consultation with appropriate officials in the State of Texas, is authorized and directed to make grants to an institution (or a consortium of such institutions) to assist such institution in planning, establishing, and operating a Center for the Study of Western Hemispheric Trade (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Center”). The Commissioner of Customs shall make the first grant not later than December 1, 1994, and the Center shall be established not later than February 1, 1995.


(b) Scope of CenterThe Center shall be a year-round program operated by an institution located in the State of Texas (or a consortium of such institutions), the purpose of which is to promote and study trade between and among Western Hemisphere countries. The Center shall conduct activities designed to examine—(1) the impact of the NAFTA on the economies in, and trade within, the Western Hemisphere;

(2) the negotiation of any future free trade agreements, including possible accessions to the NAFTA; and

(3) adjusting tariffs, reducing nontariff barriers, improving relations among customs officials, and promoting economic relations among countries in the Western Hemisphere.


(c) Consultation; selection criteriaThe Commissioner of Customs shall consult with appropriate officials of the State of Texas and private sector authorities with respect to selecting, planning, and establishing the Center. In selecting the appropriate institution, the Commissioner of Customs shall give consideration to—(1) the institution’s ability to carry out the programs and activities described in this section; and

(2) any resources the institution can provide the Center in addition to Federal funds provided under this program.


(d) Programs and activitiesThe Center shall conduct the following activities:(1) Provide forums for international discussion and debate for representatives from count</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Commissioner of Customs, after consultation with appropriate officials in the State of Texas, is authorized and directed to make grants to an institution (or a consortium of such institutions) to assist such institution in planning, establishing, and operating a Center for the Study of Western Hemispheric Trade (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Center”). The Commissioner of Customs shall make the first grant not later than December 1, 1994, and the Center shall be established not later than February 1, 1995.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scope of Center The Center shall be a year-round program operated by an institution located in the State of Texas (or a consortium of such institutions), the purpose of which is to promote and study trade between and among Western Hemisphere countries. The Center shall conduct activities designed to examine—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation; selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation; selection criteria The Commissioner of Customs shall consult with appropriate officials of the State of Texas and private sector authorities with respect to selecting, planning, and establishing the Center. In selecting the appropriate institution, the Commissioner of Customs shall give consideration to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs and activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Programs and activities The Center shall conduct the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for seminars and publications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fees for seminars and publications Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a grant made under this section may provide that the Center may charge a reasonable fee for attendance at seminars and conferences and for copies of publications, studies, reports, and other documents the Center publishes. The Center may waive such fees in any case in which it determines imposing a fee would impose a financial hardship and the purposes of the Center would be served by granting such a waiver.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Duration of grant The Commissioner of Customs is directed to make grants to any institution or institutions selected as the Center for fiscal years 1994, 1995, 1996, and 1997.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report The Commissioner of Customs shall, no later than July 1, 1994, and annually thereafter for years for which grants are made, submit a written report to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives. The first report shall include— Each subsequent report shall include information with respect to the operations of the Center, the collaboration of the Center with, and dissemination of information to, Government policymakers and the business community with respect to the study of Western Hemispheric trade by the Center, and the plan and efforts of the Center to continue operations after grants under this section have expired.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>