<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2804" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2804/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/2804/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2804"><akn:num>2804</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions to reduce or eliminate tariff and nontariff barriers affecting United States wine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2804. Actions to reduce or eliminate tariff and nontariff barriers affecting United States wine(a) Consultations with major wine trading countriesThe President shall direct the Trade Representative to enter into consultations with each major wine trading country to seek a reduction or elimination of that country’s tariff barriers and nontariff barriers to (or other distortions of) trade in United States wine.


(b) Reports to Congress on actions taken to expand export opportunities(1) the 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. President shall notify each of the Committees regarding the extent and effect of the efforts undertaken since the submission of the report required under section 854(a) of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 [19 U.S.C. 2135 note], and during the 12-month period beginning on October 30, 1984, to expand opportunities in each major wine trading country for exports of United States wine. Such notification, which shall be in the form of a separate written report (that must be submitted within 30 days after the close of that 12-month period) for each major wine trading country, shall include—(A) a description of each act, policy, and practice (and of its legal basis and operation) in that country that constitutes a tariff barrier or nontariff barrier to (or other distortion of) trade in United States wine (and that description shall be based upon an updating of the report that was submitted to the Congress under section 854(a) of the Trade Agreements Act of 1979);

(B) an assessment of the extent to which each such act, policy, or practice is subject to international agreements to which the United States is a party;

(C) information with respect to any action taken, or proposed to be taken, under existing authority to eliminate or reduce each such act, policy, or practice, including, but not limited to—(i) any action under the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.], and

(ii) any negotiation or consultation with any foreign government</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2804_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultations with major wine trading countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consultations with major wine trading countries The President shall direct the Trade Representative to enter into consultations with each major wine trading country to seek a reduction or elimination of that country’s tariff barriers and nontariff barriers to (or other distortions of) trade in United States wine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2804_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress on actions taken to expand export opportunities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports to Congress on actions taken to expand export opportunities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2804_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement of rights If the President, after taking into account information and advice received under subsections (a) and (b), section 2805 of this title or from other sources, determines that action is appropriate to respond to any act, policy, or practice of a major wine trading country constitutes a tariff barrier or nontariff barrier to (or other distortion of) trade in United States wine and— the President, shall take all appropriate and feasible action under the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.] to enforce the rights of the United States under any such trade agreement or to obtain the elimination of such act, policy, or practice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>