<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3004" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3004/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3004/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3004"><akn:num>3004</akn:num><akn:heading>Enactment of Harmonized Tariff Schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3004. Enactment of Harmonized Tariff Schedule(a) Omitted

(b) Modifications to Harmonized Tariff ScheduleAt the earliest practicable date after August 23, 1988, the President shall—(1) proclaim such modifications to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule as are consistent with the standards applied in converting the old Schedules into the format of the Convention, as reflected in such Publication No. 2030 and Supplement No. 1.11 So in original. thereto, and as are necessary or appropriate to implement—(A) the future outstanding staged rate reductions authorized by the Congress in—(i) the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.) and the Trade Agreements Act of 1979 (19 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.) to reflect the tariff reductions that resulted from the Tokyo Round of multilateral trade negotiations, and

(ii) the United States-Israel Free Trade Area Implementation Act of 1985 [19 U.S.C. 2112 note] to reflect the tariff reduction resulting from the United States-Israel Free Trade Area Agreement,


(B) the applicable provisions of—(i) statutes enacted,

(ii) executive actions taken, and

(iii) final judicial decisions rendered,


after January 1, 1988, and before January 1, 1989, and

(C) such technical rectifications as the President considers necessary; and


(2) take such action as the President considers necessary to bring trade agreements to which the United States is a party into conformity with the Harmonized Tariff Schedule.


(c) Status of Harmonized Tariff Schedule(1) The following shall be considered to be statutory provisions of law for all purposes:(A) The provisions of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule as enacted by this chapter.

(B) Each statutory amendment to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule.

(C) Each modification or change made to the Harmonized Tariff Schedule by the President under authority of law (including section 604 of the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2483]).


(2) Neither the enactment of this chapter nor the subsequent enactment of any amendment to the Harmo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3004_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3004_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modifications to Harmonized Tariff Schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Modifications to Harmonized Tariff Schedule At the earliest practicable date after August 23, 1988, the President shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3004_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of Harmonized Tariff Schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Status of Harmonized Tariff Schedule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3004_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim informational use of Harmonized Tariff Schedule classifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Interim informational use of Harmonized Tariff Schedule classifications Each— during the period between August 23, 1988, and January 1, 1989, shall, if the proclamation, notice, or decision contains a reference to the tariff classification of any article, include, for informational purposes, a reference to the classification of that article under the Harmonized Tariff Schedule.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>