<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3109" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3109/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3109/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3109"><akn:num>3109</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of data; action to ensure compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3109. Submission of data; action to ensure compliance(a) Submission of dataThe Federal Communications Commission (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Commission”) shall periodically submit to appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and of the Senate any data collected and otherwise made public under Report No. DC–1105, “Information Reporting Requirements Established for Common Carriers”, adopted February 25, 1988, relating to FCC Docket No. 86–494, adopted December 23, 1987.


(b) Action to ensure compliance(1)(A) Any product of a foreign country that is subject to registration or approval by the Commission may be entered only if—(i) such product conforms with all applicable rules and regulations of the Commission, and

(ii) the information which is required on Federal Communications Commission Form 740 on August 23, 1988, is provided to the appropriate customs officer at the time of such entry in such form and manner as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe.


(B) For purposes of this paragraph, the term “entered” means entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, in the customs territory of the United States.


(2) The Commission, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Trade Representative shall provide such assistance in the enforcement of paragraph (1) as the Secretary of the Treasury may request.

(3) The Secretary of the Treasury shall compile the information collected under paragraph (1)(A)(ii) into a summary and shall annually submit such summary to the Congress until the authority to negotiate trade agreements under chapter 17 of this title expires. Such information shall also be made available to the public.


(Pub. L. 100–418, title I, § 1380, Aug. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 1223.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextChapter 17 of this title, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), was in the original “part 1 of subtitle A”, meaning part 1 (§§ 1101–1117) of subtitle A of title I of Pub. L. 100–418, Aug. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 1121, whic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3109_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission of data The Federal Communications Commission (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Commission”) shall periodically submit to appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and of the Senate any data collected and otherwise made public under Report No. DC–1105, “Information Reporting Requirements Established for Common Carriers”, adopted February 25, 1988, relating to FCC Docket No. 86–494, adopted December 23, 1987.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3109_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to ensure compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Action to ensure compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>