<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3202" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3202/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3202/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3202"><akn:num>3202</akn:num><akn:heading>Beneficiary country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3202. Beneficiary country(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this chapter—(1) The term “beneficiary country” means any country listed in subsection (b)(1) with respect to which there is in effect a proclamation by the President designating such country as a beneficiary country for purposes of this chapter.

(2) The term “entered” means entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, in the customs territory of the United States.

(3) The term “HTS” means Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.


(b) Countries eligible for designation; congressional notification(1) In designating countries as beneficiary countries under this chapter, the President shall consider only the following countries or successor political entities:Bolivia
Ecuador
Colombia
Peru.


(2) Before the President designates any country as a beneficiary country for purposes of this chapter, he shall notify the House of Representatives and the Senate of his intention to make such designation, together with the considerations entering into such decision.


(c) Limitations on designationThe President shall not designate any country a beneficiary country under this chapter—(1) if such country is a Communist country;

(2) if such country—(A) has nationalized, expropriated or otherwise seized ownership or control of property owned by a United States citizen or by a corporation, partnership, or association which is 50 percent or more beneficially owned by United States citizens,

(B) has taken steps to repudiate or nullify—(i) any existing contract or agreement with, or

(ii) any patent, trademark, or other intellectual property of,


a United States citizen or a corporation, partnership, or association, which is 50 percent or more beneficially owned by United States citizens, the effect of which is to nationalize, expropriate, or otherwise seize ownership or control of property so owned, or

(C) has imposed or enforced taxes or other exactions, restrictive maintenance or operational conditions, o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3202_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3202_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Countries eligible for designation; congressional notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Countries eligible for designation; congressional notification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3202_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations on designation The President shall not designate any country a beneficiary country under this chapter— Paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (5), and (7) shall not prevent the designation of any country as a beneficiary country under this chapter if the President determines that such designation will be in the national economic or security interest of the United States and reports such determination to the Congress with his reasons therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3202_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors affecting designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Factors affecting designation In determining whether to designate any country a beneficiary country under this chapter, the President shall take into account—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3202_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal or suspension of designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Withdrawal or suspension of designation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3202_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>