<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3203" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3203/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3203/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3203"><akn:num>3203</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible articles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3203. Eligible articles(a) In general(1) Unless otherwise excluded from eligibility (or otherwise provided for) by this chapter, the duty-free treatment (or preferential treatment) provided under this chapter shall apply to any article which is the growth, product, or manufacture of a beneficiary country if—(A) that article is imported directly from a beneficiary country into the customs territory of the United States; and

(B) the sum of—(i) the cost or value of the materials produced in a beneficiary country or 2 or more beneficiary countries under this chapter, or a beneficiary country under the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act [19 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.] or 2 or more such countries, plus

(ii) the direct costs of processing operations performed in a beneficiary country or countries (under this chapter or the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act),


is not less than 35 percent of the appraised value of such article at the time it is entered.


For purposes of determining the percentage referred to in subparagraph (B), the term “beneficiary country” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the United States Virgin Islands. If the cost or value of materials produced in the customs territory of the United States (other than the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico) is included with respect to an article to which this paragraph applies, an amount not to exceed 15 percent of the appraised value of the article at the time it is entered that is attributed to such United States cost or value may be applied toward determining the percentage referred to in subparagraph (B).

(2) The Secretary of the Treasury shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out paragraph (1) including, but not limited to, regulations providing that, in order to be eligible for duty-free treatment under this chapter, an article must be wholly the growth, product, or manufacture of a beneficiary country, or must be a new or different article of commerce which has been grown, prod</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions and special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of duty-free treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Suspension of duty-free treatment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency relief with respect to perishable products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Emergency relief with respect to perishable products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees under section 624 of title 7</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fees under No proclamation issued pursuant to this chapter shall affect fees imposed pursuant to section 624 of title 7.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3203_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tariff-rate quotas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Tariff-rate quotas No quantity of an agricultural product subject to a tariff-rate quota that exceeds the in-quota quantity shall be eligible for duty-free treatment under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>