<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3204" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3204/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3204/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3204"><akn:num>3204</akn:num><akn:heading>International Trade Commission reports on impact of this chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3204. International Trade Commission reports on impact of this chapter(a) Reporting requirements(1) In generalThe United States International Trade Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”) shall submit to Congress and the President biennial reports regarding the economic impact of this chapter on United States industries and consumers, and, in conjunction with other agencies, the effectiveness of this chapter in promoting drug-related crop eradication and crop substitution efforts of the beneficiary countries.


(2) SubmissionDuring the period that this chapter is in effect, the report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted on December 31 of each year that the report required by section 2704 of this title is not submitted.


(3) Treatment of Puerto Rico, etc.For purposes of this section, industries in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the insular possessions of the United States are considered to be United States industries.



(b) Report requirements(1) Each report required under subsection (a) shall include, but not be limited to, an assessment by the Commission regarding—(A) the actual effect, during the period covered by the report, of this chapter on the United States economy generally as well as on those specific domestic industries which produce articles that are like, or directly competitive with, articles being imported into the United States from beneficiary countries;

(B) the probable future effect that this chapter will have on the United States economy generally, as well as on such domestic industries, before the provisions of this chapter terminate; and

(C) the estimated effect that this chapter has had on the drug-related crop eradication and crop substitution efforts of the beneficiary countries.


(2) In preparing the assessments required under paragraph (1), the Commission shall, to the extent practicable—(A) analyze the production, trade and consumption of United States products affected by this chapter, taking into</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3204_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3204_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3204_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission dates; public comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission dates; public comment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>