<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3472" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3472/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3472/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3472"><akn:num>3472</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement on Environmental Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3472. Agreement on Environmental Cooperation(a) Commission for Environmental Cooperation(1) MembershipThe United States is authorized to participate in the Commission for Environmental Cooperation in accordance with the North American Agreement on Environmental Cooperation.


(2) Contributions to budgetThere are authorized to be appropriated to the President (or such agency as the President may designate) $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1994 and 1995 for United States contributions to the annual budget of the Commission for Environmental Cooperation pursuant to Article 43 of the North American Agreement on Environmental Cooperation. Funds authorized to be appropriated for such contributions by this paragraph are in addition to any funds otherwise available for such contributions. Funds authorized to be appropriated by this paragraph are authorized to be made available until expended.



(b) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) the term “Commission for Environmental Cooperation” means the commission established by Part Three of the North American Agreement on Environmental Cooperation; and

(2) the term “North American Agreement on Environmental Cooperation” means the North American Agreement on Environmental Cooperation Between the Government of the United States of America, the Government of Canada, and the Government of the United Mexican States (signed at Mexico City, Washington, and Ottawa on September 8, 9, 12, and 14, 1993).


(Pub. L. 103–182, title V, § 532, Dec. 8, 1993, 107 Stat. 2164; Pub. L. 116–113, title VI, § 601, Jan. 29, 2020, 134 Stat. 78; Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title VI, § 601(a)(1), (2), Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2149.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2020—Pub. L. 116–260, § 601(a)(1), (2), provided that section 601 of Pub. L. 116–113 does not apply to this section and revived the provisions of this section as if such section 601 had not been enacted. See below.
Pub. L. 116–113, § 601, which repealed this section effective on the date the USM</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3472_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission for Environmental Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Commission for Environmental Cooperation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3472_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>