<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3512" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3512/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3512/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3512"><akn:num>3512</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship of agreements to United States law and State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3512. Relationship of agreements to United States law and State law(a) Relationship of agreements to United States law(1) United States law to prevail in conflictNo provision of any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, nor the application of any such provision to any person or circumstance, that is inconsistent with any law of the United States shall have effect.


(2) ConstructionNothing in this Act shall be construed—(A) to amend or modify any law of the United States, including any law relating to—(i) the protection of human, animal, or plant life or health,

(ii) the protection of the environment, or

(iii) worker safety, or


(B) to limit any authority conferred under any law of the United States, including section 2411 of this title,


unless specifically provided for in this Act.


(b) Relationship of agreements to State law(1) Federal-State consultation(A) In generalOn December 8, 1994, the President shall, through the intergovernmental policy advisory committees on trade established under section 2114c(2)(A) of this title, consult with the States for the purpose of achieving conformity of State laws and practices with the Uruguay Round Agreements.


(B) Federal-State consultation processThe Trade Representative shall establish within the Office of the United States Trade Representative a Federal-State consultation process for addressing issues relating to the Uruguay Round Agreements that directly relate to, or will potentially have a direct effect on, the States. The Federal-State consultation process shall include procedures under which—(i) the States will be informed on a continuing basis of matters under the Uruguay Round Agreements that directly relate to, or will potentially have a direct impact on, the States;

(ii) the States will be provided an opportunity to submit, on a continuing basis, to the Trade Representative information and advice with respect to matters referred to in clause (i); and

(iii) the Trade Representative will take into account th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship of agreements to United States law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Relationship of agreements to United States law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship of agreements to State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relationship of agreements to State law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of agreement with respect to private remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effect of agreement with respect to private remedies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of administrative action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Statement of administrative action The statement of administrative action approved by the Congress under section 3511(a) of this title shall be regarded as an authoritative expression by the United States concerning the interpretation and application of the Uruguay Round Agreements and this Act in any judicial proceeding in which a question arises concerning such interpretation or application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>