<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3531" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3531/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3531/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3531"><akn:num>3531</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3531. Definitions
For purposes of this part:(1) Administering authorityThe term “administering authority” has the meaning given that term in section 1677(1) of this title.


(2) Appellate BodyThe term “Appellate Body” means the Appellate Body established under Article 17.1 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding.


(3) Appropriate congressional committees; congressional committees(A) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the committees referred to in subparagraph (B) and any other committees of the Congress that have jurisdiction involving the matter with respect to which consultations are to be held.


(B) Congressional committeesThe term “congressional committees” means the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.



(4) Dispute settlement panel; panelThe terms “dispute settlement panel” and “panel” mean a panel established pursuant to Article 6 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding.


(5) Dispute Settlement BodyThe term “Dispute Settlement Body” means the Dispute Settlement Body administering the rules and procedures set forth in the Dispute Settlement Understanding.


(6) Dispute Settlement UnderstandingThe term “Dispute Settlement Understanding” means the Understanding on Rules and Procedures Governing the Settlement of Disputes referred to in section 3511(d)(16) of this title.


(7) General CouncilThe term “General Council” means the General Council established under paragraph 2 of Article IV of the WTO Agreement.


(8) Ministerial ConferenceThe term “Ministerial Conference” means the Ministerial Conference established under paragraph 1 of Article IV of the WTO Agreement.


(9) Other termsThe terms “Antidumping Agreement”, “Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures”, and “Safeguards Agreement” mean the agreements referred to in section 3511(d)(7), (12), and (13) of this title, respectively.


(Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 121, Dec. 8, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administering authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Administering authority The term “administering authority” has the meaning given that term in section 1677(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appellate Body</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appellate Body The term “Appellate Body” means the Appellate Body established under Article 17.1 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees; congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Appropriate congressional committees; congressional committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute settlement panel; panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Dispute settlement panel; panel The terms “dispute settlement panel” and “panel” mean a panel established pursuant to Article 6 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute Settlement Body</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Dispute Settlement Body The term “Dispute Settlement Body” means the Dispute Settlement Body administering the rules and procedures set forth in the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute Settlement Understanding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Dispute Settlement Understanding The term “Dispute Settlement Understanding” means the Understanding on Rules and Procedures Governing the Settlement of Disputes referred to in section 3511(d)(16) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) General Council The term “General Council” means the General Council established under paragraph 2 of Article IV of the WTO Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ministerial Conference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Ministerial Conference The term “Ministerial Conference” means the Ministerial Conference established under paragraph 1 of Article IV of the WTO Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Other terms The terms “Antidumping Agreement”, “Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures”, and “Safeguards Agreement” mean the agreements referred to in section 3511(d)(7), (12), and (13) of this title, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>