<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3532" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3532/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3532/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3532"><akn:num>3532</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of Uruguay Round Agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3532. Implementation of Uruguay Round Agreements(a) DecisionmakingIn the implementation of the Uruguay Round Agreements and the functioning of the World Trade Organization, it is the objective of the United States to ensure that the Ministerial Conference and the General Council continue the practice of decisionmaking by consensus followed under the GATT 1947, as required by paragraph 1 of article IX of the WTO Agreement.


(b) Consultations with congressional committeesIn furtherance of the objective set forth in subsection (a), the Trade Representative shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees before any vote is taken by the Ministerial Conference or the General Council relating to—(1) the adoption of an interpretation of the WTO Agreement or another multilateral trade agreement,

(2) the amendment of any such agreement,

(3) the granting of a waiver of any obligation under any such agreement,

(4) the adoption of any amendment to the rules or procedures of the Ministerial Conference or the General Council,

(5) the accession of a state or separate customs territory to the WTO Agreement, or

(6) the adoption of any other decision,


if the action described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), or (6) would substantially affect the rights or obligations of the United States under the WTO Agreement or another multilateral trade agreement or potentially entails a change in Federal or State law.

(c) Report on decisions(1) In generalNot later than 30 days after the end of any calendar year in which the Ministerial Conference or the General Council adopts by vote any decision to take any action described in paragraph (1), (2), (4), or (6) of subsection (b), the Trade Representative shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees describing—(A) the nature of the decision;

(B) the efforts made by the United States to have the matter decided by consensus pursuant to paragraph 1 of article IX of the WTO Agreement, and the results of t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisionmaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Decisionmaking In the implementation of the Uruguay Round Agreements and the functioning of the World Trade Organization, it is the objective of the United States to ensure that the Ministerial Conference and the General Council continue the practice of decisionmaking by consensus followed under the GATT 1947, as required by paragraph 1 of article IX of the WTO Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultations with congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultations with congressional committees In furtherance of the objective set forth in subsection (a), the Trade Representative shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees before any vote is taken by the Ministerial Conference or the General Council relating to— if the action described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), or (6) would substantially affect the rights or obligations of the United States under the WTO Agreement or another multilateral trade agreement or potentially entails a change in Federal or State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on decisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report on decisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation on report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consultation on report Promptly after the submission of a report under subsection (c), the Trade Representative shall consult with the appropriate congressional committees with respect to the report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>