<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3533" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3533/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3533/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3533"><akn:num>3533</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute settlement panels and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3533. Dispute settlement panels and procedures(a) Review by PresidentThe President shall review annually the WTO panel roster and shall include the panel roster and the list of persons serving on the Appellate Body in the annual report submitted by the President under section 2213(a) of this title.


(b) Qualifications of appointees to panelsThe Trade Representative shall—(1) seek to ensure that persons appointed to the WTO panel roster are well-qualified, and that the roster includes persons with expertise in the subject areas covered by the Uruguay Round Agreements; and

(2) inform the President of persons nominated to the roster by other WTO member countries.


(c) Rules governing conflicts of interestThe Trade Representative shall seek the establishment by the General Council and the Dispute Settlement Body of rules governing conflicts of interest by persons serving on panels and members of the Appellate Body and shall describe, in the annual report submitted under section 3534 of this title, any progress made in establishing such rules.


(d) Notification of disputesPromptly after a dispute settlement panel is established to consider the consistency of Federal or State law with any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, the Trade Representative shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of—(1) the nature of the dispute, including the matters set forth in the request for the establishment of the panel, the legal basis of the complaint, and the specific measures, in particular any State or Federal law cited in the request for establishment of the panel;

(2) the identity of the persons serving on the panel; and

(3) whether there was any departure from the rule of consensus with respect to the selection of persons to serve on the panel.


(e) Notice of appeals of panel reportsIf an appeal is taken of a report of a panel in a proceeding described in subsection (d), the Trade Representative shall, promptly after the notice of appeal is filed, notify the appr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Review by President The President shall review annually the WTO panel roster and shall include the panel roster and the list of persons serving on the Appellate Body in the annual report submitted by the President under section 2213(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications of appointees to panels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualifications of appointees to panels The Trade Representative shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules governing conflicts of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rules governing conflicts of interest The Trade Representative shall seek the establishment by the General Council and the Dispute Settlement Body of rules governing conflicts of interest by persons serving on panels and members of the Appellate Body and shall describe, in the annual report submitted under section 3534 of this title, any progress made in establishing such rules.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of disputes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification of disputes Promptly after a dispute settlement panel is established to consider the consistency of Federal or State law with any of the Uruguay Round Agreements, the Trade Representative shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of appeals of panel reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice of appeals of panel reports If an appeal is taken of a report of a panel in a proceeding described in subsection (d), the Trade Representative shall, promptly after the notice of appeal is filed, notify the appropriate congressional committees of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions upon circulation of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Actions upon circulation of reports Promptly after the circulation of a report of a panel or of the Appellate Body to WTO members in a proceeding described in subsection (d), the Trade Representative shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for agency action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Requirements for agency action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultations regarding review of WTO rules and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Consultations regarding review of WTO rules and procedures Before the review is conducted of the dispute settlement rules and procedures of the WTO that is provided for in the Decision on the Application of the Understanding on Rules and Procedures Governing the Settlement of Disputes, as such decision is set forth in the Ministerial Declarations and Decisions adopted on April 15, 1994, together with the Uruguay Round Agreements, the Trade Representative shall consult with the congressional committees regarding the policy of the United States concerning the review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>