<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3538" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3538/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3538/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3538"><akn:num>3538</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative action following WTO panel reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3538. Administrative action following WTO panel reports(a) Action by United States International Trade Commission(1) Advisory reportIf a dispute settlement panel finds in an interim report under Article 15 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding, or the Appellate Body finds in a report under Article 17 of that Understanding, that an action by the International Trade Commission in connection with a particular proceeding is not in conformity with the obligations of the United States under the Antidumping Agreement, the Safeguards Agreement, or the Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures, the Trade Representative may request the Commission to issue an advisory report on whether title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [19 U.S.C. 1671 et seq.] or title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2251 et seq.], as the case may be, permits the Commission to take steps in connection with the particular proceeding that would render its action not inconsistent with the findings of the panel or the Appellate Body concerning those obligations. The Trade Representative shall notify the congressional committees of such request.


(2) Time limits for reportThe Commission shall transmit its report under paragraph (1) to the Trade Representative—(A) in the case of an interim report described in paragraph (1), within 30 calendar days after the Trade Representative requests the report; and

(B) in the case of a report of the Appellate Body, within 21 calendar days after the Trade Representative requests the report.


(3) Consultations on request for Commission determinationIf a majority of the Commissioners issues an affirmative report under paragraph (1), the Trade Representative shall consult with the congressional committees concerning the matter.


(4) Commission determinationNotwithstanding any provision of the Tariff Act of 1930 [19 U.S.C. 1202 et seq.] or title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2251 et seq.], if a majority of the Commissioners issues an affirmative rep</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3538_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by United States International Trade Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Action by United States International Trade Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3538_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by administering authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Action by administering authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3538_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effects of determinations; notice of implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effects of determinations; notice of implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3538_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity for comment by interested parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Opportunity for comment by interested parties Prior to issuing a determination under this section, the administering authority or the Commission, as the case may be, shall provide interested parties with an opportunity to submit written comments and, in appropriate cases, may hold a hearing, with respect to the determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>