<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3551" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3551/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3551/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3551"><akn:num>3551</akn:num><akn:heading>Working party on worker rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3551. Working party on worker rights(a) In generalThe President shall seek the establishment in the GATT 1947, and, upon entry into force of the WTO Agreement with respect to the United States, in the WTO, of a working party to examine the relationship of internationally recognized worker rights, as defined in section 2467(4) of this title, to the articles, objectives, and related instruments of the GATT 1947 and of the WTO, respectively.


(b) Objectives of working partyThe objectives of the United States for the working party described in subsection (a) are to—(1) explore the linkage between international trade and internationally recognized worker rights, as defined in section 2467(4) of this title, taking into account differences in the level of development among countries;

(2) examine the effects on international trade of the systematic denial of such rights;

(3) consider ways to address such effects; and

(4) develop methods to coordinate the work program of the working party with the International Labor Organization.


(c) Report to CongressThe President shall report to the Congress, not later than 1 year after December 8, 1994, on the progress made in establishing the working party under this section, and on United States objectives with respect to the working party’s work program.


(Pub. L. 103–465, title I, § 131, Dec. 8, 1994, 108 Stat. 4839; Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1954(a)(6), Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1928.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Subsecs. (a), (b)(1). Pub. L. 104–188 substituted “2467(4)” for “2462(a)(4)”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1996 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 104–188 applicable to articles entered on or after Oct. 1, 1996, with provisions relating to retroactive application, see section 1953 of Pub. L. 104–188, set out as an Effective Date note under section 2461 of this title.

Effective DatePub. L. 103–465, title I, § 138, Dec. 8, 1994, 108 Stat. 4842, provided that:
“(a) In General.—Except as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3551_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The President shall seek the establishment in the GATT 1947, and, upon entry into force of the WTO Agreement with respect to the United States, in the WTO, of a working party to examine the relationship of internationally recognized worker rights, as defined in section 2467(4) of this title, to the articles, objectives, and related instruments of the GATT 1947 and of the WTO, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3551_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objectives of working party</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Objectives of working party The objectives of the United States for the working party described in subsection (a) are to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3551_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report to Congress The President shall report to the Congress, not later than 1 year after December 8, 1994, on the progress made in establishing the working party under this section, and on United States objectives with respect to the working party’s work program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>