<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3571" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3571/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3571/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3571"><akn:num>3571</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsidies enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3571. Subsidies enforcement(a) Assistance regarding multilateral subsidy remediesThe administering authority shall provide information to the public upon request, and, to the extent feasible, assistance and advice to interested parties concerning—(1) remedies and benefits available under relevant provisions of the Subsidies Agreement, and

(2) the procedures relating to such remedies and benefits.


(b) Prohibited subsidies(1) Notification of Trade RepresentativeIf the administering authority determines pursuant to title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [19 U.S.C. 1671 et seq.] that a class or kind of merchandise is benefiting from a subsidy which is prohibited under Article 3 of the Subsidies Agreement, the administering authority shall notify the Trade Representative and shall provide the Trade Representative with the information upon which the administering authority based its determination.


(2) Request by interested party regarding prohibited subsidyAn interested party may request that the administering authority determine if there is reason to believe that merchandise produced in a WTO member country is benefiting from a subsidy which is prohibited under Article 3 of the Subsidies Agreement. The request shall contain such information as the administering authority may require to support the allegations contained in the request. If the administering authority, after analyzing the request and other information reasonably available to the administering authority, determines that there is reason to believe that such merchandise is benefiting from a subsidy which is prohibited under Article 3 of the Subsidies Agreement, the administering authority shall so notify the Trade Representative, and shall include supporting information with the notification.



(c) Subsidies actionable under Agreement(1) In generalIf the administering authority determines pursuant to title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 [19 U.S.C. 1671 et seq.] that a class or kind of merchandise is benefi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3571_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance regarding multilateral subsidy remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assistance regarding multilateral subsidy remedies The administering authority shall provide information to the public upon request, and, to the extent feasible, assistance and advice to interested parties concerning—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3571_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited subsidies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibited subsidies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3571_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsidies actionable under Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subsidies actionable under Agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3571_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiation of section 2411 investigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Initiation of section 2411 investigation On the basis of the notification and information provided by the administering authority pursuant to subsection (b) or (c), such other information as the Trade Representative may have or obtain, and where applicable, after consultation with an interested party referred to in subsection (b)(2) or (c)(2), the Trade Representative shall, unless such interested party objects, determine as expeditiously as possible, in accordance with the procedures in section 302(b)(1) of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2412(b)(1)), whether to initiate an investigation pursuant to title III of that Act (19 U.S.C. 2411 et seq.). At the request of the Trade Representative, the administering authority and the Commission shall assist the Trade Representative in an investigation initiated pursuant to this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3571_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonactionable subsidies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nonactionable subsidies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3571_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification, consultation, and publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notification, consultation, and publication</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3571_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation of other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cooperation of other agencies All agencies, departments, and independent agencies of the Federal Government shall cooperate fully with one another in carrying out the provisions of this section, and, upon the request of the administering authority, shall furnish to the administering authority all records, papers, and information in their possession which relate to the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3571_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3571_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of proprietary information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Treatment of proprietary information Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the administering authority may provide the Trade Representative with a copy of proprietary information submitted to, or obtained by, the administering authority that the Trade Representative considers relevant in carrying out its responsibilities under this subchapter. The Trade Representative shall protect from public disclosure proprietary information obtained from the administering authority under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>