<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3601" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3601/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3601/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3601"><akn:num>3601</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of tariff-rate quotas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3601. Administration of tariff-rate quotas(a) Orderly marketingIn implementing the tariff-rate quotas set out in Schedule XX for the entry, or withdrawal from warehouse, for consumption of goods in the United States, the President shall take such action as may be necessary to ensure that imports of agricultural products do not disrupt the orderly marketing of commodities in the United States.


(b) Inadequate supplyWhere imports of an agricultural product are subject to a tariff-rate quota, and where the President determines and proclaims that the supply of the same or directly competitive or substitutable agricultural product will be inadequate, because of a natural disaster, disease, or major national market disruption, to meet domestic demand at reasonable prices, the President may temporarily increase the quantity of imports of the agricultural product that is subject to the in-quota rate of duty established under the tariff-rate quota.


(c) MonitoringThe Secretary of Agriculture shall monitor the domestic supply of agricultural products subject to a tariff-rate quota as the Secretary considers appropriate and shall advise the President when the domestic supply of the products and substitutable products combined with the estimated imports of the products under the tariff-rate quota may be inadequate to meet domestic demand at reasonable prices.


(d) Coverage of tariff-rate quotas(1) ExclusionsThe President may, subject to terms and conditions determined appropriate by the President, provide that the entry, or withdrawal from warehouse, for consumption in the United States of an agricultural product shall not be subject to the over-quota rate of duty established under a tariff-rate quota if the agricultural product—(A) is imported by, or for the account of, any agency of the United States or of any foreign embassy;

(B) is imported as a sample for taking orders, for the personal use of the importer, or for the testing of equipment;

(C) is a commercial sample</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3601_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Orderly marketing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Orderly marketing In implementing the tariff-rate quotas set out in Schedule XX for the entry, or withdrawal from warehouse, for consumption of goods in the United States, the President shall take such action as may be necessary to ensure that imports of agricultural products do not disrupt the orderly marketing of commodities in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3601_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inadequate supply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inadequate supply Where imports of an agricultural product are subject to a tariff-rate quota, and where the President determines and proclaims that the supply of the same or directly competitive or substitutable agricultural product will be inadequate, because of a natural disaster, disease, or major national market disruption, to meet domestic demand at reasonable prices, the President may temporarily increase the quantity of imports of the agricultural product that is subject to the in-quota rate of duty established under the tariff-rate quota.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3601_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Monitoring The Secretary of Agriculture shall monitor the domestic supply of agricultural products subject to a tariff-rate quota as the Secretary considers appropriate and shall advise the President when the domestic supply of the products and substitutable products combined with the estimated imports of the products under the tariff-rate quota may be inadequate to meet domestic demand at reasonable prices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3601_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage of tariff-rate quotas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coverage of tariff-rate quotas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>