<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3602"><akn:num>3602</akn:num><akn:heading>Special agricultural safeguard authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3602. Special agricultural safeguard authority(a) Determination of trigger levelsConsistent with Article 5 as determined by the President, the President shall cause to be published in the Federal Register—(1) the list of special safeguard agricultural goods not later than the date of entry into force of the WTO Agreement with respect to the United States; and

(2) for each special safeguard agricultural good—(A) the trigger level specified in subparagraph 1(a) of Article 5, on an annual basis;

(B) the trigger price specified in subparagraph 1(b) of Article 5; and

(C) the relevant period.



(b) Determination of safeguardIf the President determines with respect to a special safeguard agricultural good that it is appropriate to impose—(1) the price-based safeguard in accordance with subparagraph 1(b) of Article 5; or

(2) the volume-based safeguard in accordance with subparagraph 1(a) of Article 5,


the President shall, consistent with Article 5 as determined by the President, determine the amount of the duty to be imposed, the period such duty shall be in effect, and any other terms and conditions applicable to the duty.

(c) Imposition of safeguardThe President shall direct the Secretary of the Treasury to impose a duty on a special safeguard agricultural good entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption in the United States in accordance with a determination made under subsection (b).


(d) No simultaneous safeguardA duty may not be in effect for a special safeguard agricultural good pursuant to this section during any period in which such good is the subject of any action proclaimed pursuant to section 2252 or 2253 of this title.


(e) Exclusion of originating goods of USMCA countries(1) In generalThe President shall exempt from any duty imposed under this section any good that qualifies as an originating good under section 4531 of this title of a USMCA country with respect to which preferential tariff treatment is provided under the USMCA.


(2) Def</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of trigger levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination of trigger levels Consistent with Article 5 as determined by the President, the President shall cause to be published in the Federal Register—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of safeguard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of safeguard If the President determines with respect to a special safeguard agricultural good that it is appropriate to impose— the President shall, consistent with Article 5 as determined by the President, determine the amount of the duty to be imposed, the period such duty shall be in effect, and any other terms and conditions applicable to the duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of safeguard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Imposition of safeguard The President shall direct the Secretary of the Treasury to impose a duty on a special safeguard agricultural good entered, or withdrawn from warehouse, for consumption in the United States in accordance with a determination made under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No simultaneous safeguard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No simultaneous safeguard A duty may not be in effect for a special safeguard agricultural good pursuant to this section during any period in which such good is the subject of any action proclaimed pursuant to section 2252 or 2253 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of originating goods of USMCA countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusion of originating goods of USMCA countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advice of Secretary of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Advice of Secretary of Agriculture The Secretary of Agriculture shall advise the President on the implementation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Termination date This section shall cease to be effective on the date, as determined by the President, that the special safeguard provisions of Article 5 are no longer in force with respect to the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>