<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3704"><akn:num>3704</akn:num><akn:heading>United States-Sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3704. United States-Sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum(a) Declaration of policyThe President shall convene annual high-level meetings between appropriate officials of the United States Government and officials of the governments of sub-Saharan African countries in order to foster close economic ties between the United States and sub-Saharan Africa.


(b) EstablishmentNot later than 12 months after May 18, 2000, the President, after consulting with Congress and the governments concerned, shall establish a United States-Sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum (in this section referred to as the “Forum”).


(c) RequirementsIn creating the Forum, the President shall meet the following requirements:(1) The President shall direct the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of State, and the United States Trade Representative to host the first annual meeting with their counterparts from the governments of sub-Saharan African countries eligible under section 3703 of this title, and those sub-Saharan African countries that the President determines are taking substantial positive steps towards meeting the eligibility requirements in section 3703 of this title. The purpose of the meeting shall be to discuss expanding trade and investment relations between the United States and sub-Saharan Africa and the implementation of this chapter including encouraging joint ventures between small and large businesses. The President shall also direct the Secretaries and the United States Trade Representative to invite to the meeting representatives from appropriate sub-Saharan African regional organizations and government officials from other appropriate countries in sub-Saharan Africa.

(2)(A) The President, in consultation with the Congress, shall encourage United States nongovernmental organizations to host annual meetings with nongovernmental organizations from sub-Saharan Africa in conjunction with the annual meetings o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Declaration of policy The President shall convene annual high-level meetings between appropriate officials of the United States Government and officials of the governments of sub-Saharan African countries in order to foster close economic ties between the United States and sub-Saharan Africa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment Not later than 12 months after May 18, 2000, the President, after consulting with Congress and the governments concerned, shall establish a United States-Sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum (in this section referred to as the “Forum”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements In creating the Forum, the President shall meet the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information by USIS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Dissemination of information by USIS In order to assist in carrying out the purposes of the Forum, the United States Information Service shall disseminate regularly, through multiple media, economic information in support of the free market economic reforms described in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3704_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>HIV/AIDS effect on the sub-Saharan African workforce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) HIV/AIDS effect on the sub-Saharan African workforce In selecting issues of common interest to the United States-Sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum, the President shall instruct the United States delegates to the Forum to promote a review by the Forum of the HIV/AIDS epidemic in each sub-Saharan African country and the effect of the HIV/AIDS epidemic on economic development in each country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>