<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3721" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3721/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/3721/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3721"><akn:num>3721</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain textiles and apparel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3721. Treatment of certain textiles and apparel(a) Preferential treatmentTextile and apparel articles described in subsection (b) that are imported directly into the customs territory of the United States from a beneficiary sub-Saharan African country described in section 2466a(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, shall enter the United States free of duty and free of any quantitative limitations in accordance with the provisions set forth in subsection (b), if the country has satisfied the requirements set forth in section 3722 of this title.


(b) Products coveredSubject to subsection (c), the preferential treatment described in subsection (a) shall apply only to the following textile and apparel products:(1) Apparel articles assembled in one or more beneficiary sub-Saharan African countriesApparel articles sewn or otherwise assembled in one or more beneficiary sub-Saharan African countries from fabrics wholly formed and cut, or from components knit-to-shape, in the United States from yarns wholly formed in the United States, or both (including fabrics not formed from yarns, if such fabrics are classifiable under heading 5602 or 5603 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States and are wholly formed and cut in the United States) that are—(A) entered under subheading 9802.00.80 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States; or

(B) entered under chapter 61 or 62 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, if, after such assembly, the articles would have qualified for entry under subheading 9802.00.80 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States but for the fact that the articles were embroidered or subjected to stone-washing, enzyme-washing, acid washing, perma-pressing, oven-baking, bleaching, garment-dyeing, screen printing, or other similar processes.


(2) Other apparel articles assembled in one or more beneficiary sub-Saharan African countriesApparel articles sewn or otherwise assembled in one or mo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferential treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preferential treatment Textile and apparel articles described in subsection (b) that are imported directly into the customs territory of the United States from a beneficiary sub-Saharan African country described in section 2466a(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, shall enter the United States free of duty and free of any quantitative limitations in accordance with the provisions set forth in subsection (b), if the country has satisfied the requirements set forth in section 3722 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Products covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Products covered Subject to subsection (c), the preferential treatment described in subsection (a) shall apply only to the following textile and apparel products:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lesser developed countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Lesser developed countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of quotas on textile and apparel imports from Kenya and Mauritius</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of quotas on textile and apparel imports from Kenya and Mauritius The President shall eliminate the existing quotas on textile and apparel articles imported into the United States— The Customs Service shall provide the necessary technical assistance to Kenya and Mauritius in the development and implementation of the visa systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section and section 3722 of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3721_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effective date This section takes effect on October 1, 2000, and shall remain in effect through September 30, 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>