<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4013" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4013/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4013/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4013"><akn:num>4013</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementing actions in anticipation of entry into force and initial regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4013. Implementing actions in anticipation of entry into force and initial regulations(a) Implementing actions(1) Proclamation authorityAfter August 2, 2005—(A) the President may proclaim such actions, and

(B) other appropriate officers of the United States Government may issue such regulations,


as may be necessary to ensure that any provision of this chapter, or amendment made by this chapter, that takes effect on the date the Agreement enters into force is appropriately implemented on such date, but no such proclamation or regulation may have an effective date earlier than the date the Agreement enters into force.

(2) Effective date of certain proclaimed actionsAny action proclaimed by the President under the authority of this chapter that is not subject to the consultation and layover provisions under section 4014 of this title may not take effect before the 15th day after the date on which the text of the proclamation is published in the Federal Register.


(3) Waiver of 15-day restrictionThe 15-day restriction contained in paragraph (2) on the taking effect of proclaimed actions is waived to the extent that the application of such restriction would prevent the taking effect on the date the Agreement enters into force of any action proclaimed under this section.



(b) Initial regulationsInitial regulations necessary or appropriate to carry out the actions required by or authorized under this chapter or proposed in the statement of administrative action submitted under section 4011(a)(2) of this title to implement the Agreement shall, to the maximum extent feasible, be issued within 1 year after the date on which the Agreement enters into force. In the case of any implementing action that takes effect on a date after the date on which the Agreement enters into force, initial regulations to carry out that action shall, to the maximum extent feasible, be issued within 1 year after such effective date.


(Pub. L. 109–53, title I, § 103, Aug. 2, 2005, 119 Stat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4013_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementing actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Implementing actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4013_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Initial regulations Initial regulations necessary or appropriate to carry out the actions required by or authorized under this chapter or proposed in the statement of administrative action submitted under section 4011(a)(2) of this title to implement the Agreement shall, to the maximum extent feasible, be issued within 1 year after the date on which the Agreement enters into force. In the case of any implementing action that takes effect on a date after the date on which the Agreement enters into force, initial regulations to carry out that action shall, to the maximum extent feasible, be issued within 1 year after such effective date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>