<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4015" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4015/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4015/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4015"><akn:num>4015</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of dispute settlement proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4015. Administration of dispute settlement proceedings(a) Establishment or designation of officeThe President is authorized to establish or designate within the Department of Commerce an office that shall be responsible for providing administrative assistance to panels established under chapter 20 of the Agreement. The office may not be considered to be an agency for purposes of section 552 of title 5.


(b) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2005 to the Department of Commerce such sums as may be necessary for the establishment and operations of the office established or designated under subsection (a) and for the payment of the United States share of the expenses of panels established under chapter 20 of the Agreement.


(Pub. L. 109–53, title I, § 105, Aug. 2, 2005, 119 Stat. 466.)

Termination of SectionFor termination of section by section 107(d) of Pub. L. 109–53, see Effective and Termination Dates note below.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective and Termination DatesSection effective on the date the Dominican Republic-Central America-United States Free Trade Agreement enters into force (Mar. 1, 2006) and to cease to have effect on the date the Agreement ceases to be in force with respect to the United States, and, during any period in which a country ceases to be a CAFTA–DR country, to cease to have effect with respect to such country, see section 107 of Pub. L. 109–53, set out as a note under section 4001 of this title.

Executive Documents

Delegation of Functions
Proc. No. 7987, Feb. 28, 2006, 71 F.R. 10828, provided in par. (3) that the Secretary of Commerce is authorized to exercise the President’s authority under subsec. (a) of this section to establish or designate an office within the Department of Commerce to carry out the functions set forth in this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4015_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment or designation of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment or designation of office The President is authorized to establish or designate within the Department of Commerce an office that shall be responsible for providing administrative assistance to panels established under chapter 20 of the Agreement. The office may not be considered to be an agency for purposes of section 552 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4015_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year after fiscal year 2005 to the Department of Commerce such sums as may be necessary for the establishment and operations of the office established or designated under subsection (a) and for the payment of the United States share of the expenses of panels established under chapter 20 of the Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>