<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4033" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4033/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4033/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4033"><akn:num>4033</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of origin</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4033. Rules of origin(a) Application and interpretationIn this section:(1) Tariff classificationThe basis for any tariff classification is the HTS.


(2) Reference to HTSWhenever in this section there is a reference to a chapter, heading, or subheading, such reference shall be a reference to a chapter, heading, or subheading of the HTS.


(3) Cost or valueAny cost or value referred to in this section shall be recorded and maintained in accordance with the generally accepted accounting principles applicable in the territory of the country in which the good is produced (whether the United States or another CAFTA–DR country).



(b) Originating goodsFor purposes of this chapter and for purposes of implementing the preferential tariff treatment provided for under the Agreement, except as otherwise provided in this section, a good is an originating good if—(1) the good is a good wholly obtained or produced entirely in the territory of one or more of the CAFTA–DR countries;

(2) the good—(A) is produced entirely in the territory of one or more of the CAFTA–DR countries, and—(i) each of the nonoriginating materials used in the production of the good undergoes an applicable change in tariff classification specified in Annex 4.1 of the Agreement; or

(ii) the good otherwise satisfies any applicable regional value-content or other requirements specified in Annex 4.1 of the Agreement; and


(B) satisfies all other applicable requirements of this section; or


(3) the good is produced entirely in the territory of one or more of the CAFTA–DR countries, exclusively from materials described in paragraph (1) or (2).


(c) Regional value-content(1) In generalFor purposes of subsection (b)(2), the regional value-content of a good referred to in Annex 4.1 of the Agreement, except for goods to which paragraph (4) applies, shall be calculated by the importer, exporter, or producer of the good, on the basis of the build-down method described in paragraph (2) or the build-up method desc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application and interpretation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application and interpretation In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Originating goods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Originating goods For purposes of this chapter and for purposes of implementing the preferential tariff treatment provided for under the Agreement, except as otherwise provided in this section, a good is an originating good if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional value-content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regional value-content</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value of materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Value of materials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accumulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Accumulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>De minimis amounts of nonoriginating materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) De minimis amounts of nonoriginating materials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fungible goods and materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fungible goods and materials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accessories, spare parts, or tools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Accessories, spare parts, or tools</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Packaging materials and containers for retail sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Packaging materials and containers for retail sale Packaging materials and containers in which a good is packaged for retail sale, if classified with the good, shall be disregarded in determining whether all the nonoriginating materials used in the production of the good undergo the applicable change in tariff classification set out in Annex 4.1 of the Agreement, and, if the good is subject to a regional value-content requirement, the value of such packaging materials and containers shall be taken into account as originating or nonoriginating materials, as the case may be, in calculating the regional value-content of the good.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4033_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Packing materials and containers for shipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Packing materials and containers for shipment Packing materials and containers for shipment shall be disregarded in determining whether a good is an originating good.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>