<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4082" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4082/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4082/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4082"><akn:num>4082</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination and provision of relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4082. Determination and provision of relief(a) Determination(1) In generalIf a positive determination is made under section 4081(b) of this title, the President shall determine whether, as a result of the elimination of a duty under the Agreement, a CAFTA–DR textile or apparel article of a specified CAFTA–DR country is being imported into the United States in such increased quantities, in absolute terms or relative to the domestic market for that article, and under such conditions as to cause serious damage, or actual threat thereof, to a domestic industry producing an article that is like, or directly competitive with, the imported article.


(2) Serious damageIn making a determination under paragraph (1), the President—(A) shall examine the effect of increased imports on the domestic industry, as reflected in changes in such relevant economic factors as output, productivity, utilization of capacity, inventories, market share, exports, wages, employment, domestic prices, profits, and investment, none of which is necessarily decisive; and

(B) shall not consider changes in technology or consumer preference as factors supporting a determination of serious damage or actual threat thereof.


(3) Deadline for determinationThe President shall make the determination under paragraph (1) no later than 30 days after the completion of any consultations held pursuant to article 3.23.4 of the Agreement.



(b) Provision of relief(1) In generalIf a determination under subsection (a) is affirmative, the President may provide relief from imports of the article that is the subject of such determination, as provided in paragraph (2), to the extent that the President determines necessary to remedy or prevent the serious damage and to facilitate adjustment by the domestic industry.


(2) Nature of reliefThe relief that the President is authorized to provide under this subsection with respect to imports of an article is an increase in the rate of duty imposed on the article to a leve</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Provision of relief</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>