<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4111"><akn:num>4111</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic reports and meetings on labor obligations and labor capacity-building provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4111. Periodic reports and meetings on labor obligations and labor capacity-building provisions(a) Reports to Congress(1) In generalNot later than the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date the Agreement enters into force, and not later than the end of each 2-year period thereafter during the succeeding 14-year period, the President shall report to the Congress on the progress made by the CAFTA–DR countries in—(A) implementing Chapter Sixteen and Annex 16.5 of the Agreement; and

(B) implementing the White Paper.


(2) White PaperIn this section, the term “White Paper” means the report of April 2005 of the Working Group of the Vice Ministers Responsible for Trade and Labor in the Countries of Central America and the Dominican Republic entitled “The Labor Dimension in Central America and the Dominican Republic - Building on Progress: Strengthening Compliance and Enhancing Capacity”.


(3) Contents of reportsEach report under paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) A description of the progress made by the Labor Cooperation and Capacity Building Mechanism established by article 16.5 and Annex 16.5 of the Agreement, and the Labor Affairs Council established by article 16.4 of the Agreement, in achieving their stated goals, including a description of the capacity-building projects undertaken, funds received, and results achieved, in each CAFTA–DR country.

(B) Recommendations on how the United States can facilitate full implementation of the recommendations contained in the White Paper.

(C) A description of the work done by the CAFTA–DR countries with the International Labor Organization to implement the recommendations contained in the White Paper, and the efforts of the CAFTA–DR countries with international organizations, through the Labor Cooperation and Capacity Building Mechanism referred to in subparagraph (A), to advance common commitments regarding labor matters.

(D) A summary of public comments received on—(i) capacity-building efforts by the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic meetings of Secretary of Labor with labor ministers of CAFTA–DR countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Periodic meetings of Secretary of Labor with labor ministers of CAFTA–DR countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>