<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4210" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4210/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4210/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4210"><akn:num>4210</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4210. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Agreement on AgricultureThe term “Agreement on Agriculture” means the agreement referred to in section 3511(d)(2) of this title.


(2) Agreement on SafeguardsThe term “Agreement on Safeguards” means the agreement referred to in section 3511(d)(13) of this title.


(3) Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing MeasuresThe term “Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures” means the agreement referred to in section 3511(d)(12) of this title.


(4) Antidumping AgreementThe term “Antidumping Agreement” means the Agreement on Implementation of Article VI of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade 1994 referred to in section 3511(d)(7) of this title.


(5) Appellate BodyThe term “Appellate Body” means the Appellate Body established under Article 17.1 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding.


(6) Common multilateral environmental agreement(A) In generalThe term “common multilateral environmental agreement” means any agreement specified in subparagraph (B) or included under subparagraph (C) to which both the United States and one or more other parties to the negotiations are full parties, including any current or future mutually agreed upon protocols, amendments, annexes, or adjustments to such an agreement.


(B) Agreements specifiedThe agreements specified in this subparagraph are the following:(i) The Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora, done at Washington March 3, 1973 (27 UST 1087; TIAS 8249).

(ii) The Montreal Protocol on Substances that Deplete the Ozone Layer, done at Montreal September 16, 1987.

(iii) The Protocol of 1978 Relating to the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships, 1973, done at London February 17, 1978.

(iv) The Convention on Wetlands of International Importance Especially as Waterfowl Habitat, done at Ramsar February 2, 1971 (TIAS 11084).

(v) The Convention on the Conservation of Antarctic Marine Living Resources, done at Can</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement on Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agreement on Agriculture The term “Agreement on Agriculture” means the agreement referred to in section 3511(d)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement on Safeguards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Agreement on Safeguards The term “Agreement on Safeguards” means the agreement referred to in section 3511(d)(13) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures The term “Agreement on Subsidies and Countervailing Measures” means the agreement referred to in section 3511(d)(12) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antidumping Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Antidumping Agreement The term “Antidumping Agreement” means the Agreement on Implementation of Article VI of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade 1994 referred to in section 3511(d)(7) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appellate Body</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Appellate Body The term “Appellate Body” means the Appellate Body established under Article 17.1 of the Dispute Settlement Understanding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common multilateral environmental agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Common multilateral environmental agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Core labor standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Core labor standards The term “core labor standards” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute Settlement Understanding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Dispute Settlement Understanding The term “Dispute Settlement Understanding” means the Understanding on Rules and Procedures Governing the Settlement of Disputes referred to in section 3511(d)(16) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enabling Clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Enabling Clause The term “Enabling Clause” means the Decision on Differential and More Favourable Treatment, Reciprocity and Fuller Participation of Developing Countries (L/4903), adopted November 28, 1979, under GATT 1947 (as defined in section 3501 of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4210_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Environmental laws The term “environmental laws”, with respect to the laws of the United States, means environmental statutes and regulations enforceable by action of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>