<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4301"><akn:num>4301</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4301. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Automated Commercial EnvironmentThe term “Automated Commercial Environment” means the Automated Commercial Environment computer system authorized under section 58c(f)(4) of this title.


(2) Commercial operations of U.S. Customs and Border ProtectionThe term “commercial operations of U.S. Customs and Border Protection” includes—(A) administering any customs revenue function (as defined in section 215 of title 6);

(B) coordinating efforts of the Department of Homeland Security with respect to trade facilitation and trade enforcement;

(C) coordinating with the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement with respect to—(i) investigations relating to trade enforcement; and

(ii) the development and implementation of the joint strategic plan required by section 4314 of this title;


(D) coordinating, on behalf of the Department of Homeland Security, efforts among Federal agencies to facilitate legitimate trade and to enforce the customs and trade laws of the United States, including representing the Department of Homeland Security in interagency fora addressing such efforts;

(E) coordinating with customs authorities of foreign countries to facilitate legitimate international trade and enforce the customs and trade laws of the United States and the customs and trade laws of foreign countries;

(F) collecting, assessing, and disseminating information as appropriate and in accordance with any law regarding cargo destined for the United States—(i) to ensure that such cargo complies with the customs and trade laws of the United States; and

(ii) to facilitate the legitimate international trade of such cargo;


(G) soliciting and considering on a regular basis input from private sector entities, including the Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee established by section 4316 of this title and the Trade Support Network, with respect to, as appropriate—(i) the implementation of changes to the customs and trade laws o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Automated Commercial Environment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Automated Commercial Environment The term “Automated Commercial Environment” means the Automated Commercial Environment computer system authorized under section 58c(f)(4) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial operations of U.S. Customs and Border Protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Commercial operations of U.S. Customs and Border Protection The term “commercial operations of U.S. Customs and Border Protection” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Commissioner The term “Commissioner” means the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, as described in section 211(b) of title 6.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customs and trade laws of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Customs and trade laws of the United States The term “customs and trade laws of the United States” includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private sector entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Private sector entity The term “private sector entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Trade enforcement The term “trade enforcement” means the enforcement of the customs and trade laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade facilitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Trade facilitation The term “trade facilitation” refers to policies and activities of U.S. Customs and Border Protection with respect to facilitating the movement of merchandise into and out of the United States in a manner that complies with the customs and trade laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>