<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4313"><akn:num>4313</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational seminars to improve efforts to classify and appraise imported articles, to improve trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4313. Educational seminars to improve efforts to classify and appraise imported articles, to improve trade enforcement efforts, and to otherwise facilitate legitimate international trade(a) EstablishmentThe Commissioner and the Director shall establish and carry out on a fiscal year basis educational seminars to—(1) improve the ability of personnel of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to classify and appraise articles imported into the United States in accordance with the customs and trade laws of the United States;

(2) improve the trade enforcement efforts of personnel of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and personnel of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement; and

(3) otherwise improve the ability and effectiveness of personnel of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and personnel of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to facilitate legitimate international trade.


(b) Content(1) Classifying and appraising imported articlesIn carrying out subsection (a)(1), the Commissioner, the Director, and interested parties in the private sector selected under subsection (c) shall provide instruction and related instructional materials at each educational seminar carried out under this section to personnel of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and, as appropriate, to personnel of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement on the following:(A) Conducting a physical inspection of an article imported into the United States, including testing of samples of the article, to determine if the article is mislabeled in the manifest or other accompanying documentation.

(B) Reviewing the manifest and other accompanying documentation of an article imported into the United States to determine if the country of origin of the article listed in the manifest or other accompanying documentation is accurate.

(C) Customs valuation.

(D) Industry supply chains and other related matters as determined to be appropriate by the Commissioner.


(2) Trade enforcement effortsIn carrying out su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Commissioner and the Director shall establish and carry out on a fiscal year basis educational seminars to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Content</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Selection process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for antidumping and countervailing duty orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rule for antidumping and countervailing duty orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Performance standards The Commissioner and the Director shall establish performance standards to measure the development and level of achievement of educational seminars carried out under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reporting Not later than September 30, 2016, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner and the Director shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the effectiveness of educational seminars carried out under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>