<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4314" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4314/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4314/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4314"><akn:num>4314</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint strategic plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4314. Joint strategic plan(a) In generalNot later than one year after February 24, 2016, and every 2 years thereafter, the Commissioner and the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement shall jointly develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a joint strategic plan.


(b) ContentsThe joint strategic plan required under this section shall be comprised of a comprehensive multiyear plan for trade enforcement and trade facilitation, and shall include—(1) a summary of actions taken during the 2-year period preceding the submission of the plan to improve trade enforcement and trade facilitation, including a description and analysis of specific performance measures to evaluate the progress of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement in meeting each such responsibility;

(2) a statement of objectives and plans for further improving trade enforcement and trade facilitation;

(3) a specific identification of the priority trade issues described in section 4322 of this title that can be addressed in order to enhance trade enforcement and trade facilitation, and a description of strategies and plans for addressing each such issue, including—(A) a description of the targeting methodologies used for enforcement activities with respect to each such issue;

(B) recommendations for improving such enforcement activities; and

(C) a description of the implementation of previous recommendations for improving such enforcement activities;


(4) a description of efforts made to improve consultation and coordination among and within Federal agencies, and in particular between U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, regarding trade enforcement and trade facilitation;

(5) a description of the training that has occurred to date within U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to improve trade enforcement and trade facilitation, including traini</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4314_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than one year after February 24, 2016, and every 2 years thereafter, the Commissioner and the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement shall jointly develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a joint strategic plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4314_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents The joint strategic plan required under this section shall be comprised of a comprehensive multiyear plan for trade enforcement and trade facilitation, and shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4314_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4314_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Form of plan The joint strategic plan required under this section shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>