<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4316" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4316/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4316/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4316"><akn:num>4316</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4316. Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee(a) EstablishmentNot later than the date that is 60 days after February 24, 2016, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly establish a Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Committee”).


(b) Membership(1) In generalThe Advisory Committee shall be comprised of—(A) 20 individuals appointed under paragraph (2);

(B) the Assistant Secretary for Tax Policy of the Department of the Treasury and the Commissioner, who shall jointly co-chair meetings of the Advisory Committee; and

(C) the Assistant Secretary for Policy and the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, who shall serve as deputy co-chairs of meetings of the Advisory Committee.


(2) Appointment(A) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly appoint 20 individuals from the private sector to the Advisory Committee.


(B) RequirementsIn making appointments under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall appoint members—(i) to ensure that the membership of the Advisory Committee is representative of the individuals and firms affected by the commercial operations of U.S. Customs and Border Protection; and

(ii) without regard to political affiliation.


(C) TermsEach individual appointed to the Advisory Committee under this paragraph shall be appointed for a term of not more than 3 years, and may be reappointed to subsequent terms, but may not serve more than 2 terms sequentially.



(3) Transfer of membershipThe Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security may transfer members serving on the Advisory Committee on Commercial Operations of the United States Customs Service established under section 9503(c) of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987 (19 U.S.C. 2071 note) 11 See References in Text note below. on the day before F</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Not later than the date that is 60 days after February 24, 2016, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security shall jointly establish a Commercial Customs Operations Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Committee”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Advisory Committee established under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Meetings Notwithstanding section 1009(f) of title 5, the Advisory Committee shall meet at the call of the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security, or at the call of not less than ⅔ of the membership of the Advisory Committee. The Advisory Committee shall meet at least 4 times each calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual report Not later than December 31, 2016, and annually thereafter, the Advisory Committee shall submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives a report that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Termination Section 1013(a) of title 5 shall not apply to the Advisory Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conforming amendment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Conforming amendment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>