<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4321"><akn:num>4321</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of importer risk assessment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4321. Establishment of importer risk assessment program(a) In generalNot later than the date that is 180 days after February 24, 2016, the Commissioner shall establish a program that directs U.S. Customs and Border Protection to adjust bond amounts for importers, including new importers and nonresident importers, based on risk assessments of such importers conducted by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, in order to protect the revenue of the Federal Government.


(b) RequirementsThe Commissioner shall ensure that, as part of the program established under subsection (a), U.S. Customs and Border Protection—(1) develops risk assessment guidelines for importers, including new importers and nonresident importers, to determine if and to what extent—(A) to adjust bond amounts of imported products of such importers; and

(B) to increase screening of imported products of such importers;


(2) develops procedures to ensure increased oversight of imported products of new importers, including nonresident importers, relating to the enforcement of the priority trade issues described in section 4322 of this title;

(3) develops procedures to ensure increased oversight of imported products of new importers, including new nonresident importers, by Centers of Excellence and Expertise established under section 4317 of this title; and

(4) establishes a centralized database of new importers, including new nonresident importers, to ensure accuracy of information that is required to be provided by such importers to U.S. Customs and Border Protection.


(c) Exclusion of certain importersThis section shall not apply to an importer that is a validated Tier 2 or Tier 3 participant in the Customs–Trade Partnership Against Terrorism program established under subtitle B of title II of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 (6 U.S.C. 961 et seq.).


(d) ReportNot later than the date that is 2 years after February 24, 2016, the Inspector General of the Department of the Tre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than the date that is 180 days after February 24, 2016, the Commissioner shall establish a program that directs U.S. Customs and Border Protection to adjust bond amounts for importers, including new importers and nonresident importers, based on risk assessments of such importers conducted by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, in order to protect the revenue of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements The Commissioner shall ensure that, as part of the program established under subsection (a), U.S. Customs and Border Protection—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4321_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of certain importers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusion of certain importers This section shall not apply to an importer that is a validated Tier 2 or Tier 3 participant in the Customs–Trade Partnership Against Terrorism program established under subtitle B of title II of the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 (6 U.S.C. 961 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4321_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than the date that is 2 years after February 24, 2016, the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives a report detailing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4321_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>