<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4332" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4332/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4332/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4332"><akn:num>4332</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint import safety rapid response plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4332. Joint import safety rapid response plan(a) In generalNot later than December 31, 2016, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the interagency Import Safety Working Group established under section 4331 of this title, shall develop a plan (to be known as the “joint import safety rapid response plan”) that sets forth protocols and defines practices for U.S. Customs and Border Protection to use—(1) in taking action in response to, and coordinating Federal responses to, an incident in which cargo destined for or merchandise entering the United States has been identified as posing a threat to the health or safety of consumers in the United States; and

(2) in recovering from or mitigating the effects of actions and responses to an incident described in paragraph (1).


(b) ContentsThe joint import safety rapid response plan shall address—(1) the statutory and regulatory authorities and responsibilities of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and other Federal agencies in responding to an incident described in subsection (a)(1);

(2) the protocols and practices to be used by U.S. Customs and Border Protection when taking action in response to, and coordinating Federal responses to, such an incident;

(3) the measures to be taken by U.S. Customs and Border Protection and other Federal agencies in recovering from or mitigating the effects of actions taken in response to such an incident after the incident to ensure the resumption of the entry of merchandise into the United States; and

(4) exercises that U.S. Customs and Border Protection may conduct in conjunction with Federal, State, and local agencies, and private sector entities, to simulate responses to such an incident.


(c) Updates of planThe Secretary of Homeland Security shall review and update the joint import safety rapid response plan, as appropriate, after conducting exercises under subsection (d).


(d) Import health and safety exercises(1) In generalThe Secretary of Homeland Security a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4332_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than December 31, 2016, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the interagency Import Safety Working Group established under section 4331 of this title, shall develop a plan (to be known as the “joint import safety rapid response plan”) that sets forth protocols and defines practices for U.S. Customs and Border Protection to use—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4332_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents The joint import safety rapid response plan shall address—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4332_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Updates of plan The Secretary of Homeland Security shall review and update the joint import safety rapid response plan, as appropriate, after conducting exercises under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4332_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Import health and safety exercises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Import health and safety exercises</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>