<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4344" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4344/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4344/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4344"><akn:num>4344</akn:num><akn:heading>National Intellectual Property Rights Coordination Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4344. National Intellectual Property Rights Coordination Center(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary of Homeland Security shall—(1) establish within U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement a National Intellectual Property Rights Coordination Center; and

(2) appoint an Assistant Director to head the National Intellectual Property Rights Coordination Center.


(b) DutiesThe Assistant Director of the National Intellectual Property Rights Coordination Center shall—(1) coordinate the investigation of sources of merchandise that infringe intellectual property rights to identify organizations and individuals that produce, smuggle, or distribute such merchandise;

(2) conduct and coordinate training with other domestic and international law enforcement agencies on investigative best practices—(A) to develop and expand the capability of such agencies to enforce intellectual property rights; and

(B) to develop metrics to assess whether the training improved enforcement of intellectual property rights;


(3) coordinate, with U.S. Customs and Border Protection, activities conducted by the United States to prevent the importation or exportation of merchandise that infringes intellectual property rights;

(4) support the international interdiction of merchandise destined for the United States that infringes intellectual property rights;

(5) collect and integrate information regarding infringement of intellectual property rights from domestic and international law enforcement agencies and other non-Federal sources;

(6) develop a means to receive and organize information regarding infringement of intellectual property rights from such agencies and other sources;

(7) disseminate information regarding infringement of intellectual property rights to other Federal agencies, as appropriate;

(8) develop and implement risk-based alert systems, in coordination with U.S. Customs and Border Protection, to improve the targeting of persons that repeatedly infringe intellectual property right</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4344_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4344_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Assistant Director of the National Intellectual Property Rights Coordination Center shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4344_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination with other agencies In carrying out the duties described in subsection (b), the Assistant Director of the National Intellectual Property Rights Coordination Center shall coordinate with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4344_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private sector outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Private sector outreach</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>