<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4401"><akn:num>4401</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of interest in certain distributions of antidumping duties and countervailing duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4401. Inclusion of interest in certain distributions of antidumping duties and countervailing duties(a) In generalThe Secretary of Homeland Security shall deposit all interest described in subsection (c) into the special account established under section 1675c(e) of this title (repealed by subtitle F of title VII of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 (Public Law 109–171; 120 Stat. 154)) for inclusion in distributions described in subsection (b) made on or after February 24, 2016.


(b) Distributions describedDistributions described in this subsection are distributions of antidumping duties and countervailing duties assessed on or after October 1, 2000, that are made under section 1675c of this title (repealed by subtitle F of title VII of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 (Public Law 109–171; 120 Stat. 154)), with respect to entries of merchandise that—(1) were made on or before September 30, 2007; and

(2) were, in accordance with section 822 of the Claims Resolution Act of 2010 (19 U.S.C. 1675c note), unliquidated, not in litigation, and not under an order of liquidation from the Department of Commerce on December 8, 2010.


(c) Interest described(1) Interest realizedInterest described in this subsection is interest earned on antidumping duties or countervailing duties described in subsection (b) that is realized through application of a payment received on or after October 1, 2014, by U.S. Customs and Border Protection under, or in connection with—(A) a customs bond pursuant to a court order or judgment; or

(B) a settlement with respect to a customs bond, including any payment made to U.S. Customs and Border Protection with respect to that bond by a surety.


(2) Types of interestInterest described in paragraph (1) includes the following:(A) Interest accrued under section 1677g of this title.

(B) Interest accrued under section 1505(d) of this title.

(C) Equitable interest under common law and interest under section 580 of this title awarded by a court against</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Homeland Security shall deposit all interest described in subsection (c) into the special account established under section 1675c(e) of this title (repealed by subtitle F of title VII of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 (Public Law 109–171; 120 Stat. 154)) for inclusion in distributions described in subsection (b) made on or after February 24, 2016.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Distributions described Distributions described in this subsection are distributions of antidumping duties and countervailing duties assessed on or after October 1, 2000, that are made under section 1675c of this title (repealed by subtitle F of title VII of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 (Public Law 109–171; 120 Stat. 154)), with respect to entries of merchandise that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interest described</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4401_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>