<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4405" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4405/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4405/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4405"><akn:num>4405</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade Enforcement Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4405. Trade Enforcement Trust Fund(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the Trade Enforcement Trust Fund (in this section referred to as the “Trust Fund”), consisting of amounts transferred to the Trust Fund under subsection (b) and any amounts that may be credited to the Trust Fund under subsection (c).


(b) Transfer of amounts(1) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Trust Fund, from the general fund of the Treasury, for each fiscal year that begins on or after February 24, 2016, through fiscal year 2026, an amount equal to $15,000,000 (or a lesser amount as required pursuant to paragraph (2)).


(2) LimitationThe total amount in the Trust Fund at any time may not exceed $30,000,000.


(3) Frequency of transfersThe Secretary shall transfer amounts required to be transferred to the Trust Fund under paragraph (1) not less frequently than quarterly from the general fund of the Treasury to the Trust Fund in a manner that ensures that the total amount in the Trust Fund at the end of the quarter does not exceed the limitation established under paragraph (2).



(c) Investment of amounts(1) Investment of amountsThe Secretary shall invest such portion of the Trust Fund as is not required to meet current withdrawals in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States.


(2) Interest and proceedsThe interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Trust Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Trust Fund.



(d) Availability of amounts from Trust Fund(1) In generalThe United States Trade Representative shall, on the basis of the advice of the Trade Policy Committee and relevant subordinate bodies of the TPC, use or transfer for the use by Federal agencies represented on the TPC amounts in the Trust Fund, only as provided by appropriations Acts, for mak</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4405_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the Trade Enforcement Trust Fund (in this section referred to as the “Trust Fund”), consisting of amounts transferred to the Trust Fund under subsection (b) and any amounts that may be credited to the Trust Fund under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4405_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4405_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Investment of amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4405_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of amounts from Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of amounts from Trust Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4405_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report Not later than 18 months after the entry into force of any free trade agreement entered into after February 24, 2016, the United States Trade Representative, in consultation with the Federal agencies represented on the TPC, shall submit to Congress a report on the actions taken under subsection (d) in connection with that agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4405_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comptroller General study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Comptroller General study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4405_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>