<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4433" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4433/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4433/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4433"><akn:num>4433</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification and certification to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4433. Notification and certification to Congress(a) Initial notificationNot later than 60 days before an agreement with the government of a foreign country to establish U.S. Customs and Border Protection preclearance operations in such foreign country enters into force, the Secretary shall provide the appropriate congressional committees with—(1) a copy of the agreement to establish such preclearance operations, which shall include—(A) the identification of the foreign country with which U.S. Customs and Border Protection intends to enter into a preclearance agreement;

(B) the location at which such preclearance operations will be conducted; and

(C) the terms and conditions for U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel operating at the location;


(2) an assessment of the impact such preclearance operations will have on legitimate trade and travel, including potential impacts on passengers traveling to the United States;

(3) an assessment of the impacts such preclearance operations will have on U.S. Customs and Border Protection domestic port of entry staffing;

(4) country-specific information on the anticipated homeland security benefits associated with establishing such preclearance operations;

(5) information on potential security vulnerabilities associated with commencing such preclearance operations and mitigation plans to address such potential security vulnerabilities;

(6) a U.S. Customs and Border Protection staffing model for such preclearance operations and plans for how such positions would be filled; and

(7) information on the anticipated costs over the 5 fiscal years after the agreement enters into force associated with commencing such preclearance operations.


(b) Further notification relating to preclearance operations established at airportsNot later than 45 days before an agreement with the government of a foreign country to establish U.S. Customs and Border Protection preclearance operations at an airport in such country enters into fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4433_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Initial notification Not later than 60 days before an agreement with the government of a foreign country to establish U.S. Customs and Border Protection preclearance operations in such foreign country enters into force, the Secretary shall provide the appropriate congressional committees with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4433_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Further notification relating to preclearance operations established at airports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Further notification relating to preclearance operations established at airports Not later than 45 days before an agreement with the government of a foreign country to establish U.S. Customs and Border Protection preclearance operations at an airport in such country enters into force, the Secretary, in addition to complying with the notification requirements under subsection (a), shall provide the appropriate congressional committees with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4433_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certifications relating to preclearance operations established at airports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certifications relating to preclearance operations established at airports Not later than 60 days before an agreement with the government of a foreign country to establish U.S. Customs and Border Protection preclearance operations at an airport in such country enters into force, the Secretary, in addition to complying with the notification requirements under subsections (a) and (b), shall provide the appropriate congressional committees with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4433_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of existing agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amendment of existing agreements Not later than 30 days before a substantially amended preclearance agreement with the government of a foreign country in effect as of February 24, 2016, enters into force, the Secretary shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4433_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Implementation plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4433_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classified report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Classified report The report required under subsection (c)(5) may be submitted in classified form if the Secretary determines that such form is appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>