<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4451" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4451/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4451/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4451"><akn:num>4451</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on certain U.S. Customs and Border Protection agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4451. Report on certain U.S. Customs and Border Protection agreements(a) In generalNot later than one year after entering into an agreement under a program specified in subsection (b), and annually thereafter until the termination of the program, the Commissioner shall submit to the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:(1) A description of the development of the program, including an identification of the authority under which the program operates.

(2) A description of the type of entity with which U.S. Customs and Border Protection entered into the agreement and the amount that entity reimbursed U.S. Customs and Border Protection under the agreement.

(3) An identification of the type of port of entry to which the agreement relates and an assessment of how the agreement provides economic benefits and security benefits (if applicable) at the port of entry.

(4) A description of the services provided by U.S. Customs and Border Protection under the agreement during the year preceding the submission of the report.

(5) The amount of fees collected under the agreement during that year.

(6) The total operating expenses of the program during that year.

(7) A detailed accounting of how the fees collected under the agreement have been spent during that year.

(8) A summary of any complaints or criticism received by U.S. Customs and Border Protection during that year regarding the agreement.

(9) An assessment of the compliance of the entity described in paragraph (2) with the terms of the agreement.

(10) Recommendations with respect to how activities conducted pursuant to the agreement could function more effectively or better produce economic benefits and security benefits (if applicable).

(11) A summary of the benefits to and challenges faced by U.S. Customs and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4451_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than one year after entering into an agreement under a program specified in subsection (b), and annually thereafter until the termination of the program, the Commissioner shall submit to the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4451_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program specified</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program specified A program specified in this subsection is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>