<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4454" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4454/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4454/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4454"><akn:num>4454</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade preferences for Nepal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4454. Trade preferences for Nepal(a) FindingsCongress makes the following findings:(1) Nepal is among the least developed countries in the world, with a per capita gross national income of $730 in 2014.

(2) Nepal suffered a devastating earthquake in April 2015, with subsequent aftershocks. More than 9,000 people died and approximately 23,000 people were injured.


(b) Eligibility requirements(1) In generalThe President may authorize the provision of preferential treatment under this section to articles that are imported directly from Nepal into the customs territory of the United States pursuant to subsection (c) if the President determines—(A) that Nepal meets the requirements set forth in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 3703(a) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title; and

(B) after taking into account the factors set forth in paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (c) of section 502 of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2462), that Nepal meets the eligibility requirements of such section 502.


(2) Withdrawal, suspension, or limitation of preferential treatment; mandatory graduationThe provisions of subsections (d) and (e) of section 502 of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2462) shall apply with respect to Nepal to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to beneficiary developing countries under title V of that Act (19 U.S.C. 2461 et seq.).



(c) Eligible articles(1) In generalAn article described in paragraph (2) may enter the customs territory of the United States free of duty.


(2) Articles described(A) In generalAn article is described in this paragraph if—(i)(I) the article is the growth, product, or manufacture of Nepal; and

(II) in the case of a textile or apparel article, Nepal is the country of origin of the article, as determined under section 102.21 of title 19, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the day before February 24, 2016);


(ii) the article is imported directly from Nepal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4454_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings Congress makes the following findings:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4454_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4454_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible articles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible articles</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4454_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade facilitation and capacity building</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Trade facilitation and capacity building</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4454_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporting requirement Not later than one year after February 24, 2016, and annually thereafter, the President shall monitor, review, and report to Congress on the implementation of this section, the compliance of Nepal with subsection (b)(1), and the trade and investment policy of the United States with respect to Nepal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4454_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of preferential treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Termination of preferential treatment No preferential treatment extended under this section shall remain in effect after December 31, 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4454_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effective date The provisions of this section shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after February 24, 2016.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>