<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4502"><akn:num>4502</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4502. Definitions
In this Act:(1) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.


(2) HTSThe term “HTS” means the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.


(3) Identical goodsThe term “identical goods” means goods that are the same in all respects relevant to the rule of origin that qualifies the goods as originating goods.


(4) International Trade CommissionThe term “International Trade Commission” means the United States International Trade Commission.


(5) MexicoThe term “Mexico” means the United Mexican States.


(6) NAFTAThe term “NAFTA” means the North American Free Trade Agreement approved by Congress under section 101(a)(1) of the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (19 U.S.C. 3311(a)(1)).11 See References in Text note below.


(7) Preferential tariff treatmentThe term “preferential tariff treatment” means the customs duty rate that is applicable to an originating good (as defined in section 4531(a) of this title) under the USMCA.


(8) Trade RepresentativeThe term “Trade Representative” means the United States Trade Representative.


(9) USMCAThe term “USMCA” means the Agreement between the United States of America, the United Mexican States, and Canada, which is—(A) attached as an Annex to the Protocol Replacing the North American Free Trade Agreement with the Agreement between the United States of America, the United Mexican States, and Canada, done at Buenos Aires on November 30, 2018, as amended by the Protocol of Amendment to the Agreement Between the United States of America, the United Mexican States, and Canada, done at Mexico City on December 10, 2019; and

(B) approved by Congress under section 4511(a)(1) of this title.


(10) USMCA countryExcept as otherwise provided, the term “USMCA country” means—(A) Canada for such time as the USMCA is in force with respect to, a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>HTS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) HTS The term “HTS” means the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identical goods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Identical goods The term “identical goods” means goods that are the same in all respects relevant to the rule of origin that qualifies the goods as originating goods.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Trade Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) International Trade Commission The term “International Trade Commission” means the United States International Trade Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mexico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Mexico The term “Mexico” means the United Mexican States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>NAFTA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) NAFTA The term “NAFTA” means the North American Free Trade Agreement approved by Congress under section 101(a)(1) of the North American Free Trade Agreement Implementation Act (19 U.S.C. 3311(a)(1)).11 See References in Text note below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferential tariff treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Preferential tariff treatment The term “preferential tariff treatment” means the customs duty rate that is applicable to an originating good (as defined in section 4531(a) of this title) under the USMCA.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade Representative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Trade Representative The term “Trade Representative” means the United States Trade Representative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>USMCA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) USMCA The term “USMCA” means the Agreement between the United States of America, the United Mexican States, and Canada, which is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>USMCA country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) USMCA country Except as otherwise provided, the term “USMCA country” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>