<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4531" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4531/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4531/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4531"><akn:num>4531</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of origin</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4531. Rules of origin(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) AquacultureThe term “aquaculture” means the farming of aquatic organisms, including fish, molluscs, crustaceans, other aquatic invertebrates, and aquatic plants from seed stock such as eggs, fry, fingerlings, or larvae, by intervention in the rearing or growth processes to enhance production such as regular stocking, feeding, or protection from predators.


(2) Customs Valuation AgreementThe term “Customs Valuation Agreement” means the Agreement on Implementation of Article VII of the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade 1994 referred to in section 3511(d)(8) of this title.


(3) Fungible good or fungible materialThe term “fungible good” or “fungible material” means a good or material, as the case may be, that is interchangeable with another good or material for commercial purposes and the properties of which are essentially identical to such other good or material.


(4) Good wholly obtained or produced entirely in the territory of one or more USMCA countriesThe term “good wholly obtained or produced entirely in the territory of one or more USMCA countries” means any of the following:(A) A mineral good or other naturally occurring substance extracted or taken from the territory of one or more USMCA countries.

(B) A plant, plant good, vegetable, or fungus grown, cultivated, harvested, picked, or gathered in the territory of one or more USMCA countries.

(C) A live animal born and raised in the territory of one or more USMCA countries.

(D) A good obtained in the territory of one or more USMCA countries from a live animal.

(E) An animal obtained by hunting, trapping, fishing, gathering, or capturing in the territory of one or more USMCA countries.

(F) A good obtained in the territory of one or more USMCA countries from aquaculture.

(G) A fish, shellfish, or other marine life taken from the sea, seabed, or subsoil outside the territory of one or more USMCA countries and outside the territorial sea of any </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application and interpretation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application and interpretation In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Originating goods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Originating goods</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional value content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regional value content</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accumulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Accumulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>De minimis amounts of nonoriginating materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) De minimis amounts of nonoriginating materials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fungible goods and materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fungible goods and materials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accessories, spare parts, tools, and instructional or other information materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Accessories, spare parts, tools, and instructional or other information materials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Packaging materials and containers for retail sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Packaging materials and containers for retail sale Packaging materials and containers in which a good is packaged for retail sale, if classified with the good, shall be disregarded in determining whether all of the nonoriginating materials used in the production of the good undergo the applicable process or change in tariff classification requirement set forth in Annex 4–B of the USMCA, or whether the good is a good wholly obtained or produced entirely in the territory of one or more USMCA countries. If the good is subject to a regional value content requirement set forth in that Annex, the value of such packaging materials and containers shall be taken into account as originating or nonoriginating materials, as the case may be, in calculating the regional value content of the good.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4531_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Packing materials and containers for shipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Packing materials and containers for shipment Packing materials and containers for shipment shall be disregarded in determining whether a good is an originating good.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>