<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4533" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4533/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4533/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4533"><akn:num>4533</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions regarding verification of claims under the USMCA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4533. Actions regarding verification of claims under the USMCA(a) Verification(1) Origin verification(A) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury may, pursuant to article 5.9 of the USMCA, conduct a verification of whether a good is an originating good under section 4531 or 4532 of this title.


(B) Additional requirementsIf the Secretary conducts a verification under subparagraph (A), the President may direct the Secretary—(i) during the verification process, to release the good only upon payment of duties or provision of security; and

(ii) if the Secretary makes a negative determination under subsection (b), to take action under subsection (c).



(2) Textile and apparel goods(A) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury may, pursuant to article 6.6 of the USMCA, conduct a verification described in subparagraph (C) with respect to a textile or apparel good.


(B) Additional requirementsIf the Secretary conducts a verification under subparagraph (A) with respect to a textile or apparel good, the President may direct the Secretary—(i) during the verification process, to take appropriate action described in subparagraph (D); and

(ii) if the Secretary makes a negative determination described in subsection (b), to take action under subsection (c).


(C) Verification describedA verification described in this subparagraph with respect to a textile or apparel good is—(i) a verification of whether the good qualifies for preferential tariff treatment under the USMCA; or

(ii) a verification of whether customs offenses are occurring or have occurred with respect to the good.


(D) Action during verificationAppropriate action described in this subparagraph may consist of—(i) release of the textile or apparel good that is the subject of a verification described in subparagraph (C) upon payment of duties or provision of security;

(ii) suspension of preferential tariff treatment under the USMCA with respect to—(I) the textile or apparel good that is the subject of a verificati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4533_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Verification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4533_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negative determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Negative determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4533_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action based on determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Action based on determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4533_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of circumvention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prevention of circumvention In making a determination under this section, including whether to accept or reject a claim for preferential tariff treatment under the USMCA, the Secretary shall interpret the requirements of this section in a manner to avoid and prevent circumvention of those requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>