<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4552" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4552/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4552/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4552"><akn:num>4552</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential action regarding USMCA imports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4552. Presidential action regarding USMCA imports(a) In generalIn determining whether to take action under chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2251 et seq.] with respect to imports from a USMCA country, the President shall determine whether—(1) imports from such country, considered individually, account for a substantial share of total imports; or

(2) imports from a USMCA country, considered individually, or in exceptional circumstances imports from USMCA countries considered collectively, contribute importantly to the serious injury, or threat thereof, found by the International Trade Commission.


(b) Exclusion of USMCA importsIn determining the nature and extent of action to be taken under chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2251 et seq.], the President shall exclude from such action imports from a USMCA country if the President makes a negative determination under subsection (a)(1) or (2) with respect to imports from such country.


(c) Action after exclusion of USMCA country imports(1) In generalIf the President, under subsection (b), excludes imports from a USMCA country or countries from action under chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2251 et seq.] but thereafter determines that a surge in imports from that country or countries is undermining the effectiveness of the action—(A) the President may take appropriate action under such chapter 1 to include those imports in the action; and

(B) any entity that is representative of an industry for which such action is being taken may request the International Trade Commission to conduct an investigation of the surge in such imports.


(2) InvestigationUpon receiving a request under paragraph (1)(B), the International Trade Commission shall conduct an investigation to determine whether a surge in such imports undermines the effectiveness of the action. The International Trade Commission shall submit the findings of its investigation to the President</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4552_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In determining whether to take action under chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2251 et seq.] with respect to imports from a USMCA country, the President shall determine whether—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4552_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of USMCA imports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exclusion of USMCA imports In determining the nature and extent of action to be taken under chapter 1 of title II of the Trade Act of 1974 [19 U.S.C. 2251 et seq.], the President shall exclude from such action imports from a USMCA country if the President makes a negative determination under subsection (a)(1) or (2) with respect to imports from such country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4552_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action after exclusion of USMCA country imports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Action after exclusion of USMCA country imports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4552_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Condition applicable to quantitative restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Condition applicable to quantitative restrictions Any action taken under this section proclaiming a quantitative restriction shall permit the importation of a quantity or value of the article which is not less than the quantity or value of such article imported into the United States during the most recent period that is representative of imports of such article, with allowance for reasonable growth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>