<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4571" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4571/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4571/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4571"><akn:num>4571</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4571. Definitions
In this part:(1) Border commercial zoneThe term “border commercial zone” means—(A) the area of United States territory of the municipalities along the United States-Mexico international border and the commercial zones of such municipalities as described in subpart B of part 372 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations; and

(B) any additional border crossing and associated commercial zones listed in the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration OP–2 application instructions or successor documents.


(2) Cargo originating in MexicoThe term “cargo originating in Mexico” means any cargo that enters the United States by commercial motor vehicle from Mexico, including cargo that may have originated in a country other than Mexico.


(3) Change in circumstancesThe term “change in circumstance” may include a substantial increase in services supplied by the grantee of a grant of authority.


(4) Commercial motor vehicleThe term “commercial motor vehicle” means a commercial motor vehicle, as such term is defined in paragraph (1) of section 31132 of title 49, that meets the requirements of subparagraph (A) of such paragraph.


(5) Cross-border long-haul trucking servicesThe term “cross-border long-haul trucking services” means—(A) the transportation by commercial motor vehicle of cargo originating in Mexico to a point in the United States outside of a border commercial zone; or

(B) the transportation by commercial motor vehicle of cargo originating in the United States from a point in the United States outside of a border commercial zone to a point in a border commercial zone or a point in Mexico.


(6) DriverThe term “driver” means a person that drives a commercial motor vehicle in cross-border long-haul trucking services.


(7) Grant of authorityThe term “grant of authority” means registration granted pursuant to section 13902 of title 49, or a successor provision, to persons of Mexico to conduct cross-border long-haul trucking services in the United S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Border commercial zone</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Border commercial zone The term “border commercial zone” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cargo originating in Mexico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Cargo originating in Mexico The term “cargo originating in Mexico” means any cargo that enters the United States by commercial motor vehicle from Mexico, including cargo that may have originated in a country other than Mexico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change in circumstances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Change in circumstances The term “change in circumstance” may include a substantial increase in services supplied by the grantee of a grant of authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial motor vehicle</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Commercial motor vehicle The term “commercial motor vehicle” means a commercial motor vehicle, as such term is defined in paragraph (1) of section 31132 of title 49, that meets the requirements of subparagraph (A) of such paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross-border long-haul trucking services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Cross-border long-haul trucking services The term “cross-border long-haul trucking services” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Driver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Driver The term “driver” means a person that drives a commercial motor vehicle in cross-border long-haul trucking services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Grant of authority The term “grant of authority” means registration granted pursuant to section 13902 of title 49, or a successor provision, to persons of Mexico to conduct cross-border long-haul trucking services in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interested party</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Interested party The term “interested party” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Material harm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Material harm The term “material harm” means a significant loss in the share of the United States market or relevant sub-market for cross-border long-haul trucking services held by persons of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4571_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operator or supplier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Operator or supplier The term “operator” or “supplier” means an entity that has been granted registration under section 13902 of title 49 to provide cross-border long-haul trucking services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>