<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4574" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4574/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4574/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4574"><akn:num>4574</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by President with respect to affirmative determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4574. Action by President with respect to affirmative determination(a) In generalNot later than the date that is 30 days after the date on which the President receives a report of the Commission in which the Commission’s determination under section 4572 of this title is affirmative or which contains a determination that the President may treat as affirmative in accordance with section 1330(d)(1) of this title—(1) the President shall, subject to subsection (b), issue an order to the Secretary of Transportation specifying the relief to be provided, consistent with subsection (c), and directing the relief to be carried out; and

(2) the Secretary of Transportation shall carry out such relief.


(b) ExceptionThe President is not required to provide relief under this section if the President determines that provision of such relief—(1) is not in the national economic interest of the United States; or

(2) would cause serious harm to the national security of the United States.


(c) Nature of relief(1) In generalThe relief the President is authorized to provide under this subsection is as follows:(A)(i) With respect to a determination relating to an investigation under section 4572(a)(1) of this title, the denial or imposition of limitations on a request for a new grant of authority by the persons of Mexico that are the subject of the investigation.

(ii) With respect to a determination relating to an investigation under section 4572(a)(1) of this title, the revocation of, or restrictions on, grants of authority issued to the persons of Mexico that are the subject of the investigation since the date of the petition, request, or resolution.


(B) With respect to a determination relating to an investigation under section 4572(a)(2) or (3) of this title, the revocation or imposition of limitations on an existing grant of authority by the persons of Mexico that are the subject of the investigation.

(C) With respect to a determination relating to an investigation under sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4574_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than the date that is 30 days after the date on which the President receives a report of the Commission in which the Commission’s determination under section 4572 of this title is affirmative or which contains a determination that the President may treat as affirmative in accordance with section 1330(d)(1) of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4574_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception The President is not required to provide relief under this section if the President determines that provision of such relief—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4574_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nature of relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nature of relief</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4574_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Period of relief</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4574_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Commission and the Secretary of Transportation are authorized to promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>