<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4584" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4584/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4584/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4584"><akn:num>4584</akn:num><akn:heading>Requests for review of determinations by competent investigating authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4584. Requests for review of determinations by competent investigating authorities(a) DefinitionsAs used in this section:(1) Competent investigating authorityThe term “competent investigating authority” means the competent investigating authority, as defined in article 10.8, of a USMCA country.


(2) United States SecretaryThe term “United States Secretary” means that officer of the United States referred to in article 10.16.



(b) Requests for review by United StatesIn the case of a final determination of a competent investigating authority, requests by the United States for binational panel review of such determination under article 10.12 shall be made by the United States Secretary.


(c) Requests for review by personIn the case of a final determination of a competent investigating authority, a person, within the meaning of paragraph 5 of article 10.12, may request a binational panel review of such determination by filing such a request with the United States Secretary within the time limit provided for in paragraph 4 of article 10.12. The receipt of such request by the United States Secretary shall be deemed to be a request for binational panel review within the meaning of article 10.12. The request for such panel review shall be without prejudice to any challenge before a binational panel of the basis for a particular request for review.


(d) Service of request for reviewWhenever binational panel review of a final determination made by a competent investigating authority is requested under this section, the United States Secretary shall serve a copy of the request on all persons who would otherwise be entitled under the law of the importing country to commence proceedings for judicial review of the determination.


(Pub. L. 116–113, title IV, § 414, formerly Pub. L. 103–182, title IV, § 404, Dec. 8, 1993, 107 Stat. 2137; renumbered § 414 of Pub. L. 116–113 and amended Pub. L. 116–113, title V, § 504(e), Jan. 29, 2020, 134 Stat. 75.)

Editorial Notes
Codific</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4584_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4584_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requests for review by United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requests for review by United States In the case of a final determination of a competent investigating authority, requests by the United States for binational panel review of such determination under article 10.12 shall be made by the United States Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4584_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requests for review by person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requests for review by person In the case of a final determination of a competent investigating authority, a person, within the meaning of paragraph 5 of article 10.12, may request a binational panel review of such determination by filing such a request with the United States Secretary within the time limit provided for in paragraph 4 of article 10.12. The receipt of such request by the United States Secretary shall be deemed to be a request for binational panel review within the meaning of article 10.12. The request for such panel review shall be without prejudice to any challenge before a binational panel of the basis for a particular request for review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4584_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of request for review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Service of request for review Whenever binational panel review of a final determination made by a competent investigating authority is requested under this section, the United States Secretary shall serve a copy of the request on all persons who would otherwise be entitled under the law of the importing country to commence proceedings for judicial review of the determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>