<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4585" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4585/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4585/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4585"><akn:num>4585</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of procedure for panels and committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4585. Rules of procedure for panels and committees(a) Rules of procedure for binational panelsThe administering authority shall prescribe rules, negotiated in accordance with paragraph 14 of article 10.12, governing, with respect to binational panel reviews—(1) requests for such reviews, complaints, other pleadings, and other papers;

(2) the amendment, filing, and service of such pleadings and papers;

(3) the joinder, suspension, and termination of such reviews; and

(4) other appropriate procedural matters.


(b) Rules of procedure for extraordinary challenge committeesThe administering authority shall prescribe rules, negotiated in accordance with paragraph 2 of Annex 10–B.3, governing the procedures for reviews by extraordinary challenge committees.


(c) Rules of procedure for safeguarding panel review systemThe administering authority shall prescribe rules, negotiated in accordance with Annex 10–B.4, governing the procedures for special committees described in such Annex.


(d) Publication of rulesThe rules prescribed under subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall be published in the Federal Register.


(e) Administering authorityAs used in this section, the term “administering authority” has the meaning given such term in section 1677(1) of this title.


(Pub. L. 116–113, title IV, § 415, formerly Pub. L. 103–182, title IV, § 405, Dec. 8, 1993, 107 Stat. 2137; renumbered § 415 of Pub. L. 116–113 and amended Pub. L. 116–113, title V, § 504(f), Jan. 29, 2020, 134 Stat. 75.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 3435 of this title prior to renumbering by Pub. L. 116–113.

Amendments2020—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 116–113, § 504(f)(3)(A), substituted “article 10.12” for “article 1904” in introductory provisions.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 116–113, § 504(f)(3)(B), substituted “Annex 10–B.3” for “Annex 1904.13”.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 116–113, § 504(f)(3)(C), substituted “Annex 10–B.4” for “Annex 1905.6”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4585_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of procedure for binational panels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules of procedure for binational panels The administering authority shall prescribe rules, negotiated in accordance with paragraph 14 of article 10.12, governing, with respect to binational panel reviews—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4585_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of procedure for extraordinary challenge committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rules of procedure for extraordinary challenge committees The administering authority shall prescribe rules, negotiated in accordance with paragraph 2 of Annex 10–B.3, governing the procedures for reviews by extraordinary challenge committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4585_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of procedure for safeguarding panel review system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rules of procedure for safeguarding panel review system The administering authority shall prescribe rules, negotiated in accordance with Annex 10–B.4, governing the procedures for special committees described in such Annex.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4585_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publication of rules The rules prescribed under subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall be published in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4585_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administering authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administering authority As used in this section, the term “administering authority” has the meaning given such term in section 1677(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>