<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4587" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4587/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4587/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4587"><akn:num>4587</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of industries facing subsidized imports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4587. Identification of industries facing subsidized imports(a) PetitionsAny entity, including a trade association, firm, certified or recognized union, or group of workers, that is representative of a United States industry and has reason to believe—(1) that—(A) as a result of implementation of provisions of the USMCA, the industry is likely to face increased competition from subsidized imports, from a USMCA country, with which it directly competes; or

(B) the industry is likely to face increased competition from subsidized imports with which it directly competes from any other country designated by the President, following consultations with the Congress, as benefiting from a reduction of tariffs or other trade barriers under a trade agreement that enters into force with respect to the United States after January 1, 1994; and


(2) that the industry is likely to experience a deterioration of its competitive position before more effective rules and disciplines relating to the use of government subsidies have been developed with respect to the country concerned;


may file with the Trade Representative a petition that such industry be identified under this section.

(b) Identification of industryWithin 90 days after receipt of a petition under subsection (a), the Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall decide whether to identify the industry on the basis that there is a reasonable likelihood that the industry may face both the subsidization described in subsection (a)(1) and the deterioration described in subsection (a)(2).


(c) Action after identificationAt the request of an entity that is representative of an industry identified under subsection (b), the Trade Representative shall—(1) compile and make available to the industry information under section 2418 of this title;

(2) recommend to the President that an investigation by the International Trade Commission be requested under section 332 of the Tariff Act of 1930 [19 U.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4587_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Petitions Any entity, including a trade association, firm, certified or recognized union, or group of workers, that is representative of a United States industry and has reason to believe— may file with the Trade Representative a petition that such industry be identified under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4587_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of industry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification of industry Within 90 days after receipt of a petition under subsection (a), the Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall decide whether to identify the industry on the basis that there is a reasonable likelihood that the industry may face both the subsidization described in subsection (a)(1) and the deterioration described in subsection (a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4587_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action after identification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Action after identification At the request of an entity that is representative of an industry identified under subsection (b), the Trade Representative shall— The industry may request the Trade Representative to take appropriate action to update (as often as annually) any information obtained under paragraph (1) or (2), or both, as the case may be, until an agreement on more effective rules and disciplines relating to government subsidies is reached between the United States and the USMCA countries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4587_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiation of action under other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Initiation of action under other law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4587_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of decisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect of decisions Any decision, whether positive or negative, or any action by the Trade Representative or the Secretary of Commerce under this section shall not in any way—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4587_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Standing Nothing in this section may be construed to alter in any manner the requirements in effect before January 29, 2020, for standing under any law of the United States or to add any additional requirements for standing under any law of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>