<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4621" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4621/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4621/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4621"><akn:num>4621</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of USMCA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4621. Termination of USMCA(a) Termination of USMCA country statusDuring any period in which a country ceases to be a USMCA country, this Act (other than this subsection and title IX) and the amendments made by this Act shall cease to have effect with respect to that country.


(b) Termination of USMCAOn the date on which the USMCA ceases to be in force with respect to the United States, this Act and the amendments made by this Act (other than this subsection and title IX) shall cease to have effect.


(Pub. L. 116–113, title VI, § 621, Jan. 29, 2020, 134 Stat. 80.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 116–113, Jan. 29, 2020, 134 Stat. 11, known as the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act. Title IX of the Act (134 Stat. 98) provides for USMCA supplemental appropriations and is not classified to the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 4501 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4621_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of USMCA country status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Termination of USMCA country status During any period in which a country ceases to be a USMCA country, this Act (other than this subsection and title IX) and the amendments made by this Act shall cease to have effect with respect to that country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4621_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of USMCA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Termination of USMCA On the date on which the USMCA ceases to be in force with respect to the United States, this Act and the amendments made by this Act (other than this subsection and title IX) shall cease to have effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>