<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4713" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4713/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4713/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4713"><akn:num>4713</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4713. Monitoring actions(a) In generalThe Interagency Environment Committee shall carry out monitoring actions, which shall include the monitoring actions described in subsections (b), (c), and (d), with respect to the implementation and maintenance of the environmental obligations of the USMCA countries.


(b) Review of CEC Secretariat submissions(1) In generalNot later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretariat of the Commission for Environmental Cooperation prepares a factual record under article 24.28 of the USMCA relating to a submission filed under article 24.27 of the USMCA with respect to a USMCA country, the Interagency Environment Committee—(A) shall review the factual record; and

(B) may, based on findings of the review under subparagraph (A) that the USMCA country is not in compliance with its environmental obligations, request enforcement actions under section 4714 of this title with respect to the USMCA country.


(2) Written justificationIf the Interagency Environment Committee finds that a USMCA country is not in compliance with its environmental obligations under paragraph (1)(B) and determines not to request enforcement actions under section 4714 of this title with respect to the USMCA country, the Committee shall, not later than 30 days after the date on which it makes the determination, provide to the appropriate congressional committees a written explanation and justification of the determination.



(c) Review of reports of United States environment attachés to MexicoThe Interagency Environment Committee shall—(1) review each report submitted to the Committee under section 4732(b)(2) of this title; and

(2) based on the findings of each such report, assess the efforts of Mexico to comply with its environmental obligations.


(d) United States implementation of Environment Cooperation and Customs Verification Agreement(1) Verification of shipmentsThe Interagency Environment Committee—(A) may request verification of particular shipm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Interagency Environment Committee shall carry out monitoring actions, which shall include the monitoring actions described in subsections (b), (c), and (d), with respect to the implementation and maintenance of the environmental obligations of the USMCA countries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of CEC Secretariat submissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review of CEC Secretariat submissions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of reports of United States environment attachés to Mexico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review of reports of United States environment attachés to Mexico The Interagency Environment Committee shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States implementation of Environment Cooperation and Customs Verification Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) United States implementation of Environment Cooperation and Customs Verification Agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application Subsections (c) and (d) shall apply with respect to Mexico for such time as the USMCA is in force with respect to, and the United States applies the USMCA to, Mexico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>