<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4731" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4731/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/4731/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4731"><akn:num>4731</akn:num><akn:heading>Border water infrastructure improvement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4731. Border water infrastructure improvement authority(a) In generalThe Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall, in coordination with eligible public entities, carry out the planning, design, construction, and operation and maintenance of high priority treatment works in the covered area to treat wastewater (including stormwater), nonpoint sources of pollution, and related matters resulting from international transboundary water flows originating in Mexico.


(b) Report to CongressNot later than 1 year after January 29, 2020, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on activities carried out pursuant to this section.


(c) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Covered areaThe term “covered area” means the portion of the Tijuana River watershed that is in the United States.


(2) Eligible public entitiesThe term “eligible public entities” means—(A) the United States Section of the International Boundary and Water Commission;

(B) the Corps of Engineers;

(C) the North American Development Bank;

(D) the Department of State;

(E) any other appropriate Federal agency;

(F) the State of California; and

(G) any of the following entities with jurisdiction over any part of the covered area:(i) A local government.

(ii) An Indian Tribe.

(iii) A regional water board.

(iv) A public wastewater utility.



(3) Treatment worksThe term “treatment works” has the meaning given that term in section 1292 of title 33.



(Pub. L. 116–113, title VIII, § 821, Jan. 29, 2020, 134 Stat. 95.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4731_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall, in coordination with eligible public entities, carry out the planning, design, construction, and operation and maintenance of high priority treatment works in the covered area to treat wastewater (including stormwater), nonpoint sources of pollution, and related matters resulting from international transboundary water flows originating in Mexico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4731_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report to Congress Not later than 1 year after January 29, 2020, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on activities carried out pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4731_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>