<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/58c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/58c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/58c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_58c"><akn:num>58c</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for certain customs services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 58c. Fees for certain customs services(a) Schedule of feesIn addition to any other fee authorized by law, the Secretary of the Treasury shall charge and collect the following fees (subject to adjustment under subsection (l)) for the provision of customs services in connection with the following:(1) For the arrival of a commercial vessel of 100 net tons or more, $397.

(2) For the arrival of a commercial truck, $5.

(3) For the arrival of each railroad car carrying passengers or commercial freight, $7.50.

(4) For all arrivals made during a calendar year by a private vessel or private aircraft, $25.

(5)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), for the arrival of each passenger aboard a commercial vessel or commercial aircraft from a place outside the United States (other than a place referred to in subsection (b)(1)(A)(i) of this section), $5.

(B) For the arrival of each passenger aboard a commercial vessel from a place referred to in subsection (b)(1)(A)(i) of this section, $1.75.


(6) For each item of dutiable mail for which a document is prepared by a customs officer (other than an item subject to a fee under subsection (b)(9)(D)), $5.

(7) For each customs broker permit held by an individual, partnership, association, or corporate customs broker, $125 per year.

(8) For the arrival of a barge or other bulk carrier from Canada or Mexico, $100.

(9)(A) For the processing of merchandise that is formally entered or released during any fiscal year, a fee in an amount equal to 0.21 11 See Rates for Merchandise Processing Fees notes below. percent ad valorem, unless adjusted under subparagraph (B).

(B)(i) The Secretary of the Treasury may adjust the ad valorem rate specified in subparagraph (A) to an ad valorem rate (but not to a rate of more than 0.21 1 percent nor less than 0.15 percent) and the amounts specified in subsection (b)(8)(A)(i) (but not to more than $485 nor less than $21) to rates and amounts which would, if charged, offset the salaries and expenses that wil</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Schedule of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Schedule of fees In addition to any other fee authorized by law, the Secretary of the Treasury shall charge and collect the following fees (subject to adjustment under subsection (l)) for the provision of customs services in connection with the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations on fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Collection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of customs services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Provision of customs services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disposition of fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations and enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effect on other authority Except with respect to customs services for which fees are imposed under subsection (a), nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to charge fees under section 58a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Effective dates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>