<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6"><akn:num>6</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of customs officers for foreign service; status; rejection of designated customs officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6. Designation of customs officers for foreign service; status; rejection of designated customs officer; applicability of civil service laws
Any officer of the customs service designated by the Secretary of the Treasury for foreign service, shall, through the Department of State, be regularly and officially attached to the diplomatic missions of the United States in the countries in which they are to be stationed, and when such officers are assigned to countries in which there are no diplomatic missions of the United States, appropriate recognition and standing with full facilities for discharging their official duties shall be arranged by the Department of State. The Secretary of State may reject the name of any such officer whose assignment to the foreign post for which he has been designated would, in his judgment, be prejudicial to the public policy of the United States. The appointment of such customs officers shall be made pursuant to the civil service laws and regulations upon the nomination of the principal officer in charge of the office to which such appointments are to be made.
(Mar. 4, 1923, ch. 251, § 2, 42 Stat. 1453; Jan. 13, 1925, ch. 76, 43 Stat. 748; May 28, 1926, ch. 411, § 1, 44 Stat. 669; June 17, 1930, ch. 497, title IV, §§ 518, 649, 46 Stat. 737, 762; June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 39, 62 Stat. 992; Pub. L. 91–271, title III, § 303, June 2, 1970, 84 Stat. 292.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1970—Pub. L. 91–271 struck out provisions authorizing Secretary of the Treasury to appoint, prescribe designations and duties, and fix compensation of deputies and other customs officers, laborers, and other employees.
1948—Act June 25, 1948, struck out fourth sentence relating to appointment and compensation of clerks of Customs Court.
1930—Act June 17, 1930, § 649, substituted “Treasury attachés” for “Customs attachés”.
Act June 17, 1930, § 518, authorized Secretary of the Treasury to appoint and fix compensation of clerks of Customs Court.
1926—Act May 28, 1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>