<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/81o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/81o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/19/81o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_81o"><akn:num>81o</akn:num><akn:heading>Residents of zone</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 81o. Residents of zone(a) Persons allowed to reside in zoneNo person shall be allowed to reside within the zone except Federal, State, or municipal officers or agents whose resident presence is deemed necessary by the Board.


(b) Rules and regulations for employees entering and leaving zoneThe Board shall prescribe rules and regulations regarding employees and other persons entering and leaving the zone. All rules and regulations concerning the protection of the revenue shall be approved by the Secretary of the Treasury.


(c) Exclusion from zone of goods or process of treatmentThe Board may at any time order the exclusion from the zone of any goods or process of treatment that in its judgment is detrimental to the public interest, health, or safety.


(d) Retail trade within zoneNo retail trade shall be conducted within the zone except under permits issued by the grantee and approved by the Board. Such permittees shall sell no goods except such domestic or duty-paid or duty-free goods as are brought into the zone from customs territory.


(e) Exemption from State and local ad valorem taxation of tangible personal propertyTangible personal property imported from outside the United States and held in a zone for the purpose of storage, sale, exhibition, repackaging, assembly, distribution, sorting, grading, cleaning, mixing, display, manufacturing, or processing, and tangible personal property produced in the United States and held in a zone for exportation, either in its original form or as altered by any of the above processes, shall be exempt from State and local ad valorem taxation.


(June 18, 1934, ch. 590, § 15, 48 Stat. 1002; Pub. L. 98–573, title II, § 231(b)(1), Oct. 30, 1984, 98 Stat. 2991.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1984—Subsec. (e). Pub. L. 98–573 added subsec. (e).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1984 AmendmentPub. L. 98–573, title II, § 231(b)(2), Oct. 30, 1984, 98 Stat. 2991, provided that: “The amendment made by paragra</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_81o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons allowed to reside in zone</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Persons allowed to reside in zone No person shall be allowed to reside within the zone except Federal, State, or municipal officers or agents whose resident presence is deemed necessary by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_81o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations for employees entering and leaving zone</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rules and regulations for employees entering and leaving zone The Board shall prescribe rules and regulations regarding employees and other persons entering and leaving the zone. All rules and regulations concerning the protection of the revenue shall be approved by the Secretary of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_81o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion from zone of goods or process of treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusion from zone of goods or process of treatment The Board may at any time order the exclusion from the zone of any goods or process of treatment that in its judgment is detrimental to the public interest, health, or safety.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_81o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retail trade within zone</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Retail trade within zone No retail trade shall be conducted within the zone except under permits issued by the grantee and approved by the Board. Such permittees shall sell no goods except such domestic or duty-paid or duty-free goods as are brought into the zone from customs territory.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_81o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from State and local ad valorem taxation of tangible personal property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemption from State and local ad valorem taxation of tangible personal property Tangible personal property imported from outside the United States and held in a zone for the purpose of storage, sale, exhibition, repackaging, assembly, distribution, sorting, grading, cleaning, mixing, display, manufacturing, or processing, and tangible personal property produced in the United States and held in a zone for exportation, either in its original form or as altered by any of the above processes, shall be exempt from State and local ad valorem taxation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>