<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_103"><akn:num>103</akn:num><akn:heading>National Highway System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 103. National Highway System(a) In General.—For the purposes of this title, the Federal-aid system is the National Highway System, which includes the Interstate System.

(b) National Highway System.—(1) Description.—The National Highway System consists of the highway routes and connections to transportation facilities that shall—(A) serve major population centers, international border crossings, ports, airports, public transportation facilities, and other intermodal transportation facilities and other major travel destinations;

(B) meet national defense requirements; and

(C) serve interstate and interregional travel and commerce.


(2) Components.—The National Highway System described in paragraph (1) consists of the following:(A) The National Highway System depicted on the map submitted by the Secretary of Transportation to Congress with the report entitled “Pulling Together: The National Highway System and its Connections to Major Intermodal Terminals” and dated May 24, 1996, and modifications approved by the Secretary before the date of enactment of the MAP–21.

(B) Other urban and rural principal arterial routes, and border crossings on those routes, that were not included on the National Highway System before the date of enactment of the MAP–21.

(C) Other connector highways (including toll facilities) that were not included in the National Highway System before the date of enactment of the MAP–21 but that provide motor vehicle access between arterial routes on the National Highway System and a major intermodal transportation facility.

(D) A strategic highway network that—(i) consists of a network of highways that are important to the United States strategic defense policy, that provide defense access, continuity, and emergency capabilities for the movement of personnel, materials, and equipment in both peacetime and wartime, and that were not included on the National Highway System before the date of enactment of the MAP–21;

(ii) may include highways on </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purposes of this title, the Federal-aid system is the National Highway System, which includes the Interstate System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Highway System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>