<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_106"><akn:num>106</akn:num><akn:heading>Project approval and oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 106. Project approval and oversight(a) In General.—(1) Submission of plans, specifications, and estimates.—Except as otherwise provided in this section, each State transportation department shall submit to the Secretary for approval such plans, specifications, and estimates for each proposed project as the Secretary may require.

(2) Project agreement.—The Secretary shall act on the plans, specifications, and estimates as soon as practicable after the date of their submission and shall enter into a formal project agreement with the State transportation department recipient formalizing the conditions of the project approval.

(3) Contractual obligation.—The execution of the project agreement shall be deemed a contractual obligation of the Federal Government for the payment of the Federal share of the cost of the project.

(4) Guidance.—In taking action under this subsection, the Secretary shall be guided by section 109.


(b) Project Agreement.—(1) Provision of state funds.—The project agreement shall make provision for State funds required to pay the State’s non-Federal share of the cost of construction of the project (including payments made pursuant to a long-term concession agreement, such as availability payments) and to pay for maintenance of the project after completion of construction.

(2) Representations of state.—If a part of the project is to be constructed at the expense of, or in cooperation with, political subdivisions of the State, the Secretary may rely on representations made by the State transportation department with respect to the arrangements or agreements made by the State transportation department and appropriate local officials for ensuring that the non-Federal contribution will be provided under paragraph (1).


(c) Assumption by States of Responsibilities of the Secretary.—(1) NHS projects.—For projects under this title that are on the National Highway System, including projects on the Interstate System, the State may assume the responsib</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assumption by States of Responsibilities of the Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of the Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nothing in this section, section 133, or section 149 shall affect or discharge any responsibility or obligation of the Secretary under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value Engineering Analysis.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life-Cycle Cost Analysis.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Major Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A recipient of Federal financial assistance for a project under this title with an estimated total cost of $100,000,000 or more that is not covered by subsection (h) shall prepare an annual financial plan. Annual financial plans prepared under this subsection shall be made available to the Secretary for review upon the request of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Advanced Modeling Technologies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>