<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/116" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/116/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/116/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_116"><akn:num>116</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 116. Maintenance(a) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Preventive maintenance.—The term “preventive maintenance” includes pavement preservation programs and activities.

(2) Pavement preservation programs and activities.—The term “pavement preservation programs and activities” means programs and activities employing a network level, long-term strategy that enhances pavement performance by using an integrated, cost-effective set of practices that extend pavement life, improve safety, and meet road user expectations.


(b) It shall be the duty of the State transportation department or other direct recipient to maintain, or cause to be maintained, any project constructed under the provisions of this chapter or constructed under the provisions of prior Acts.

(c) Agreement.—In any State in which the State transportation department or other direct recipient is without legal authority to maintain a project described in subsection (b), the transportation department or direct recipient shall enter into a formal agreement with the appropriate officials of the county or municipality in which the project is located to provide for the maintenance of the project.

(d) If at any time the Secretary shall find that any project constructed under the provisions of this chapter, or constructed under the provisions of prior Acts, is not being properly maintained, he shall call such fact to the attention of the State transportation department or other direct recipient. If, within ninety days after receipt of such notice, such project has not been put in proper condition of maintenance, the Secretary shall withhold approval of further projects of all types in the State highway district, municipality, county, other political or administrative subdivision of the State, or the entire State in which such project is located, whichever the Secretary deems most appropriate, until such project shall have been put in proper condition of maintenance.

(e) Preventiv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_116_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_116_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) It shall be the duty of the State transportation department or other direct recipient to maintain, or cause to be maintained, any project constructed under the provisions of this chapter or constructed under the provisions of prior Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_116_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In any State in which the State transportation department or other direct recipient is without legal authority to maintain a project described in subsection (b), the transportation department or direct recipient shall enter into a formal agreement with the appropriate officials of the county or municipality in which the project is located to provide for the maintenance of the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_116_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If at any time the Secretary shall find that any project constructed under the provisions of this chapter, or constructed under the provisions of prior Acts, is not being properly maintained, he shall call such fact to the attention of the State transportation department or other direct recipient. If, within ninety days after receipt of such notice, such project has not been put in proper condition of maintenance, the Secretary shall withhold approval of further projects of all types in the State highway district, municipality, county, other political or administrative subdivision of the State, or the entire State in which such project is located, whichever the Secretary deems most appropriate, until such project shall have been put in proper condition of maintenance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_116_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preventive Maintenance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A preventive maintenance activity shall be eligible for Federal assistance under this title if the State demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the activity is a cost-effective means of extending the useful life of a Federal-aid highway.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>