<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/123" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/123/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/123/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_123"><akn:num>123</akn:num><akn:heading>Relocation of utility facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 123. Relocation of utility facilities(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Cost of relocation.—The term “cost of relocation” includes the entire amount paid by a utility properly attributable to the relocation of a utility facility, minus any increase in the value of the new facility and any salvage value derived from the old facility.

(2) Early utility relocation project.—The term “early utility relocation project” means utility relocation activities identified by the State for performance before completion of the environmental review process for the transportation project.

(3) Environmental review process.—The term “environmental review process” has the meaning given the term in section 139(a).

(4) Transportation project.—The term “transportation project” means a project.

(5) Utility facility.—The term “utility facility” means any privately, publicly, or cooperatively owned line, facility, or system for producing, transmitting, or distributing communications, power, electricity, light, heat, gas, oil, crude products, water, steam, waste, stormwater not connected with highway drainage, or any other similar commodity, including any fire or police signal system or street lighting system, that directly or indirectly serves the public.

(6) Utility relocation activity.—The term “utility relocation activity” means an activity necessary for the relocation of a utility facility, including preliminary and final design, surveys, real property acquisition, materials acquisition, and construction.


(b) Reimbursement to States.—(1) In general.—If a State pays for the cost of relocation of a utility facility necessitated by the construction of a transportation project, Federal funds may be used to reimburse the State for the cost of relocation in the same proportion as Federal funds are expended on the transportation project.

(2) Limitation.—Federal funds shall not be used to reimburse a State under this section if the payment to the utility—(A) violates the law of the S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_123_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_123_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement to States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_123_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Other Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nothing in this section affects the applicability of other requirements that would otherwise apply to an early utility relocation project, including any applicable requirements under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>