<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/135" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/135/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/135/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_135"><akn:num>135</akn:num><akn:heading>Statewide and nonmetropolitan transportation planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 135. Statewide and nonmetropolitan transportation planning(a) General Requirements.—(1) Development of plans and programs.—Subject to section 134, to accomplish the objectives stated in section 134(a), each State shall develop a statewide transportation plan and a statewide transportation improvement program for all areas of the State.

(2) Contents.—The statewide transportation plan and the transportation improvement program developed for each State shall provide for the development and integrated management and operation of transportation systems and facilities (including accessible pedestrian walkways, bicycle transportation facilities, and intermodal facilities that support intercity transportation, including intercity buses and intercity bus facilities and commuter van pool providers) that will function as an intermodal transportation system for the State and an integral part of an intermodal transportation system for the United States.

(3) Process of development.—The process for developing the statewide plan and the transportation improvement program shall provide for consideration of all modes of transportation and the policies stated in section 134(a) and shall be continuing, cooperative, and comprehensive to the degree appropriate, based on the complexity of the transportation problems to be addressed.


(b) Coordination With Metropolitan Planning; State Implementation Plan.—A State shall—(1) coordinate planning carried out under this section with the transportation planning activities carried out under section 134 for metropolitan areas of the State and with statewide trade and economic development planning activities and related multistate planning efforts; and

(2) develop the transportation portion of the State implementation plan as required by the Clean Air Act (42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.).


(c) Interstate Agreements.—(1) In general.—Two or more States may enter into agreements or compacts, not in conflict with any law of the United States, for cooper</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination With Metropolitan Planning; State Implementation Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A State shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of Planning Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In carrying out planning under this section, each State shall, at a minimum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Long-range Statewide Transportation Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statewide Transportation Improvement Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance-based Planning Processes Evaluation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Funds apportioned under section 104(b)(6) and set aside under section 5305(g) of title 49 shall be available to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_135_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Certain State Laws as Congestion Management Processes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) For purposes of this section and section 134, and sections 5303 and 5304 of title 49, State laws, rules, or regulations pertaining to congestion management systems or programs may constitute the congestion management process under this section and section 134, and sections 5303 and 5304 of title 49, if the Secretary finds that the State laws, rules, or regulations are consistent with, and fulfill the intent of, the purposes of this section and section 134 and sections 5303 and 5304 of title 49, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>