<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/136" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/136/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/136/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_136"><akn:num>136</akn:num><akn:heading>Control of junkyards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 136. Control of junkyards(a) The Congress hereby finds and declares that the establishment and use and maintenance of junkyards in areas adjacent to the Interstate System and the primary system should be controlled in order to protect the public investment in such highways, to promote the safety and recreational value of public travel, and to preserve natural beauty.

(b) Federal-aid highway funds apportioned on or after January 1, 1968, to any State which the Secretary determines has not made provision for effective control of the establishment and maintenance along the Interstate System and the primary system of outdoor junkyards, which are within one thousand feet of the nearest edge of the right-of-way and visible from the main traveled way of the system, shall be reduced by amounts equal to 7 percent of the amounts which would otherwise be apportioned to such State under paragraphs (1) through (6) of section 104(b), until such time as such State shall provide for such effective control. Any amount which is withheld from apportionment to any State hereunder shall be reapportioned to the other States. Whenever he determines it to be in the public interest, the Secretary may suspend, for such periods as he deems necessary, the application of this subsection to a State.

(c) Effective control means that by January 1, 1968, such junkyards shall be screened by natural objects, plantings, fences, or other appropriate means so as not to be visible from the main traveled way of the system, or shall be removed from sight.

(d) The term “junk” shall mean old or scrap copper, brass, rope, rags, batteries, paper, trash, rubber debris, waste, or junked, dismantled, or wrecked automobiles, or parts thereof, iron, steel, and other old or scrap ferrous or nonferrous material.

(e) The term “automobile graveyard” shall mean any establishment or place of business which is maintained, used, or operated for storing, keeping, buying, or selling wrecked, scrapped, ruined, or disman</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Congress hereby finds and declares that the establishment and use and maintenance of junkyards in areas adjacent to the Interstate System and the primary system should be controlled in order to protect the public investment in such highways, to promote the safety and recreational value of public travel, and to preserve natural beauty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal-aid highway funds apportioned on or after January 1, 1968, to any State which the Secretary determines has not made provision for effective control of the establishment and maintenance along the Interstate System and the primary system of outdoor junkyards, which are within one thousand feet of the nearest edge of the right-of-way and visible from the main traveled way of the system, shall be reduced by amounts equal to 7 percent of the amounts which would otherwise be apportioned to such State under paragraphs (1) through (6) of section 104(b), until such time as such State shall provide for such effective control. Any amount which is withheld from apportionment to any State hereunder shall be reapportioned to the other States. Whenever he determines it to be in the public interest, the Secretary may suspend, for such periods as he deems necessary, the application of this subsection to a State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effective control means that by January 1, 1968, such junkyards shall be screened by natural objects, plantings, fences, or other appropriate means so as not to be visible from the main traveled way of the system, or shall be removed from sight.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term “junk” shall mean old or scrap copper, brass, rope, rags, batteries, paper, trash, rubber debris, waste, or junked, dismantled, or wrecked automobiles, or parts thereof, iron, steel, and other old or scrap ferrous or nonferrous material.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The term “automobile graveyard” shall mean any establishment or place of business which is maintained, used, or operated for storing, keeping, buying, or selling wrecked, scrapped, ruined, or dismantled motor vehicles or motor vehicle parts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The term “junkyard” shall mean an establishment or place of business which is maintained, operated, or used for storing, keeping, buying, or selling junk, or for the maintenance or operation of an automobile graveyard, and the term shall include garbage dumps and sanitary fills.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notwithstanding any provision of this section, junkyards, auto graveyards, and scrap metal processing facilities may be operated within areas adjacent to the Interstate System and the primary system which are within one thousand feet of the nearest edge of the right-of-way and which are zoned industrial under authority of State law, or which are not zoned under authority of State law, but are used for industrial activities, as determined by the several States subject to approval by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notwithstanding any provision of this section, any junkyard in existence on the date of enactment of this section which does not conform to the requirements of this section and which the Secretary finds as a practical matter cannot be screened, shall not be required to be removed until July 1, 1970.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Federal share of landscaping and screening costs under this section shall be 75 per centum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Just compensation shall be paid the owner for the relocation, removal, or disposal of junk­yards lawfully established under State law. The Federal share of such compensation shall be 75 per centum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>