<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/147" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/147/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/147/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_147"><akn:num>147</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 147. Construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities(a) Program.—The Secretary shall carry out a program for construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities in accordance with section 129(c).

(b) Federal Share.—The Federal share of the cost of construction of ferry boats, ferry terminals, and ferry maintenance facilities under this section shall be 80 percent.

(c) Distribution of Funds.—Of the amounts made available to ferry systems and public entities responsible for developing ferries under this section for a fiscal year, 100 percent shall be allocated in accordance with the formula set forth in subsection (d).

(d) Formula.—Of the amounts allocated under subsection (c)—(1) 35 percent shall be allocated among eligible entities in the proportion that—(A) the number of ferry passengers, including passengers in vehicles, carried by each ferry system in the most recent calendar year for which data is available; bears to

(B) the number of ferry passengers, including passengers in vehicles, carried by all ferry systems in the most recent calendar year for which data is available;


(2) 35 percent shall be allocated among eligible entities in the proportion that—(A) the number of vehicles carried by each ferry system in the most recent calendar year for which data is available; bears to

(B) the number of vehicles carried by all ferry systems in the most recent calendar year for which data is available; and


(3) 30 percent shall be allocated among eligible entities in the proportion that—(A) the total route nautical miles serviced by each ferry system in the most recent calendar year for which data is available; bears to

(B) the total route nautical miles serviced by all ferry systems in the most recent calendar year for which data is available.



(e) Redistribution of Unobligated Amounts.—The Secretary shall—(1) withdraw amounts allocated to an eligible entity under subsection (c) that remain unobligated by the end of the third fiscal year fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall carry out a program for construction of ferry boats and ferry terminal facilities in accordance with section 129(c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Federal share of the cost of construction of ferry boats, ferry terminals, and ferry maintenance facilities under this section shall be 80 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Of the amounts made available to ferry systems and public entities responsible for developing ferries under this section for a fiscal year, 100 percent shall be allocated in accordance with the formula set forth in subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formula.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Of the amounts allocated under subsection (c)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redistribution of Unobligated Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum Amount.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notwithstanding subsection (c), a State with an eligible entity that meets the requirements of this section shall receive not less than $100,000 under this section for a fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) There are authorized to be appropriated out of the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of Availability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Notwithstanding section 118(b), funds made available to carry out this section shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_147_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) All provisions of this chapter that are applicable to the National Highway System, other than provisions relating to apportionment formula and Federal share, shall apply to funds made available to carry out this section, except as determined by the Secretary to be inconsistent with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>