<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/150" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/150/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/150/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_150"><akn:num>150</akn:num><akn:heading>National goals and performance management measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 150. National goals and performance management measures(a) Declaration of Policy.—Performance management will transform the Federal-aid highway program and provide a means to the most efficient investment of Federal transportation funds by refocusing on national transportation goals, increasing the accountability and transparency of the Federal-aid highway program, and improving project decisionmaking through performance-based planning and programming.

(b) National Goals.—It is in the interest of the United States to focus the Federal-aid highway program on the following national goals:(1) Safety.—To achieve a significant reduction in traffic fatalities and serious injuries on all public roads.

(2) Infrastructure condition.—To maintain the highway infrastructure asset system in a state of good repair.

(3) Congestion reduction.—To achieve a significant reduction in congestion on the National Highway System.

(4) System reliability.—To improve the efficiency of the surface transportation system.

(5) Freight movement and economic vitality.—To improve the National Highway Freight Network, strengthen the ability of rural communities to access national and international trade markets, and support regional economic development.

(6) Environmental sustainability.—To enhance the performance of the transportation system while protecting and enhancing the natural environment.

(7) Reduced project delivery delays.—To reduce project costs, promote jobs and the economy, and expedite the movement of people and goods by accelerating project completion through eliminating delays in the project development and delivery process, including reducing regulatory burdens and improving agencies’ work practices.


(c) Establishment of Performance Measures.—(1) In general.—Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the MAP–21, the Secretary, in consultation with State departments of transportation, metropolitan planning organizations, and other stakeholders, shall promulgat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_150_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of Policy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Performance management will transform the Federal-aid highway program and provide a means to the most efficient investment of Federal transportation funds by refocusing on national transportation goals, increasing the accountability and transparency of the Federal-aid highway program, and improving project decisionmaking through performance-based planning and programming.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_150_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Goals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) It is in the interest of the United States to focus the Federal-aid highway program on the following national goals:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_150_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Performance Measures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_150_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Performance Targets.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_150_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting on Performance Targets.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of the MAP–21 and biennially thereafter, a State shall submit to the Secretary a report that describes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>