<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/153" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/153/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/153/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_153"><akn:num>153</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of safety belts and motorcycle helmets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 153. Use of safety belts and motorcycle helmets(a) Authority To Make Grants.—The Secretary may make grants to a State in a fiscal year in accordance with this section if the State has in effect in such fiscal year—(1) a law which makes unlawful throughout the State the operation of a motorcycle if any individual on the motorcycle is not wearing a motorcycle helmet; and

(2) a law which makes unlawful throughout the State the operation of a passenger vehicle whenever an individual in a front seat of the vehicle (other than a child who is secured in a child restraint system) does not have a safety belt properly fastened about the individual’s body.


(b) Use of Grants.—A grant made to a State under this section shall be used to adopt and implement a traffic safety program to carry out the following purposes:(1) Education.—To educate the public about motorcycle and passenger vehicle safety and motorcycle helmet, safety belt, and child restraint system use and to involve public health education agencies and other related agencies in these efforts.

(2) Training.—To train law enforcement officers in the enforcement of State laws described in subsection (a).

(3) Monitoring.—To monitor the rate of compliance with State laws described in subsection (a).

(4) Enforcement.—To enforce State laws described in subsection (a).


(c) Maintenance of Effort.—A grant may not be made to a State under this section in any fiscal year unless the State enters into such agreements with the Secretary as the Secretary may require to ensure that the State will maintain its aggregate expenditures from all other sources for any traffic safety program described in subsection (b) at or above the average level of such expenditures in the State’s 2 fiscal years preceding the date of the enactment of this section.

(d) Federal Share.—A State may not receive a grant under this section in more than 3 fiscal years. The Federal share payable for a grant under this section shall not exceed—(1) in the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Make Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary may make grants to a State in a fiscal year in accordance with this section if the State has in effect in such fiscal year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A grant made to a State under this section shall be used to adopt and implement a traffic safety program to carry out the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of Effort.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A grant may not be made to a State under this section in any fiscal year unless the State enters into such agreements with the Secretary as the Secretary may require to ensure that the State will maintain its aggregate expenditures from all other sources for any traffic safety program described in subsection (b) at or above the average level of such expenditures in the State’s 2 fiscal years preceding the date of the enactment of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A State may not receive a grant under this section in more than 3 fiscal years. The Federal share payable for a grant under this section shall not exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Aggregate Amount of Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The aggregate amount of grants made to a State under this section shall not exceed 90 percent of the amount apportioned to such State for fiscal year 1990 under section 402.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Measurements of Rates of Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For the purposes of subsections (f)(2) and (f)(3), a State shall measure compliance with State laws described in subsection (a) using methods which conform to guidelines issued by the Secretary ensuring that such measurements are accurate and representative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) For the purposes of this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) There is authorized to be appropriated out of the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) to carry out this section $17,000,000 for fiscal year 1992. From sums made available to carry out section 402 of this title, the Secretary shall make available $17,000,000 for fiscal year 1992 and $24,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1993 and 1994 to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>