<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/154" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/154/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/154/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_154"><akn:num>154</akn:num><akn:heading>Open container requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 154. Open container requirements(a) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Alcoholic beverage.—The term “alcoholic beverage” has the meaning given the term in section 158(c).

(2) Motor vehicle.—The term “motor vehicle” means a vehicle driven or drawn by mechanical power and manufactured primarily for use on public highways, but does not include a vehicle operated exclusively on a rail or rails.

(3) Open alcoholic beverage container.—The term “open alcoholic beverage container” means any bottle, can, or other receptacle—(A) that contains any amount of alcoholic beverage; and

(B)(i) that is open or has a broken seal; or

(ii) the contents of which are partially removed.



(4) Passenger area.—The term “passenger area” shall have the meaning given the term by the Secretary by regulation.


(b) Open Container Laws.—(1) In general.—For the purposes of this section, each State shall have in effect a law that prohibits the possession of any open alcoholic beverage container, or the consumption of any alcoholic beverage, in the passenger area of any motor vehicle (including possession or consumption by the driver of the vehicle) located on a public highway, or the right-of-way of a public highway, in the State.

(2) Motor vehicles designed to transport many passengers.—For the purposes of this section, if a State has in effect a law that makes unlawful the possession of any open alcoholic beverage container by the driver (but not by a passenger)—(A) in the passenger area of a motor vehicle designed, maintained, or used primarily for the transportation of persons for compensation; or

(B) in the living quarters of a house coach or house trailer,


the State shall be deemed to have in effect a law described in this subsection with respect to such a motor vehicle for each fiscal year during which the law is in effect.


(c) Transfer of Funds.—(1) Fiscal years 2001 and 2002.—On October 1, 2000, and October 1, 2001, if a State has not enacted or i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Open Container Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>