<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/164" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/164/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/164/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_164"><akn:num>164</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum penalties for repeat offenders for driving while intoxicated or driving under the influence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 164. Minimum penalties for repeat offenders for driving while intoxicated or driving under the influence(a) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) 24-7 sobriety program.—The term “24-7 sobriety program” has the meaning given the term in section 405(d)(7)(A).

(2) Alcohol concentration.—The term “alcohol concentration” means grams of alcohol per 100 milliliters of blood or grams of alcohol per 210 liters of breath.

(3) Driving while intoxicated; driving under the influence.—The terms “driving while intoxicated” and “driving under the influence” mean driving or being in actual physical control of a motor vehicle while having an alcohol concentration above the permitted limit as established by each State.

(4) Motor vehicle.—The term “motor vehicle” means a vehicle driven or drawn by mechanical power and manufactured primarily for use on public highways, but does not include a vehicle operated solely on a rail line or a commercial vehicle.

(5) Repeat intoxicated driver law.—The term “repeat intoxicated driver law” means a State law or combination of laws or programs that provides, as a minimum penalty, that an individual convicted of a second or subsequent offense for driving while intoxicated or driving under the influence after a previous conviction for that offense shall—(A) receive, for a period of not less than 1 year—(i) a suspension of all driving privileges;

(ii) a restriction on driving privileges that limits the individual to operating only motor vehicles with an ignition interlock device installed, unless a special exception applies;

(iii) a restriction on driving privileges that limits the individual to operating motor vehicles only if participating in, and complying with, a 24-7 sobriety program; or

(iv) any combination of clauses (i) through (iii);


(B) receive an assessment of the individual’s degree of abuse of alcohol and treatment as appropriate; and

(C) receive—(i) in the case of the second offense—(I) an assignmen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>