<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/170" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/170/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/170/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_170"><akn:num>170</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding flexibility for transportation emergencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 170. Funding flexibility for transportation emergencies(a) In General.—Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a State may use up to 100 percent of any covered funds of the State to repair or replace a transportation facility that has suffered serious damage as a result of a natural disaster or catastrophic failure from an external cause.

(b) Declaration of Emergency.—Funds may be used under this section only for a disaster or emergency declared by the President pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.).

(c) Repayment.—Funds used under subsection (a) shall be repaid to the program from which the funds were taken in the event that such repairs or replacement are subsequently covered by a supplemental appropriation of funds.

(d) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Covered funds.—The term “covered funds” means any amounts apportioned to a State under section 104(b), other than amounts suballocated to metropolitan areas and other areas of the State under section 133(d), but including any such amounts required to be set aside for a purpose other than the repair or replacement of a transportation facility under this section.

(2) Transportation facility.—The term “transportation facility” means any facility eligible for assistance under section 125.


(Added Pub. L. 112–141, div. A, title I, § 1515(a), July 6, 2012, 126 Stat. 573.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is Pub. L. 93–288, May 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 143, which is classified principally to chapter 68 (§ 5121 et seq.) of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 5121 of Title 42 and Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 2012, see section 3(a) of Pub. L. 112–141, set out as an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a State may use up to 100 percent of any covered funds of the State to repair or replace a transportation facility that has suffered serious damage as a result of a natural disaster or catastrophic failure from an external cause.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of Emergency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funds may be used under this section only for a disaster or emergency declared by the President pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funds used under subsection (a) shall be repaid to the program from which the funds were taken in the event that such repairs or replacement are subsequently covered by a supplemental appropriation of funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>