<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/206" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/206/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/206/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_206"><akn:num>206</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreational trails program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 206. Recreational trails program(a) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Motorized recreation.—The term “motorized recreation” means off-road recreation using any motor-powered vehicle, except for a motorized wheelchair.

(2) Recreational trail.—The term “recreational trail” means a thoroughfare or track across land or snow, used for recreational purposes such as—(A) pedestrian activities, including wheelchair use;

(B) skating or skateboarding;

(C) equestrian activities, including carriage driving;

(D) nonmotorized snow trail activities, including skiing;

(E) bicycling or use of other human-powered vehicles;

(F) aquatic or water activities; and

(G) motorized vehicular activities, including all-terrain vehicle riding, motorcycling, snowmobiling, use of off-road light trucks, or use of other off-road motorized vehicles.



(b) Program.—In accordance with this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, shall carry out a program to provide and maintain recreational trails.

(c) State Responsibilities.—To be eligible for apportionments under this section—(1) the Governor of the State shall designate the State agency or agencies that will be responsible for administering apportionments made to the State under this section; and

(2) the State shall establish a State recreational trail advisory committee that represents both motorized and nonmotorized recreational trail users, which shall meet not less often than once per fiscal year.


(d) Use of Apportioned Funds.—(1) In general.—Funds apportioned to a State to carry out this section shall be obligated for recreational trails and related projects that—(A) have been planned and developed under the laws, policies, and administrative procedures of the State; and

(B) are identified in, or further a specific goal of, a recreational trail plan, or a statewide comprehensive outdoor recreation plan required by chapter 2003 of t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In accordance with this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, shall carry out a program to provide and maintain recreational trails.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To be eligible for apportionments under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Apportioned Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Benefit or Mitigation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) To the extent practicable and consistent with the other requirements of this section, a State should give consideration to project proposals that provide for the redesign, reconstruction, nonroutine maintenance, or relocation of recreational trails to benefit the natural environment or to mitigate and minimize the impact to the natural environment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses Not Permitted.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A State may not obligate funds apportioned to carry out this section for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Funds authorized to carry out this section shall be available for obligation in the same manner as if the funds were apportioned under chapter 1, except that the Federal share of the cost of a project under this section shall be determined in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Other Apportioned Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Funds apportioned to a State under section 104(b) that are obligated for a recreational trail or a related project shall be administered as if the funds were made available to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>