<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_322"><akn:num>322</akn:num><akn:heading>Magnetic levitation transportation technology deployment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 322. Magnetic levitation transportation technology deployment program(a) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Eligible project costs.—The term “eligible project costs”—(A) means the capital cost of the fixed guideway infrastructure of a MAGLEV project, including land, piers, guideways, propulsion equipment and other components attached to guideways, power distribution facilities (including substations), control and communications facilities, access roads, and storage, repair, and maintenance facilities, but not including costs incurred for a new station; and

(B) includes the costs of preconstruction planning activities.


(2) Full project costs.—The term “full project costs” means the total capital costs of a MAGLEV project, including eligible project costs and the costs of stations, vehicles, and equipment.

(3) MAGLEV.—The term “MAGLEV” means transportation systems employing magnetic levitation that would be capable of safe use by the public at a speed in excess of 240 miles per hour.

(4) Partnership potential.—The term “partnership potential” has the meaning given the term in the commercial feasibility study of high-speed ground transportation conducted under section 1036 of the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 (105 Stat. 1978).


(b) Financial Assistance.—(1) In general.—The Secretary shall make available financial assistance to pay the Federal share of full project costs of eligible projects selected under this section. Financial assistance made available under this section and projects assisted with the assistance shall be subject to section 5333(a) of title 49, United States Code.

(2) Federal share.—The Federal share of full project costs under paragraph (1) shall be not more than ⅔.

(3) Use of assistance.—Financial assistance provided under paragraph (1) shall be used only to pay eligible project costs of projects selected under this section.


(c) Solicitation of Applications for Assistance.—Not lat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation of Applications for Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall solicit applications from States, or authorities designated by 1 or more States, for financial assistance authorized by subsection (b) for planning, design, and construction of eligible MAGLEV projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_322_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) To be eligible to receive financial assistance under subsection (b), a project shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_322_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Selection Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prior to soliciting applications, the Secretary shall establish criteria for selecting which eligible projects under subsection (d) will receive financial assistance under subsection (b). The criteria shall include the extent to which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_322_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Selection.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_322_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint Ventures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A project undertaken by a joint venture of United States and non-United States persons (including a project involving the deployment of non-United States MAGLEV technology in the United States) shall be eligible for financial assistance under this section if the project is eligible under subsection (d) and selected under subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_322_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_322_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-Speed Project.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>