<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/328" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/328/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/328/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_328"><akn:num>328</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for environmental restoration and pollution abatement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 328. Eligibility for environmental restoration and pollution abatement(a) In General.—Subject to subsection (b), environmental restoration and pollution abatement to minimize or mitigate the impacts of any transportation project funded under this title (including retrofitting and construction of stormwater treatment systems to meet Federal and State requirements under sections 401 and 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. 1341; 1342)) may be carried out to address water pollution or environmental degradation caused wholly or partially by a transportation facility.

(b) Maximum Expenditure.—In a case in which a transportation facility is undergoing reconstruction, rehabilitation, resurfacing, or restoration, the expenditure of funds under this section for environmental restoration or pollution abatement described in subsection (a) shall not exceed 20 percent of the total cost of the reconstruction, rehabilitation, resurfacing, or restoration of the facility.

(Added Pub. L. 109–59, title VI, § 6006(b), Aug. 10, 2005, 119 Stat. 1872.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_328_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsection (b), environmental restoration and pollution abatement to minimize or mitigate the impacts of any transportation project funded under this title (including retrofitting and construction of stormwater treatment systems to meet Federal and State requirements under sections 401 and 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (33 U.S.C. 1341; 1342)) may be carried out to address water pollution or environmental degradation caused wholly or partially by a transportation facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_328_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Expenditure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In a case in which a transportation facility is undergoing reconstruction, rehabilitation, resurfacing, or restoration, the expenditure of funds under this section for environmental restoration or pollution abatement described in subsection (a) shall not exceed 20 percent of the total cost of the reconstruction, rehabilitation, resurfacing, or restoration of the facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>