<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_605"><akn:num>605</akn:num><akn:heading>Program administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 605. Program administration(a) Requirement.—The Secretary shall establish a uniform system to service the Federal credit instruments made available under the TIFIA program.

(b) Fees.—The Secretary may collect and spend fees, contingent on authority being provided in appropriations Acts, at a level that is sufficient to cover—(1) the costs of services of expert firms retained pursuant to subsection (d); and

(2) all or a portion of the costs to the Federal Government of servicing the Federal credit instruments.


(c) Servicer.—(1) In general.—The Secretary may appoint a financial entity to assist the Secretary in servicing the Federal credit instruments.

(2) Duties.—A servicer appointed under paragraph (1) shall act as the agent for the Secretary.

(3) Fee.—A servicer appointed under paragraph (1) shall receive a servicing fee, subject to approval by the Secretary.


(d) Assistance From Expert Firms.—The Secretary may retain the services of expert firms, including counsel, in the field of municipal and project finance to assist in the underwriting and servicing of Federal credit instruments.

(e) Expedited Processing.—The Secretary shall implement procedures and measures to economize the time and cost involved in obtaining approval and the issuance of credit assistance under the TIFIA program.

(f) Assistance to Small Projects.—(1) Reservation of funds.—Of the funds made available to carry out the TIFIA program for each fiscal year, and after the set aside under section 608(a)(6), not less than $2,000,000 shall be made available for the Secretary to use in lieu of fees collected under subsection (b) for projects under the TIFIA program having eligible project costs that are reasonably anticipated not to equal or exceed $75,000,000.

(2) Release of funds.—Any funds not used under paragraph (1) in a fiscal year shall be made available on October 1 of the following fiscal year to provide credit assistance to any project under the TIFIA program.


(Added Pub. L. 105–</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall establish a uniform system to service the Federal credit instruments made available under the TIFIA program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may collect and spend fees, contingent on authority being provided in appropriations Acts, at a level that is sufficient to cover—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_605_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Servicer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_605_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance From Expert Firms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may retain the services of expert firms, including counsel, in the field of municipal and project finance to assist in the underwriting and servicing of Federal credit instruments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_605_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited Processing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall implement procedures and measures to economize the time and cost involved in obtaining approval and the issuance of credit assistance under the TIFIA program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_605_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to Small Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>