<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/610" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/610/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/23/610/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_610"><akn:num>610</akn:num><akn:heading>State infrastructure bank program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 610. State infrastructure bank program(a) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Capital project.—The term “capital project” has the meaning such term has under section 5302 of title 49.

(2) Other forms of credit assistance.—The term “other forms of credit assistance” includes any use of funds in an infrastructure bank—(A) to provide credit enhancements;

(B) to serve as a capital reserve for bond or debt instrument financing;

(C) to subsidize interest rates;

(D) to insure or guarantee letters of credit and credit instruments against credit risk of loss;

(E) to finance purchase and lease agreements with respect to transit projects;

(F) to provide bond or debt financing instrument security; and

(G) to provide other forms of debt financing and methods of leveraging funds that are approved by the Secretary and that relate to the project with respect to which such assistance is being provided.


(3) State.—The term “State” has the meaning such term has under section 401.

(4) Capitalization.—The term “capitalization” means the process used for depositing funds as initial capital into a State infrastructure bank to establish the infrastructure bank.

(5) Cooperative agreement.—The term “cooperative agreement” means written consent between a State and the Secretary which sets forth the manner in which the infrastructure bank established by the State in accordance with this section will be administered.

(6) Loan.—The term “loan” means any form of direct financial assistance from a State infrastructure bank that is required to be repaid over a period of time and that is provided to a project sponsor for all or part of the costs of the project.

(7) Guarantee.—The term “guarantee” means a contract entered into by a State infrastructure bank in which the bank agrees to take responsibility for all or a portion of a project sponsor’s financial obligations for a project under specified conditions.

(8) Initial assistance.—The term “initial ass</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to the provisions of this section, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with States for the establishment of State infrastructure banks for making loans and providing other forms of credit assistance to public and private entities carrying out or proposing to carry out projects eligible for assistance under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate Compacts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forms of Assistance From State Infrastructure Banks.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Subject to subsection (e), funds in an infrastructure bank established under this section may be used only to provide assistance for projects eligible for assistance under this title and capital projects defined in section 5302 of title 49, and any other projects relating to surface transportation that the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Infrastructure Bank Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In order to establish an infrastructure bank under this section, the State establishing the bank shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Federal Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States not Obligated.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The deposit of Federal funds into an infrastructure bank established under this section shall not be construed as a commitment, guarantee, or obligation on the part of the United States to any third party, nor shall any third party have any right against the United States for payment solely by virtue of the contribution. Any security or debt-financing instrument issued by the infrastructure bank shall expressly state that the security or instrument does not constitute a commitment, guarantee, or obligation of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Federal Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Sections 3335 and 6503 of title 31 shall not apply to funds deposited into an infrastructure bank under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>