<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/1201" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/1201/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/1201/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1201"><akn:num>1201</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of members of the Merit Systems Protection Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1201. Appointment of members of the Merit Systems Protection Board
The Merit Systems Protection Board is composed of 3 members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, not more than 2 of whom may be adherents of the same political party. The members of the Board shall be individuals who, by demonstrated ability, background, training, or experience are especially qualified to carry out the functions of the Board. No member of the Board may hold another office or position in the Government of the United States, except as otherwise provided by law or at the direction of the President. The Board shall have an official seal which shall be judicially noticed. The Board shall have its principal office in the District of Columbia and may have field offices in other appropriate locations.
(Added Pub. L. 95–454, title II, § 202(a), Oct. 13, 1978, 92 Stat. 1121; amended Pub. L. 101–12, § 3(a)(1), Apr. 10, 1989, 103 Stat. 16.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1989—Pub. L. 101–12 substituted “The members” for “The Chairman and members” in second sentence.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1989 AmendmentPub. L. 101–12, § 11, Apr. 10, 1989, 103 Stat. 35, provided that: “This Act and the amendments made by this Act [see Short Title of 1989 Amendment note below] shall take effect 90 days following the date of enactment of this Act [Apr. 10, 1989].”


Effective DateSubchapter effective 90 days after Oct. 13, 1978, see section 907 of Pub. L. 95–454, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under section 1101 of this title.

Short Title of 1989 AmendmentPub. L. 101–12, § 1, Apr. 10, 1989, 103 Stat. 16, provided that: “This Act [enacting subchapters II and III of this chapter and section 3352 of this title, amending this section and sections 1202 to 1206, 1209, 1211, 2302, 2303, 3393, 7502, 7512, 7521, 7542, 7701, and 7703 of this title and section 4139 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, repealing section</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>