<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13104"><akn:num>13104</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13104. Contents of reports(a) Annual and Termination Reports.—Each report filed pursuant to section 13103(d) and (e) of this title shall include a full and complete statement with respect to the following:(1) Income.—(A) In general.—The source, type, and amount or value of income (other than income referred to in subparagraph (B)) from any source (other than from current employment by the United States Government), and the source, date, and amount of honoraria from any source, received during the preceding calendar year, aggregating $200 or more in value and, effective January 1, 1991, the source, date, and amount of payments made to charitable organizations in lieu of honoraria, and the reporting individual shall simultaneously file with the applicable supervising ethics office, on a confidential basis, a corresponding list of recipients of all such payments, together with the dates and amounts of such payments.

(B) Dividends, rents, interest, and capital gains.—The source and type of income which consists of dividends, rents, interest, and capital gains, received during the preceding calendar year which exceeds $200 in amount or value, and an indication of which of the following categories the amount or value of such item of income is within—(i) not more than $1,000;

(ii) greater than $1,000 but not more than $2,500;

(iii) greater than $2,500 but not more than $5,000;

(iv) greater than $5,000 but not more than $15,000;

(v) greater than $15,000 but not more than $50,000;

(vi) greater than $50,000 but not more than $100,000;

(vii) greater than $100,000 but not more than $1,000,000;

(viii) greater than $1,000,000 but not more than $5,000,000; or

(ix) greater than $5,000,000.



(2) Gifts and reimbursements.—(A) Gifts.—The identity of the source, a brief description, and the value of all gifts aggregating more than the minimal value as established by section 7342(a)(5) of this title, or $250, whichever is greater, received from any source other than a relat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual and Termination Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each report filed pursuant to section 13103(d) and (e) of this title shall include a full and complete statement with respect to the following: With respect to revolving charge accounts, only those with an outstanding liability which exceeds $10,000 as of the close of the preceding calendar year need be reported under this paragraph. Reporting is not required under this paragraph of any transaction solely by and between the reporting individual, the individual’s spouse, or dependent children. The preceding sentence shall not require any individual to include in such report any information which is considered confidential as a result of a privileged relationship, established by law, between such individual and any person, nor shall it require an individual to report any information with respect to any person for whom services were provided by any firm or association of which such individual was a member, partner, or employee unless such individual was directly involved in the provis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports for New Employees, Nominees, and Candidates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report After Termination of Employment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In the case of any individual described in section 13103(e) of this title, any reference to the preceding calendar year shall be considered also to include that part of the calendar year of filing up to the date of the termination of employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Categories for Reporting Amounts or Values.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13104_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting Information Relating to Spouse or Dependent Child.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports required by subsections (a), (b), and (c) of section 13103 of this title shall, with respect to the spouse and dependent child of the reporting individual, contain only information listed in paragraphs (1), (3), and (4) of subsection (a), as specified in this paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13104_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trusts and Other Financial Arrangements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) but such individual shall report the category of the amount of income received by the individual, the individual’s spouse, or any dependent child from the trust or other entity under subsection (a)(1)(B).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13104_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Political Campaign Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Political campaign funds, including campaign receipts and expenditures, need not be included in any report filed pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13104_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gifts and Reimbursements Received While Individual Not Officer or Employee of Federal Government.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) A report filed pursuant to subsection (a), (d), or (e) of section 13103 of this title need not contain the information described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of subsection (a)(2) with respect to gifts and reimbursements received in a period when the reporting individual was not an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13104_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Reportable Retirement Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A reporting individual shall not be required under this subchapter to report—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>