<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13103"><akn:num>13103</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons required to file</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13103. Persons required to file(a) Reports Filed Upon Entering a Filing Position.—Within 30 days of assuming the position of an officer or employee described in subsection (f), an individual shall file a report containing the information described in section 13104(b) of this title unless the individual has left another position described in subsection (f) within 30 days prior to assuming such new position or has already filed a report under this subchapter with respect to nomination for the new position or as a candidate for the position.

(b) Reports for Nominees to Positions Requiring Senate Confirmation.—(1) In general.—Within 5 days of the transmittal by the President to the Senate of the nomination of an individual (other than an individual nominated for appointment to a position as a Foreign Service Officer or a grade or rank in the uniformed services for which the pay grade prescribed by section 201 of title 37 is O–6 or below) to a position, appointment to which requires the advice and consent of the Senate, such individual shall file a report containing the information described in section 13104(b) of this title. Such individual shall, not later than the date of the first hearing to consider the nomination of such individual, make current the report filed pursuant to this paragraph by filing the information required by section 13104(a)(1)(A) of this title with respect to income and honoraria received as of the date which occurs 5 days before the date of such hearing. Nothing in this chapter shall prevent any congressional committee from requesting, as a condition of confirmation, any additional financial information from any Presidential nominee whose nomination has been referred to that committee.

(2) Public announcement of intended nomination.—An individual whom the President or the President-elect has publicly announced he or she intends to nominate to a position may file the report required by paragraph (1) at any time after that public announcement,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports Filed Upon Entering a Filing Position.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Within 30 days of assuming the position of an officer or employee described in subsection (f), an individual shall file a report containing the information described in section 13104(b) of this title unless the individual has left another position described in subsection (f) within 30 days prior to assuming such new position or has already filed a report under this subchapter with respect to nomination for the new position or as a candidate for the position.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports for Nominees to Positions Requiring Senate Confirmation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports for Candidates for Elected Federal Office.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Within 30 days of becoming a candidate as defined in section 301 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (52 U.S.C. 30101), in a calendar year for nomination or election to the office of President, Vice President, or Member of Congress, or on or before May 15 of that calendar year, whichever is later, but in no event later than 30 days before the election, and on or before May 15 of each successive year an individual continues to be a candidate, an individual other than an incumbent President, Vice President, or Member of Congress shall file a report containing the information described in section 13104(b) of this title. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, in any calendar year in which an individual continues to be a candidate for any office but all elections for such office relating to such candidacy were held in prior calendar years, such individual need not file a report unless the individual becomes a candidate for another vacancy in that office or another office durin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Any individual who is an officer or employee described in subsection (f) during any calendar year and performs the duties of the position or office for a period in excess of 60 days in that calendar year shall file on or before May 15 of the succeeding year a report containing the information described in section 13104(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13103_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Any individual who occupies a position described in subsection (f) shall, on or before the 30th day after termination of employment in such position, file a report containing the information described in section 13104(a) of this title covering the preceding calendar year if the report required by subsection (d) has not been filed and covering the portion of the calendar year in which such termination occurs up to the date the individual left such office or position, unless such individual has accepted employment in another position described in subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13103_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals Required To File.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The officers and employees referred to in subsections (a), (d), and (e) are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13103_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extensions of Time for Filing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13103_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The provisions of subsections (a), (b), and (e) shall not apply to an individual who, as determined by the designated agency ethics official or Secretary concerned (or in the case of a Presidential appointee under subsection (b), the Director of the Office of Government Ethics), the congressional ethics committees, or the Judicial Conference, is not reasonably expected to perform the duties of the individual’s office or position for more than 60 days in a calendar year, except that if such individual performs the duties of the office or position for more than 60 days in a calendar year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>