<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13123" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13123/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13123/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13123"><akn:num>13123</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13123. Administrative provisions(a) Assistance to Director.—Upon the request of the Director, each executive agency is directed to—(1) make its services, personnel, and facilities available to the Director to the greatest practicable extent for the performance of functions under this chapter; and

(2) except when prohibited by law, furnish to the Director all information and records in its possession which the Director may determine to be necessary for the performance of the Director’s duties.


The authority of the Director under this section includes the authority to request assistance from the inspector general of an agency in conducting investigations pursuant to the Office of Government Ethics responsibilities under this chapter. The head of any agency may detail such personnel and furnish such services, with or without reimbursement, as the Director may request to carry out the provisions of this chapter.

(b) Gift Acceptance Authority.—(1) In general.—The Director is authorized to accept and utilize on behalf of the United States, any gift, donation, bequest, or devise of money, use of facilities, personal property, or services for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Office of Government Ethics.

(2) Limitations.—No gift may be accepted—(A) that attaches conditions inconsistent with applicable laws or regulations; or

(B) that is conditioned upon or will require the expenditure of appropriated funds that are not available to the Office of Government Ethics.


(3) Criteria for determining appropriateness of gift acceptance.—The Director shall establish written rules setting forth the criteria to be used in determining whether the acceptance of contributions of money, services, use of facilities, or personal property under this subsection would reflect unfavorably upon the ability of the Office of Government Ethics, or any employee of such Office, to carry out its responsibilities or official duties in a fair and objective manner, or would c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13123_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to Director.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Upon the request of the Director, each executive agency is directed to— The authority of the Director under this section includes the authority to request assistance from the inspector general of an agency in conducting investigations pursuant to the Office of Government Ethics responsibilities under this chapter. The head of any agency may detail such personnel and furnish such services, with or without reimbursement, as the Director may request to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13123_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gift Acceptance Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>