<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13146" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13146/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/13146/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13146"><akn:num>13146</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditional termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13146. Conditional termination
This subchapter shall cease to be effective if the provisions of section 703 of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 (Public Law 101–194, 5 U.S.C. 5318 note) are repealed.
(Pub. L. 117–286, § 3(c), Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4305.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


13146(no source)


This section is added in accordance with section 603 of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 (Public Law 101–194, 26 U.S.C. 7701 note). Section 603 of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 provides that amendments made by title VI of the Act (103 Stat. 1760) shall cease to be effective if the provisions of section 703 of the Act (5 U.S.C. 5318 note) are repealed, in which case the laws in effect before the amendments made by title VI of the Act shall be deemed to be reenacted. Among other things, the amendments made by title VI of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 enacted a general rewrite of title V of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, which is restated as this subchapter. If the provisions of section 703 of the Ethics Reform Act of 1989 (Public Law 101–194, 5 U.S.C. 5318 note) are repealed, then this subchapter shall cease to be effective, and the prior provisions of title V of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 shall be deemed to be reenacted. The prior provisions of title V of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (Public Law 95–521, 92 Stat. 1864) relate to an amendment to section 207 of title 18, United States Code, which has previously been executed to text.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>