<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/2905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/2905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/2905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2905"><akn:num>2905</akn:num><akn:heading>Oath; renewal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2905. Oath; renewal(a) An employee of an Executive agency or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia who, on original appointment, subscribed to the oath of office required by section 3331 of this title is not required to renew the oath because of a change in status so long as his service is continuous in the agency in which he is employed, unless, in the opinion of the head of the Executive agency, the Secretary of a military department with respect to an employee of his department, or the Commissioners of the District of Columbia, the public interest so requires.

(b) An individual who, on appointment as an employee of a House of Congress, subscribed to the oath of office required by section 3331 of this title is not required to renew the oath so long as his service as an employee of that House of Congress is continuous.

(Pub. L. 89–554, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 412.)











Historical and Revision Notes


DerivationU.S. CodeRevised Statutes andStatutes at Large


(a)5 U.S.C. 17b.Aug. 14, 1937, ch. 624, 50 Stat. 640.Nov. 22, 1943, ch. 303, 57 Stat. 591.
(b)5 U.S.C. 17c.Mar. 28, 1955, ch. 17, 69 Stat. 14.


In subsection (a), the word “civilian” is omitted as unnecessary because of the definition of “employee” in section 2105. The words “Executive agency” are coextensive with and substituted for “executive departments and independent establishments of the United States” because of the definition of “Executive agency” in section 105. The words “the Secretary of a military department with respect to an employee of his department” are inserted to preserve the application of the source law. Before enactment of the National Security Act Amendments of 1949 (63 Stat. 578), the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, and the Department of the Air Force were Executive departments. The National Security Act Amendments of 1949 established the Department of Defense as an Executive Department including the Department of the Army, t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An employee of an Executive agency or an individual employed by the government of the District of Columbia who, on original appointment, subscribed to the oath of office required by section 3331 of this title is not required to renew the oath because of a change in status so long as his service is continuous in the agency in which he is employed, unless, in the opinion of the head of the Executive agency, the Secretary of a military department with respect to an employee of his department, or the Commissioners of the District of Columbia, the public interest so requires.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An individual who, on appointment as an employee of a House of Congress, subscribed to the oath of office required by section 3331 of this title is not required to renew the oath so long as his service as an employee of that House of Congress is continuous.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>