<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3116" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3116/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3116/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3116"><akn:num>3116</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited hiring authority for post-secondary students; competitive service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3116. Expedited hiring authority for post-secondary students; competitive service(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Director.—The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.

(2) Institution of higher education.—The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1001(a)).

(3) Student.—The term “student” means an individual enrolled or accepted for enrollment in an institution of higher education who is pursuing a baccalaureate or graduate degree on at least a part-time basis as determined by the institution of higher education.


(b) Appointment.—(1) In general.—The head of an agency may make a time-limited appointment of a student, without regard to any provision of sections 3309 through 3319 and 3330, to a position in the competitive service at the GS–11 level, or an equivalent level, or below for which the student is qualified.

(2) Restrictions.—An appointment under paragraph (1) shall be made in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Director.


(c) Public Notice.—(1) In general.—The head of an agency making an appointment under subsection (b) shall publicly advertise positions available under this section.

(2) Requirements.—In carrying out paragraph (1), the head of an agency shall—(A) adhere to merit system principles;

(B) advertise positions in a manner that provides for diverse and qualified applicants; and

(C) ensure potential applicants have appropriate information relevant to the positions available.



(d) Limitation on Appointments.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), the total number of students that the head of an agency may appoint under this section during a fiscal year may not exceed the number equal to 15 percent of the number of students that the agency head appointed during the previous fiscal year to a position at the GS–11 level, or an equivalent level, or below.

(2) Exceptions.—Under a regulat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3116_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3116_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3116_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Notice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3116_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Appointments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3116_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The head of an agency may, without regard to any provision of chapter 33 or any other provision of law relating to the examination, certification, and appointment of individuals in the competitive service, convert a student serving in an appointment under subsection (b) to a permanent appointment in the competitive service within the agency without further competition if the student—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3116_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The head of an agency shall, without regard to any provision of chapter 35 or 75, terminate the appointment of a student appointed under subsection (b) upon completion of the designated academic course of study unless the student is selected for conversion under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3116_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Director shall issue interim regulations, with an opportunity for comment, for the administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3116_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3116_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Provision Regarding the Department of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>