<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3161" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3161/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3161/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3161"><akn:num>3161</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment and compensation of employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3161. Employment and compensation of employees(a) Definition of Temporary Organization.—For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “temporary organization” means a commission, committee, board, or other organization that—(1) is established by law or Executive order for a specific period not in excess of three years for the purpose of performing a specific study or other project; and

(2) is terminated upon the completion of the study or project or upon the occurrence of a condition related to the completion of the study or project.


(b) Employment Authority.—(1) Notwithstanding the provisions of chapter 51 of this title, the head of a temporary organization may appoint persons to positions of employment in a temporary organization in such numbers and with such skills as are necessary for the performance of the functions required of a temporary organization.

(2) The period of an appointment under paragraph (1) may not exceed three years, except that under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management the period of appointment may be extended for up to an additional two years.

(3) The positions of employment in a temporary organization are in the excepted service of the civil service.


(c) Detail Authority.—Upon the request of the head of a temporary organization, the head of any department or agency of the Government may detail, on a nonreimbursable basis, any personnel of the department or agency to that organization to assist in carrying out its duties.

(d) Compensation.—(1) The rate of basic pay for an employee appointed under subsection (b) shall be established under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of this title.

(2) The rate of basic pay for the chairman, a member, an executive director, a staff director, or another executive level position of a temporary organization may not exceed the maximum rate of basic pay established for t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3161_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of Temporary Organization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “temporary organization” means a commission, committee, board, or other organization that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3161_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3161_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Upon the request of the head of a temporary organization, the head of any department or agency of the Government may detail, on a nonreimbursable basis, any personnel of the department or agency to that organization to assist in carrying out its duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3161_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3161_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) An employee of a temporary organization, whether employed on a full-time or part-time basis, may be allowed travel and transportation expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of this title, while traveling away from the employee’s regular place of business in the performance of services for the temporary organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3161_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) An employee appointed under subsection (b) shall be afforded the same benefits and entitlements as are provided temporary employees under this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3161_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return Rights.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) An employee serving under a career or career conditional appointment or the equivalent in an agency who transfers to or converts to an appointment in a temporary organization with the consent of the head of the agency is entitled to be returned to the employee’s former position or a position of like seniority, status, and pay without grade or pay retention in the agency if the employee—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3161_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary and Intermittent Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The head of a temporary organization may procure for the organization temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3161_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of Volunteer Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>