<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3303" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3303/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3303/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3303"><akn:num>3303</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive service; recommendations of Senators or Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3303. Competitive service; recommendations of Senators or Representatives
An individual concerned in examining an applicant for or appointing him in the competitive service may not receive or consider a recommendation of the applicant by a Senator or Representative, except as to the character or residence of the applicant.
(Pub. L. 89–554, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 418; Pub. L. 103–94, § 8(a), Oct. 6, 1993, 107 Stat. 1006; Pub. L. 104–197, title III, § 315(a), Sept. 16, 1996, 110 Stat. 2416.)











Historical and Revision Notes


DerivationU.S. CodeRevised Statutes andStatutes at Large


 5 U.S.C. 642.Jan. 16, 1883, ch. 27, § 10, 22 Stat. 406.


The prohibition is restated in positive form. The words “An individual concerned in examining an applicant for or appointing him in the competitive service” are substituted for “any person concerned in making any examination or appointment under this act”. The word “applicant” is substituted for “person who shall apply for office or place under the provisions of this act”. The word “Representative” is substituted for “Member of the House of Representatives”.
Standard changes are made to conform with the definitions applicable and the style of this title as outlined in the preface to the report.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–197 substituted “Competitive service; recommendations of Senators or Representatives” for “Political recommendations” in section catchline and amended text generally, substituting provisions prohibiting receipt or consideration of recommendations of applicants in competitive service made by Senators or Representatives for provisions which directed that personnel actions be taken without solicitation of or regard to such recommendations from Members of Congress, congressional employees, any elected official of the government of any State (including D.C. and Puerto Rico) or subdivision thereof, or political party official, prohibited such persons from making such recommendations, prohibit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>