<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3304"><akn:num>3304</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive service; examinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3304. Competitive service; examinations(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Agency.—The term “agency” means an Executive agency.

(2) Director.—The term “Director” means the Director of the Office.

(3) Examination.—The term “examination” means the process by which an applicant demonstrates knowledge, skills, abilities, and competencies.

(4) Examining agency.—The term “examining agency” means—(A) the Office; or

(B) an agency to which the Director has delegated examining authority under section 1104(a)(2).


(5) Office.—The term “Office” means the Office of Personnel Management.

(6) Passing score.—The term “passing score” means a minimum acceptable score or rating, consistent with applicable law, that may include a quantitative or qualitative assessment that an applicant can pass or fail.

(7) Relevant committees.—The term “relevant committees” means—(A) the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives.


(8) Subject matter expert.—The term “subject matter expert” means an employee or selecting official—(A) who possesses an understanding of the duties of, and knowledge, skills, and abilities required for, the position for which the employee or selecting official is developing or administering an examination; and

(B) whom the delegated examining unit of the examining agency that employs the employee or selecting official designates to assist in the development and administration of technical assessments.


(9) Technical assessment.—The term “technical assessment” means a position-specific tool that is relevant to the position for which the tool is developed that—(A) allows for the demonstration of job-related skills, abilities, knowledge, and competencies;

(B) is based upon a job analysis; and

(C) does not solely include or principally rely upon a self-assessment from an automated examination.



(b) Rules.—The President may prescribe rules which sh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The President may prescribe rules which shall provide, as nearly as conditions of good administration warrant, for— The Office shall prescribe, by regulation, criteria for identifying such positions and may delegate authority to make determinations under such criteria.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examinations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Assessment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Agency Talent Teams.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Personnel Management Talent Team.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Director may establish a Federal talent team to support agency talent teams by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Director shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to implement and interpret this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination or Exception Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) An individual may be appointed in the competitive service only if he has passed an examination or is specifically excepted from examination under section 3302 of this title. This subsection does not take from the President any authority conferred by section 3301 of this title that is consistent with the provisions of this title governing the competitive service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technicians.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3304_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of Experience.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The office 22 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. of Personnel Management shall promulgate regulations on the manner and extent that experience of an individual in a position other than the competitive service, such as the excepted service (as defined under section 2103) in the legislative or judicial branch, or in any private or nonprofit enterprise, may be considered in making appointments to a position in the competitive service (as defined under section 2102). In promulgating such regulations OPM shall not grant any preference based on the fact of service in the legislative or judicial branch. The regulations shall be consistent with the principles of equitable competition and merit based appointments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>