<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/3502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3502"><akn:num>3502</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of retention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3502. Order of retention(a) The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations for the release of competing employees in a reduction in force which give due effect to—(1) tenure of employment;

(2) military preference, subject to section 3501(a)(3) of this title;

(3) length of service; and

(4) efficiency or performance ratings.


In computing length of service, a competing employee—
(A) who is not a retired member of a uniformed service is entitled to credit for the total length of time in active service in the armed forces;

(B) who is a retired member of a uniformed service is entitled to credit for—(i) the length of time in active service in the armed forces during a war, or in a campaign or expedition for which a campaign badge has been authorized; or

(ii) the total length of time in active service in the armed forces if he is included under section 3501(a)(3)(A), (B), or (C) of this title; and


(C) is entitled to credit for—(i) service rendered as an employee of a county committee established pursuant to section 8(b) of the Soil Conservation and Allotment Act or of a committee or association of producers described in section 10(b) of the Agricultural Adjustment Act; and

(ii) service rendered as an employee described in section 2105(c) if such employee moves or has moved, on or after January 1, 1966, without a break in service of more than 3 days, from a position in a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard to a position in the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively, that is not described in section 2105(c).



(b) A preference eligible described in section 2108(3)(C) of this title who has a compensable service-connected disability of 30 percent or more and whose performance has not been rated unacceptable under a performance appraisal system implemented under chapter 43 of this title is entitled to be retained in preference to other preference eligibles.

(c) An employee who is enti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe regulations for the release of competing employees in a reduction in force which give due effect to— In computing length of service, a competing employee—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A preference eligible described in section 2108(3)(C) of this title who has a compensable service-connected disability of 30 percent or more and whose performance has not been rated unacceptable under a performance appraisal system implemented under chapter 43 of this title is entitled to be retained in preference to other preference eligibles.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3502_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An employee who is entitled to retention preference and whose performance has not been rated unacceptable under a performance appraisal system implemented under chapter 43 of this title is entitled to be retained in preference to other competing employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3502_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3502_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3502_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>