<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/405" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/405/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/405/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_405"><akn:num>405</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 405. Reports(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Disallowed cost.—The term “disallowed cost” means a questioned cost that management, in a management decision, has sustained or agreed should not be charged to the Government.

(2) Final action.—The term “final action” means—(A) the completion of all actions that the management of an establishment has concluded, in its management decision, are necessary with respect to the findings and recommendations included in an audit report; and

(B) in the event that the management of an establishment concludes no action is necessary, final action occurs when a management decision has been made.


(3) Management decision.—The term “management decision” means the evaluation by the management of an establishment of the findings and recommendations included in an audit report and the issuance of a final decision by management concerning its response to the findings and recommendations, including actions concluded to be necessary.

(4) Questioned cost.—The term “questioned cost” means a cost that is questioned by the Office because of—(A) an alleged violation of a provision of a law, regulation, contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or other agreement or document governing the expenditure of funds;

(B) a finding that, at the time of the audit, the cost is not supported by adequate documentation; or

(C) a finding that the expenditure of funds for the intended purpose is unnecessary or unreasonable.


(5) Recommendation that funds be put to better use.—The term “recommendation that funds be put to better use” means a recommendation by the Office that funds could be used more efficiently if management of an establishment took actions to implement and complete the recommendation, including—(A) reductions in outlays;

(B) deobligation of funds from programs or operations;

(C) withdrawal of interest subsidy costs on loans or loan guarantees, insurance, or bonds;

(D) costs not incurred by implementing recommended improvements relat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_405_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_405_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Semiannual Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Each Inspector General shall, not later than April 30 and October 31 of each year, prepare semiannual reports summarizing the activities of the Office during the immediately preceding 6-month periods ending March 31 and September 30. The reports shall include, but need not be limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_405_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing Semiannual Reports to Head of Establishment and Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Semiannual reports of each Inspector General shall be furnished to the head of the establishment involved not later than April 30 and October 31 of each year and shall be transmitted by the head of the establishment to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of the Congress within 30 days after receipt of the report, together with a report by the head of the establishment containing— except that the statement may exclude any audit reports that are under formal administrative or judicial appeal or upon which management of an establishment has agreed to pursue a legislative solution, but the statement shall identify the number of reports in each category so excluded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_405_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports Available to Public.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Within 60 days of the transmission of the semiannual reports of each Inspector General to Congress, the head of each establishment shall make copies of the report available to the public upon request and at a reasonable cost. Within 60 days after the transmission of the semiannual reports of each establishment head to Congress, the head of each establishment shall make copies of the report available to the public upon request and at a reasonable cost.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_405_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting Serious Problems, Abuses, or Deficiencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Each Inspector General shall report immediately to the head of the establishment involved whenever the Inspector General becomes aware of particularly serious or flagrant problems, abuses, or deficiencies relating to the administration of programs and operations of the establishment. The head of the establishment shall transmit any such report to the appropriate committees or subcommittees of Congress within 7 calendar days, together with a report by the head of the establishment containing any comments the establishment head deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_405_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Public Disclosure of Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>