<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/412" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/412/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/412/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_412"><akn:num>412</akn:num><akn:heading>Special provisions concerning the Department of the Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 412. Special provisions concerning the Department of the Treasury(a) In General.—(1) Authority of secretary of treasury over certain audits and investigations.—Notwithstanding the 2d sentence and last sentence of section 403(a) of this title, the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of the Treasury with respect to audits or investigations, or the issuance of subpoenas, which require access to sensitive information concerning—(A) ongoing criminal investigations or proceedings;

(B) undercover operations;

(C) the identity of confidential sources, including protected witnesses;

(D) deliberations and decisions on policy matters, including documented information used as a basis for making policy decisions, the disclosure of which could reasonably be expected to have a significant influence on the economy or market behavior;

(E) intelligence or counterintelligence matters; or

(F) other matters the disclosure of which would constitute a serious threat to national security or to the protection of any person or property authorized protection by section 3056 of title 18, section 3056A of title 18, or any provision of the Presidential Protection Assistance Act of 1976 (Public Law 94–524, 18 U.S.C. 3056 note).


(2) Authority of secretary of treasury to prohibit carrying out or completing certain audits and investigations.—With respect to the information described under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury may prohibit the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury from carrying out or completing any audit or investigation, from accessing information described in paragraph (1), or from issuing any subpoena, after such Inspector General has decided to initiate, carry out, or complete such audit or investigation, access such information, or to issue such subpoena, if the Secretary determines that such prohibition is necessary to prevent the disclosure of any information des</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight Responsibility for Internal Investigations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits and Investigations in Department of Treasury.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury may initiate, conduct and supervise such audits and investigations in the Department of the Treasury (including the bureau referred to in subsection (b)) as the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Provide Written Notice to Tax and Trade Bureau.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury initiates an audit or investigation under subsection (c) concerning the bureau referred to in subsection (b), the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury may provide the head of the office of such bureau referred to in subsection (b) with written notice that the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury has initiated such an audit or investigation. If the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury issues a notice under the preceding sentence, no other audit or investigation shall be initiated into the matter under audit or investigation by the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury, and any other audit or investigation of such matter shall cease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit or Investigation Shall Not Affect Final Decision Under Section 6406 of Internal Revenue Code of 1986.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) An audit or investigation conducted by the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury or the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall not affect a final decision of the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s delegate under section 6406 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (26 U.S.C. 6406).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and Responsibilities of Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall exercise all duties and responsibilities of an Inspector General of an establishment with respect to the Department of the Treasury and the Secretary of the Treasury on all matters relating to the Internal Revenue Service. The Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration shall have sole authority under this chapter to conduct an audit or investigation of the Internal Revenue Service Oversight Board and the Chief Counsel for the Internal Revenue Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ability To Lead Large and Complex Organization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In addition to the requirements of the 1st sentence of section 403(a) of this title, the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration should have demonstrated ability to lead a large and complex organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Appointment of Employee of Internal Revenue Service to Certain Positions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) An individual appointed to the position of Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration, the Assistant Inspector General for Auditing of the Office of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration under section 403(d)(1)(B)(i) of this title (or, effective November 27, 2017, section 403(d)(2)(B)(i) of this title), the Assistant Inspector General for Investigations of the Office of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration under section 403(d)(1)(B)(ii) of this title (or, effective November 27, 2017, section 403(d)(2)(B)(ii) of this title), or any position of Deputy Inspector General of the Office of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration may not be an employee of the Internal Revenue Service—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>