<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/416" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/416/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/416/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_416"><akn:num>416</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional provisions with respect to Inspectors General of the intelligence community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 416. Additional provisions with respect to Inspectors General of the intelligence community(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Intelligence committees.—The term “intelligence committees” means the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.

(2) Urgent concern.—The term “urgent concern” means any of the following:(A) A serious or flagrant problem, abuse, violation of law or Executive order, or deficiency relating to the funding, administration, or operations of an intelligence activity involving classified information, but does not include differences of opinions concerning public policy matters.

(B) A false statement to Congress, or a willful withholding from Congress, on an issue of material fact relating to the funding, administration, or operation of an intelligence activity.

(C) An action, including a personnel action described in section 2302(a)(2)(A) of this title constituting reprisal or threat of reprisal prohibited under section 407(c) of this title in response to an employee’s reporting an urgent concern in accordance with this section.


(3) Employee.—The term “employee” includes a former employee or former contractor, if the complaint or information reported pursuant to this section arises from or relates to the period during which the former employee or former contractor was an employee or contractor, as the case may be.

(4) Intelligence community.—The term “intelligence community” has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (50 U.S.C. 3003).


(b) Complaint or Information With Respect to Urgent Concern.—(1) To whom reports may be made; support for written submission.—(A) Inspector general of department of defense.—An employee of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, the National Reconnaissance Office, or the National Security Agency, or of a contractor of any of those Agencies, who i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Complaint or Information With Respect to Urgent Concern.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial Determinations and Transmittals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forwarding Transmittals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Upon receipt of a transmittal from the Inspector General under subsection (c), the head of the establishment shall, within 7 calendar days of such receipt, forward such transmittal to the intelligence committees, together with any comments the head of the establishment considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submitting Complaint or Information to Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Inspector General shall notify an employee who reports a complaint or information under this section of each action taken under this section with respect to the complaint or information. Such notice shall be provided not later than 3 days after any such action is taken.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Judicial Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) An action taken by the head of an establishment or an Inspector General under subsections (b) through (f) shall not be subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of Submission and Date.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) An individual who has submitted a complaint or information to an Inspector General under this section may notify any member of the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives or the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, or a staff member of either such Committee, of the fact that such individual has made a submission to that particular Inspector General, and of the date on which such submission was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection for Individuals Making Authorized Disclosures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>