<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/423" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/423/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/423/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_423"><akn:num>423</akn:num><akn:heading>Pay of Inspectors General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 423. Pay of Inspectors General(a) Certain Inspectors General.—(1) In general.—Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the annual rate of basic pay of the Inspector General of the Intelligence Community, the Inspector General of the Central Intelligence Agency, and the Special Inspector General for Afghanistan Reconstruction shall be that of an Inspector General as defined under section 401 of this title.

(2) Prohibition of cash bonus or awards.—Section 403(f) of this title shall apply to the Inspectors General described under paragraph (1).


(b) Inspectors General of Designated Federal Entities.—Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Inspector General of each designated Federal entity (as those terms are defined under section 415(a) of this title) shall, for pay and all other purposes, be classified at a grade, level, or rank designation, as the case may be, at or above those of a majority of the senior level executives of that designated Federal entity (such as a General Counsel, Chief Information Officer, Chief Financial Officer, Chief Human Capital Officer, or Chief Acquisition Officer). The pay of an Inspector General of a designated Federal entity (as those terms are defined under section 415(a) of this title) shall be not less than the average total compensation (including bonuses) of the senior level executives of that designated Federal entity calculated on an annual basis.

(c) Savings Provision for Newly Appointed Inspectors General.—(1) In general.—The provisions of section 3392 of this title, other than the terms “performance awards” and “awarding of ranks” in subsection (c)(1) of that section, shall apply to career appointees of the Senior Executive Service who are appointed to the position of Inspector General.

(2) Nonreduction in pay.—Notwithstanding any other provision of law, career Federal employees serving on an appointment made pursuant to statutory authority found other than in section 3392 of this title shall not suffer a redu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Inspectors General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspectors General of Designated Federal Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Inspector General of each designated Federal entity (as those terms are defined under section 415(a) of this title) shall, for pay and all other purposes, be classified at a grade, level, or rank designation, as the case may be, at or above those of a majority of the senior level executives of that designated Federal entity (such as a General Counsel, Chief Information Officer, Chief Financial Officer, Chief Human Capital Officer, or Chief Acquisition Officer). The pay of an Inspector General of a designated Federal entity (as those terms are defined under section 415(a) of this title) shall be not less than the average total compensation (including bonuses) of the senior level executives of that designated Federal entity calculated on an annual basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings Provision for Newly Appointed Inspectors General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>