<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5304a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5304a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5304a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5304a"><akn:num>5304a</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to fix an alternative level of comparability payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5304a. Authority to fix an alternative level of comparability payments(a) If, because of national emergency or serious economic conditions affecting the general welfare, the President should consider the level of comparability payments which would otherwise be payable under section 5304 in any year to be inappropriate, the President shall—(1) prepare and transmit to Congress, at least 1 month before those comparability payments (disregarding this section) would otherwise become payable, a report describing the alternative level of payments which the President instead intends to provide, including the reasons why such alternative level is considered necessary; and

(2) implement the alternative level of payments beginning on the same date as would otherwise apply, for the year involved, under section 5304.


(b) The requirements set forth in paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively, of section 5303(b) shall apply with respect to any decision to exercise any authority to fix an alternative level of comparability payments under this section.

(Added Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 101(a)(1)], Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1427, 1436.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on such date as the President shall determine, but not earlier than 90 days, and not later than 180 days, after Nov. 5, 1990, see section 529 [title III, § 305] of Pub. L. 101–509, set out as an Effective Date of 1990 Amendment note under section 5301 of this title.

Special Rule Relating to Comparability Payments in 1994Pub. L. 101–509, title VI, § 634, Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1482, provided that:
“Notwithstanding any other provision of law (including any provision of the Federal Employees Pay Comparability Act of 1990 [see Short Title of 1990 Amendment note set out under section 5301 of this title] and any provision of law amended by such Act), for purposes of any comparability payments scheduled to take effect under section 5304 of title 5, United States Code</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) If, because of national emergency or serious economic conditions affecting the general welfare, the President should consider the level of comparability payments which would otherwise be payable under section 5304 in any year to be inappropriate, the President shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The requirements set forth in paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively, of section 5303(b) shall apply with respect to any decision to exercise any authority to fix an alternative level of comparability payments under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>