<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5304"><akn:num>5304</akn:num><akn:heading>Locality-based comparability payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5304. Locality-based comparability payments(a) Pay disparities shall be identified and reduced as follows:(1) Comparability payments shall be payable within each locality determined to have a pay disparity greater than 5 percent.

(2)(A) The localities having pay disparities, and the size of those disparities, shall, for purposes of any comparability payment scheduled to take effect in any calendar year, be determined in accordance with the appropriate report, as prepared and submitted to the President under subsection (d)(1) for purposes of such calendar year.

(B) Any computation necessary to determine the size of the comparability payment to become payable for any locality in a year (as well as any determination as to the size of any pay disparity remaining after that comparability payment is made) shall likewise be made using data contained in the appropriate report (described in subparagraph (A)) so prepared and submitted for purposes of such calendar year.


(3) Subject to paragraph (4), the amount of the comparability payments payable under this subsection in a calendar year within any locality in which a comparability payment is payable shall be computed using such percentage as the President determines for such locality under subsection (d)(2), except that—(A) the percentage for the first calendar year in which any amounts are payable under this section may not be less than ⅕ of the amount needed to reduce the pay disparity of the locality involved to 5 percent;

(B) the percentage for the second calendar year in which any amounts are payable under this section may not be less than 3⁄10 of the amount needed to reduce the pay disparity of the locality involved to 5 percent;

(C) the percentage for the third calendar year in which any amounts are payable under this section may not be less than ⅖ of the amount needed to reduce the pay disparity of the locality involved to 5 percent;

(D) the percentage for the fourth calendar year in which any amounts are pa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pay disparities shall be identified and reduced as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) After the ninth calendar year (referred to in subsection (a)(3)(I)), the level of comparability payments payable within such locality may be reduced for any subsequent calendar year, but only if, or to the extent that, the reduction would not immediately create another pay disparity in excess of 5 percent within the locality (taking into consideration any comparability payments remaining payable).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In order to carry out this section, the President shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5304_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Office of Personnel Management may prescribe regulations, consistent with the provisions of this section, governing the payment of comparability payments to employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>