<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5305"><akn:num>5305</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5305. Special pay authority(a)(1) Whenever the Office of Personnel Management finds that the Government’s recruitment or retention efforts with respect to 1 or more occupations in 1 or more areas or locations are, or are likely to become, significantly handicapped due to any of the circumstances described in subsection (b), the Office may establish for the areas or locations involved, with respect to individuals in positions paid under any of the pay systems referred to in subsection (c), higher minimum rates of pay for 1 or more grades or levels, occupational groups, series, classes, or subdivisions thereof, and may make corresponding increases in all rates of the pay range for each such grade or level. However, a minimum rate so established may not exceed the maximum rate of basic pay (excluding any locality-based comparability payment under section 5304 or similar provision of law) for the grade or level by more than 30 percent, and no rate may be established under this section in excess of the rate of basic pay payable for level IV of the Executive Schedule. In the case of individuals not subject to the provisions of this title governing appointment in the competitive service, the President may designate another agency to authorize special rates under this section.

(2) The head of an agency may determine that a category of employees of the agency will not be covered by a special rate authorization established under this section. The head of an agency shall provide written notice to the Office of Personnel Management (or other agency designated by the President to authorize special rates under the last sentence of paragraph (1)) which identifies the specific category or categories of employees that will not be covered by special rates authorized under this section. If the head of an agency removes a category of employees from coverage under a special rate authorization after that authorization takes effect, the loss of coverage will take effect on the first da</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The circumstances referred to in subsection (a) are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority under subsection (a) may be exercised with respect to positions paid under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Within the limitations applicable under the preceding provisions of this section, rates of pay established under this section may be revised from time to time by the Office of Personnel Management (or by such other agency as the President may designate under the last sentence of subsection (a)(1)). The actions and revisions have the force and effect of statute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) An increase in a rate of pay established under this section is not an equivalent increase in pay within the meaning of section 5335.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) When a schedule of special rates established under this section is adjusted under subsection (d), a covered employee’s special rate will be adjusted in accordance with conversion rules prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management (or by such other agency as the President may under the last sentence of subsection (a)(1) designate).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) An employee shall not for any purpose be considered to be entitled to a rate of pay established under this section with respect to any period for which such employee is entitled to a higher rate of basic pay under any other provision of law. For purposes of this subsection, the term “basic pay” includes any applicable locality-based comparability payment under section 5304 or similar provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) If an employee who is receiving a rate of pay under this section becomes subject, by virtue of moving to a new official duty station, to a different pay schedule, such employee’s new rate of pay shall be initially established under conversion rules prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management (or such other agency as the President may under the last sentence of subsection (a)(1) designate) in conformance with the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5305_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) A rate determined under a schedule of special rates established under this section shall be considered to be part of basic pay for purposes of subchapter III of chapter 83, chapter 84, chapter 87, subchapter V of chapter 55, and section 5941, and for such other purposes as may be expressly provided for by law or as the Office of Personnel Management may by regulation prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>