<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5311"><akn:num>5311</akn:num><akn:heading>The Executive Schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5311. The Executive Schedule
The Executive Schedule, which is divided into five pay levels, is the basic pay schedule for positions, other than Senior Executive Service positions and positions in the Federal Bureau of Investigation and Drug Enforcement Administration Senior Executive Service, to which this subchapter applies.
(Pub. L. 89–554, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 459; Pub. L. 95–454, title IV, §§ 408(b)(1), 414(b)(1), Oct. 13, 1978, 92 Stat. 1173, 1178; Pub. L. 96–54, § 2(a)(24), Aug. 14, 1979, 93 Stat. 382; Pub. L. 100–325, § 2(h)(1), (2), May 30, 1988, 102 Stat. 582; Pub. L. 101–509, title V, § 529 [title I, § 104(c)], Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1427, 1447.)











Historical and Revision Notes


DerivationU.S. CodeRevised Statutes andStatutes at Large


 5 U.S.C. 2210.Aug. 14, 1964, Pub. L. 88–426, § 302, 78 Stat. 415.


The words “There is hereby established” are omitted as executed. The word “offices” is omitted as included in “positions”. The words “Executive Schedule” are substituted for “Federal Executive Salary Schedule”.
Standard changes are made to conform with the definitions applicable and the style of this title as outlined in the preface to the report.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1990—Pub. L. 101–509 struck out “(a)” before “The Executive Schedule, which” and struck out subsec. (b) which read as follows:
“(1) Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Civil Service Reform Act of 1978, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall determine the number and classification of executive level positions in existence in the executive branch on that date of enactment, and shall publish the determination in the Federal Register. Effective beginning on the date of the publication, the number of executive level positions within the executive branch may not exceed the number published under this subsection.
“(2) For the purpose of this subsection, ‘executive level position’ means—
“(A) any office or position in the civil servic</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>