<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5563" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5563/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5563/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5563"><akn:num>5563</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotments; continuance, suspension, initiation, resumption, or increase while in a missing status; </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5563. Allotments; continuance, suspension, initiation, resumption, or increase while in a missing status; limitations(a) An allotment (including one for the purchase of United States savings bonds) made by an employee before he was in a missing status may be continued for the period he is in that status, notwithstanding the end of the period for which the allotment was made.

(b) In the absence of an allotment or when an allotment is insufficient for a purpose authorized by the head of the agency concerned, he or his designee may authorize such a new or increased allotment as circumstances warrant, which is payable for the period the employee concerned is in a missing status.

(c) All allotments from the pay and allowances of an employee in a missing status may not total more than the amount of pay and allowances he is permitted to allot under regulations prescribed by the head of the agency concerned.

(d) A premium paid by the United States on insurance issued on the life of an employee, which is unearned because it covers a period after his death, reverts to the appropriation of the agency concerned.

(e) Subject to subsections (f) and (g) of this section, the head of the agency concerned or his designee may direct the initiation, continuance, discontinuance, increase, decrease, suspension, or resumption of an allotment from the pay and allowances of an employee in a missing status when that action is in the interests of the employee, his dependents, or the United States.

(f) When the head of the agency concerned officially reports that an employee in a missing status is alive, an allotment under subsections (a)–(d) of this section may be paid, subject to section 5562 of this title, until the date the head of the agency concerned receives evidence that the employee is dead or has returned to the controllable jurisdiction of the agency concerned.

(g) When an employee in a missing status is continued in that status under section 5565 of this title, an allotment</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5563_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An allotment (including one for the purchase of United States savings bonds) made by an employee before he was in a missing status may be continued for the period he is in that status, notwithstanding the end of the period for which the allotment was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5563_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In the absence of an allotment or when an allotment is insufficient for a purpose authorized by the head of the agency concerned, he or his designee may authorize such a new or increased allotment as circumstances warrant, which is payable for the period the employee concerned is in a missing status.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5563_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) All allotments from the pay and allowances of an employee in a missing status may not total more than the amount of pay and allowances he is permitted to allot under regulations prescribed by the head of the agency concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5563_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A premium paid by the United States on insurance issued on the life of an employee, which is unearned because it covers a period after his death, reverts to the appropriation of the agency concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5563_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subject to subsections (f) and (g) of this section, the head of the agency concerned or his designee may direct the initiation, continuance, discontinuance, increase, decrease, suspension, or resumption of an allotment from the pay and allowances of an employee in a missing status when that action is in the interests of the employee, his dependents, or the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5563_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) When the head of the agency concerned officially reports that an employee in a missing status is alive, an allotment under subsections (a)–(d) of this section may be paid, subject to section 5562 of this title, until the date the head of the agency concerned receives evidence that the employee is dead or has returned to the controllable jurisdiction of the agency concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5563_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) When an employee in a missing status is continued in that status under section 5565 of this title, an allotment under subsections (a)–(d) of this section may be continued, increased, or initiated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5563_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) When the head of the agency concerned considers it essential for the well-being and protection of the dependents of an employee in active service (other than an employee in a missing status), he may, with or without the consent of the employee and subject to termination on specific request of the employee—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>