<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5595" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5595/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5595/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5595"><akn:num>5595</akn:num><akn:heading>Severance pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5595. Severance pay(a) For the purpose of this section—(1) “agency” means—(A) an Executive agency;

(B) the Library of Congress;

(C) the Government Publishing Office;

(D) the government of the District of Columbia;

(E) the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, the Federal Judicial Center, and the courts named by section 610 of title 28; and

(F) the Office of the Architect of the Capitol; and


(2) “employee” means—(A) an individual employed in or under an agency; and

(B) an individual employed by a county committee established under section 590h(b) of title 16;


but does not include—
(i) an employee (other than a member of the Senior Executive Service or the Federal Bureau of Investigation and Drug Enforcement Administration Senior Executive Service, or an employee whose pay is fixed under section 5376) whose rate of basic pay is fixed at a rate provided for one of the levels of the Executive Schedule or is in excess of the maximum rate for the Executive Schedule;

(ii) an employee serving under an appointment with a definite time limitation, except one so appointed for full-time employment without a break in service of more than 3 days following service under an appointment without time limitation;

(iii) an alien employee who occupies a position outside the several States, the District of Columbia, and the areas and installations in the Republic of Panama made available to the United States pursuant to the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 and related agreements (as described in section 3(a) of the Panama Canal Act of 1979);

(iv) an employee who is subject to subchapter III of chapter 83 of this title or any other retirement statute or retirement system applicable to an employee as defined by section 2105 of this title or a member of a uniformed service and who, at the time of separation from the service, has fulfilled the requirements for immediate annuity under such a statute or system;

(v) an employee who, at the time of separation from the ser</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under regulations prescribed by the President or such officer or agency as he may designate, an employee who— is entitled to be paid severance pay in regular pay periods by the agency from which separated. However, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts may prescribe regulations to effect the application and operation of this section to the agencies specified in subsection (a)(1)(E) of this section. The Architect of the Capitol may prescribe regulations to effect the application and operation of this section to the agency specified in subsection (a)(1)(F) of this section. The Director of the Government Publishing Office may prescribe regulations to effect the application and operation of this section to the agency specified in subsection (a)(1)(C) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Severance pay consists of— Total severance pay under this section may not exceed 1 year’s pay at the rate received immediately before separation. For the purpose of this subsection, “basic pay” includes premium pay under section 5545(c)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If an employee is reemployed by the Government of the United States or the government of the District of Columbia before the end of the period covered by payments of severance pay, the payments shall be discontinued beginning with the date of reemployment and the service represented by the unexpired portion of the period shall be recredited to the employee for use in any later computations of severance pay. For the purpose of subsection (b) (1) of this section, reemployment that causes severance pay to be discontinued is deemed employment continuous with that serving as the basis for severance pay.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If the employee dies before the end of the period covered by payments of severance pay, the payments of severance pay with respect to the employee shall be continued as if the employee were living and shall be paid on a pay period basis to the survivor of the employee in accordance with section 5582(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Severance pay under this section is not a basis for payment, and may not be included in the basis for computation, of any other type of United States or District of Columbia Government benefits. A period covered by severance pay is not a period of United States or District of Columbia Government service or employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Agriculture shall prescribe regulations to effect the application and operation of this section to an individual named by subsection (a)(2)(B) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5595_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>