<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5737a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5737a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5737a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5737a"><akn:num>5737a</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees temporarily deployed in contingency operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5737a. Employees temporarily deployed in contingency operations(a) Definitions.—For purposes of this section—(1) the term “covered employee” means an individual who—(A) is an employee of an Executive agency or a military department, excluding a Government controlled corporation; and

(B) is assigned on a temporary change of station in support of a contingency operation;


(2) the term “temporary change of station”, as used with respect to an employee, means an assignment—(A) from the employee’s official duty station to a temporary duty station; and

(B) for which such employee is eligible for expenses under section 5737; and


(3) the term “contingency operation” has the meaning given such term by section 1482a(c) of title 10.


(b) Quarters and Rations.—The head of an agency may provide quarters and rations, without charge, to any covered employee of such agency during the period of such employee’s temporary assignment (as described in subsection (a)(1)(B)).

(c) Storage of Motor Vehicle.—The head of an agency may provide for the storage, without charge, or for the reimbursement of the cost of storage, of a motor vehicle that is owned or leased by a covered employee of such agency (or by a dependent of such an employee) and that is for the personal use of the covered employee. This subsection shall apply—(1) with respect to storage during the period of the employee’s temporary assignment (as described in subsection (a)(1)(B)); and

(2) in the case of a covered employee, with respect to not more than one motor vehicle as of any given time.


(d) Relationship to Other Benefits.—Any benefits under this section shall be in addition to (and not in lieu of) any other benefits for which the covered employee is otherwise eligible.

(Added Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XI, § 1104(a), Jan. 28, 2008, 122 Stat. 346.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5737a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5737a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quarters and Rations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The head of an agency may provide quarters and rations, without charge, to any covered employee of such agency during the period of such employee’s temporary assignment (as described in subsection (a)(1)(B)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5737a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Storage of Motor Vehicle.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The head of an agency may provide for the storage, without charge, or for the reimbursement of the cost of storage, of a motor vehicle that is owned or leased by a covered employee of such agency (or by a dependent of such an employee) and that is for the personal use of the covered employee. This subsection shall apply—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5737a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Any benefits under this section shall be in addition to (and not in lieu of) any other benefits for which the covered employee is otherwise eligible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>