<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5928" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5928/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5928/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5928"><akn:num>5928</akn:num><akn:heading>Danger pay allowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5928. Danger pay allowance
An employee serving in a foreign area may be granted a danger pay allowance on the basis of civil insurrection, civil war, terrorism, or wartime conditions which threaten physical harm or imminent danger to the health or well-being of the employee. A danger pay allowance may not exceed 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee, except that if an employee is granted an additional differential under section 5925(b) of this title with respect to an assignment, the sum of that additional differential and any danger pay allowance granted to the employee with respect to that assignment may not exceed 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee. The presence of nonessential personnel or dependents shall not preclude payment of an allowance under this section. In each instance where an allowance under this section is initiated or terminated, the Secretary of State shall inform the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate of the action taken and the circumstances justifying it.
(Added Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2311(a), Oct. 17, 1980, 94 Stat. 2166; amended Pub. L. 98–164, title I, § 131, Nov. 22, 1983, 97 Stat. 1028; Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title V, § 591(b), Jan. 23, 2004, 118 Stat. 207; Pub. L. 109–140, § 4(c), Dec. 22, 2005, 119 Stat. 2651.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2005—Pub. L. 109–140 substituted “35 percent of the basic pay of the employee” for “25 percent of the basic pay of the employee or 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee in the case of an employee of the United States Agency for International Development” in two places.
2004—Pub. L. 108–199 inserted “or 35 percent of the basic pay of the employee in the case of an employee of the United States Agency for International Development” after “25 percent of the basic pay of the employee” in two places.
1983—Pub. L. 98–164 inserted provision that presence of nonessential personnel or dependents shall not preclude payment of a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>