<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5948" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5948/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/5948/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5948"><akn:num>5948</akn:num><akn:heading>Physicians comparability allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5948. Physicians comparability allowances(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and in order to recruit and retain highly qualified Government physicians, the head of an agency, subject to the provisions of this section, section 5307, and such regulations as the President or his designee may prescribe, may enter into a service agreement with a Government physician which provides for such physician to complete a specified period of service in such agency in return for an allowance for the duration of such agreement in an amount to be determined by the agency head and specified in the agreement, but not to exceed—(1) $14,000 per annum if, at the time the agreement is entered into, the Government physician has served as a Government physician for twenty-four months or less, or

(2) $30,000 per annum if the Government physician has served as a Government physician for more than twenty-four months.


For the purpose of determining length of service as a Government physician, service as a physician under section 4104 or 4114 11 See References in Text note below. of title 38 or active service as a medical officer in the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service under Title II of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. ch. 6A) shall be deemed service as a Government physician.

(b) An allowance may not be paid pursuant to this section to any physician who—(1) is employed on less than a half-time or intermittent basis,

(2) occupies an internship or residency training position,

(3) is a reemployed annuitant, or

(4) is fulfilling a scholarship obligation.


(c) The head of an agency, pursuant to such regulations, criteria, and conditions as the President or his designee may prescribe, shall determine categories of positions applicable to physicians in such agency with respect to which there is a significant recruitment and retention problem. Only physicians serving in such positions shall be eligible for an allowance pursuant to this section. The amounts o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, and in order to recruit and retain highly qualified Government physicians, the head of an agency, subject to the provisions of this section, section 5307, and such regulations as the President or his designee may prescribe, may enter into a service agreement with a Government physician which provides for such physician to complete a specified period of service in such agency in return for an allowance for the duration of such agreement in an amount to be determined by the agency head and specified in the agreement, but not to exceed— For the purpose of determining length of service as a Government physician, service as a physician under section 4104 or 4114 11 See References in Text note below. of title 38 or active service as a medical officer in the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service under Title II of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. ch. 6A) shall be deemed service as a Government physician.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An allowance may not be paid pursuant to this section to any physician who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The head of an agency, pursuant to such regulations, criteria, and conditions as the President or his designee may prescribe, shall determine categories of positions applicable to physicians in such agency with respect to which there is a significant recruitment and retention problem. Only physicians serving in such positions shall be eligible for an allowance pursuant to this section. The amounts of each such allowance shall be determined by the agency head, subject to such regulations, criteria, and conditions as the President or his designee may prescribe, and shall be the minimum amount necessary to deal with the recruitment and retention problem for each such category of physicians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Any agreement entered into by a physician under this section shall be for a period of one year of service in the agency involved unless the physician requests an agreement for a longer period of service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Unless otherwise provided for in the agreement under subsection (f) of this section, an agreement under this section shall provide that the physician, in the event that such physician voluntarily, or because of misconduct, fails to complete at least one year of service pursuant to such agreement, shall be required to refund the total amount received under this section, unless the head of the agency, pursuant to such regulations as may be prescribed under this section by the President or his designee, determines that such failure is necessitated by circumstances beyond the control of the physician.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Any agreement under this section shall specify, subject to such regulations as the President or his designee may prescribe, the terms under which the head of the agency and the physician may elect to terminate such agreement, and the amounts, if any, required to be refunded by the physician for each reason for termination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Any regulations, criteria, or conditions that may be prescribed under this section by the President or his designee shall not be applicable to the Tennessee Valley Authority, and the Tennessee Valley Authority shall have sole responsibility for administering the provisions of this section with respect to Government physicians employed by the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5948_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Not later than June 30 of each year, the President shall submit to each House of Congress a written report on the operation of this section. Each report shall include, with respect to the year covered by such report, information as to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>