<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/6304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/6304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/6304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6304"><akn:num>6304</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual leave; accumulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6304. Annual leave; accumulation(a) Except as provided by subsections (b), (d), (e), (f), and (g) of this section, annual leave provided by section 6303 of this title, which is not used by an employee, accumulates for use in succeeding years until it totals not more than 30 days at the beginning of the first full biweekly pay period, or corresponding period for an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods, occurring in a year.

(b) Annual leave not used by an employee of the Government of the United States in one of the following classes of employees stationed outside the United States accumulates for use in succeeding years until it totals not more than 45 days at the beginning of the first full biweekly pay period, or corresponding period for an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods, occurring in a year:(1) Individuals directly recruited or transferred by the Government of the United States from the United States or its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico for employment outside the area of recruitment or from which transferred.

(2) Individuals employed locally but—(A)(i) who were originally recruited from the United States or its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico but outside the area of employment;

(ii) who have been in substantially continuous employment by other agencies of the United States, United States firms, interests, or organizations, international organizations in which the United States participates, or foreign governments; and

(iii) whose conditions of employment provide for their return transportation to the United States or its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; or


(B)(i) who were at the time of employment temporarily absent, for the purpose of travel or formal study, from the United States, or from their respective places of residence in its territories or possessions including the Commonwealth of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided by subsections (b), (d), (e), (f), and (g) of this section, annual leave provided by section 6303 of this title, which is not used by an employee, accumulates for use in succeeding years until it totals not more than 30 days at the beginning of the first full biweekly pay period, or corresponding period for an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods, occurring in a year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual leave not used by an employee of the Government of the United States in one of the following classes of employees stationed outside the United States accumulates for use in succeeding years until it totals not more than 45 days at the beginning of the first full biweekly pay period, or corresponding period for an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods, occurring in a year:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual leave in excess of the amount allowable— remains to the credit of the employee until used. The excess annual leave is reduced at the beginning of the first full biweekly pay period, or corresponding period for an employee who is not paid on the basis of biweekly pay periods, occurring in a year, by the amount of annual leave the employee used during the preceding year in excess of the amount which accrued during that year, until the employee’s accumulated leave does not exceed the amount allowed under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual leave otherwise accruable after June 30, 1960, which is lost by operation of this section because of administrative error and which is not credited under subsection (d)(2) of this section because the employee is separated before the error is discovered, is subject to credit and liquidation by lump-sum payment only if a claim therefor is filed within 3 years immediately following the date of discovery of the error. Payment shall be made by the agency of employment when the lump-sum payment provisions of section 5551 of this title last became applicable to the employee at the rate of basic pay in effect on the date the lump-sum provisions became applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>