<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/6308" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/6308/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/6308/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6308"><akn:num>6308</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers between positions under different leave systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6308. Transfers between positions under different leave systems(a) The annual and sick leave to the credit of an employee who transfers between positions under different leave systems without a break in service shall be transferred to his credit in the employing agency on an adjusted basis under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, unless the individual is excepted from this subchapter by section 6301(2)(ii), (iii), (vi), or (vii) of this title. However, when a former member receiving a retirement annuity under sections 521–535 of title 4, District of Columbia Code, is reemployed in a position to which this subchapter applies, his sick leave balance may not be recredited to his account on the later reemployment.

(b) The annual leave, sick leave, and home leave to the credit of a nonappropriated fund employee of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard described in section 2105(c) who moves without a break in service of more than 3 days to a position in the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively, that is subject to this subchapter shall be transferred to the employee’s credit. The annual leave, sick leave, and home leave to the credit of an employee of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard who is subject to this subchapter and who moves without a break in service of more than 3 days to a position under a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively, described in section 2105(c), shall be transferred to the employee’s credit under the nonappropriated fund instrumentality. The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, may provide for a transfer of funds in an amount equal to the value of the transferred annual leave to compensate the gaining entity for the cost of a transfer of annual leave under this subsection.

(Pub. L. 89–554, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 521; Pub. L. 95–454, title IX, § 906(a)(2), Oct. 13, 1978, 92 Stat. 1224; P</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6308_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The annual and sick leave to the credit of an employee who transfers between positions under different leave systems without a break in service shall be transferred to his credit in the employing agency on an adjusted basis under regulations prescribed by the Office of Personnel Management, unless the individual is excepted from this subchapter by section 6301(2)(ii), (iii), (vi), or (vii) of this title. However, when a former member receiving a retirement annuity under sections 521–535 of title 4, District of Columbia Code, is reemployed in a position to which this subchapter applies, his sick leave balance may not be recredited to his account on the later reemployment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6308_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The annual leave, sick leave, and home leave to the credit of a nonappropriated fund employee of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard described in section 2105(c) who moves without a break in service of more than 3 days to a position in the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively, that is subject to this subchapter shall be transferred to the employee’s credit. The annual leave, sick leave, and home leave to the credit of an employee of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard who is subject to this subchapter and who moves without a break in service of more than 3 days to a position under a nonappropriated fund instrumentality of the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, respectively, described in section 2105(c), shall be transferred to the employee’s credit under the nonappropriated fund instrumentality. The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, may provide for a transfer of funds in an amount equal to the valu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>