<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8124" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8124/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8124/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8124"><akn:num>8124</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings and award; hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8124. Findings and award; hearings(a) The Secretary of Labor shall determine and make a finding of facts and make an award for or against payment of compensation under this subchapter after—(1) considering the claim presented by the beneficiary and the report furnished by the immediate superior; and

(2) completing such investigation as he considers necessary.


(b)(1) Before review under section 8128(a) of this title, a claimant for compensation not satisfied with a decision of the Secretary under subsection (a) of this section is entitled, on request made within 30 days after the date of the issuance of the decision, to a hearing on his claim before a representative of the Secretary. At the hearing, the claimant is entitled to present evidence in further support of his claim. Within 30 days after the hearing ends, the Secretary shall notify the claimant in writing of his further decision and any modifications of the award he may make and of the basis of his decision.

(2) In conducting the hearing, the representative of the Secretary is not bound by common law or statutory rules of evidence, by technical or formal rules of procedure, or by section 554 of this title except as provided by this subchapter, but may conduct the hearing in such manner as to best ascertain the rights of the claimant. For this purpose, he shall receive such relevant evidence as the claimant adduces and such other evidence as he determines necessary or useful in evaluating the claim.


(Pub. L. 89–554, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 545; Pub. L. 90–83, § 1(58), Sept. 11, 1967, 81 Stat. 210.)











Historical and Revision Notes



1966 Act


DerivationU.S. CodeRevised Statutes andStatutes at Large


 5 U.S.C. 786.Sept. 7, 1916, ch. 458, § 36, 39 Stat. 749.


The last sentence of former section 786 is omitted as surplusage because it is covered by section 8147.
Administration of this subchapter was transferred to the Secretary of Labor by section 1 of 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 19, 64 Stat. 1271 (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8124_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Labor shall determine and make a finding of facts and make an award for or against payment of compensation under this subchapter after—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8124_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>