<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8140" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8140/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8140/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8140"><akn:num>8140</akn:num><akn:heading>Members of the Reserve Officers’ Training Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8140. Members of the Reserve Officers’ Training Corps(a) Subject to the provisions of this section, this subchapter applies to a member of, or applicant for membership in, the Reserve Officers’ Training Corps of the Army, Navy, or Air Force who suffers an injury, disability, or death incurred, or an illness contracted, in line of duty—(1) while engaged in a flight or in flight instruction under chapter 103 of title 10; or

(2) during the period of the member’s attendance at training or a practice cruise under chapter 103 of title 10, United States Code, beginning when the authorized travel to the training or practice cruise begins and ending when authorized travel from the training or practice cruise ends.


(b) For the purpose of this section, an injury, disability, death, or illness of a member referred to in subsection (a) may be considered as incurred or contracted in line of duty only if the injury, disability, or death is incurred, or the illness is contracted, by the member during a period described in that subsection. Subject to review by the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of the military department concerned (under regulations prescribed by that Secretary), shall determine whether an injury, disability, or death was incurred, or an illness was contracted, by a member in line of duty.

(c) In computing the compensation payable under this section, the monthly pay received by the injured or deceased individual, in cash and kind, is deemed $150.

(d) The Secretary of the military department concerned shall cooperate fully with the Department of Labor in the prompt investigation and prosecution of a case involving the legal liability of a third party other than the United States.

(e) An individual may not receive disability benefits under this section while on active duty with the armed forces, but these benefits may be reinstated when the individual is released from that active duty.

(f) Expenses incurred by a military department in providing hospitaliza</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8140_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to the provisions of this section, this subchapter applies to a member of, or applicant for membership in, the Reserve Officers’ Training Corps of the Army, Navy, or Air Force who suffers an injury, disability, or death incurred, or an illness contracted, in line of duty—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8140_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For the purpose of this section, an injury, disability, death, or illness of a member referred to in subsection (a) may be considered as incurred or contracted in line of duty only if the injury, disability, or death is incurred, or the illness is contracted, by the member during a period described in that subsection. Subject to review by the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of the military department concerned (under regulations prescribed by that Secretary), shall determine whether an injury, disability, or death was incurred, or an illness was contracted, by a member in line of duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8140_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In computing the compensation payable under this section, the monthly pay received by the injured or deceased individual, in cash and kind, is deemed $150.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8140_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of the military department concerned shall cooperate fully with the Department of Labor in the prompt investigation and prosecution of a case involving the legal liability of a third party other than the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8140_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) An individual may not receive disability benefits under this section while on active duty with the armed forces, but these benefits may be reinstated when the individual is released from that active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8140_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expenses incurred by a military department in providing hospitalization, medical and surgical care, necessary transportation incident to that hospitalization or medical and surgical care, or in connection with a funeral and burial on behalf of an individual covered by subsection (a) of this section shall be reimbursed by the Secretary of Labor from the Employees’ Compensation Fund in accordance with this subchapter. However, reimbursement may not be made for hospitalization or medical or surgical care provided an individual by a military department in a facility of a military department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8140_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For purposes of this section, the term “applicant for membership” includes a student enrolled, during a semester or other enrollment term, in a course which is part of Reserve Officers’ Training Corps instruction at an educational institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>