<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8143b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8143b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8143b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8143b"><akn:num>8143b</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees in fire protection activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8143b. Employees in fire protection activities(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Employee in fire protection activities.—The term “employee in fire protection activities” means an employee employed as a firefighter (including a wildland firefighter), paramedic, emergency medical technician, rescue worker, ambulance personnel, or hazardous material worker who—(A) is trained in fire suppression;

(B) has the legal authority and responsibility to engage in fire suppression;

(C) is engaged in the prevention, control, or extinguishment of fires or response to emergency situations in which life, property, or the environment is at risk, including the prevention, control, suppression, or management of wildland fires; and

(D) performs the activities described in subparagraph (C) as a primary responsibility of the job of the employee.


(2) Rule.—The term “rule” has the meaning given the term in section 804.

(3) Secretary.—The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.


(b) Certain Illnesses and Diseased 11 So in original. Probably should be “Diseases”. Deemed to Be Proximately Caused by Employment in Fire Protection Activities.—(1) In general.—For a claim under this subchapter of disability or death of an employee who has been employed for not less than 5 years in aggregate as an employee in fire protection activities, an illness or disease specified on the list established under paragraph (2) shall be deemed to be proximately caused by the employment of that employee, if the employee is diagnosed with that illness or disease not later than 10 years after the last activedate 22 So in original. of employment as an employee in fire protection activities.

(2) Establishment of initial list.—There is established under this section the following list of illnesses and diseases:(A) Bladder cancer.

(B) Brain cancer.

(C) Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease.

(D) Colorectal cancer.

(E) Esophageal cancer.

(F) Kidney cancer.

(G) Leukemias.

(H) Lung cancer.

(I) Mesot</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8143b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8143b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Illnesses and Diseased 11 So in original. Probably should be “Diseases”. Deemed to Be Proximately Caused by Employment in Fire Protection Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>