<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8332" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8332/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8332/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8332"><akn:num>8332</akn:num><akn:heading>Creditable service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8332. Creditable service(a) The total service of an employee or Member is the full years and twelfth parts thereof, excluding from the aggregate the fractional part of a month, if any.

(b) The service of an employee shall be credited from the date of original employment to the date of separation on which title to annuity is based in the civilian service of the Government. Except as provided in paragraph (13) 11 So in original. Probably should be paragraph “(14)”. of this subsection, credit may not be allowed for a period of separation from the service in excess of 3 calendar days. The service includes—(1) employment as a substitute in the postal field service;

(2) service in the Pan American Sanitary Bureau;

(3) subject to sections 8334(c) and 8339(i) of this title, service performed before July 10, 1960, as an employee of a county committee established under section 590h(b) of title 16 or of a committee or an association of producers described by section 610(b) of title 7;

(4) service as a student-employee as defined by section 5351 of this title only if he later becomes subject to this subchapter;

(5) a period of satisfactory service of a volunteer or volunteer leader under chapter 34 of title 22 only if he later becomes subject to this subchapter;

(6) employment under section 709 of title 32 or any prior corresponding provision of law;

(7) a period of service of a volunteer under part A of title VIII of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, or a period of service of a full-time volunteer enrolled in a program of at least one year’s duration under part A, B,22 See References in Text note below. or C of title I of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 only if he later becomes subject to this subchapter;

(8) subject to sections 8334(c) and 8339(i) of this title, service performed after February 18, 1929, and before noon on January 3, 1971, as a United States Capitol Guide;

(9) subject to sections 8334(c) and 8339(i) of this title, service as a substi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The total service of an employee or Member is the full years and twelfth parts thereof, excluding from the aggregate the fractional part of a month, if any.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The service of an employee shall be credited from the date of original employment to the date of separation on which title to annuity is based in the civilian service of the Government. Except as provided in paragraph (13) 11 So in original. Probably should be paragraph “(14)”. of this subsection, credit may not be allowed for a period of separation from the service in excess of 3 calendar days. The service includes— The Office of Personnel Management shall accept the certification of the Secretary of Agriculture or his designee concerning service for the purpose of this subchapter of the type performed by an employee named by paragraph (3) of this subsection. The Office of Personnel Management shall accept the certification of the Secretary of Commerce or his designee concerning service for the purpose of this subchapter of the type performed by an employee named by paragraph (14) of this subsection. The Office of Personnel Management shall accept the certification of the Capitol </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For the purpose of section 8339(c)(1) of this title, a Member—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) This subchapter does not affect the right of an employee or Member to retired pay, pension, or compensation in addition to an annuity payable under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Credit shall be allowed for leaves of absence without pay granted an employee while performing military service or while receiving benefits under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title. An employee or former employee who returns to duty after a period of separation is deemed, for the purpose of this subsection, to have been in a leave of absence without pay for that part of the period in which he was receiving benefits under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title or any earlier statute on which such subchapter is based. Except for a substitute in the postal field service and service described in paragraph (14) of subsection (b) of this section,,33 So in original. credit may not be allowed for so much of other leaves of absence without pay as exceeds 6 months in the aggregate in a calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) An employee who during the period of a war, or of a national emergency as proclaimed by the President or declared by Congress, leaves his position to enter the military service is deemed, for the purpose of this subchapter, as not separated from his civilian position because of that military service, unless he applies for and receives a lump-sum credit under this subchapter. However, the employee is deemed as not retaining his civilian position after December 31, 1956, or after the expiration of 5 years of that military service, whichever is later.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) An employee who— may not be allowed credit for service which is used in the computation of an annuity under section 8339(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) An individual who qualifies as an employee under section 8331(1)(E) of this title is entitled to credit for his service as a United States Commissioner, which is not credited for the purpose of this subchapter for service performed by him in a capacity other than Commissioner, on the basis of— Credit for service performed as Commissioner may not exceed 313 days in a year before July 1, 1945, or 260 days in a year after June 30, 1945. For the purpose of this subchapter, the employment and pay of a Commissioner is deemed on a daily basis when actually employed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8332_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>