<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8337" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8337/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8337/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8337"><akn:num>8337</akn:num><akn:heading>Disability retirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8337. Disability retirement(a) An employee who completes 5 years of civilian service and has become disabled shall be retired on the employee’s own application or on application by the employee’s agency. Any employee shall be considered to be disabled only if the employee is found by the Office of Personnel Management to be unable, because of disease or injury, to render useful and efficient service in the employee’s position and is not qualified for reassignment, under procedures prescribed by the Office, to a vacant position which is in the agency at the same grade or level and in which the employee would be able to render useful and efficient service. For the purpose of the preceding sentence, an employee of the United States Postal Service shall be considered not qualified for a reassignment described in that sentence if the reassignment is to a position in a different craft or is inconsistent with the terms of a collective bargaining agreement covering the employee. A judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces who completes 5 years of civilian service and who is found by the Office to be disabled for useful and efficient service as a judge of such court or who is removed for mental or physical disability under section 942(c) of title 10 shall be retired on the judge’s own application or upon such removal. A Member who completes 5 years of Member service and is found by the Office to be disabled for useful and efficient service as a Member because of disease or injury shall be retired on the Member’s own application. An annuity authorized by this section is computed under section 8339(g) of this title, unless the employee or Member is eligible for a higher annuity computed under section 8339(a) through (e), (n), (q), (r), or (s).

(b) A claim may be allowed under this section only if the application is filed with the Office before the employee or Member is separated from the service or within 1 year thereafter. This time limitation may be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8337_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An employee who completes 5 years of civilian service and has become disabled shall be retired on the employee’s own application or on application by the employee’s agency. Any employee shall be considered to be disabled only if the employee is found by the Office of Personnel Management to be unable, because of disease or injury, to render useful and efficient service in the employee’s position and is not qualified for reassignment, under procedures prescribed by the Office, to a vacant position which is in the agency at the same grade or level and in which the employee would be able to render useful and efficient service. For the purpose of the preceding sentence, an employee of the United States Postal Service shall be considered not qualified for a reassignment described in that sentence if the reassignment is to a position in a different craft or is inconsistent with the terms of a collective bargaining agreement covering the employee. A judge of the United States Court of App</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8337_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A claim may be allowed under this section only if the application is filed with the Office before the employee or Member is separated from the service or within 1 year thereafter. This time limitation may be waived by the Office for an employee or Member who at the date of separation from service or within 1 year thereafter is mentally incompetent, if the application is filed with the Office within 1 year from the date of restoration of the employee or Member to competency or the appointment of a fiduciary, whichever is earlier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8337_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An annuitant receiving disability retirement annuity from the Fund shall be examined under the direction of the Office— unless his disability is permanent in character. If the annuitant fails to submit to examination as required by this section, payment of the annuity shall be suspended until continuance of the disability is satisfactorily established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8337_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If an annuitant receiving disability retirement annuity from the Fund, before becoming 60 years of age, recovers from his disability, payment of the annuity terminates on reemployment by the Government or 1 year after the date of the medical examination showing the recovery, whichever is earlier. If an annuitant receiving disability retirement annuity from the Fund, before becoming 60 years of age, is restored to an earning capacity fairly comparable to the current rate of pay of the position occupied at the time of retirement, payment of the annuity terminates on reemployment by the Government or 180 days after the end of the calendar year in which earning capacity is so restored, whichever is earlier. Earning capacity is deemed restored if in any calendar year the income of the annuitant from wages or self-employment or both equals at least 80 percent of the current rate of pay of the position occupied immediately before retirement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8337_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If an annuitant whose annuity is terminated under subsection (d) of this section is not reemployed in a position in which he is subject to this subchapter, he is deemed, except for service credit, to have been involuntarily separated from the service for the purpose of this subchapter as of the date of termination of the disability annuity, and after that termination is entitled to annuity under the applicable provisions of this subchapter. If an annuitant whose annuity is heretofore or hereafter terminated because of an earning capacity provision of this subchapter or an earlier statute— his annuity shall be restored at the same rate effective the first of the year following any calendar year in which his income from wages or self-employment or both is less than 80 percent of the current rate of pay of the position occupied immediately before retirement. If an annuitant whose annuity is heretofore or hereafter terminated because of a medical finding that he has recovered from disa</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8337_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8337_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) If an individual is entitled to an annuity under this subchapter, and the individual receives a lump-sum payment for compensation under section 8135 based on the disability or death of the same person, so much of the compensation as has been paid for a period extended beyond the date payment of the annuity commences, as determined by the Department of Labor, shall be refunded to that Department for credit to the Employees’ Compensation Fund. Before the individual may receive the annuity, the individual shall— Deductions from the annuity may be made from accrued or accruing payments. The amounts deducted and withheld from the annuity shall be transmitted to the Department of Labor for reimbursement to the Employees’ Compensation Fund. When the Department of Labor finds that the financial circumstances of an individual entitled to an annuity under this subchapter warrant deferred refunding, deductions from the annuity may be prorated against and paid from accruing payments in such ma</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8337_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>