<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8340" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8340/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8340/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8340"><akn:num>8340</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-of-living adjustment of annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8340. Cost-of-living adjustment of annuities(a) For the purpose of this section—(1) the term “base quarter”, as used with respect to a year, means the calendar quarter ending on September 30, of such year; and

(2) the price index for a base quarter is the arithmetical mean of such index for the 3 months comprising such quarter.


(b) Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, effective December 1 of each year, each annuity payable from the Fund having a commencing date not later than such December 1 shall be increased by the percent change in the price index for the base quarter of such year over the price index for the base quarter of the preceding year in which an adjustment under this subsection was made, adjusted to the nearest ⅒ of 1 percent.

(c) Eligibility for an annuity increase under this section is governed by the commencing date of each annuity payable from the Fund as of the effective date of an increase, except as follows:(1) The first increase (if any) made under subsection (b) of this section to an annuity which is payable from the Fund to an employee or Member who retires, to the widow, widower, or former spouse,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. of a deceased employee or Member, or to the widow, widower, former spouse, or insurable interest designee of a deceased annuitant whose annuity has not been increased under this subsection or subsection (b) of this section, shall be equal to the product (adjusted to the nearest ⅒ of 1 percent) of—(A) 1⁄12 of the applicable percent change computed under subsection (b) of this section, multiplied by

(B) the number of months (not to exceed 12 months, counting any portion of a month as a month)—(i) for which the annuity was payable from the Fund before the effective date of the increase, or

(ii) in the case of a widow, widower, former spouse, or insurable interest designee of a deceased annuitant whose annuity has not been so increased, since the annuity was first payable t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8340_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8340_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, effective December 1 of each year, each annuity payable from the Fund having a commencing date not later than such December 1 shall be increased by the percent change in the price index for the base quarter of such year over the price index for the base quarter of the preceding year in which an adjustment under this subsection was made, adjusted to the nearest ⅒ of 1 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8340_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility for an annuity increase under this section is governed by the commencing date of each annuity payable from the Fund as of the effective date of an increase, except as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8340_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) This section does not authorize an increase in an additional annuity purchased at retirement by voluntary contributions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8340_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The monthly installment of annuity after adjustment under this section shall be rounded to the next lowest dollar. However, the monthly installment shall after adjustment reflect an increase of at least $1.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8340_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective September 1, 1966, or on the commencing date of annuity, whichever is later, the annuity of each surviving spouse whose entitlement to annuity payable from the Fund resulted from the death of— is increased by 10 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8340_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>