<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8347" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8347/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8347/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8347"><akn:num>8347</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8347. Administration; regulations(a) The Office of Personnel Management shall administer this subchapter. Except as otherwise specifically provided herein, the Office shall perform, or cause to be performed, such acts and prescribe such regulations as are necessary and proper to carry out this subchapter.

(b) Applications under this subchapter shall be in such form as the Office prescribes. Agencies shall support the applications by such certificates as the Office considers necessary to the determination of the rights of applicants. The Office shall adjudicate all claims under this subchapter.

(c) The Office shall determine questions of disability and dependency arising under this subchapter. Except to the extent provided under subsection (d) of this section, the decisions of the Office concerning these matters are final and conclusive and are not subject to review. The Office may direct at any time such medical or other examinations as it considers necessary to determine the facts concerning disability or dependency of an individual receiving or applying for annuity under this subchapter. The Office may suspend or deny annuity for failure to submit to examination.

(d)(1) Subject to paragraph (2) of this subsection, an administrative action or order affecting the rights or interests of an individual or of the United States under this subchapter may be appealed to the Merit Systems Protection Board under procedures prescribed by the Board.

(2) In the case of any individual found by the Office to be disabled in whole or in part on the basis of the individual’s mental condition, and that finding was made pursuant to an application by an agency for purposes of disability retirement under section 8337(a) of this title, the procedures under section 7701 of this title shall apply and the decision of the Board shall be subject to judicial review under section 7703 of this title.


(e) The Office shall fix the fees for examinations made under this subchapter by physici</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Office of Personnel Management shall administer this subchapter. Except as otherwise specifically provided herein, the Office shall perform, or cause to be performed, such acts and prescribe such regulations as are necessary and proper to carry out this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications under this subchapter shall be in such form as the Office prescribes. Agencies shall support the applications by such certificates as the Office considers necessary to the determination of the rights of applicants. The Office shall adjudicate all claims under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Office shall determine questions of disability and dependency arising under this subchapter. Except to the extent provided under subsection (d) of this section, the decisions of the Office concerning these matters are final and conclusive and are not subject to review. The Office may direct at any time such medical or other examinations as it considers necessary to determine the facts concerning disability or dependency of an individual receiving or applying for annuity under this subchapter. The Office may suspend or deny annuity for failure to submit to examination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Office shall fix the fees for examinations made under this subchapter by physicians or surgeons who are not medical officers of the United States. The fees and reasonable traveling and other expenses incurred in connection with the examinations are paid from appropriations for the cost of administering this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Office shall select three actuaries, to be known as the Board of Actuaries of the Civil Service Retirement System. The Office shall fix the pay of the members of the Board, except members otherwise in the employ of the United States. The Board shall report annually on the actuarial status of the System and furnish its advice and opinion on matters referred to it by the Office. The Board may recommend to the Office and to Congress such changes as in the Board’s judgment are necessary to protect the public interest and maintain the System on a sound financial basis. The Office shall keep, or cause to be kept, such records as it considers necessary for making periodic actuarial valuations of the System. The Board shall make actuarial valuations every 5 years, or oftener if considered necessary by the Office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Office may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an employee or group of employees in or under an Executive agency whose employment is temporary or intermittent. However, the Office may not exclude any employee who occupies a position on a part-time career employment basis (as defined in section 3401(2) of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Office, on recommendation by the Mayor of the District of Columbia, may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an individual or group of individuals employed by the government of the District of Columbia whose employment is temporary or intermittent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Architect of the Capitol may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an employee under the Office of the Architect of the Capitol whose employment is temporary or of uncertain duration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8347_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Librarian of Congress may exclude from the operation of this subchapter an employee under the Library of Congress whose employment is temporary or of uncertain duration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>