<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8348" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8348/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8348/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8348"><akn:num>8348</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8348. Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund(a) There is a Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund. The Fund—(1) is appropriated for the payment of—(A) benefits as provided by this subchapter or by the provisions of chapter 84 of this title which relate to benefits payable out of the Fund; and

(B) administrative expenses incurred by the Office of Personnel Management in placing in effect each annuity adjustment granted under section 8340 or 8462 of this title, in administering survivor annuities and elections providing therefor under sections 8339 and 8341 of this title or subchapters II and IV of chapter 84 of this title, in administering alternative forms of annuities under sections 8343a and 8420a (and related provisions of law), in making an allotment or assignment made by an individual under section 8345(h) or 8465(b) of this title, in administering fraud prevention under sections 8345, 8345a, 8466, and 8466a of this title, and in withholding taxes pursuant to section 3405 of title 26 or section 8345(k) or 8469 of this title;


(2) is made available, subject to such annual limitation as the Congress may prescribe, for any expenses incurred by the Office in connection with the administration of this chapter, chapter 84 of this title, and other retirement and annuity statutes; and

(3) is made available, subject to such annual limitation as the Congress may prescribe, for any expenses incurred by the Merit Systems Protection Board in the administration of appeals authorized under sections 8347(d) and 8461(e) of this title.


(b) The Secretary of the Treasury may accept and credit to the Fund money received in the form of a donation, gift, legacy, or bequest, or otherwise contributed for the benefit of civil-service employees generally.

(c) The Secretary shall immediately invest in interest-bearing securities of the United States such currently available portions of the Fund as are not immediately required for payments from the Fund. The income deri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is a Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund. The Fund—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of the Treasury may accept and credit to the Fund money received in the form of a donation, gift, legacy, or bequest, or otherwise contributed for the benefit of civil-service employees generally.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall immediately invest in interest-bearing securities of the United States such currently available portions of the Fund as are not immediately required for payments from the Fund. The income derived from these investments constitutes a part of the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are extended to authorize the issuance at par of public-debt obligations for purchase by the Fund. The obligations issued for purchase by the Fund shall have maturities fixed with due regard for the needs of the Fund and bear interest at a rate equal to the average market yield computed as of the end of the calendar month next preceding the date of the issue, borne by all marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States then forming a part of the public debt which are not due or callable until after the expiration of 4 years from the end of that calendar month. If the average market yield is not a multiple of ⅛ of 1 percent, the rate of interest on the obligations shall be the multiple of ⅛ of 1 percent nearest the average market yield.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may purchase other interest-bearing obligations of the United States, or obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States, on original issue or at the market price only if he determines that the purchases are in the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Any statute which authorizes— is deemed to authorize appropriations to the Fund to finance the unfunded liability created by that statute, in 30 equal annual installments with interest computed at the rate used in the then most recent valuation of the Civil Service Retirement System and with the first payment thereof due as of the end of the fiscal year in which each new or liberalized benefit, extension of coverage, or increase in pay is effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) At the end of each fiscal year, the Office shall notify the Secretary of the Treasury of the amount equivalent to (1) interest on the unfunded liability computed for that year at the interest rate used in the then most recent valuation of the System, and (2) that portion of disbursement for annuities for that year which the Office estimates is attributable to credit allowed for military service, less an amount determined by the Office to be appropriate to reflect the value of the deposits made to the credit of the Fund under section 8334(j) of this title. Before closing the accounts for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall credit to the Fund, as a Government contribution, out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, the following percentages of such amounts: 10 percent for 1971; 20 percent for 1972; 30 percent for 1973; 40 percent for 1974; 50 percent for 1975; 60 percent for 1976; 70 percent for 1977; 80 percent for 1978; 90 percent for 1979; </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8348_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>