<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8402"><akn:num>8402</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Employees’ Retirement System; exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8402. Federal Employees’ Retirement System; exclusions(a) The provisions of this chapter comprise the Federal Employees’ Retirement System.

(b) The provisions of this chapter shall not apply with respect to—(1) any individual who has performed service of a type described in subparagraph (C), (D), (E), or (F) of section 210(a)(5) of the Social Security Act continuously since December 31, 1983 (determined in accordance with the provisions of section 210(a)(5)(B) of the Social Security Act, relating to continuity of employment); or

(2)(A) any employee or Member who has separated from the service after—(i) having been subject to—(I) subchapter III of chapter 83 of this title;

(II) subchapter I of chapter 8 of title I of the Foreign Service Act of 1980; or

(III) the benefit structure for employees of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System appointed before January 1, 1984, that is a component of the Retirement Plan for Employees of the Federal Reserve System, established under section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act; and


(ii) having completed—(I) at least 5 years of civilian service creditable under subchapter III of chapter 83 of this title;

(II) at least 5 years of civilian service creditable under subchapter I of chapter 8 of title I of the Foreign Service Act of 1980; or

(III) at least 5 years of civilian service (other than any service performed in the employ of a Federal Reserve Bank) creditable under the benefit structure for employees of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System appointed before January 1, 1984, that is a component of the Retirement Plan for Employees of the Federal Reserve System, established under section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act,


determined without regard to any deposit or redeposit requirement under either such subchapter or under such benefit structure, or any requirement that the individual become subject to either such subchapter or to such benefit structure after performing the service involved; or

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The provisions of this chapter comprise the Federal Employees’ Retirement System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The provisions of this chapter shall not apply with respect to— except to the extent provided for under subsection (d) of this section or title III of the Federal Employees’ Retirement System Act of 1986 pursuant to an election under such title to become subject to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Paragraph (2) of subsection (b) shall not apply to an individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A bankruptcy judge or magistrate judge who is covered by section 377 of title 28 or section 2(c) of the Retirement and Survivors’ Annuities for Bankruptcy Judges and Magistrates Act of 1988 shall be excluded from the operation of this chapter, other than subchapters III and VII of such chapter, if the judge or magistrate judge notifies the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts of an election of a retirement annuity under those provisions. Upon such election, the judge or magistrate judge shall be entitled to a lump-sum credit under section 8424 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8402_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A judge who is covered by section 7296 of title 38 shall be excluded from the operation of this chapter if the judge notifies the Director of the Office of Personnel Management of an election of a retirement annuity under that section. Upon such election, the judge shall be entitled to a lump-sum credit under section 8424 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8402_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A judge of the United States Court of Federal Claims who is covered by section 178 of title 28 shall be excluded from the operation of this chapter, other than subchapters III and VII of such chapter, if the judge notifies the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts of an election of a retirement annuity under those provisions. Upon such election, the judge shall be entitled to a lump-sum credit under section 8424 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>