<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8411" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8411/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8411/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8411"><akn:num>8411</akn:num><akn:heading>Creditable service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8411. Creditable service(a)(1) The total service of an employee or Member is the full years and twelfth parts thereof, excluding from the aggregate the fractional part of a month, if any.

(2) Credit may not be allowed for a period of separation from the service in excess of 3 calendar days.


(b) For the purpose of this chapter, creditable service of an employee or Member includes—(1) employment as an employee, and any service as a Member (including the period from the date of the beginning of the term for which elected or appointed to the date of taking office as a Member), after December 31, 1986;

(2) except as provided in subsection (f), service with respect to which deductions and withholdings under section 204(a)(1) of the Federal Employees’ Retirement Contribution Temporary Adjustment Act of 1983 have been made;

(3) except as provided in subsection (f) or (h), any civilian service (performed before January 1, 1989, other than any service under paragraph (1) or (2)) which, but for the amendments made by subsections (a)(4) and (b) of section 202 of the Federal Employees’ Retirement System Act of 1986, would be creditable under subchapter III of chapter 83 of this title (determined without regard to any deposit or redeposit requirement under such subchapter, any requirement that the individual become subject to such subchapter after performing the service involved, or any requirement that the individual give notice in writing to the official by whom such individual is paid of such individual’s desire to become subject to such subchapter);

(4) a period of service (other than any service under any other paragraph of this subsection and other than any military service) that was creditable under the Foreign Service Pension System described in subchapter II of chapter 8 11 See References in Text note below. of the Foreign Service Act of 1980, if the employee or Member waives credit for such service under the Foreign Service Pension System and makes a payment to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For the purpose of this chapter, creditable service of an employee or Member includes— Paragraph (5) shall not apply in the case of any employee as to whom subsection (g) (or, to the extent subchapter III of chapter 83 is involved, section 8332(n)) otherwise applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Credit under this chapter shall be allowed for leaves of absence without pay granted an employee while performing military service, or while receiving benefits under subchapter I of chapter 81. An employee or former employee who returns to duty after a period of separation is deemed, for the purpose of this subsection, to have been on leave of absence without pay for that part of the period in which that individual was receiving benefits under subchapter I of chapter 81. Credit may not be allowed for so much of other leaves of absence without pay as exceeds 6 months in the aggregate in a calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Credit shall be allowed for periods of approved leave without pay granted an employee to serve as a full-time officer or employee of an organization composed primarily of employees (as defined by section 8331(1) or 8401(11)), subject to the employee arranging to pay, through the employee’s employing agency, within 60 days after commencement of such leave without pay, amounts equal to the retirement deductions and agency contributions which would be applicable under sections 8422(a) and 8423(a), respectively, if the employee were in pay status. If the election and all payments provided by this subsection are not made, the employee may not receive credit for the periods of leave without pay, notwithstanding the third sentence of subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Any employee who— shall be treated for all purposes of this subchapter as if any service that would have been creditable under the retirement system established under section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act was service performed while subject to this subchapter if any employee and employer deductions, contributions or rights with respect to the employee’s service are transferred from such retirement system to the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) An employee or Member shall be allowed credit for service as a volunteer or volunteer leader under part A of title VIII of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964, as a full-time volunteer enrolled in a program of at least 1 year’s duration under part A, B,1 or C of title I of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, or as a volunteer or volunteer leader under the Peace Corps Act performed at any time prior to the separation on which the entitlement to any annuity under this subchapter is based if the employee or Member has made a deposit with interest, if any, with respect to such service under section 8422(f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) 22 So in original. Two subsecs. (i) have been enacted. For purposes of subsection (b)(5), the term “Bank Plan” means the benefit structure in which employees of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System appointed on or after January 1, 1984, participate, which benefit structure is a component of the Retirement Plan for Employees of the Federal Reserve System, established under section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (and any redesignated or successor version of such benefit structure, if so identified in writing by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System for purposes of this chapter).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>