<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8416" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8416/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8416/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8416"><akn:num>8416</akn:num><akn:heading>Survivor reduction for a current spouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8416. Survivor reduction for a current spouse(a)(1) If an employee or Member is married at the time of retiring under this chapter, the reduction described in section 8419(a) shall be made unless the employee or Member and the spouse jointly waive, by written election, any right which the spouse may have to a survivor annuity under section 8442 based on the service of such employee or Member. A waiver under this paragraph shall be filed with the Office under procedures prescribed by the Office.

(2) Notwithstanding paragraph (1), an employee or Member who is married at the time of retiring under this chapter may waive the annuity for a surviving spouse without the spouse’s consent if the employee or Member establishes to the satisfaction of the Office (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Office)—(A) that the spouse’s whereabouts cannot be determined; or

(B) that, due to exceptional circumstances, requiring the employee or Member to seek the spouse’s consent would otherwise be inappropriate.


(3) Except as provided in subsection (d), a waiver made under this subsection shall be irrevocable.


(b)(1) Upon remarriage, a retired employee or Member who was married at the time of retirement (including an employee or Member whose annuity was not reduced to provide a survivor annuity for the employee’s or Member’s spouse or former spouse as of the time of retirement) may irrevocably elect during such marriage, in a signed writing received by the Office within 2 years after such remarriage or, if later, within 2 years after the death or remarriage of any former spouse of such employee or Member who was entitled to a survivor annuity under section 8445 (or of the last such surviving former spouse, if there was more than one), a reduction in the employee’s or Member’s annuity under section 8419(a) for the purpose of providing an annuity for such employee’s or Member’s spouse in the event such spouse survives the employee or Member.

(2) The election and reduct</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8416_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8416_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8416_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8416_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>