<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8421a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8421a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8421a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8421a"><akn:num>8421a</akn:num><akn:heading>Reductions on account of earnings from work performed while entitled to an annuity supplement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8421a. Reductions on account of earnings from work performed while entitled to an annuity supplement(a) Except as provided in subsection (c), the amount of the annuity supplement to which an individual is entitled under section 8421 for any month (determined without regard to subsection (c) of such section) shall be reduced by the amount of any excess earnings of such individual which are required to be charged to such supplement for such month, as determined under subsection (b).

(b) The amount of an individual’s excess earnings shall be charged to months as follows:(1)(A) There shall be charged to each month of a year under subsection (a) an amount equal to the individual’s excess earnings (as determined under paragraph (2) with respect to such year), divided by the number of the individual’s supplement entitlement months for such year (as determined under paragraph (3)).

(B) Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the amount charged to a month under subsection (a) may not exceed the amount of the annuity supplement to which the individual is entitled under section 8421 for such month (determined without regard to subsection (c) of such section).


(2) The excess earnings based on which reductions under subsection (a) shall be made with respect to an individual in a year—(A) shall be equal to 50 percent of so much of such individual’s earnings for the immediately preceding year as exceeds the applicable exempt amount for such preceding year; but

(B) may not exceed the total amount of the annuity supplement payments to which such individual was entitled for such preceding year under section 8421 (determined without regard to subsection (c) of such section, and without regard to this section).


(3)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), the number of an individual’s supplement entitlement months for a year shall be 12.

(B) The number determined under subparagraph (A) shall be reduced so as not to include any month after which such individual ceases to be entitled to an an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (c), the amount of the annuity supplement to which an individual is entitled under section 8421 for any month (determined without regard to subsection (c) of such section) shall be reduced by the amount of any excess earnings of such individual which are required to be charged to such supplement for such month, as determined under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The amount of an individual’s excess earnings shall be charged to months as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) This section shall not apply to an individual described in section 8412(e) during any period in which the individual, after separating from the service as described in that section, is employed as an—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8421a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Office shall prescribe regulations under which this section shall be applied in the case of a reemployed annuitant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>