<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8433" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8433/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8433/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8433"><akn:num>8433</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits and election of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8433. Benefits and election of benefits(a) An employee or Member who separates from Government employment is entitled to the amount of the balance in the employee’s or Member’s account (except for the portion of such amount forfeited under section 8432(g) of this title, if any) as provided in this section.

(b) Subject to section 8435 of this title, any employee or Member who separates from Government employment is entitled and may elect to withdraw from the Thrift Savings Fund the balance of the employee’s or Member’s account as—(1) an annuity;

(2) a single payment;

(3) 2 or more substantially equal payments to be made not less frequently than annually; or

(4) any combination of payments as provided under paragraphs (1) through (3) as the Executive Director may prescribe by regulation.


(c)(1) In addition to the right provided under subsection (b) to withdraw the balance of the account, an employee or Member who separates from Government service may make one or more withdrawals of any amount in the same manner as a single payment is made in accordance with subsection (b)(2) from the employee’s or Member’s account.

(2) An employee or Member may request that the amount withdrawn from the Thrift Savings Fund in accordance with subsection (b)(2) be transferred to an eligible retirement plan.

(3) The Executive Director shall make each transfer elected under paragraph (2) directly to an eligible retirement plan or plans (as defined in section 402(c)(8) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) identified by the employee, Member, former employee, or former Member for whom the transfer is made.

(4) A transfer may not be made for an employee, Member, former employee, or former Member under paragraph (2) until the Executive Director receives from that individual the information required by the Executive Director specifically to identify the eligible retirement plan or plans to which the transfer is to be made.

(5) Withdrawals under this subsection shall be subject to s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An employee or Member who separates from Government employment is entitled to the amount of the balance in the employee’s or Member’s account (except for the portion of such amount forfeited under section 8432(g) of this title, if any) as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to section 8435 of this title, any employee or Member who separates from Government employment is entitled and may elect to withdraw from the Thrift Savings Fund the balance of the employee’s or Member’s account as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notwithstanding subsection (b), if an employee or Member separates from Government employment, and such employee’s or Member’s nonforfeitable account balance is less than an amount that the Executive Director prescribes by regulation, the Executive Director shall pay the nonforfeitable account balance to the participant in a single payment, unless an election under section 8432b(h)(2) is made to treat such separation for purposes of this subsection as if it had never occurred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8433_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>