<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8434" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8434/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8434/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8434"><akn:num>8434</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuities: methods of payment; election; purchase</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8434. Annuities: methods of payment; election; purchase(a)(1) The Board shall prescribe methods of payment of annuities under this subchapter.

(2) The methods of payment prescribed under paragraph (1) shall include, but not be limited to—(A) a method which provides for the payment of a monthly annuity only to an annuitant during the life of the annuitant;

(B) a method which provides for the payment of a monthly annuity to an annuitant for the joint lives of the annuitant and the spouse of the annuitant and an appropriate monthly annuity to the one of them who survives the other of them for the life of the survivor;

(C) a method described in subparagraph (A) which provides for automatic adjustments in the amount of the annuity payable so long as the amount of the annuity payable in any one year shall not be less than the amount payable in the previous year;

(D) a method described in subparagraph (B) which provides for automatic adjustments in the amount of the annuity payable so long as the amount of the annuity payable in any one year shall not be less than the amount payable in the previous year; and

(E) a method which provides for the payment of a monthly annuity—(i) to the annuitant for the joint lives of the annuitant and an individual who is designated by the annuitant under regulations prescribed by the Executive Director and (I) is a former spouse of the annuitant, or (II) has an insurable interest in the annuitant; and

(ii) to the one of them who survives the other of them for the life of the survivor.




(b) Subject to section 8435(b) of this title, under such regulations as the Executive Director shall prescribe, an employee, Member, former employee, or former Member who elects under section 8433 of this title to receive an annuity under this subchapter shall elect, on or before the date on which an annuity contract is purchased to provide for that annuity, one of the methods of payment prescribed under subsection (a).

(c) Notwithstanding the eli</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8434_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8434_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to section 8435(b) of this title, under such regulations as the Executive Director shall prescribe, an employee, Member, former employee, or former Member who elects under section 8433 of this title to receive an annuity under this subchapter shall elect, on or before the date on which an annuity contract is purchased to provide for that annuity, one of the methods of payment prescribed under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8434_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding the elimination of a method of payment by the Board, an employee, Member, former employee, or former Member may elect the eliminated method if the elimination of such method becomes effective less than 5 years before the date on which that individual’s annuity commences.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8434_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8434_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>