<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8440d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8440d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8440d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8440d"><akn:num>8440d</akn:num><akn:heading>Judges of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8440d. Judges of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims(a)(1) A judge of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims may elect to contribute to the Thrift Savings Fund.

(2) An election may be made under paragraph (1) as provided under section 8432(b) of this title for individuals subject to this chapter.


(b)(1) Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the provisions of this subchapter and subchapter VII of this chapter shall apply with respect to a judge making contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund.

(2) The amount contributed by a judge of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims for any pay period may not exceed the maximum percentage of such judge’s basic pay for such pay period allowable under section 8440f. Basic pay does not include any retired pay paid pursuant to section 7296 of title 38.

(3) No contributions may be made for the benefit of a judge under section 8432(c) of this title.

(4) Section 8433(b) of this title applies with respect to a judge who elects to make contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund and retires under section 7296(b) of title 38.

(5) Section 8433(b) of this title applies in the case of a judge who elects to make contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund and thereafter ceases to serve as a judge of the United States Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims but does not retire under section 7296(b) of title 38.

(6) The provisions of section 8351(b)(7) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title shall apply with respect to a judge who has elected to contribute to the Thrift Savings Fund under this section.


(Added Pub. L. 102–82, § 5(a)(1), Aug. 6, 1991, 105 Stat. 376, § 8440c; renumbered § 8440d, Pub. L. 102–198, § 7(c)(4)(A), Dec. 9, 1991, 105 Stat. 1625, as amended by Pub. L. 102–378, § 5(d)(1), Oct. 2, 1992, 106 Stat. 1358; amended Pub. L. 103–226, § 9(h), Mar. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 121; Pub. L. 105–368, title V, § 512(b)(1)(A), (2)(A), Nov. 11, 1998, 112 Stat. 3342; Pub.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8440d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8440d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>