<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8440e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8440e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8440e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8440e"><akn:num>8440e</akn:num><akn:heading>Members of the uniformed services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8440e. Members of the uniformed services(a) For purposes of this section—(1) the term “basic pay” means basic pay payable under section 204 of title 37;

(2) the term “full TSP member” means a member described in subsection (e)(1);

(3) the term “member” has the meaning given the term in section 211 of title 37; and

(4) the term “Secretary concerned” has the meaning given the term in section 101 of title 37.


(b)(1) Any member eligible to participate in the Thrift Savings Plan by virtue of section 211(b) of title 37 may contribute to the Thrift Savings Fund.

(2)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an election to contribute to the Thrift Savings Fund under this section may be made as provided under section 8432(b).

(B)(i) Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), any individual who is a member as of the effective date that applies with respect to such individual under section 663 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000 may make the first such election during the 60-day period beginning on such effective date.

(ii) An election made under this subparagraph shall take effect on the first day of the first applicable pay period beginning after the close of the 60-day period referred to in clause (i).




(c) Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of this subchapter and subchapter VII shall apply with respect to members making contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund, and such members shall, for purposes of this subchapter and subchapter VII, be considered employees within the meaning of section 8401(11).

(d)(1)(A) The amount contributed by a member described in section 211(a)(1) of title 37 for any pay period out of basic pay may not exceed the maximum percentage of such member’s basic pay for such pay period allowable under section 8440f.

(B) The amount contributed by a member described in section 211(a)(2) of title 37 for any pay period out of any compensation received under section 206 of title 37 may not exceed the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8440e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8440e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8440e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of this subchapter and subchapter VII shall apply with respect to members making contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund, and such members shall, for purposes of this subchapter and subchapter VII, be considered employees within the meaning of section 8401(11).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8440e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8440e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modernized Retirement System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>