<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8468" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8468/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8468/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8468"><akn:num>8468</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuities and pay on reemployment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8468. Annuities and pay on reemployment(a) If an annuitant, except a disability annuitant whose annuity is terminated because of the annuitant’s recovery or restoration of earning capacity, becomes employed in an appointive or elective position, an amount equal to the annuity allocable to the period of actual employment shall be deducted from the annuitant’s pay, except for lump-sum leave payment purposes under section 5551. Unless the annuitant’s appointment is on an intermittent basis or is to a position as a justice or judge (as defined by section 451 of title 28) or as an employee subject to another retirement system for Government employees, or unless the annuitant is serving as President, deductions for the Fund shall be withheld from the annuitant’s pay under section 8422(a) and contributions under section 8423 shall be made. The deductions and contributions referred to in the preceding provisions of this subsection shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the Fund. The annuitant’s lump-sum credit may not be reduced by annuity paid during the reemployment.

(b)(1)(A) If an annuitant subject to deductions under the second sentence of subsection (a) serves on a full-time basis for at least 1 year, or on a part-time basis for periods equivalent to at least 1 year of full-time service, the annuitant’s annuity on termination of reemployment shall be increased by an annuity computed under section 8415(a) through (i) as may apply based on the period of reemployment and the basic pay, before deduction, averaged during the reemployment.

(B)(i) If the annuitant is receiving a reduced annuity as provided in section 8419, the increase in annuity payable under subparagraph (A) is reduced by 10 percent and the survivor annuity or combination of survivor annuities payable under section 8442 or 8445 (or both) is increased by 50 percent of the increase in annuity payable under subparagraph (A), unless, at the time of claiming the increase pa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) If an annuitant, except a disability annuitant whose annuity is terminated because of the annuitant’s recovery or restoration of earning capacity, becomes employed in an appointive or elective position, an amount equal to the annuity allocable to the period of actual employment shall be deducted from the annuitant’s pay, except for lump-sum leave payment purposes under section 5551. Unless the annuitant’s appointment is on an intermittent basis or is to a position as a justice or judge (as defined by section 451 of title 28) or as an employee subject to another retirement system for Government employees, or unless the annuitant is serving as President, deductions for the Fund shall be withheld from the annuitant’s pay under section 8422(a) and contributions under section 8423 shall be made. The deductions and contributions referred to in the preceding provisions of this subsection shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the Fund. The annuitant’s lum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) This section does not apply to an individual appointed to serve as a Governor of the Board of Governors of the United States Postal Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If an annuitant becomes employed as a justice or judge of the United States, as defined by section 451 of title 28, the annuitant may, at any time prior to resignation or retirement from regular active service as such a justice or judge, apply for and be paid, in accordance with section 8424(a), the amount (if any) by which the lump-sum credit exceeds the total annuity paid, notwithstanding the time limitation contained in such section for filing an application for payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A reference in this section to an “annuity” shall not be considered to include any amount payable from a source other than the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8468_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>