<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8509" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8509/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8509/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8509"><akn:num>8509</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Employees Compensation Account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8509. Federal Employees Compensation Account(a) The Federal Employees Compensation Account (as established by section 909 of the Social Security Act, and hereafter in this section referred to as the “Account”) in the Unemployment Trust Fund (as established by section 904 of such Act) shall consist of—(1) funds appropriated to or transferred thereto, and

(2) amounts deposited therein pursuant to subsection (c).


(b) Moneys in the Account shall be available only for the purpose of making payments to States pursuant to agreements entered into under this chapter and making payments of compensation under this chapter in States which do not have in effect such an agreement.

(c)(1) Each employing agency shall deposit into the Account amounts equal to the expenditures incurred under this chapter on account of Federal service performed by employees and former employees of that agency.

(2) Deposits required by paragraph (1) shall be made during each calendar quarter and the amount of the deposit to be made by any employing agency during any quarter shall be based on a determination by the Secretary of Labor as to the amounts of payments, made prior to such quarter from the Account based on Federal service performed by employees of such agency after December 31, 1980, with respect to which deposit has not previously been made. The amount to be deposited by any employing agency during any calendar quarter shall be adjusted to take account of any overpayment or underpayment of deposit during any previous quarter for which adjustment has not already been made.

(3) If any Federal agency does not deposit in the Federal Employees Compensation Account any amount before the date 30 days after the date on which the Secretary of Labor has notified such agency that it is required to so deposit such amount, the Secretary of Labor shall notify the Secretary of the Treasury of the failure to make such deposit and the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer such amount to the Federal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8509_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Federal Employees Compensation Account (as established by section 909 of the Social Security Act, and hereafter in this section referred to as the “Account”) in the Unemployment Trust Fund (as established by section 904 of such Act) shall consist of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8509_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Moneys in the Account shall be available only for the purpose of making payments to States pursuant to agreements entered into under this chapter and making payments of compensation under this chapter in States which do not have in effect such an agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8509_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8509_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Labor shall certify to the Secretary of the Treasury the amount of the deposit which each employing agency is required to make to the Account during any calendar quarter, and the Secretary of the Treasury shall notify the Secretary of Labor as to the date and amount of any deposit made to such Account by any such agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8509_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prior to the beginning of each fiscal year (commencing with the fiscal year which begins October 1, 1981) the Secretary of Labor shall estimate— and if, on the basis of such estimate, he determines that the amount described in paragraph (2) is in excess of the amount necessary— he shall certify the amount of such excess to the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer, from the Account to the general fund of the Treasury, an amount equal to such excess.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8509_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Labor is authorized to establish such rules and regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8509_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Any funds appropriated after the establishment of the Account, for the making of payments for which expenditures are authorized to be made from moneys in the Account, shall be made to the Account; and there are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Account, from time to time, such sums as may be necessary to assure that there will, at all times, be sufficient sums available in the Account to meet the expenditures authorized to be made from moneys therein.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8509_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) For purposes of this section, the term “Federal service” includes Federal service as defined in section 8521(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>