<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8706" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8706/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8706/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8706"><akn:num>8706</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of insurance; assignment of ownership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8706. Termination of insurance; assignment of ownership(a) A policy purchased under this chapter shall contain a provision, approved by the Office of Personnel Management, to the effect that insurance on an employee stops on his separation from the service or 12 months after discontinuance of his pay, whichever is earlier, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to an individual policy of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office. Justices and judges of the United States described in section 8701(a)(5)(ii) and (iii) of this chapter are deemed to continue in active employment for purposes of this chapter.

(b)(1) In the case of any employee who retires on an immediate annuity and has been insured under this chapter throughout—(A) the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date of the employee’s retirement, or

(B) the full period or periods of service during which the employee was entitled to be insured, if fewer than 5 years,


life insurance, without accidental death and dismemberment insurance, may be continued, under conditions determined by the Office.

(2) In the case of any employee who becomes entitled to receive compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee and has been insured under this chapter throughout—(A) the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date the employee becomes entitled to compensation, or

(B) the full period or periods of service during which the employee was entitled to be insured, if fewer than 5 years,


life insurance, without accidental death and dismemberment insurance, may be continued, under conditions determined by the Office, during the period the employee is receiving compensation and is held by the Secretary of Labor or the Secretary’s delegate to be unable to return to duty.

(3) The amount of life insurance continued under paragraph (1) or (2) of this subsection shall be continued, with o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A policy purchased under this chapter shall contain a provision, approved by the Office of Personnel Management, to the effect that insurance on an employee stops on his separation from the service or 12 months after discontinuance of his pay, whichever is earlier, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to an individual policy of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office. Justices and judges of the United States described in section 8701(a)(5)(ii) and (iii) of this chapter are deemed to continue in active employment for purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of this section, an employee who enters on approved leave without pay to serve as a full-time officer or employee of an organization composed primarily of employees as defined by section 8701(a) of this title, within 60 days after entering on that leave without pay, may elect to continue his insurance and arrange to pay currently into the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund, through his employing agency, both employee and agency contributions from the beginning of leave without pay. The employing agency shall forward the premium payments to the Fund. If the employee does not so elect, his insurance will continue during nonpay status and stop as provided by subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If the insurance of an employee stops because of separation from the service or suspension without pay, and the separation or suspension is thereafter officially found to have been erroneous, the employee is deemed to have been insured during the period of erroneous separation or suspension. Deductions otherwise required by section 8707 of this chapter shall not be withheld from any backpay awarded for the period of separation or suspension unless death or accidental dismemberment of the employee occurs during such period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) If the insurance of a former employee receiving a disability annuity under section 8337 of this title stops because of the termination of such annuity, and such annuity is thereafter restored under the second or third sentence of subsection (e) of such section, such former employee may, under regulations prescribed by the Office, elect to resume the insurance coverage which was so stopped.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8706_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The insurance of an employee under a policy purchased under section 8709 shall not be invalidated based on a finding that the employee erroneously became insured, or erroneously continued insurance upon retirement or entitlement to compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title, if such finding occurs after the erroneous insurance and applicable withholdings have been in force for 2 years during the employee’s lifetime.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>