<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8707" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8707/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8707/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8707"><akn:num>8707</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee deductions; withholding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8707. Employee deductions; withholding(a) Subject to subsection (c)(2), during each period in which an employee is insured under a policy purchased by the Office of Personnel Management under section 8709 of this title, there shall be withheld from the employee’s pay a share of the cost of the group life insurance and accidental death and dismemberment insurance.

(b)(1) Subject to subsection (c)(2), whenever life insurance continues after an employee retires on an immediate annuity or while the employee is receiving compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee, as provided in section 8706(b) of this title, deductions for insurance shall be withheld from the employee’s annuity or compensation, except that, in any case in which the insurance is continued as provided in section 8706(b)(3)(A) of this title, the deductions shall not be made for months after the calendar month in which the employee becomes 65 years of age.

(2) Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of this subsection, insurance shall be so continued without cost (other than as provided under section 8706(b)(3)(B)) to each employee who so retires, or commences receiving compensation, on or before December 31, 1989.


(c)(1) The amount withheld from the pay, annuity, or compensation of each employee subject to insurance deductions shall be at the rate, adjusted to the nearest half-cent, of 66⅔ percent of the level cost as determined by the Office for each $1,000 of the employee’s basic insurance amount.

(2) An employee who is subject to withholdings under this section and whose pay, annuity, or compensation is insufficient to cover such withholdings may nevertheless continue insurance if the employee arranges to pay currently into the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund, through the agency or retirement system that administers pay, annuity, or compensation, an amount equal to the withholdings that would otherwise be required under this section.


(d) If an </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8707_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsection (c)(2), during each period in which an employee is insured under a policy purchased by the Office of Personnel Management under section 8709 of this title, there shall be withheld from the employee’s pay a share of the cost of the group life insurance and accidental death and dismemberment insurance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8707_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8707_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8707_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If an agency fails to withhold the proper amount of life insurance deductions from an individual’s salary, compensation, or retirement annuity, the collection of unpaid deductions may be waived by the agency if, in the judgment of the agency, the individual is without fault and recovery would be against equity and good conscience. However, if the agency so waives the collection of unpaid deductions, the agency shall submit an amount equal to the sum of the uncollected deductions and related agency contributions required under section 8708 of this title to the Office for deposit to the Employees’ Life Insurance Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>