<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8708" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8708/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8708/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8708"><akn:num>8708</akn:num><akn:heading>Government contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8708. Government contributions(a) For each period in which an employee is insured under a policy of insurance purchased by the Office of Personnel Management under section 8709 of this title, a sum equal to one-half the amount which is withheld from the pay of the employee under section 8707 of this title shall be contributed from the appropriation or fund which is used to pay him.

(b) When an employee is paid by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer may contribute the sum required by subsection (a) of this section from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives.

(c) When the employee is an elected official, the sum required by subsection (a) of this section is contributed from an appropriation or fund available for payment of other salaries of the same office or establishment.

(d)(1) Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, for each period in which an employee continues life insurance after retirement or while in receipt of compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee, as provided under section 8706(b) of this title, a sum equal to one-half of the amount which is withheld from the employee’s annuity or compensation under section 8707 of this title shall be contributed by the Office from annual appropriations which are authorized to be made for that purpose and which may be made available until expended.

(2) Contributions under this subsection—(A) shall not be made other than with respect to individuals who retire, or commence receiving compensation, after December 31, 1989;

(B) shall not be made with respect to any individual for months after the calendar month in which such individual becomes 65 years of age; and

(C) shall, in the case of any individual who elects coverage under subparagraph (B) of section 8706(b)(3) of this title, be equal to the amount which would apply under this subsection if such individual had </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8708_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For each period in which an employee is insured under a policy of insurance purchased by the Office of Personnel Management under section 8709 of this title, a sum equal to one-half the amount which is withheld from the pay of the employee under section 8707 of this title shall be contributed from the appropriation or fund which is used to pay him.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8708_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) When an employee is paid by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer may contribute the sum required by subsection (a) of this section from the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8708_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) When the employee is an elected official, the sum required by subsection (a) of this section is contributed from an appropriation or fund available for payment of other salaries of the same office or establishment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8708_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>