<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8711"><akn:num>8711</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic tables of premium rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8711. Basic tables of premium rates(a) A policy purchased under this chapter shall include, for the first policy year, basic tables of premium rates as follows:(1) For group life insurance, a schedule of basic premium rates by age which the Office of Personnel Management determines to be consistent with the lowest schedule of basic premium rates generally charged for new group life insurance policies issued to large employers.

(2) For group accidental death and dismemberment insurance, a basic premium rate which the Office determines is consistent with the lowest rate generally charged for new group accidental death and dismemberment policies issued to large employers.


The schedule for group life insurance, except as otherwise provided by this section, shall be applied to the distribution by age of the amounts of group life insurance under the policy at its date of issuance to determine an average basic premium rate per $1,000 of life insurance.

(b) The policy shall provide that the basic premium rates determined for the first policy year continue for later policy years except as readjusted for a later year based on experience under the policy. The company issuing the policy may make the readjustment on a basis that the Office determines in advance of the policy year is consistent with the general practice of life insurance companies under policies of group life and group accidental death and dismemberment insurance issued to large employers.

(c) The policy shall provide that if the Office determines that ascertaining the actual age distribution of the amounts of group life insurance in force at the date of issue of the policy or at the end of the first or any later year of insurance thereunder would not be possible except at a disproportionately high expense, the Office may approve the determination of a tentative average group life premium rate, for the first or any later policy year, instead of using the actual age distribution. The Office, on request by t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A policy purchased under this chapter shall include, for the first policy year, basic tables of premium rates as follows: The schedule for group life insurance, except as otherwise provided by this section, shall be applied to the distribution by age of the amounts of group life insurance under the policy at its date of issuance to determine an average basic premium rate per $1,000 of life insurance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The policy shall provide that the basic premium rates determined for the first policy year continue for later policy years except as readjusted for a later year based on experience under the policy. The company issuing the policy may make the readjustment on a basis that the Office determines in advance of the policy year is consistent with the general practice of life insurance companies under policies of group life and group accidental death and dismemberment insurance issued to large employers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The policy shall provide that if the Office determines that ascertaining the actual age distribution of the amounts of group life insurance in force at the date of issue of the policy or at the end of the first or any later year of insurance thereunder would not be possible except at a disproportionately high expense, the Office may approve the determination of a tentative average group life premium rate, for the first or any later policy year, instead of using the actual age distribution. The Office, on request by the company issuing the policy, shall redetermine the tentative average premium rate during any policy year, if experience indicates that the assumptions made in determining that rate were incorrect for that year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The policy shall stipulate the maximum expense and risk charges for the first policy year. The Office shall determine these charges on a basis consistent with the general level of charges made by life insurance companies under policies of group life and accidental death and dismemberment insurance issued to large employers. The maximum charges continue from year to year, except that the Office may redetermine them for any year either by agreement with the company issuing the policy or on written notice given to the company at least 1 year before the beginning of the year for which the redetermined maximum charges will be effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>