<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8714c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8714c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8714c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8714c"><akn:num>8714c</akn:num><akn:heading>Optional life insurance on family members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8714c. Optional life insurance on family members(a) Under the conditions, directives, and terms specified in sections 8709 through 8712 of this title, the Office of Personnel Management, without regard to section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, may purchase a policy which shall make available to each employee insured under section 8702 of this title amounts of optional life insurance (without accidental death and dismemberment insurance) on the employee’s family members.

(b)(1) The optional life insurance on family members provided under this section shall be made available to each eligible employee who has elected coverage under this section, under conditions the Office shall prescribe, in multiples, at the employee’s election, of 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5 times—(A) $5,000 for a spouse; and

(B) $2,500 for each child described under section 8701(d).


(2) An employee may reduce or stop coverage elected pursuant to this section at any time.


(c)(1) Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the optional life insurance on family members shall stop at the earlier of the employee’s death, the employee’s separation from the service, or 12 months after discontinuance of pay, subject to a provision for temporary extension of life insurance coverage and for conversion to individual policies of life insurance under conditions approved by the Office.

(2) In the case of any employee who retires on an immediate annuity or who becomes entitled to receive compensation under subchapter I of chapter 81 of this title because of disease or injury to the employee and who has had in force insurance under this section for no less than—(A) the 5 years of service immediately preceding the date of retirement or entitlement to compensation, or

(B) the full period or periods of service during which the insurance was available to the employee, if fewer than 5 years,


optional life insurance on family members may be continued under the same conditions as provided in section 8714b(c)(2) throug</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8714c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under the conditions, directives, and terms specified in sections 8709 through 8712 of this title, the Office of Personnel Management, without regard to section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41, may purchase a policy which shall make available to each employee insured under section 8702 of this title amounts of optional life insurance (without accidental death and dismemberment insurance) on the employee’s family members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8714c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8714c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8714c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8714c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The cost of the optional life insurance on family members shall be determined from time to time by the Office on the basis of the employee’s age relative to such age groups as the Office establishes under section 8714a(e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8714c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The amount of optional life insurance which is in force under this section on a family member of an employee or former employee on the date of the death of the family member shall be paid, on the establishment of a valid claim by the employee, to such employee or, in the event of the death of the employee before payment can be made, to the person or persons entitled to the group life insurance in force on the employee under section 8705 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>