<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8902a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8902a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8902a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8902a"><akn:num>8902a</akn:num><akn:heading>Debarment and other sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8902a. Debarment and other sanctions(a)(1) For the purpose of this section—(A) the term “provider of health care services or supplies” or “provider” means a physician, hospital, or other individual or entity which furnishes health care services or supplies;

(B) the term “individual covered under this chapter” or “covered individual” means an employee, annuitant, family member, or former spouse covered by a health benefits plan described by section 8903 or 8903a;

(C) an individual or entity shall be considered to have been “convicted” of a criminal offense if—(i) a judgment of conviction for such offense has been entered against the individual or entity by a Federal, State, or local court;

(ii) there has been a finding of guilt against the individual or entity by a Federal, State, or local court with respect to such offense;

(iii) a plea of guilty or nolo contendere by the individual or entity has been accepted by a Federal, State, or local court with respect to such offense; or

(iv) in the case of an individual, the individual has entered a first offender or other program pursuant to which a judgment of conviction for such offense has been withheld;


without regard to the pendency or outcome of any appeal (other than a judgment of acquittal based on innocence) or request for relief on behalf of the individual or entity; and

(D) the term “should know” means that a person, with respect to information, acts in deliberate ignorance of, or in reckless disregard of, the truth or falsity of the information, and no proof of specific intent to defraud is required; 11 So in original. The semicolon probably should be a period.


(2)(A) Notwithstanding section 8902(j) or any other provision of this chapter, if, under subsection (b), (c), or (d) a provider is barred from participating in the program under this chapter, no payment may be made by a carrier pursuant to any contract under this chapter (either to such provider or by reimbursement) for any service or supply f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Office of Personnel Management shall bar the following providers of health care services or supplies from participating in the program under this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Office may bar the following providers of health care services from participating in the program under this chapter: Any determination under paragraph (4) relating to whether a charge for health care services or supplies is substantially in excess of the needs of the covered individual shall be made by trained reviewers based on written medical protocols developed by physicians. In the event such a determination cannot be made based on such protocols, a physician in an appropriate specialty shall be consulted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Whenever the Office determines— the Office may, in addition to any other penalties that may be prescribed by law, and after consultation with the Attorney General, impose a civil monetary penalty of not more than $10,000 for any item or service involved. In addition, such a provider shall be subject to an assessment of not more than twice the amount claimed for each such item or service. In addition, the Office may make a determination in the same proceeding to bar such provider from participating in the program under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Office—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In making a determination relating to the appropriateness of imposing or the period of any debarment under this section (where such debarment is not mandatory), or the appropriateness of imposing or the amount of any civil penalty or assessment under this section, the Office shall take into account—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A civil action to recover civil monetary penalties or assessments under subsection (d) shall be brought by the Attorney General in the name of the United States, and may be brought in the United States district court for the district where the claim involved was presented or where the person subject to the penalty resides. Amounts recovered under this section shall be paid to the Office for deposit into the Employees Health Benefits Fund. The amount of a penalty or assessment as finally determined by the Office, or other amount the Office may agree to in compromise, may be deducted from any sum then or later owing by the United States to the party against whom the penalty or assessment has been levied.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8902a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Office shall prescribe regulations under which, with respect to services or supplies furnished by a debarred provider to a covered individual during the period of such provider’s debarment, payment or reimbursement under this chapter may be made, notwithstanding the fact of such debarment, if such individual did not know or could not reasonably be expected to have known of the debarment. In any such instance, the carrier involved shall take appropriate measures to ensure that the individual is informed of the debarment and the minimum period of time remaining under the terms of the debarment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>