<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8903c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8903c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8903c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8903c"><akn:num>8903c</akn:num><akn:heading>Postal Service Health Benefits Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8903c. Postal Service Health Benefits Program(a) Definitions.—In this section—(1) the term “covered Medicare individual” means an individual who is entitled to benefits under Medicare part A, but excluding an individual who is eligible to enroll under such part under section 1818 or 1818A of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395i–2, 1395i–2a);

(2) the term “initial contract year” means the contract year beginning in January of 2025;

(3) the term “initial participating carrier” means a carrier that enters into a contract with the Office to participate in the Program during the initial contract year;

(4) the term “Medicare part A” means part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395c et seq.);

(5) the term “Medicare part B” means part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395j et seq.);

(6) the term “Office” means the Office of Personnel Management;

(7) the term “Postal Service” means the United States Postal Service;

(8) the term “Postal Service annuitant” means an annuitant enrolled in a health benefits plan under this chapter whose Government contribution is required to be paid under section 8906(g)(2);

(9) the term “Postal Service employee” means an employee of the Postal Service enrolled in a health benefits plan under this chapter whose Government contribution is paid by the Postal Service;

(10) the term “Postal Service Medicare covered annuitant” means an individual who—(A) is a Postal Service annuitant; and

(B) is a covered Medicare individual;


(11) the term “Program” means the Postal Service Health Benefits Program established under subsection (c) within the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program;

(12) the term “Program plan” means a health benefits plan offered under the Program; and

(13) the definitions set forth in section 8901 shall apply, and for the purposes of applying such definitions in carrying out this section, a Postal Service employee and Postal Service annuitant shall be treated in the sam</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The requirements under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Postal Service Health Benefits Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of Coverage.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Each Postal Service employee and Postal Service annuitant who elects to receive health benefits coverage under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of Medicare Enrollment for Certain Annuitants and Their Family Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transitional Open Season.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>OPM Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medicare Coordination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Postal Service Contribution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8903c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserves.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>