<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8905a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8905a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8905a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8905a"><akn:num>8905a</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8905a. Continued coverage(a) Any individual described in subsection (b) may elect to continue coverage under this chapter in accordance with the provisions of this section.

(b) This section applies with respect to—(1) any employee who—(A) is separated from service, whether voluntarily or involuntarily, except that if the separation is involuntary, this section shall not apply if the separation is for gross misconduct (as defined under regulations which the Office of Personnel Management shall prescribe); and

(B) would not otherwise be eligible for any benefits under this chapter (determined without regard to any temporary extension of coverage and without regard to any benefits available under a nongroup contract);


(2) any individual who—(A) ceases to meet the requirements for being considered an unmarried dependent child under this chapter;

(B) on the day before so ceasing to meet the requirements referred to in subparagraph (A), was covered under a health benefits plan under this chapter as a member of the family of an employee or annuitant; and

(C) would not otherwise be eligible for any benefits under this chapter (determined without regard to any temporary extension of coverage and without regard to any benefits available under a nongroup contract); and


(3) any employee who—(A) is enrolled in a health benefits plan under this chapter;

(B) is a member of a reserve component of the armed forces;

(C) is called or ordered to active duty in support of a contingency operation (as defined in section 101(a)(13) of title 10);

(D) is placed on leave without pay or separated from service to perform active duty; and

(E) serves on active duty for a period of more than 30 consecutive days.



(c)(1) The Office shall prescribe regulations and provide for the inclusion of appropriate terms in contracts with carriers to provide that—(A) with respect to an employee who becomes (or will become) eligible for continued coverage under this section as a result of separa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8905a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any individual described in subsection (b) may elect to continue coverage under this chapter in accordance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8905a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) This section applies with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8905a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8905a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8905a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8905a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>