<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8958" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8958/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/8958/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8958"><akn:num>8958</akn:num><akn:heading>Premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8958. Premiums(a) Each eligible individual obtaining supplemental dental coverage under this chapter shall be responsible for 100 percent of the premiums for such coverage.

(b) The Office shall prescribe regulations specifying the terms and conditions under which individuals are required to pay the premiums for enrollment.

(c) The amount necessary to pay the premiums for enrollment may—(1) in the case of an employee, be withheld from the pay of such an employee;

(2) in the case of an annuitant, be withheld from the annuity of such an annuitant;

(3) in the case of a covered TRICARE-eligible individual who receives pay from the Federal Government or an annuity from the Federal Government due to the death of a member of the uniformed services (as defined in section 101 of title 10), and is not a former spouse of a member of the uniformed services, be withheld from—(A) the pay (including retired pay) of such individual; or

(B) the annuity paid to such individual; or


(4) in the case of a covered TRICARE-eligible individual who is not described in paragraph (3), be billed to such individual directly.


(d) All amounts withheld under this section shall be paid directly to the qualified company.

(e) Each participating qualified company shall maintain accounting records that contain such information and reports as the Office may require.

(f)(1) The Employee Health Benefits Fund is available, without fiscal year limitation, for reasonable expenses incurred by the Office in administering this chapter before the first day of the first contract period, including reasonable implementation costs.

(2)(A) There is established in the Employees Health Benefits Fund a Dental Benefits Administrative Account, which shall be available to the Office, without fiscal year limitation, to defray reasonable expenses incurred by the Office in administering this chapter after the start of the first contract year.

(B) A contract under this chapter shall include appropriate provisions </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8958_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each eligible individual obtaining supplemental dental coverage under this chapter shall be responsible for 100 percent of the premiums for such coverage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8958_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Office shall prescribe regulations specifying the terms and conditions under which individuals are required to pay the premiums for enrollment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8958_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The amount necessary to pay the premiums for enrollment may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8958_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) All amounts withheld under this section shall be paid directly to the qualified company.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8958_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Each participating qualified company shall maintain accounting records that contain such information and reports as the Office may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8958_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>