<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/9813" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/9813/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/9813/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9813"><akn:num>9813</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited appointments to Senior Executive Service positions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9813. Limited appointments to Senior Executive Service positions(a) In this section—(1) the term “career reserved position” means a position in the Administration designated under section 3132(b) which may be filled only by—(A) a career appointee; or

(B) a limited emergency appointee or a limited term appointee—(i) who, immediately before entering the career reserved position, was serving under a career or career-conditional appointment outside the Senior Executive Service; or

(ii) whose limited emergency or limited term appointment is approved in advance by the Office of Personnel Management;



(2) the term “limited emergency appointee” has the meaning given under section 3132; and

(3) the term “limited term appointee” means an individual appointed to a Senior Executive Service position in the Administration to meet a bona fide temporary need, as determined by the Administrator.


(b) The number of career reserved positions which are filled by an appointee as described under subsection (a)(1)(B) may not exceed 10 percent of the total number of Senior Executive Service positions allocated to the Administration.

(c) Notwithstanding sections 3132 and 3394(b)—(1) the Administrator may appoint an individual to any Senior Executive Service position in the Administration as a limited term appointee under this section for a period of—(A) 4 years or less to a position the duties of which will expire at the end of such term; or

(B) 1 year or less to a position the duties of which are continuing; and


(2) in rare circumstances, the Administrator may authorize an extension of a limited appointment under—(A) paragraph (1)(A) for a period not to exceed 2 years; and

(B) paragraph (1)(B) for a period not to exceed 1 year.



(d) A limited term appointee who has been appointed in the Administration from a career or career-conditional appointment outside the Senior Executive Service shall have reemployment rights in the agency from which appointed, or in another agency, un</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9813_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9813_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The number of career reserved positions which are filled by an appointee as described under subsection (a)(1)(B) may not exceed 10 percent of the total number of Senior Executive Service positions allocated to the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9813_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding sections 3132 and 3394(b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9813_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A limited term appointee who has been appointed in the Administration from a career or career-conditional appointment outside the Senior Executive Service shall have reemployment rights in the agency from which appointed, or in another agency, under requirements and conditions established by the Office of Personnel Management. The Office shall have the authority to direct such placement in any agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9813_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notwithstanding section 3394(b) and section 3395—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9813_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A limited term appointee may not serve more than 7 consecutive years under any combination of limited appointments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9813_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notwithstanding section 5384, the Administrator may authorize performance awards to limited term appointees in the Administration in the same amounts and in the same manner as career appointees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>