<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/9902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/9902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/9902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9902"><akn:num>9902</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Defense personnel authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9902. Department of Defense personnel authorities(a) Performance Management and Workforce Incentives.—(1) The Secretary, in coordination with the Director, shall promulgate regulations providing for the following:(A) A fair, credible, and transparent performance appraisal system for employees.

(B) A fair, credible, and transparent system for linking employee bonuses and other performance-based actions to performance appraisals of employees.

(C) A process for ensuring ongoing performance feedback and dialogue among supervisors, managers, and employees throughout the appraisal period and setting timetables for review.

(D) Development of attractive career paths.

(E) Development of “performance assistance plans” that are designed to give employees formal training, on-the-job training, counseling, mentoring, and other assistance.


(2) In developing the regulations required by this subsection, the Secretary, in coordination with the Director, may waive the requirements of chapter 43 (other than sections 4302 and 4303(e)) and the regulations implementing such chapter, to the extent necessary to achieve the objectives of this subsection.

(3)(A) The Secretary may establish a fund, to be known as the “Department of Defense Civilian Workforce Incentive Fund” (in this paragraph referred to as the “Fund”).

(B) The Fund shall consist of the following:(i) Amounts appropriated to the Fund.

(ii) Amounts available for compensation of employees that are transferred to the Fund.


(C) Amounts in the Fund shall be available for the following:(i) Incentive payments for employees based on team or individual performance (which payments shall be in addition to basic pay).

(ii) Incentive payments to attract or retain employees with particular or superior qualifications or abilities.


(D) The authority provided in this paragraph is in addition to, and does not supersede or replace, any authority or source of funding otherwise available to the Secretary to pay bonuses or make incen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance Management and Workforce Incentives.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexibilities Relating to Appointments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for Use of New Personnel Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In establishing any new performance management and workforce incentive system under subsection (a) or utilizing appointment flexibilities under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9902_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of Training Program for Supervisors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9902_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions Regarding National Level Bargaining.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9902_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions Related to Separation and Retirement Incentives.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9902_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions Relating to Reemployment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9902_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>