<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/9905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/9905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/5/9905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9905"><akn:num>9905</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct hire authority for certain personnel of the Department of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9905. Direct hire authority for certain personnel of the Department of Defense(a) In General.—The Secretary of Defense may appoint, without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 (other than sections 3303, 3307, and 3328 of such chapter), qualified candidates to any of the following positions in the competitive service in the Department of Defense:(1) Any position involved with Department maintenance activities, including depot-level maintenance and repair.

(2) Any cyber workforce position.

(3) Any individual in the acquisition workforce that manages any services contracts necessary to the operation and maintenance of programs of the Department.

(4) Any science, technology, or engineering position, including any such position at the Major Range and Test Facilities Base, in order to allow development of new systems and provide for the maintenance of legacy systems.

(5) Any scientific, technical, engineering, or mathematics positions, including technicians, within the defense acquisition workforce, or any category of acquisition positions within the Department designated by the Secretary as a shortage or critical need category.

(6) Any scientific, technical, engineering, or mathematics position, except any such position within any defense Scientific and Technology Reinvention Laboratory, for which a qualified candidate is required to possess a bachelor’s degree or an advanced degree, or for which a veteran candidate is being considered.

(7) Any category of medical or health professional positions within the Department designated by the Secretary as a shortage category or critical need occupation.

(8) Any childcare services position for which there is a critical hiring need and a shortage of childcare providers.

(9) Any financial management, accounting, auditing, actuarial, cost estimation, operational research, or business or business administration position for which a qualified candidate is required to possess a finance, accounting, managem</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may appoint, without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 (other than sections 3303, 3307, and 3328 of such chapter), qualified candidates to any of the following positions in the competitive service in the Department of Defense:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of Other Hiring Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) During the period beginning on the effective date of the regulations issued to carry out the hiring authority with respect to positions described in paragraphs (5) through (10) of subsection (a) and ending on the date described in subsection (b)(1), the Secretary of Defense may not exercise or otherwise use any hiring authority provided under the following provisions of law:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>