<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/32/113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/32/113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/32/113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_113"><akn:num>113</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal financial assistance for support of additional duties assigned to the Army National Guard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 113. Federal financial assistance for support of additional duties assigned to the Army National Guard(a) Authority.—The Secretary of the Army may provide financial assistance to a State to support activities carried out by the Army National Guard of the State in the performance of duties that the Secretary has assigned, with the consent of the Chief of the National Guard Bureau, to the Army National Guard of the State. The Secretary shall determine the amount of the assistance that is appropriate for the purpose.

(b) Covered Activities.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), financial assistance may be provided for the performance of an activity by the Army National Guard under subsection (a) only if—(A) the activity is carried out in the performance of a responsibility of the Secretary of the Army under paragraph (6), (10), or (11) of section 7013(b) of title 10; and

(B) the Army National Guard was selected to perform the activity under competitive procedures that permit all qualified public-sector and private-sector sources to submit offers and be considered for selection to perform the activity on the basis of the offers, subject to the exceptions provided in section 3204(a) of title 10.


(2) Paragraph (1)(B) does not apply to an activity that, on October 17, 1998, was performed for the Federal Government by employees of the Federal Government or employees of a State.


(c) Disbursement Through National Guard Bureau.—The Secretary of the Army shall disburse any contribution under this section through the Chief of the National Guard Bureau.

(d) Availability of Funds.—Funds appropriated for the Army for a fiscal year are available for providing financial assistance under this section in support of activities carried out by the Army National Guard during that fiscal year.

(Added Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, § 386(a), Nov. 18, 1997, 111 Stat. 1712; amended Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title III, § 375(a), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 1992; Pub. L. 106–65, div</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Army may provide financial assistance to a State to support activities carried out by the Army National Guard of the State in the performance of duties that the Secretary has assigned, with the consent of the Chief of the National Guard Bureau, to the Army National Guard of the State. The Secretary shall determine the amount of the assistance that is appropriate for the purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbursement Through National Guard Bureau.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of the Army shall disburse any contribution under this section through the Chief of the National Guard Bureau.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funds appropriated for the Army for a fiscal year are available for providing financial assistance under this section in support of activities carried out by the Army National Guard during that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>