<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/32/509" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/32/509/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/32/509/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_509"><akn:num>509</akn:num><akn:heading>National Guard Youth Challenge Program of opportunities for civilian youth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 509. National Guard Youth Challenge Program of opportunities for civilian youth(a) Program Authority and Purpose.—The Secretary of Defense may use the National Guard to conduct a civilian youth opportunities program, to be known as the “National Guard Youth Challenge Program”, which shall consist of at least a 22-week residential program and a 12-month post-residential mentoring period. The Program shall seek to improve life skills and employment potential of participants by providing military-based training and supervised work experience, together with the core program components of assisting participants to receive a high school diploma or its equivalent, leadership development, promoting fellowship and community service, developing life coping skills and job skills, and improving physical fitness and health and hygiene.

(b) Conduct of the Program.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall provide for the conduct of the Program in such States as the Secretary considers to be appropriate.

(2) The Secretary shall carry out the Program using—(A) funds appropriated directly to the Secretary of Defense for the Program, except that the amount of funds appropriated directly to the Secretary and expended for the Program in fiscal year 2001 or 2002 may not exceed $62,500,000; and

(B) nondefense funds made available or transferred to the Secretary of Defense by other Federal agencies to support the Program.


(3) Federal funds made available or transferred to the Secretary of Defense under paragraph (2)(B) by other Federal agencies to support the Program may be expended for the Program in excess of the fiscal year limitation specified in paragraph (2)(A).

(4) The Secretary of Defense shall remain the executive agent to carry out the Program regardless of the source of funds for the Program or any transfer of jurisdiction over the Program within the executive branch. As provided in subsection (a), the Secretary may use the National Guard to conduct the Program.


(c) Program </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Authority and Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may use the National Guard to conduct a civilian youth opportunities program, to be known as the “National Guard Youth Challenge Program”, which shall consist of at least a 22-week residential program and a 12-month post-residential mentoring period. The Program shall seek to improve life skills and employment potential of participants by providing military-based training and supervised work experience, together with the core program components of assisting participants to receive a high school diploma or its equivalent, leadership development, promoting fellowship and community service, developing life coping skills and job skills, and improving physical fitness and health and hygiene.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conduct of the Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching Funds Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons Eligible To Participate in Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A school dropout from secondary school shall be eligible to participate in the Program. The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe the standards and procedures for selecting participants from among school dropouts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Benefits for Participants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equipment and Facilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of Participants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_509_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) To carry out the Program in a State, the Governor of the State or, in the case of the District of Columbia, the commanding general of the District of Columbia National Guard may supplement funds made available under the Program out of other resources (including gifts) available to the Governor or the commanding general. The Governor or the commanding general may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of money, other property, or services for the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>