<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/32/709" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/32/709/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/32/709/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_709"><akn:num>709</akn:num><akn:heading>Technicians: employment, use, status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 709. Technicians: employment, use, status(a) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force, as the case may be, and subject to subsections (b) and (c), persons may be employed as technicians in—(1) the organizing, administering, instructing, or training of the National Guard;

(2) the maintenance and repair of supplies issued to the National Guard or the armed forces; and

(3) the performance of the following additional duties to the extent that the performance of those duties does not interfere with the performance of the duties described by paragraphs (1) and (2):(A) Support of operations or missions undertaken by the technician’s unit at the request of the President or the Secretary of Defense.

(B) Support of Federal training operations or Federal training missions assigned in whole or in part to the technician’s unit.

(C) Instructing or training in the United States or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or possessions of the United States of—(i) active-duty members of the armed forces;

(ii) members of foreign military forces (under the same authorities and restrictions applicable to active-duty members providing such instruction or training);

(iii) Department of Defense contractor personnel; or

(iv) Department of Defense civilian employees.




(b) Except as authorized in subsection (c), a person employed under subsection (a) must meet each of the following requirements:(1) Be a military technician (dual status) as defined in section 10216(a) of title 10.

(2) Be a member of the National Guard.

(3) Hold the military grade specified by the Secretary concerned for that position.

(4) While performing duties as a military technician (dual status), wear the uniform appropriate for the member’s grade and component of the armed forces.


(c)(1) A person may be employed under subsection (a) as a non-dual status technician (as defined by section 10217 of title 10) if the technician position occupied by the person has be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of the Air Force, as the case may be, and subject to subsections (b) and (c), persons may be employed as technicians in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as authorized in subsection (c), a person employed under subsection (a) must meet each of the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary concerned shall designate the adjutants general referred to in section 314 of this title to employ and administer the technicians authorized by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A technician employed under subsection (a) is an employee of the Department of the Army or the Department of the Air Force, as the case may be, and an employee of the United States. However, a position authorized by this section is outside the competitive service if the technician employed in that position is required under subsection (b) to be a member of the National Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notwithstanding any other provision of law and under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notwithstanding sections 5544(a) and 6101(a) of title 5 or any other provision of law, the Secretary concerned may prescribe the hours of duty for technicians. Notwithstanding sections 5542 and 5543 of title 5 or any other provision of law, such technicians shall be granted an amount of compensatory time off from their scheduled tour of duty equal to the amount of any time spent by them in irregular or overtime work, and shall not be entitled to compensation for such work.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary concerned may not prescribe for purposes of eligibility for Federal recognition under section 301 of this title a qualification applicable to technicians employed under subsection (a) that is not applicable pursuant to that section to the other members of the National Guard in the same grade, branch, position, and type of unit or organization involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_709_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>