<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1521" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1521/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1521/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1521"><akn:num>1521</akn:num><akn:heading>Destruction of existing stockpile of lethal chemical agents and munitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1521. Destruction of existing stockpile of lethal chemical agents and munitions(a) In generalThe Secretary of Defense shall, in accordance with the provisions of this section, carry out the destruction of the United States’ stockpile of lethal chemical agents and munitions that exists on November 8, 1985.


(b) Date for completion(1) The destruction of such stockpile shall be completed by the stockpile elimination deadline.

(2) If the Secretary of Defense determines at any time that there will be a delay in meeting the requirement in paragraph (1) for the completion of the destruction of chemical weapons by the stockpile elimination deadline, the Secretary shall immediately notify the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives of that projected delay.

(3) For purposes of this section, the term “stockpile elimination deadline” means the deadline established by the Chemical Weapons Convention, but not later than December 31, 2023.


(c) Initiation of demilitarization operationsThe Secretary of Defense may not initiate destruction of the chemical munitions stockpile stored at a site until the following support measures are in place:(1) Support measures that are required by Department of Defense and Army chemical surety and security program regulations.

(2) Support measures that are required by the general and site chemical munitions demilitarization plans specific to that installation.

(3) Support measures that are required by the permits required by the Solid Waste Disposal Act (42 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.) and the Clean Air Act (42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.) for chemical munitions demilitarization operations at that installation, as approved by the appropriate State regulatory agencies.


(d) Environmental protection and use of facilities(1) In carrying out the requirement of subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall provide for—(A) maximum protection for the environment, the general public, and the p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Defense shall, in accordance with the provisions of this section, carry out the destruction of the United States’ stockpile of lethal chemical agents and munitions that exists on November 8, 1985.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date for completion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Date for completion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiation of demilitarization operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Initiation of demilitarization operations The Secretary of Defense may not initiate destruction of the chemical munitions stockpile stored at a site until the following support measures are in place:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental protection and use of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Environmental protection and use of facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grants and cooperative agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for strategic plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Requirement for strategic plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Management organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Identification of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Annual reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1521_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quarterly briefing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Quarterly briefing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>