<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1541" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1541/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1541/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1541"><akn:num>1541</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1541. Purpose and policy(a) Congressional declarationIt is the purpose of this chapter to fulfill the intent of the framers of the Constitution of the United States and insure that the collective judgment of both the Congress and the President will apply to the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances, and to the continued use of such forces in hostilities or in such situations.


(b) Congressional legislative power under necessary and proper clauseUnder article I, section 8, of the Constitution, it is specifically provided that the Congress shall have the power to make all laws necessary and proper for carrying into execution, not only its own powers but also all other powers vested by the Constitution in the Government of the United States, or in any department or officer thereof.


(c) Presidential executive power as Commander-in-Chief; limitationThe constitutional powers of the President as Commander-in-Chief to introduce United States Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances, are exercised only pursuant to (1) a declaration of war, (2) specific statutory authorization, or (3) a national emergency created by attack upon the United States, its territories or possessions, or its armed forces.


(Pub. L. 93–148, § 2, Nov. 7, 1973, 87 Stat. 555.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 93–148, § 10, Nov. 7, 1973, 87 Stat. 559, provided that: “This joint resolution [enacting this chapter] shall take effect on the date of its enactment [Nov. 7, 1973].”


Short TitlePub. L. 93–148, § 1, Nov. 7, 1973, 87 Stat. 555, provided that: “This joint resolution [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘War Powers Resolution’.”


Rule of Construction on the Permanent Stationing of United States Armed Forces in SomaliaPub. L. 116–92, div. A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1541_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional declaration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional declaration It is the purpose of this chapter to fulfill the intent of the framers of the Constitution of the United States and insure that the collective judgment of both the Congress and the President will apply to the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances, and to the continued use of such forces in hostilities or in such situations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1541_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional legislative power under necessary and proper clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Congressional legislative power under necessary and proper clause Under article I, section 8, of the Constitution, it is specifically provided that the Congress shall have the power to make all laws necessary and proper for carrying into execution, not only its own powers but also all other powers vested by the Constitution in the Government of the United States, or in any department or officer thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1541_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential executive power as Commander-in-Chief; limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Presidential executive power as Commander-in-Chief; limitation The constitutional powers of the President as Commander-in-Chief to introduce United States Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances, are exercised only pursuant to (1) a declaration of war, (2) specific statutory authorization, or (3) a national emergency created by attack upon the United States, its territories or possessions, or its armed forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>