<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1549" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1549/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1549/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1549"><akn:num>1549</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on and notice of changes made to the legal and policy frameworks for the United States’ use o</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1549. Report on and notice of changes made to the legal and policy frameworks for the United States’ use of military force and related national security operations(a) Annual report(1) In generalNot later than March 1 of each year, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the legal and policy frameworks for the United States’ use of military force and related national security operations.


(2) Matters to be includedThe report required by paragraph (1) shall include the legal, factual, and policy justifications for any changes made to such legal and policy frameworks from the preceding year, including—(A) a list of all foreign forces, irregular forces, groups, or individuals for which a determination has been made that force could legally be used under the Authorization for Use of Military Force (Public Law 107–40), including—(i) the legal and factual basis for such determination; and

(ii) a description of whether force has been used against each such foreign force, irregular force, group, or individual; and


(B) the criteria and any changes to the criteria for designating a foreign force, irregular force, group, or individual as lawfully targetable, as a high value target, and as formally or functionally a member of a group covered under the Authorization for Use of Military Force.



(b) Notice requiredNot later than 30 days after the date on which a change is made to the legal and policy frameworks described in subsection (a)(1), the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of such change, including the legal, factual, and policy justification for such change.


(c) FormThe report required by subsection (a) and each notice required by subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex. The unclassified portion of each report shall, at a minimum, include each change made to the legal and policy frameworks during the preceding year and the legal, factual, and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1549_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1549_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice required Not later than 30 days after the date on which a change is made to the legal and policy frameworks described in subsection (a)(1), the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of such change, including the legal, factual, and policy justification for such change.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1549_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Form The report required by subsection (a) and each notice required by subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex. The unclassified portion of each report shall, at a minimum, include each change made to the legal and policy frameworks during the preceding year and the legal, factual, and policy justifications for such changes, and shall be made available to the public at the same time it is submitted to the appropriate congressional committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1549_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Appropriate congressional committees defined In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>