<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/167d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/167d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/167d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_167d"><akn:num>167d</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of crude helium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 167d. Sale of crude helium(a) Phase A: allocation transition(1) In generalThe Secretary shall offer crude helium for sale in such quantities, at such times, at not less than the minimum price established under subsection (b)(7), and under such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out this subsection with minimum market disruption.


(2) Federal purchasesFederal users may purchase refined helium with priority pipeline access under this subsection from persons who have entered into enforceable contracts to purchase an equivalent quantity of crude helium at the in-kind price from the Secretary.


(3) DurationThis subsection applies during—(A) the period beginning on October 2, 2013, and ending on September 30, 2014; and

(B) any period during which the sale of helium under subsection (b) is delayed or suspended.



(b) Phase B: auction implementation(1) In generalThe Secretary shall offer crude helium for sale in quantities not subject to auction under paragraph (2), after completion of each auction, at not less than the minimum price established under paragraph (7), and under such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines necessary—(A) to maximize total recovery of helium from the Federal Helium Reserve over the long term;

(B) to maximize the total financial return to the taxpayer;

(C) to manage crude helium sales according to the ability of the Secretary to extract and produce helium from the Federal Helium Reserve;

(D) to give priority to meeting the helium demand of Federal users in the event of any disruption to the Federal Helium Reserve; and

(E) to carry out this subsection with minimum market disruption.


(2) Auction quantitiesFor the period described in paragraph (4) and consistent with the conditions described in paragraph (8), the Secretary shall annually auction to any qualified bidder a quantity of crude helium in the Federal Helium Reserve equal to—(A) for fiscal year 2015, 10 percent of the total volume of cru</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_167d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase A: allocation transition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Phase A: allocation transition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_167d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase B: auction implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Phase B: auction implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_167d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase C: continued access for Federal users</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Phase C: continued access for Federal users</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_167d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase D: disposal of assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Phase D: disposal of assets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_167d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Helium Production Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Helium Production Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_167d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum quantity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Minimum quantity The Secretary shall offer for sale or auction during each fiscal year under subsections (a), (b), and (c) a quantity of crude helium that is the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>