<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1706" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1706/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1706/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1706"><akn:num>1706</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1706. Savings provisions(a) Termination of national emergencies pursuant to National Emergencies Act(1) Except as provided in subsection (b), notwithstanding the termination pursuant to the National Emergencies Act [50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.] of a national emergency declared for purposes of this chapter, any authorities granted by this chapter, which are exercised on the date of such termination on the basis of such national emergency to prohibit transactions involving property in which a foreign country or national thereof has any interest, may continue to be so exercised to prohibit transactions involving that property if the President determines that the continuation of such prohibition with respect to that property is necessary on account of claims involving such country or its nationals.

(2) Notwithstanding the termination of the authorities described in section 101(b) of this Act, any such authorities, which are exercised with respect to a country on the date of such termination to prohibit transactions involving any property in which such country or any national thereof has any interest, may continue to be exercised to prohibit transactions involving that property if the President determines that the continuation of such prohibition with respect to that property is necessary on account of claims involving such country or its nationals.


(b) Congressional termination of national emergencies by concurrent resolutionThe authorities described in subsection (a)(1) may not continue to be exercised under this section if the national emergency is terminated by the Congress by concurrent resolution pursuant to section 202 of the National Emergencies Act [50 U.S.C. 1622] and if the Congress specifies in such concurrent resolution that such authorities may not continue to be exercised under this section.


(c) Supplemental savings provisions; supersedure of inconsistent provisions(1) The provisions of this section are supplemental to the savings provisions of paragraph</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of national emergencies pursuant to National Emergencies Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Termination of national emergencies pursuant to National Emergencies Act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional termination of national emergencies by concurrent resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Congressional termination of national emergencies by concurrent resolution The authorities described in subsection (a)(1) may not continue to be exercised under this section if the national emergency is terminated by the Congress by concurrent resolution pursuant to section 202 of the National Emergencies Act [50 U.S.C. 1622] and if the Congress specifies in such concurrent resolution that such authorities may not continue to be exercised under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental savings provisions; supersedure of inconsistent provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Supplemental savings provisions; supersedure of inconsistent provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Periodic reports to Congress If the President uses the authority of this section to continue prohibitions on transactions involving foreign property interests, he shall report to the Congress every six months on the use of such authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>