<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1842" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1842/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1842/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1842"><akn:num>1842</akn:num><akn:heading>Pen registers and trap and trace devices for foreign intelligence and international terrorism invest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1842. Pen registers and trap and trace devices for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations(a) Application for authorization or approval(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Attorney General or a designated attorney for the Government may make an application for an order or an extension of an order authorizing or approving the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device for any investigation to obtain foreign intelligence information not concerning a United States person or to protect against international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities, provided that such investigation of a United States person is not conducted solely upon the basis of activities protected by the first amendment to the Constitution which is being conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation under such guidelines as the Attorney General approves pursuant to Executive Order No. 12333, or a successor order.

(2) The authority under paragraph (1) is in addition to the authority under subchapter I of this chapter to conduct the electronic surveillance referred to in that paragraph.


(b) Form of application; recipientEach application under this section shall be in writing under oath or affirmation to—(1) a judge of the court established by section 1803(a) of this title; or

(2) a United States Magistrate Judge under chapter 43 of title 28 who is publicly designated by the Chief Justice of the United States to have the power to hear applications for and grant orders approving the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device on behalf of a judge of that court.


(c) Executive approval; contents of applicationEach application under this section shall require the approval of the Attorney General, or a designated attorney for the Government, and shall include—(1) the identity of the Federal officer seeking to use the pen register or trap and trace device covered by the application;

(2) a certification by the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1842_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for authorization or approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application for authorization or approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1842_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of application; recipient</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form of application; recipient Each application under this section shall be in writing under oath or affirmation to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1842_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive approval; contents of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Executive approval; contents of application Each application under this section shall require the approval of the Attorney General, or a designated attorney for the Government, and shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1842_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex parte judicial order of approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Ex parte judicial order of approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1842_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Time limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1842_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cause of action barred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cause of action barred No cause of action shall lie in any court against any provider of a wire or electronic communication service, landlord, custodian, or other person (including any officer, employee, agent, or other specified person thereof) that furnishes any information, facilities, or technical assistance under subsection (d) in accordance with the terms of an order issued under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1842_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing of results</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Furnishing of results Unless otherwise ordered by the judge, the results of a pen register or trap and trace device shall be furnished at reasonable intervals during regular business hours for the duration of the order to the authorized Government official or officials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1842_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Privacy procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>