<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1862" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1862/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1862/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1862"><akn:num>1862</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to certain business records for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigatio</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1862. Access to certain business records for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations(a) Application for authorizationThe Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or a designee of the Director (whose rank shall be no lower than Assistant Special Agent in Charge) may make an application for an order authorizing a common carrier, public accommodation facility, physical storage facility, or vehicle rental facility to release records in its possession for an investigation to gather foreign intelligence information or an investigation concerning international terrorism which investigation is being conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation under such guidelines as the Attorney General approves pursuant to Executive Order No. 12333, or a successor order.


(b) Recipient and contents of applicationEach application under this section—(1) shall be made to—(A) a judge of the court established by section 1803(a) of this title; or

(B) a United States Magistrate Judge under chapter 43 of title 28 who is publicly designated by the Chief Justice of the United States to have the power to hear applications and grant orders for the release of records under this section on behalf of a judge of that court; and


(2) shall specify that—(A) the records concerned are sought for an investigation described in subsection (a);

(B) there are specific and articulable facts giving reason to believe that the person to whom the records pertain is a foreign power or an agent of a foreign power;

(E) 11 So in original. No subpars. (C) and (D) have been enacted. a statement by the applicant that, to the best knowledge of the applicant, the application fairly reflects all information that might reasonably—(i) call into question the accuracy of the application or the reasonableness of any assessment in the application conducted by the department or agency on whose behalf the application is made; or

(ii) otherwise raise doubts with respect to the findings require</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application for authorization The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or a designee of the Director (whose rank shall be no lower than Assistant Special Agent in Charge) may make an application for an order authorizing a common carrier, public accommodation facility, physical storage facility, or vehicle rental facility to release records in its possession for an investigation to gather foreign intelligence information or an investigation concerning international terrorism which investigation is being conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation under such guidelines as the Attorney General approves pursuant to Executive Order No. 12333, or a successor order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recipient and contents of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recipient and contents of application Each application under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex parte judicial order of approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ex parte judicial order of approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance; nondisclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compliance; nondisclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>