<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1864" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1864/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1864/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1864"><akn:num>1864</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of changes to retention of call detail record policies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1864. Notification of changes to retention of call detail record policies(a) Requirement to retain(1) In generalNot later than 15 days after learning that an electronic communication service provider that generates call detail records in the ordinary course of business has changed the policy of the provider on the retention of such call detail records to result in a retention period of less than 18 months, the Director of National Intelligence shall notify, in writing, the congressional intelligence committees of such change.


(2) ReportNot later than 30 days after December 18, 2015, the Director shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report identifying each electronic communication service provider that has, as of the date of the report, a policy to retain call detail records for a period of 18 months or less.



(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Call detail recordThe term “call detail record” has the meaning given that term in section 1861(k) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(2) Electronic communication service providerThe term “electronic communication service provider” has the meaning given that term in section 1881(b)(4) of this title.



(Pub. L. 114–113, div. M, title III, § 307, Dec. 18, 2015, 129 Stat. 2916.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 1861(k) of this title, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), means section 1861(k) of this title prior to the amendment of section 1861 by Pub. L. 109–177, title I, § 102(b), Mar. 9, 2006, 120 Stat. 195, set out as an Effective Date of 2006 Amendment note under section 1805 of this title, which amended section 1861 of this title, effective Mar. 15, 2020, so that such section read as it read on Oct. 25, 2001, with certain exceptions.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016, and also as part of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016, and not as part of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 which c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1864_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to retain</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement to retain</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1864_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>