<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1881b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1881b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1881b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1881b"><akn:num>1881b</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain acquisitions inside the United States targeting United States persons outside the United Sta</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1881b. Certain acquisitions inside the United States targeting United States persons outside the United States(a) Jurisdiction of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court(1) In generalThe Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court shall have jurisdiction to review an application and to enter an order approving the targeting of a United States person reasonably believed to be located outside the United States to acquire foreign intelligence information, if the acquisition constitutes electronic surveillance or the acquisition of stored electronic communications or stored electronic data that requires an order under this chapter, and such acquisition is conducted within the United States.


(2) LimitationIf a United States person targeted under this subsection is reasonably believed to be located in the United States during the effective period of an order issued pursuant to subsection (c), an acquisition targeting such United States person under this section shall cease unless the targeted United States person is again reasonably believed to be located outside the United States while an order issued pursuant to subsection (c) is in effect. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Government to seek an order or authorization under, or otherwise engage in any activity that is authorized under, any other subchapter of this chapter.



(b) Application(1) In generalEach application for an order under this section shall be made by a Federal officer in writing upon oath or affirmation to a judge having jurisdiction under subsection (a)(1). Each application shall require the approval of the Attorney General based upon the Attorney General’s finding that it satisfies the criteria and requirements of such application, as set forth in this section, and shall include—(A) the identity of the Federal officer making the application;

(B) the identity, if known, or a description of the United States person who is the target of the acquisition;

(C) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Jurisdiction of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Emergency authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release from liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Release from liability No cause of action shall lie in any court against any electronic communication service provider for providing any information, facilities, or assistance in accordance with an order or request for emergency assistance issued pursuant to subsection (c) or (d), respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appeal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Construction Except as provided in this section, nothing in this chapter shall be construed to require an application for a court order for an acquisition that is targeted in accordance with this section at a United States person reasonably believed to be located outside the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>