<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1881d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1881d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1881d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1881d"><akn:num>1881d</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint applications and concurrent authorizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1881d. Joint applications and concurrent authorizations(a) Joint applications and ordersIf an acquisition targeting a United States person under section 1881b or 1881c of this title is proposed to be conducted both inside and outside the United States, a judge having jurisdiction under section 1881b(a)(1) or 1881c(a)(1) of this title may issue simultaneously, upon the request of the Government in a joint application complying with the requirements of sections 1881b(b) and 1881c(b) of this title, orders under sections 1881b(c) and 1881c(c) of this title, as appropriate.


(b) Concurrent authorizationIf an order authorizing electronic surveillance or physical search has been obtained under section 1805 or 1824 of this title, the Attorney General may authorize, for the effective period of that order, without an order under section 1881b or 1881c of this title, the targeting of that United States person for the purpose of acquiring foreign intelligence information while such person is reasonably believed to be located outside the United States.


(c) Emergency authorization(1) Concurrent authorizationIf the Attorney General authorized the emergency employment of electronic surveillance or a physical search pursuant to section 1805 or 1824 of this title, the Attorney General may authorize, for the effective period of the emergency authorization and subsequent order pursuant to section 1805 or 1824 of this title, without a separate order under section 1881b or 1881c of this title, the targeting of a United States person subject to such emergency employment for the purpose of acquiring foreign intelligence information while such United States person is reasonably believed to be located outside the United States.


(2) Use of informationIf an application submitted to the Court pursuant to section 1804 or 1823 of this title is denied, or in any other case in which the acquisition pursuant to paragraph (1) is terminated and no order with respect to the target of the acquisi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint applications and orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Joint applications and orders If an acquisition targeting a United States person under section 1881b or 1881c of this title is proposed to be conducted both inside and outside the United States, a judge having jurisdiction under section 1881b(a)(1) or 1881c(a)(1) of this title may issue simultaneously, upon the request of the Government in a joint application complying with the requirements of sections 1881b(b) and 1881c(b) of this title, orders under sections 1881b(c) and 1881c(c) of this title, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concurrent authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Concurrent authorization If an order authorizing electronic surveillance or physical search has been obtained under section 1805 or 1824 of this title, the Attorney General may authorize, for the effective period of that order, without an order under section 1881b or 1881c of this title, the targeting of that United States person for the purpose of acquiring foreign intelligence information while such person is reasonably believed to be located outside the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Emergency authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>