<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1881a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1881a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1881a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1881a"><akn:num>1881a</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for targeting certain persons outside the United States other than United States persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1881a. Procedures for targeting certain persons outside the United States other than United States persons(a) AuthorizationNotwithstanding any other provision of law, upon the issuance of an order in accordance with subsection (j)(3) or a determination under subsection (c)(2), the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence may authorize jointly, for a period of up to 1 year from the effective date of the authorization, the targeting of persons reasonably believed to be located outside the United States to acquire foreign intelligence information.


(b) LimitationsAn acquisition authorized under subsection (a)—(1) may not intentionally target any person known at the time of acquisition to be located in the United States;

(2) may not intentionally target a person reasonably believed to be located outside the United States if the purpose of such acquisition is to target a particular, known person reasonably believed to be in the United States;

(3) may not intentionally target a United States person reasonably believed to be located outside the United States;

(4) may not intentionally acquire any communication as to which the sender and all intended recipients are known at the time of the acquisition to be located in the United States;

(5) may not intentionally acquire communications that contain a reference to, but are not to or from, a target of an acquisition authorized under subsection (a); and

(6) shall be conducted in a manner consistent with the fourth amendment to the Constitution of the United States.


(c) Conduct of acquisition(1) In generalAn acquisition authorized under subsection (a) shall be conducted only in accordance with—(A) the targeting and minimization procedures adopted in accordance with subsections (d) and (e); and

(B) upon submission of a certification in accordance with subsection (h), such certification.


(2) DeterminationA determination under this paragraph and for purposes of subsection (a) is a determination by the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization Notwithstanding any other provision of law, upon the issuance of an order in accordance with subsection (j)(3) or a determination under subsection (c)(2), the Attorney General and the Director of National Intelligence may authorize jointly, for a period of up to 1 year from the effective date of the authorization, the targeting of persons reasonably believed to be located outside the United States to acquire foreign intelligence information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations An acquisition authorized under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conduct of acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Conduct of acquisition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Targeting procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Targeting procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimization procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Minimization procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Queries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Queries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines for compliance with limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Guidelines for compliance with limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Directives and judicial review of directives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Directives and judicial review of directives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of certifications and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Judicial review of certifications and procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>