<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1885a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1885a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1885a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1885a"><akn:num>1885a</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for implementing statutory defenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1885a. Procedures for implementing statutory defenses(a) Requirement for certificationNotwithstanding any other provision of law, a civil action may not lie or be maintained in a Federal or State court against any person for providing assistance to an element of the intelligence community, and shall be promptly dismissed, if the Attorney General certifies to the district court of the United States in which such action is pending that—(1) any assistance by that person was provided pursuant to an order of the court established under section 1803(a) of this title directing such assistance;

(2) any assistance by that person was provided pursuant to a certification in writing under section 2511(2)(a)(ii)(B) or 2709(b) of title 18;

(3) any assistance by that person was provided pursuant to a directive under section 1802(a)(4), 1805b(e), as added by section 2 of the Protect America Act of 2007 (Public Law 110–55), or 1881a(i) of this title directing such assistance;

(4) in the case of a covered civil action, the assistance alleged to have been provided by the electronic communication service provider was—(A) in connection with an intelligence activity involving communications that was—(i) authorized by the President during the period beginning on September 11, 2001, and ending on January 17, 2007; and

(ii) designed to detect or prevent a terrorist attack, or activities in preparation for a terrorist attack, against the United States; and


(B) the subject of a written request or directive, or a series of written requests or directives, from the Attorney General or the head of an element of the intelligence community (or the deputy of such person) to the electronic communication service provider indicating that the activity was—(i) authorized by the President; and

(ii) determined to be lawful; or



(5) the person did not provide the alleged assistance.


(b) Judicial review(1) Review of certificationsA certification under subsection (a) shall be given effect unless </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement for certification Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a civil action may not lie or be maintained in a Federal or State court against any person for providing assistance to an element of the intelligence community, and shall be promptly dismissed, if the Attorney General certifies to the district court of the United States in which such action is pending that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations on disclosure If the Attorney General files a declaration under section 1746 of title 28 that disclosure of a certification made pursuant to subsection (a) or the supplemental materials provided pursuant to subsection (b) or (d) would harm the national security of the United States, the court shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Role of the parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Role of the parties Any plaintiff or defendant in a civil action may submit any relevant court order, certification, written request, or directive to the district court referred to in subsection (a) for review and shall be permitted to participate in the briefing or argument of any legal issue in a judicial proceeding conducted pursuant to this section, but only to the extent that such participation does not require the disclosure of classified information to such party. To the extent that classified information is relevant to the proceeding or would be revealed in the determination of an issue, the court shall review such information in camera and ex parte, and shall issue any part of the court’s written order that would reveal classified information in camera and ex parte and maintain such part under seal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondelegation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nondelegation The authority and duties of the Attorney General under this section shall be performed by the Attorney General (or Acting Attorney General) or the Deputy Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appeal The courts of appeals shall have jurisdiction of appeals from interlocutory orders of the district courts of the United States granting or denying a motion to dismiss or for summary judgment under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Removal A civil action against a person for providing assistance to an element of the intelligence community that is brought in a State court shall be deemed to arise under the Constitution and laws of the United States and shall be removable under section 1441 of title 28.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Relationship to other laws Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit any otherwise available immunity, privilege, or defense under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Applicability This section shall apply to a civil action pending on or filed after July 10, 2008.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>