<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/1906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1906"><akn:num>1906</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1906. Annual report(a) Annual report(1) The Secretary shall submit to the President and to the congressional intelligence committees an annual report of the conduct of the program required by this chapter.

(2) The report submitted to the President shall be submitted each year at the time that the President’s budget for the next fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31.

(3) The report submitted to the congressional intelligence committees shall be submitted on the date provided in section 3106 of this title.


(b) Contents of reportEach such report shall contain—(1) an analysis of the trends within language, international, area, and counterproliferation studies, along with a survey of such areas as the Secretary determines are receiving inadequate attention;

(2) the effect on those trends of activities under the program required by this chapter;

(3) an analysis of the assistance provided under the program for the previous fiscal year, to include the subject areas being addressed and the nature of the assistance provided;

(4) an analysis of the performance of the individuals who received assistance under the program during the previous fiscal year, to include the degree to which assistance was terminated under the program and the extent to which individual recipients failed to meet their obligations under the program;

(5) an analysis of the results of the program for the previous fiscal year, and cumulatively, to include, at a minimum—(A) the percentage of individuals who have received assistance under the program who subsequently became employees of the United States Government;

(B) in the case of individuals who did not subsequently become employees of the United States Government, an analysis of the reasons why they did not become employees and an explanation as to what use, if any, was made of the assistance by those recipients; and

(C) the uses made of grants to educational institutions;


(6) the current list of agencie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of report Each such report shall contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1906_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of initial report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission of initial report The first report under this section shall be submitted at the time the budget for fiscal year 1994 is submitted to Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1906_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consultation During the preparation of each report required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the members of the Board specified in paragraphs (1) through (7) of section 1903(b) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title. Each such member shall submit to the Secretary an assessment of their hiring needs in the areas of language and area studies and a projection of the deficiencies in such areas. The Secretary shall include all assessments in the report required by subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>