<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2002" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2002/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2002/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2002"><akn:num>2002</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions relating to participants and annuitants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2002. Definitions relating to participants and annuitants(a) General definitionsWhen used in subchapter II:(1) Former participantThe term “former participant” means a person who—(A) while an employee of the Agency was a participant in the system; and

(B) separates from the Agency without entitlement to immediate receipt of an annuity from the fund.


(2) Retired participantThe term “retired participant” means a person who—(A) while an employee of the Agency was a participant in the system; and

(B) is entitled to receive an annuity from the fund based upon such person’s service as a participant.


(3) Surviving spouse(A) In generalThe term “surviving spouse” means the surviving wife or husband of a participant or retired participant who (i) was married to the participant or retired participant for at least 9 months immediately preceding the participant’s or retired participant’s death, or (ii) who is the parent of a child born of the marriage.


(B) Treatment when participant dies less than 9 months after marriageIn a case in which the participant or retired participant dies within the 9-month period beginning on the date of the marriage, the requirement under subparagraph (A)(i) that a marriage have a duration of at least 9 months immediately preceding the death of the participant or retired participant shall be treated as having been met if—(i) the death of the participant or retired participant was accidental; or

(ii) the surviving wife or husband had been previously married to the participant or retired participant (and subsequently divorced) and the aggregate time married is at least 9 months.



(4) Former spouseThe term “former spouse” means a former wife or husband of a participant, former participant, or retired participant as follows:(A) Divorces on or before December 4, 1991In the case of a divorce that became final on or before December 4, 1991, such term means a former wife or husband of a participant, former participant, or retired participant who </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2002_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General definitions When used in subchapter II:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2002_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Child” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Child” defined For purposes of sections 2031 and 2052 of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>