<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2021"><akn:num>2021</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions to fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2021. Contributions to fund(a) In general(1) DefinitionIn this subsection, the term “revised annuity participant” means an individual who—(A) on December 31, 2012—(i) is not a participant;

(ii) is not performing qualifying service; and

(iii) has less than 5 years of qualifying service; and


(B) after December 31, 2012, becomes a participant performing qualifying service.


(2) Contributions(A) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (d), 7 percent of the basic pay received by a participant other than a revised annuity participant for any pay period shall be deducted and withheld from the pay of that participant and contributed to the fund.


(B) Revised annuity participantsExcept as provided in subsection (d), 9.3 percent of the basic pay received by a revised annuity participant for any pay period shall be deducted and withheld from the pay of that revised annuity participant and contributed to the fund.



(3) Agency contributions(A) In generalAn amount equal to 7 percent of the basic pay received by a participant other than a revised annuity participant shall be contributed to the fund for a pay period for the participant from the appropriation or fund which is used for payment of the participant’s basic pay.


(B) Revised annuity participantsAn amount equal to 4.7 percent of the basic pay received by a revised annuity participant shall be contributed to the fund for a pay period for the revised annuity participant from the appropriation or fund which is used for payment of the revised annuity participant’s basic pay.



(4) Deposits to the fundThe amounts deducted and withheld from basic pay, together with the amounts so contributed from the appropriation or fund, shall be deposited by the Director to the credit of the fund.



(b) Consent of participant to deductions from payEach participant shall be deemed to consent and agree to such deductions from basic pay, and payment less such deductions shall be a full and complete discharge and acquittance of a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consent of participant to deductions from pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consent of participant to deductions from pay Each participant shall be deemed to consent and agree to such deductions from basic pay, and payment less such deductions shall be a full and complete discharge and acquittance of all claims and demands whatsoever for all regular services during the period covered by such payment, except the right to the benefits to which the participant is entitled under this subchapter, notwithstanding any law, rule, or regulation affecting the individual’s pay.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of contributions after 35 years of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of contributions after 35 years of service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offset for social security taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Offset for social security taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>