<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2032" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2032/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2032/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2032"><akn:num>2032</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuities for former spouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2032. Annuities for former spouses(a) Former spouse share of participant’s annuity(1) Pro rata shareUnless otherwise expressly provided by a spousal agreement or court order under section 2094(b) of this title, a former spouse of a participant, former participant, or retired participant is entitled to an annuity—(A) if married to the participant, former participant, or retired participant throughout the creditable service of the participant, equal to 50 percent of the annuity of the participant; or

(B) if not married to the participant throughout such creditable service, equal to that proportion of 50 percent of such annuity that is the proportion that the number of days of the marriage of the former spouse to the participant during periods of creditable service of such participant under this subchapter bears to the total number of days of such creditable service.


(2) Disqualification upon remarriage before age 55A former spouse is not qualified for an annuity under this subsection if before the commencement of that annuity the former spouse remarries before becoming 55 years of age.


(3) Commencement of annuityThe annuity of a former spouse under this subsection commences on the day the participant upon whose service the annuity is based becomes entitled to an annuity under this subchapter or on the first day of the month after the divorce or annulment involved becomes final, whichever is later.


(4) Termination of annuityThe annuity of such former spouse and the right thereto terminate on—(A) the last day of the month before the month in which the former spouse dies or remarries before 55 years of age; or

(B) the date on which the annuity of the participant terminates (except in the case of an annuity subject to paragraph (5)(B)).


(5) Treatment of participant’s annuity(A) Reduction in participant’s annuityThe annuity payable to any participant shall be reduced by the amount of an annuity under this subsection paid to any former spouse based upon the serv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Former spouse share of participant’s annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Former spouse share of participant’s annuity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Former spouse survivor annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Former spouse survivor annuity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Optional additional survivor annuities for other former spouse or surviving spouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Optional additional survivor annuities for other former spouse or surviving spouse</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>