<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2051" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2051/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2051/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2051"><akn:num>2051</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement for disability or incapacity; medical examination; recovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2051. Retirement for disability or incapacity; medical examination; recovery(a) Disability retirement(1) EligibilityA participant who has become disabled shall, upon the participant’s own application or upon order of the Director, be retired on an annuity computed under subsection (b).


(2) Standard for disability determinationA participant shall be considered to be disabled only if the participant—(A) is found by the Director to be unable, because of disease or injury, to render useful and efficient service in the participant’s position; and

(B) is not qualified for reassignment, under procedures prescribed by the Director, to a vacant position in the Agency at the same grade or level and in which the participant would be able to render useful and efficient service.


(3) Time limit for application(A) One year requirementA claim may be allowed under this section only if the application is submitted before the participant is separated from the Agency or within one year thereafter.


(B) Waiver for mentally incompetent participantThe time limitation may be waived by the Director for a participant who, at the date of separation from the Agency or within one year thereafter, is mentally incompetent, if the application is filed with the Agency within one year from the date of restoration of the participant to competency or the appointment of a fiduciary, whichever is earlier.




(b) Computation of disability annuity(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), an annuity payable under subsection (a) shall be computed under section 2031(a) of this title. However, if the disabled or incapacitated participant has less than 20 years of service credit toward retirement under the system at the time of retirement, the annuity shall be computed on the assumption that the participant has had 20 years of service, but the additional service credit that may accrue to a participant under this paragraph may not exceed the difference between the participant’s age at the time</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2051_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disability retirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disability retirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2051_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of disability annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Computation of disability annuity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2051_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical examinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Medical examinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2051_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of recovered disability annuitant who is not reinstated</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of recovered disability annuitant who is not reinstated</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2051_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination of benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2051_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offset from survivor annuity for workers’ compensation payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Offset from survivor annuity for workers’ compensation payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>