<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2052" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2052/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2052/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2052"><akn:num>2052</akn:num><akn:heading>Death in service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2052. Death in service(a) Return of contributions when no annuity payableIf a participant dies and no claim for an annuity is payable under this subchapter, the participant’s lump-sum credit and any voluntary contributions made under section 2121 of this title, with interest, shall be paid in the order of precedence shown in section 2071(c) of this title.


(b) Survivor annuity for surviving spouse or former spouse(1) In generalIf a participant dies before separation or retirement from the Agency and is survived by a spouse or by a former spouse qualifying for a survivor annuity under section 2032(b) of this title, such surviving spouse shall be entitled to an annuity equal to 55 percent of the annuity computed in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection and section 2031(a) of this title, and any such surviving former spouse shall be entitled to an annuity computed in accordance with section 2032(b) of this title and paragraph (2) of this subsection as if the participant died after being entitled to an annuity under this subchapter. The annuity of such surviving spouse or former spouse shall commence on the day after the participant dies and shall terminate on the last day of the month before the death or remarriage before attaining age 55 of the surviving spouse or former spouse (subject to the payment and restoration provisions of sections 2031(b)(3)(C), 2031(i), and 2032(b)(3) of this title).


(2) ComputationThe annuity payable under paragraph (1) shall be computed in accordance with section 2031(a) of this title, except that the computation of the annuity of the participant under such section shall be at least the smaller of (A) 40 percent of the participant’s high-3 average pay, or (B) the sum obtained under such section after increasing the participant’s length of service by the difference between the participant’s age at the time of death and age 60.


(3) LimitationNotwithstanding paragraph (1), if the participant had a former spouse qual</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2052_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return of contributions when no annuity payable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Return of contributions when no annuity payable If a participant dies and no claim for an annuity is payable under this subchapter, the participant’s lump-sum credit and any voluntary contributions made under section 2121 of this title, with interest, shall be paid in the order of precedence shown in section 2071(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2052_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Survivor annuity for surviving spouse or former spouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Survivor annuity for surviving spouse or former spouse</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2052_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuities for surviving children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annuities for surviving children</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>