<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2082" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2082/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2082/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2082"><akn:num>2082</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior service credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2082. Prior service credit(a) In generalA participant may, subject to the provisions of this section, include in the participant’s period of service—(1) civilian service in the Government before becoming a participant that would be creditable toward retirement under subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5 (as determined under section 8332(b) of such title); and

(2) honorable active service in the Armed Forces before the date of the separation upon which eligibility for an annuity is based, or honorable active service in the Regular or Reserve Corps 11 See Change of Name note below. of the Public Health Service after June 30, 1960, or as a commissioned officer of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration after June 30, 1961.


(b) Limitations(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the total service of any participant shall exclude—(A) any period of civilian service on or after October 1, 1982, for which retirement deductions or deposits have not been made,

(B) any period of service for which a refund of contributions has been made, or

(C) any period of service for which contributions were not transferred pursuant to subsection (c)(1);


unless the participant makes a deposit to the fund in an amount equal to the percentages of basic pay received for such service as specified in the table contained in section 8334(c) of title 5, together with interest computed in accordance with section 8334(e) of such title. The deposit may be made in one or more installments (including by allotment from pay), as determined by the Director.

(2) Effect of retirement deductions not madeIf a participant has not paid a deposit for civilian service performed before October 1, 1982, for which retirement deductions were not made, such participant’s annuity shall be reduced by 10 percent of the deposit described in paragraph (1) remaining unpaid, unless the participant elects to eliminate the service involved for the purpose of the annuity computation.


(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2082_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A participant may, subject to the provisions of this section, include in the participant’s period of service—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2082_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2082_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer from other Government retirement systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer from other Government retirement systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2082_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to other Government retirement systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer to other Government retirement systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2082_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior military service credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prior military service credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2082_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of entitlement to social security benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect of entitlement to social security benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2082_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits paid by survivors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Deposits paid by survivors For the purpose of survivor annuities, deposits authorized by subsections (b) and (h) may also be made by the survivor of a participant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2082_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits for periods of military service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Deposits for periods of military service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>