<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2093" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2093/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2093/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2093"><akn:num>2093</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2093. Payment of benefits(a) Annuities stated as annual amountsEach annuity is stated as an annual amount, 1⁄12 of which, rounded to the next lowest dollar, constitutes the monthly rate payable on the first business day of the month after the month or other period for which it has accrued.


(b) Commencement of annuity(1) Commencement of annuity for participants generallyExcept as otherwise provided in paragraph (2), the annuity of a participant who has met the eligibility requirements for an annuity shall commence on the first day of the month after separation from the Agency or after pay ceases and the service and age requirements for title to an annuity are met.


(2) ExceptionsThe annuity of—(A) a participant involuntarily separated from the Agency;

(B) a participant retiring under section 2051 of this title due to a disability; and

(C) a participant who serves 3 days or less in the month of retirement;


shall commence on the day after separation from the Agency or the day after pay ceases and the service and age or disability requirements for title to annuity are met.

(3) Other annuitiesAny other annuity payable from the fund commences on the first day of the month after the occurrence of the event on which payment thereof is based.



(c) Termination of annuityAn annuity payable from the fund shall terminate—(1) in the case of a retired participant, on the day death or any other terminating event provided by this subchapter occurs; or

(2) in the case of a former spouse or a survivor, on the last day of the month before death or any other terminating event occurs.


(d) Application for survivor annuitiesThe annuity to a survivor shall become effective as otherwise specified but shall not be paid until the survivor submits an application for such annuity, supported by such proof of eligibility as the Director may require. If such application or proof of eligibility is not submitted during the lifetime of an otherwise eligible individual, no annuity shall </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2093_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuities stated as annual amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annuities stated as annual amounts Each annuity is stated as an annual amount, 1⁄12 of which, rounded to the next lowest dollar, constitutes the monthly rate payable on the first business day of the month after the month or other period for which it has accrued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2093_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commencement of annuity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2093_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Termination of annuity An annuity payable from the fund shall terminate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2093_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for survivor annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application for survivor annuities The annuity to a survivor shall become effective as otherwise specified but shall not be paid until the survivor submits an application for such annuity, supported by such proof of eligibility as the Director may require. If such application or proof of eligibility is not submitted during the lifetime of an otherwise eligible individual, no annuity shall be due or payable to the individual’s estate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2093_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Waiver of annuity An individual entitled to an annuity from the fund may decline to accept all or any part of the annuity by submitting a signed waiver to the Director. The waiver may be revoked in writing at any time. Payment of the annuity waived may not be made for the period during which the waiver is in effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2093_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2093_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding of State income tax from annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Withholding of State income tax from annuities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>