<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2142" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2142/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2142/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2142"><akn:num>2142</akn:num><akn:heading>Thrift Savings Plan participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2142. Thrift Savings Plan participation(a) Eligibility for Thrift Savings PlanParticipants in the system shall be deemed to be employees for the purposes of section 8351 of title 5.


(b) Management of Thrift Savings Plan accounts by DirectorSubsections (k) and (m) of section 8461 of title 5 shall apply with respect to contributions made by participants to the Thrift Savings Fund under section 8351 of such title and to earnings attributable to the investment of such contributions.


(Pub. L. 88–643, title II, § 293, as added Pub. L. 102–496, title VIII, § 802, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3242.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 293 of Pub. L. 88–643, as added Pub. L. 99–335, title V, § 504, June 6, 1986, 100 Stat. 623, related to Thrift Savings Fund participation by participants in the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System and was set out as a note under section 403 of this title prior to the general amendment of Pub. L. 88–643 by section 802 of Pub. L. 102–496.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on first day of fourth month beginning after Oct. 24, 1992, see section 805 of Pub. L. 102–496, set out as a note under section 2001 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2142_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for Thrift Savings Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligibility for Thrift Savings Plan Participants in the system shall be deemed to be employees for the purposes of section 8351 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2142_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Thrift Savings Plan accounts by Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management of Thrift Savings Plan accounts by Director Subsections (k) and (m) of section 8461 of title 5 shall apply with respect to contributions made by participants to the Thrift Savings Fund under section 8351 of such title and to earnings attributable to the investment of such contributions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>