<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2143" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2143/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2143/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2143"><akn:num>2143</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative forms of annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2143. Alternative forms of annuities(a) Authority for alternative form of annuityThe Director shall prescribe regulations under which any participant who has a life-threatening affliction or other critical medical condition may, at the time of retiring under this subchapter (other than under section 2051 of this title), elect annuity benefits under this section instead of any other benefits under this subchapter (including any survivor benefits under this subchapter) based on the service of the participant creditable under this subchapter.


(b) Basis for alternative forms of annuityThe regulations and alternative forms of annuity shall, to the maximum extent practicable, meet the requirements prescribed in section 8343a of title 5.


(c) Lump-sum creditAny lump-sum credit provided pursuant to an election under subsection (a) shall not preclude an individual from receiving other benefits provided under that subsection.


(d) Submission of regulations to congressional intelligence committeesThe Director shall submit the regulations prescribed under subsection (a) to the congressional intelligence committees before the regulations take effect.


(Pub. L. 88–643, title II, § 294, as added Pub. L. 102–496, title VIII, § 802, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3242; amended Pub. L. 103–66, title XI, § 11002(c), Aug. 10, 1993, 107 Stat. 409.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 294 of Pub. L. 88–643, as added Pub. L. 99–335, title V, § 505, June 6, 1986, 100 Stat. 624, related to alternative forms of annuities and was set out as a note under section 403 of this title prior to the general amendment of Pub. L. 88–643 by section 802 of Pub. L. 102–496.

Amendments1993—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 103–66 substituted “any participant who has a life-threatening affliction or other critical medical condition” for “a participant”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1993 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 103–66 effective Oct. 1, 1994, and applicable with respect </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2143_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for alternative form of annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority for alternative form of annuity The Director shall prescribe regulations under which any participant who has a life-threatening affliction or other critical medical condition may, at the time of retiring under this subchapter (other than under section 2051 of this title), elect annuity benefits under this section instead of any other benefits under this subchapter (including any survivor benefits under this subchapter) based on the service of the participant creditable under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2143_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis for alternative forms of annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Basis for alternative forms of annuity The regulations and alternative forms of annuity shall, to the maximum extent practicable, meet the requirements prescribed in section 8343a of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2143_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lump-sum credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Lump-sum credit Any lump-sum credit provided pursuant to an election under subsection (a) shall not preclude an individual from receiving other benefits provided under that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2143_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of regulations to congressional intelligence committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Submission of regulations to congressional intelligence committees The Director shall submit the regulations prescribed under subsection (a) to the congressional intelligence committees before the regulations take effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>