<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2154" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2154/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2154/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2154"><akn:num>2154</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for former spouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2154. Special rules for former spouses(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise specifically provided in this section, the provisions of chapter 84 of title 5 shall apply in the case of an employee of the Agency who is subject to chapter 84 of title 5 and who has a former spouse (as defined in section 8401(12) of title 5) or a qualified former spouse.


(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) EmployeeThe term “employee” means an employee of the Agency who is subject to chapter 84 of title 5, including an employee referred to in section 2152(a) of this title.


(2) Qualified former spouseThe term “qualified former spouse” means a former spouse of an employee or retired employee who—(A) in the case of a former spouse whose divorce from such employee became final on or before December 4, 1991, was married to such employee for not less than 10 years during periods of the employee’s service which are creditable under section 8411 of title 5, at least 5 years of which were spent outside the United States by both the employee and the former spouse during the employee’s service with the Agency; and

(B) in the case of a former spouse whose divorce from such employee becomes final after December 4, 1991, was married to such employee for not less than 10 years during periods of the employee’s service which are creditable under section 8411 of title 5, at least 5 years of which were spent by the employee outside the United States during the employee’s service with the Agency or otherwise in a position the duties of which qualified the employee for designation by the Director under the criteria prescribed in section 2013 of this title.


(3) Pro rata shareThe term “pro rata share” means the percentage that is equal to (A) the number of days of the marriage of the qualified former spouse to the employee during the employee’s periods of creditable service under chapter 84 of title 5, divided by (B) the total number of days of the employee’s creditable service.


(4) Spousal a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise specifically provided in this section, the provisions of chapter 84 of title 5 shall apply in the case of an employee of the Agency who is subject to chapter 84 of title 5 and who has a former spouse (as defined in section 8401(12) of title 5) or a qualified former spouse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement of qualified former spouse to retirement benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Entitlement of qualified former spouse to retirement benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified former spouse survivor benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Qualified former spouse survivor benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified former spouse Thrift Savings Plan benefit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Qualified former spouse Thrift Savings Plan benefit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of rights of qualified former spouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preservation of rights of qualified former spouses An employee may not make an election or modification of election under section 8417 or 8418 of title 5, or other section relating to the employee’s annuity under subchapter II of chapter 84 of title 5, that would diminish the entitlement of a qualified former spouse to any benefit granted to such former spouse by this section or by court order or spousal agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of share of lump-sum credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payment of share of lump-sum credit Whenever an employee or former employee becomes entitled to receive the lump-sum credit under section 8424(a) of title 5, a share (determined under subsection (c)(1)(B) of this section) of that lump-sum credit shall be paid to any qualified former spouse of such employee, unless otherwise expressly provided by any spousal agreement or court order governing disposition of the lump-sum credit involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment to qualified former spouses under court order or spousal agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Payment to qualified former spouses under court order or spousal agreement In the case of any employee or retired employee who has a qualified former spouse who is covered by a court order or who is a party to a spousal agreement— shall be determined in accordance with that spousal agreement or court order, if and to the extent expressly provided for in the terms of the spousal agreement or court order that are not inconsistent with the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of CIARDS former spouse benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Applicability of CIARDS former spouse benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>