<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2201" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2201/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2201/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2201"><akn:num>2201</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers of spoils of war</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2201. Transfers of spoils of war(a) Eligibility for transferSpoils of war in the possession, custody, or control of the United States may be transferred to any other party, including any government, group, or person, by sale, grant, loan or in any other manner, only to the extent and in the same manner that property of the same type, if otherwise owned by the United States, may be so transferred.


(b) Terms and conditionsAny transfer pursuant to subsection (a) shall be subject to all of the terms, conditions, and requirements applicable to the transfer of property of the same type otherwise owned by the United States.


(Pub. L. 103–236, title V, § 552, Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 482.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short TitlePub. L. 103–236, title V, § 551, Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 482, provided that: “This part [part B (§§ 551–556) of title V of Pub. L. 103–236, enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Spoils of War Act of 1994’.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligibility for transfer Spoils of war in the possession, custody, or control of the United States may be transferred to any other party, including any government, group, or person, by sale, grant, loan or in any other manner, only to the extent and in the same manner that property of the same type, if otherwise owned by the United States, may be so transferred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions Any transfer pursuant to subsection (a) shall be subject to all of the terms, conditions, and requirements applicable to the transfer of property of the same type otherwise owned by the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>