<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2315" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2315/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2315/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2315"><akn:num>2315</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing of preparedness for emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, chemical, and biological we</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2315. Testing of preparedness for emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, chemical, and biological weapons(a) Emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, chemical, or biological weapons(1) The Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop and carry out a program for testing and improving the responses of Federal, State, and local agencies to emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, biological, and chemical weapons and related materials.

(2) The program shall include exercises to be carried out in accordance with sections 112(c) and 238(c)(1) of title 6.

(3) In developing and carrying out the program, the Secretary shall coordinate with the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Secretary of Energy, and the heads of any other Federal, State, and local government agencies that have an expertise or responsibilities relevant to emergencies described in paragraph (1).


(b) Annual revisions of programsThe Secretary of Homeland Security shall revise the program developed under subsection (a) not later than June 1 in each fiscal year covered by the program. The revisions shall include adjustments that the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate on the basis of the lessons learned from the exercise or exercises carried out under the program in the fiscal year, including lessons learned regarding coordination problems and equipment deficiencies.


(Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1415, Sept. 23, 1996, 110 Stat. 2720; Pub. L. 107–314, div. C, title XXXI, § 3154(a), Dec. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 2738; Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1032, Jan. 6, 2006, 119 Stat. 3428.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2006—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 109–163, § 1032(a)(1), substituted “nuclear, radiological, chemical, or” for “chemical or” in heading.
Subsec. (a)(1). Pub. L. 109–163, § 1032(a)(2), substituted “Secretary of Homeland Security” for “Secretary of Defense” and “nuclear, radiological, biological, and” for “biological weapons and rela</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2315_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, chemical, or biological weapons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Emergencies involving nuclear, radiological, chemical, or biological weapons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2315_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual revisions of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual revisions of programs The Secretary of Homeland Security shall revise the program developed under subsection (a) not later than June 1 in each fiscal year covered by the program. The revisions shall include adjustments that the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate on the basis of the lessons learned from the exercise or exercises carried out under the program in the fiscal year, including lessons learned regarding coordination problems and equipment deficiencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>