<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2351"><akn:num>2351</akn:num><akn:heading>National coordinator on nonproliferation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2351. National coordinator on nonproliferation(a) Designation of positionThe President shall designate an individual to serve in the Executive Office of the President as the National Coordinator for Nonproliferation Matters.


(b) DutiesThe Coordinator, under the direction of the National Security Council, shall advise and assist the President by—(1) advising the President on nonproliferation of weapons of mass destruction, including issues related to terrorism, arms control, and international organized crime;

(2) chairing the Committee on Nonproliferation of the National Security Council; and

(3) taking such actions as are necessary to ensure that there is appropriate emphasis in, cooperation on, and coordination of, nonproliferation research efforts of the United States, including activities of Federal agencies as well as activities of contractors funded by the Federal Government.


(c) Allocation of fundsOf the total amount authorized to be appropriated under section 301,11 See References in Text note below. $2,000,000 is available to the Department of Defense for carrying out research referred to in subsection (b)(3).


(Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XIV, § 1441, Sept. 23, 1996, 110 Stat. 2727; Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1069(c)(2), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2136.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 301, referred to in subsec. (c), is section 301 of Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, Sept. 23, 1996, 110 Stat. 2475, which is not classified to the Code.

Amendments1998—Subsec. (b)(2). Pub. L. 105–261 substituted “of the National Security Council” for “established under section 1342”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Commission To Assess Organization of Federal Government To Combat Proliferation of Weapons of Mass DestructionPub. L. 104–293, title VII, subtitle A, Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3470, as amended by Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VII, § 708], Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–337, 2681–390, established the Commission t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of position</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation of position The President shall designate an individual to serve in the Executive Office of the President as the National Coordinator for Nonproliferation Matters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Coordinator, under the direction of the National Security Council, shall advise and assist the President by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocation of funds Of the total amount authorized to be appropriated under section 301,11 See References in Text note below. $2,000,000 is available to the Department of Defense for carrying out research referred to in subsection (b)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>