<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2368" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2368/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2368/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2368"><akn:num>2368</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports on the proliferation of missiles and essential components of nuclear, biological, che</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2368. Annual reports on the proliferation of missiles and essential components of nuclear, biological, chemical, and radiological weapons(a) ReportNot later than March 1, 2003, and annually thereafter, the President shall transmit to the designated congressional committees an annual report on the transfer by any country of weapons, technology, components, or materials that can be used to deliver, manufacture (including research and experimentation), or weaponize nuclear, biological, chemical or radiological weapons (in this section referred to as “NBC weapons”) to any country other than a country referred to in subsection (d) that is seeking to possess or otherwise acquire such weapons, technology, or materials, or other system that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to develop, acquire, or deliver NBC weapons.


(b) Matters to be includedEach such report shall include—(1) the transfer of all aircraft, cruise missiles, artillery weapons, unguided rockets and multiple rocket systems, and related bombs, shells, warheads and other weaponization technology and materials that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe may be intended for the delivery of NBC weapons;

(2) international transfers of MTCR equipment or technology to any country that is seeking to acquire such equipment or any other system that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe may be used to deliver NBC weapons; and

(3) the transfer of technology, test equipment, radioactive materials, feedstocks and cultures, and all other specialized materials that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to manufacture NBC weapons.


(c) Content of reportEach such report shall include the following with respect to preceding 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “the”. calendar year:(1) The status of missile, aircraft, and other NBC weapons delivery and weaponization programs in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2368_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Report Not later than March 1, 2003, and annually thereafter, the President shall transmit to the designated congressional committees an annual report on the transfer by any country of weapons, technology, components, or materials that can be used to deliver, manufacture (including research and experimentation), or weaponize nuclear, biological, chemical or radiological weapons (in this section referred to as “NBC weapons”) to any country other than a country referred to in subsection (d) that is seeking to possess or otherwise acquire such weapons, technology, or materials, or other system that the Secretary or the Secretary of Defense has reason to believe could be used to develop, acquire, or deliver NBC weapons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2368_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters to be included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Matters to be included Each such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2368_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Content of report Each such report shall include the following with respect to preceding 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “the”. calendar year:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2368_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exclusions The countries excluded under subsection (a) are Australia, Belgium, Canada, the Czech Republic, Denmark, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Iceland, Italy, Japan, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, New Zealand, Norway, Poland, Portugal, Spain, Turkey, the United Kingdom, and the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2368_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classification of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Classification of report The Secretary shall make every effort to submit all of the information required by this section in unclassified form. Whenever the Secretary submits any such information in classified form, the Secretary shall submit such classified information in an addendum and shall also submit concurrently a detailed summary, in unclassified form, of that classified information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2368_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>