<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2401"><akn:num>2401</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and mission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2401. Establishment and mission(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Department of Energy a separately organized agency to be known as the National Nuclear Security Administration (in this chapter referred to as the “Administration”).


(b) MissionThe mission of the Administration shall be the following:(1) To enhance United States national security through the military application of nuclear energy.

(2) To support the deterrence of strategic attacks against the United States by maintaining and enhancing the performance, reliability, security, and safety of the United States nuclear weapons stockpile, including the ability to design, produce, and test nuclear weapons as necessary in order to meet national security requirements.

(3) To provide the United States Navy with safe, militarily effective nuclear propulsion plants and to ensure the safe and reliable operation of those plants.

(4) To promote international nuclear safety and nonproliferation.

(5) To reduce global danger from weapons of mass destruction.

(6) To support United States leadership in science and technology.


(c) Operations and activities to be carried out consistently with certain principlesIn carrying out the mission of the Administration, the Administrator shall ensure that all operations and activities of the Administration are consistent with the principles of—(1) fulfilling, to the maximum extent possible, the requirements for nuclear weapons of the Department of Defense;

(2) protecting the environment;

(3) safeguarding the safety and health of the public and of the workforce of the Administration; and

(4) ensuring the security of the nuclear weapons, nuclear material, and classified information in the custody of the Administration.


(Pub. L. 106–65, div. C, title XXXII, § 3211, Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 957; Pub. L. 113–66, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111, Dec. 26, 2013, 127 Stat. 1049; Pub. L. 118–159, div. C, title XXXI, § 3111(a)(1), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2293.)

Editori</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Department of Energy a separately organized agency to be known as the National Nuclear Security Administration (in this chapter referred to as the “Administration”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mission The mission of the Administration shall be the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operations and activities to be carried out consistently with certain principles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operations and activities to be carried out consistently with certain principles In carrying out the mission of the Administration, the Administrator shall ensure that all operations and activities of the Administration are consistent with the principles of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>