<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2402"><akn:num>2402</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator for Nuclear Security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2402. Administrator for Nuclear Security(a) In general(1) There is at the head of the Administration an Administrator for Nuclear Security (in this chapter referred to as the “Administrator”).

(2) Pursuant to subsection (c) of section 7132 of title 42, the Under Secretary for Nuclear Security of the Department of Energy serves as the Administrator.


(b) FunctionsThe Administrator has authority over, and is responsible for, all programs and activities of the Administration (except for the functions of the Deputy Administrator for Naval Reactors specified in the Executive order referred to in section 2406(b) of this title), including the following:(1) Strategic management.

(2) Policy development and guidance.

(3) Budget formulation, guidance, and execution, and other financial matters.

(4) Resource requirements determination and allocation.

(5) Program management and direction.

(6) Safeguards and security.

(7) Emergency management and Nuclear Emergency Support Team capabilities, including all field-deployed and remote technical support to public health and safety missions, countering weapons of mass destruction operations, technical and operational nuclear forensics, and responses to United States nuclear weapon accidents.

(8) Integrated safety management.

(9) Environment, safety, and health operations.

(10) Administration of contracts, including the management and operations of the nuclear weapons production facilities and the national security laboratories.

(11) Intelligence.

(12) Counterintelligence.

(13) Personnel, including the selection, appointment, distribution, supervision, establishing of compensation, and separation of personnel in accordance with subchapter III of this chapter.

(14) Procurement of services of experts and consultants in accordance with section 3109 of title 5.

(15) Legal matters.

(16) Legislative affairs.

(17) Public affairs.

(18) Eliminating inventories of surplus fissile materials usable for nuclear weapons.

(19) Lia</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions The Administrator has authority over, and is responsible for, all programs and activities of the Administration (except for the functions of the Deputy Administrator for Naval Reactors specified in the Executive order referred to in section 2406(b) of this title), including the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Procurement authority The Administrator is the senior procurement executive for the Administration for the purposes of section 1702(c) of title 41.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Policy authority The Administrator may establish Administration-specific policies, unless disapproved by the Secretary of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership on Nuclear Weapons Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Membership on Nuclear Weapons Council The Administrator serves as a member of the Nuclear Weapons Council under section 179 of title 10.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2402_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reorganization authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reorganization authority Except as provided by subsections (b) and (c) of section 2481 of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>