<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2411" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2411/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2411/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2411"><akn:num>2411</akn:num><akn:heading>Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2411. Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation(a) Establishment(1) There is in the Administration a Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation (in this section referred to as the “Director”).

(2) The position of the Director shall be a Senior Executive Service position (as defined in section 3132(a) of title 5).


(b) Duties(1) The Director shall be the principal advisor to the Administrator, the Deputy Secretary of Energy, and the Secretary of Energy with respect to cost estimation and program evaluation for the Administration. The Director shall report directly to the Administrator.

(2) The Administrator may not delegate responsibility for receiving or acting on communications from the Director with respect to cost estimation and program evaluation for the Administration.


(c) Activities for cost estimation(1) The Director shall be the responsible for the following activities relating to cost estimation:(A) Advising the Administrator on policies and procedures for cost analysis and estimation by the Administration, including the determination of confidence levels with respect to cost estimates.

(B) Reviewing cost estimates and evaluating the performance baseline for each major atomic energy defense acquisition program.

(C) Advising the Administrator on policies and procedures for developing technology readiness assessments for major atomic energy defense acquisition programs that are consistent with the guidelines of the Department of Energy for technology readiness assessments.

(D) Reviewing technology readiness assessments for such programs to ensure that such programs are meeting levels of confidence associated with appropriate overall system performance.

(E) As directed by the Administrator, conducting independent cost estimates for such programs.


(2) A review, evaluation, or cost estimate conducted under subparagraph (B), (D), or (E) of paragraph (1) shall be considered an inherently governmental function, but the Director may u</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2411_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2411_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2411_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities for cost estimation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities for cost estimation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2411_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities for program evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities for program evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2411_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data collection and accessibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Data collection and accessibility The Administrator, acting through the Director, shall, as appropriate, seek to use procedures, processes, and policies for collecting cost data and making that data accessible that are similar to the procedures, processes, and policies used by the Defense Cost Analysis Resource Center of the Office of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation of the Department of Defense for those purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2411_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Staff The Administrator shall ensure that the Director has sufficient numbers of personnel who have competence in technical matters, budgetary matters, cost estimation, technology readiness analysis, and other appropriate matters to carry out the functions required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2411_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports by Director The Director shall submit to Congress at or about the time that the budget of the President is submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31 for each of fiscal years 2015 through 2018, a report that includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2411_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of Construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to require duplicate reviews or cost estimates for major atomic energy defense acquisition programs by the Administration or other elements of the Department of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2411_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>