<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2444" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2444/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2444/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2444"><akn:num>2444</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonproliferation and national security scholarship and fellowship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2444. Nonproliferation and national security scholarship and fellowship program(a) EstablishmentThe Administrator for Nuclear Security shall carry out a program to provide scholarships and fellowships for the purpose of enabling individuals to qualify for employment in the nonproliferation and national security programs of the National Nuclear Security Administration.


(b) Eligible individualsAn individual shall be eligible for a scholarship or fellowship under the program established under this section if the individual—(1) is a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence;

(2) has been accepted for enrollment or is currently enrolled as a full-time student at an institution of higher education (as defined in section 102(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1002(a)));

(3) is pursuing a program of education that leads to an appropriate higher education degree in a qualifying field of study, as determined by the Administrator;

(4) enters into an agreement described in subsection (c); and

(5) meets such other requirements as the Administrator prescribes.


(c) AgreementAn individual seeking a scholarship or fellowship under the program established under this section shall enter into an agreement, in writing, with the Administrator that includes the following:(1) The agreement of the Administrator to provide such individual with a scholarship or fellowship in the form of educational assistance for a specified number of school years (not to exceed five school years) during which such individual is pursuing a program of education in a qualifying field of study, which educational assistance may include payment of tuition, fees, books, laboratory expenses, and a stipend.

(2) The agreement of such individual—(A) to accept such educational assistance;

(B) to maintain enrollment and attendance in a program of education described in subsection (b)(2) until such individual completes suc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2444_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Administrator for Nuclear Security shall carry out a program to provide scholarships and fellowships for the purpose of enabling individuals to qualify for employment in the nonproliferation and national security programs of the National Nuclear Security Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2444_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible individuals An individual shall be eligible for a scholarship or fellowship under the program established under this section if the individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2444_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreement An individual seeking a scholarship or fellowship under the program established under this section shall enter into an agreement, in writing, with the Administrator that includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2444_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repayment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2444_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference for cooperative education students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preference for cooperative education students In evaluating individuals for the award of a scholarship or fellowship under the program established under this section, the Administrator may give a preference to an individual who is enrolled in, or accepted for enrollment in, an institution of higher education that has a cooperative education program with the National Nuclear Security Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2444_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination of benefits A scholarship or fellowship awarded under the program established under this section shall be taken into account in determining the eligibility of an individual receiving such scholarship or fellowship for Federal student financial assistance provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2444_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report to Congress Not later than January 1, 2010, the Administrator shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the activities carried out under the program established under this section, including any recommendations for future activities under such program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2444_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated by section 3101(a)(2) 11 See References in Text note below. for defense nuclear nonproliferation activities, $3,000,000 shall be available to carry out the program established under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>