<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2481" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2481/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2481/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2481"><akn:num>2481</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions transferred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2481. Functions transferred(a) TransfersThere are hereby transferred to the Administrator all national security functions and activities performed immediately before October 5, 1999, by the following elements of the Department of Energy:(1) The Office of Defense Programs.

(2) The Office of Nonproliferation and National Security.

(3) The Office of Fissile Materials Disposition.

(4) The nuclear weapons production facilities.

(5) The national security laboratories.

(6) The Office of Naval Reactors.


(b) Authority to transfer additional functionsThe Secretary of Energy may transfer to the Administrator any other facility, mission, or function that the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator and Congress, determines to be consistent with the mission of the Administration.


(c) Environmental remediation and waste management activitiesIn the case of any environmental remediation and waste management activity of any element of the Administration, the Secretary of Energy may determine to transfer responsibility for that activity to another element of the Department.


(d) Transfer of funds(1) Any balance of appropriations that the Secretary of Energy determines is available and needed to finance or discharge a function, power, or duty or an activity that is transferred to the Administration shall be transferred to the Administration and used for any purpose for which those appropriations were originally available. Balances of appropriations so transferred shall—(A) be credited to any applicable appropriation account of the Administration; or

(B) be credited to a new account that may be established on the books of the Department of the Treasury;and shall be merged with the funds already credited to that account and accounted for as one fund.



(2) Balances of appropriations credited to an account under paragraph (1)(A) are subject only to such limitations as are specifically applicable to that account. Balances of appropriations credited to an account und</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2481_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfers There are hereby transferred to the Administrator all national security functions and activities performed immediately before October 5, 1999, by the following elements of the Department of Energy:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2481_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to transfer additional functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to transfer additional functions The Secretary of Energy may transfer to the Administrator any other facility, mission, or function that the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator and Congress, determines to be consistent with the mission of the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2481_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental remediation and waste management activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Environmental remediation and waste management activities In the case of any environmental remediation and waste management activity of any element of the Administration, the Secretary of Energy may determine to transfer responsibility for that activity to another element of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2481_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2481_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Personnel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>