<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2525" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2525/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2525/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2525"><akn:num>2525</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual assessments and reports to the President and Congress regarding the condition of the United S</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2525. Annual assessments and reports to the President and Congress regarding the condition of the United States nuclear weapons stockpile(a) Annual assessments requiredFor each nuclear weapon type in the stockpile of the United States, each official specified in subsection (b) on an annual basis shall, to the extent such official is directly responsible for the safety, reliability, performance, or military effectiveness of that nuclear weapon type, complete an assessment of the safety, reliability, performance, or military effectiveness (as the case may be) of that nuclear weapon type.


(b) Covered officialsThe officials referred to in subsection (a) are the following:(1) The head of each national security laboratory.

(2) The Commander of the United States Strategic Command.


(c) Dual validation teams in support of assessmentsIn support of the assessments required by subsection (a), the Administrator may establish teams, known as “dual validation teams”, to provide each national security laboratory responsible for weapons design with independent evaluations of the condition of each warhead for which such laboratory has lead responsibility. A dual validation team established by the Administrator shall—(1) be comprised of weapons experts from the laboratory that does not have lead responsibility for fielding the warhead being evaluated;

(2) have access to all surveillance and underground test data for all stockpile systems for use in the independent evaluations;

(3) use all relevant available data to conduct independent calculations; and

(4) pursue independent experiments to support the independent evaluations.


(d) Use of teams of experts for assessmentsThe head of each national security laboratory shall establish and use one or more teams of experts, known as “red teams”, to assist in the assessments required by subsection (a). Each such team shall include experts from both of the other national security laboratories. Each such team for a national security </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2525_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual assessments required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual assessments required For each nuclear weapon type in the stockpile of the United States, each official specified in subsection (b) on an annual basis shall, to the extent such official is directly responsible for the safety, reliability, performance, or military effectiveness of that nuclear weapon type, complete an assessment of the safety, reliability, performance, or military effectiveness (as the case may be) of that nuclear weapon type.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2525_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Covered officials The officials referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2525_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dual validation teams in support of assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dual validation teams in support of assessments In support of the assessments required by subsection (a), the Administrator may establish teams, known as “dual validation teams”, to provide each national security laboratory responsible for weapons design with independent evaluations of the condition of each warhead for which such laboratory has lead responsibility. A dual validation team established by the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2525_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of teams of experts for assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of teams of experts for assessments The head of each national security laboratory shall establish and use one or more teams of experts, known as “red teams”, to assist in the assessments required by subsection (a). Each such team shall include experts from both of the other national security laboratories. Each such team for a national security laboratory shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2525_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report on assessments Not later than December 1 of each year, each official specified in subsection (b) shall submit to the Secretary concerned, and to the Nuclear Weapons Council, a report on the assessments that such official was required by subsection (a) to complete. The report shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2525_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submittals to the President and Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Submittals to the President and Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2525_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classified form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Classified form Each submittal under subsection (f) shall be in classified form only, with the classification level required for each portion of such submittal marked appropriately.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2525_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definition In this section, the term “Secretary concerned” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>