<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2533" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2533/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2533/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2533"><akn:num>2533</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports on critical difficulties at national security laboratories and nuclear weapons production fa</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2533. Reports on critical difficulties at national security laboratories and nuclear weapons production facilities(a) Reports by heads of laboratories and facilitiesIn the event of a difficulty at a national security laboratory or a nuclear weapons production facility that has a significant bearing on confidence in the safety or reliability of a nuclear weapon or nuclear weapon type, the head of the laboratory or facility, as the case may be, shall submit to the Administrator a report on the difficulty. The head of the laboratory or facility shall submit the report as soon as practicable after discovery of the difficulty.


(b) Transmittal by AdministratorNot later than 10 days after receipt of a report under subsection (a), the Administrator shall transmit the report (together with the comments of the Administrator) to the congressional defense committees, to the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Defense, and to the President.


(c) Omitted

(d) Inclusion of reports in annual stockpile assessmentAny report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall also be submitted to the President and Congress with the matters required to be submitted under section 2525(f) of this title for the year in which such report is submitted.


(Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLII, § 4213, formerly Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXI, § 3159, Sept. 23, 1996, 110 Stat. 2842, § 4218(b), (c), formerly Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title XIII, § 1305(c), (d), Nov. 18, 1997, 111 Stat. 1954; Pub. L. 106–65, div. C, title XXXI, § 3163(f), Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 946; renumbered Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLII, § 4213, by Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(e)(14), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1760; renumbered Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLII, § 4218(c), (d), and amended Pub. L. 112–239, div. C, title XXXI, §§ 3131(f)(1), 3164(a)(3), Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 2181, 2206; renumbered Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLII, § 4218(b), (c), and amended Pub. L. 113–66, div. C, title XXXI, § 3</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2533_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by heads of laboratories and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports by heads of laboratories and facilities In the event of a difficulty at a national security laboratory or a nuclear weapons production facility that has a significant bearing on confidence in the safety or reliability of a nuclear weapon or nuclear weapon type, the head of the laboratory or facility, as the case may be, shall submit to the Administrator a report on the difficulty. The head of the laboratory or facility shall submit the report as soon as practicable after discovery of the difficulty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2533_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmittal by Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transmittal by Administrator Not later than 10 days after receipt of a report under subsection (a), the Administrator shall transmit the report (together with the comments of the Administrator) to the congressional defense committees, to the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Defense, and to the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2533_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2533_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of reports in annual stockpile assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inclusion of reports in annual stockpile assessment Any report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall also be submitted to the President and Congress with the matters required to be submitted under section 2525(f) of this title for the year in which such report is submitted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>