<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2537" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2537/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2537/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2537"><akn:num>2537</akn:num><akn:heading>Selected Acquisition Reports and independent cost estimates and reviews of certain programs and faci</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2537. Selected Acquisition Reports and independent cost estimates and reviews of certain programs and facilities(a) Selected Acquisition Reports(1) At the end of the first quarter of each fiscal year, the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Administrator, shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on each nuclear weapon system undergoing life extension and each major alteration project (as defined in section 2753(a)(2) of this title) during the preceding fiscal year. The reports shall be known as Selected Acquisition Reports for the weapon system concerned.

(2) The information contained in the Selected Acquisition Report for a fiscal year for a nuclear weapon system shall be the information contained in the Selected Acquisition Report for each fiscal-year quarter in that fiscal year for a major defense acquisition program under section 4351 of title 10 or any successor system, expressed in terms of the nuclear weapon system.


(b) Independent cost estimates and reviews(1) The Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall submit to the congressional defense committees and the Nuclear Weapons Council the following:(A) An independent cost estimate of the following:(i) Each nuclear weapon system undergoing life extension at the completion of phase 6.2A or new weapon system at the completion of phase 2A, relating to design definition and cost study.

(ii) Each nuclear weapon system undergoing life extension at the completion of phase 6.3 or new weapon system at the completion of phase 3, relating to development engineering.

(iii) Each nuclear weapon system undergoing life extension at the completion of phase 6.4, relating to production engineering, and before the initiation of phase 6.5, relating to first production.

(iv) Each new weapon system at the completion of phase 4, relating to production engineering, and before the initiation of phase 5, relating to first production.

(v) Each new nuclear facility within the nuclear security ente</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2537_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selected Acquisition Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Selected Acquisition Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2537_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent cost estimates and reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Independent cost estimates and reviews</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2537_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for further assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority for further assessments Upon the request of the Administrator, the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation and in consultation with the Administrator, may conduct an independent cost assessment of any initiative or program of the Administration that is estimated to cost more than $500,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>