<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2538a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2538a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2538a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2538a"><akn:num>2538a</akn:num><akn:heading>Plutonium pit production capacity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2538a. Plutonium pit production capacity(a) RequirementConsistent with the requirements of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy shall ensure that the nuclear security enterprise—(1) during 2021, begins production of qualification plutonium pits;

(2) during 2024, produces not less than 10 war reserve plutonium pits;

(3) during 2025, produces not less than 20 war reserve plutonium pits;

(4) during 2026, produces not less than 30 war reserve plutonium pits; and

(5) during 2030, produces not less than 80 war reserve plutonium pits.


(b) Annual certificationNot later than March 1, 2015, and each year thereafter through 2030, the Secretary of Energy shall certify to the congressional defense committees and the Secretary of Defense that the programs and budget of the Secretary of Energy will enable the nuclear security enterprise to meet the requirements under subsection (a).


(c) PlanIf the Secretary of Energy does not make a certification under subsection (b) by March 1 of any year in which a certification is required under that subsection, by not later than May 1 of such year, the Chairman of the Nuclear Weapons Council shall submit to the congressional defense committees a plan to enable the nuclear security enterprise to meet the requirements under subsection (a). Such plan shall include identification of the resources of the Department of Energy that the Chairman determines should be redirected to support the plan to meet such requirements.


(d) Certifications on plutonium enterprise(1) RequirementNot later than 30 days after the date on which a covered project achieves a critical decision milestone, the Assistant Secretary for Environmental Management and the Deputy Administrator for Defense Programs shall jointly certify to the congressional defense committees that the operations, infrastructure, and workforce of such project are adequate to carry out the delivery and disposal of planned waste shipments relating to the plutonium enterprise, as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2538a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement Consistent with the requirements of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy shall ensure that the nuclear security enterprise—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2538a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual certification Not later than March 1, 2015, and each year thereafter through 2030, the Secretary of Energy shall certify to the congressional defense committees and the Secretary of Defense that the programs and budget of the Secretary of Energy will enable the nuclear security enterprise to meet the requirements under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2538a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Plan If the Secretary of Energy does not make a certification under subsection (b) by March 1 of any year in which a certification is required under that subsection, by not later than May 1 of such year, the Chairman of the Nuclear Weapons Council shall submit to the congressional defense committees a plan to enable the nuclear security enterprise to meet the requirements under subsection (a). Such plan shall include identification of the resources of the Department of Energy that the Chairman determines should be redirected to support the plan to meet such requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2538a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certifications on plutonium enterprise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certifications on plutonium enterprise</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2538a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2538a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on ARIES expansion before achievement of 30 pit-per-year base capability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition on ARIES expansion before achievement of 30 pit-per-year base capability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2538a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered project defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Covered project defined In this subsection, the term “covered project” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2538a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of plutonium modernization program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Management of plutonium modernization program Not later than 570 days after December 22, 2023, the Administrator for Nuclear Security shall ensure that the plutonium modernization program established by the Office of Defense Programs of the National Nuclear Security Administration, or any subsequently developed program designed to meet the requirements under subsection (a), is managed in accordance with the best practices for schedule development and cost estimating of the Government Accountability Office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>