<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2569" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2569/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2569/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2569"><akn:num>2569</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceleration of removal or security of fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2569. Acceleration of removal or security of fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment at vulnerable sites worldwide(a) Sense of Congress(1) It is the sense of Congress that the security, including the rapid removal or secure storage, of high-risk, proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment at vulnerable sites worldwide should be a top priority among the activities to achieve the national security of the United States.

(2) It is the sense of Congress that the President may establish in the Department of Energy a task force to be known as the Task Force on Nuclear Materials to carry out the program authorized by subsection (b).


(b) Program authorizedThe Secretary of Energy may carry out a program to undertake an accelerated, comprehensive worldwide effort to mitigate the threats posed by high-risk, proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment located at sites potentially vulnerable to theft or diversion.


(c) Program elements(1) Activities under the program under subsection (b) may include the following:(A) Accelerated efforts to secure, remove, or eliminate proliferation-attractive fissile materials or radiological materials in research reactors, other reactors, and other facilities worldwide.

(B) Arrangements for the secure shipment of proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment to other countries willing to accept such materials and equipment, or to the United States if such countries cannot be identified, and the provision of secure storage or disposition of such materials and equipment following shipment.

(C) The transportation of proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment from sites identified as proliferation risks to secure facilities in other countries or in the United States.

(D) The processing and packaging of proliferation-attractive fissile </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2569_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sense of Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2569_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program authorized The Secretary of Energy may carry out a program to undertake an accelerated, comprehensive worldwide effort to mitigate the threats posed by high-risk, proliferation-attractive fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment located at sites potentially vulnerable to theft or diversion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2569_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program elements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2569_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding Amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy for defense nuclear nonproliferation activities shall be available for purposes of the program under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2569_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation by other governments and organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Participation by other governments and organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2569_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>