<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2582" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2582/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2582/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2582"><akn:num>2582</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to develop future use plans for defense environmental cleanup</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2582. Requirement to develop future use plans for defense environmental cleanup(a) Authority to develop future use plansThe Secretary of Energy may develop future use plans for any defense nuclear facility at which defense environmental cleanup activities are occurring.


(b) Requirement to develop future use plansThe Secretary shall develop a future use plan for each of the following defense nuclear facilities:(1) Hanford Site, Richland, Washington.

(2) Savannah River Site, Aiken, South Carolina.

(3) Idaho National Engineering Laboratory, Idaho.


(c) Citizen advisory board(1) At each defense nuclear facility for which the Secretary of Energy intends or is required to develop a future use plan under this section and for which no citizen advisory board has been established, the Secretary shall establish a citizen advisory board.

(2) The Secretary may authorize the manager of a defense nuclear facility for which a future use plan is developed under this section (or, if there is no such manager, an appropriate official of the Department of Energy designated by the Secretary) to pay routine administrative expenses of a citizen advisory board established for that facility. Such payments shall be made from funds available to the Secretary for defense environmental cleanup activities necessary for national security programs.


(d) Requirement to consult with citizen advisory boardIn developing a future use plan under this section with respect to a defense nuclear facility, the Secretary of Energy shall consult with a citizen advisory board established pursuant to subsection (c) or a similar advisory board already in existence as of September 23, 1996, for such facility, affected local governments (including any local future use redevelopment authorities), and other appropriate State agencies.


(e) 50-year planning periodA future use plan developed under this section shall cover a period of at least 50 years.


(f) ReportNot later than 60 days after completing develo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2582_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to develop future use plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to develop future use plans The Secretary of Energy may develop future use plans for any defense nuclear facility at which defense environmental cleanup activities are occurring.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2582_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to develop future use plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement to develop future use plans The Secretary shall develop a future use plan for each of the following defense nuclear facilities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2582_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizen advisory board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Citizen advisory board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2582_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to consult with citizen advisory board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirement to consult with citizen advisory board In developing a future use plan under this section with respect to a defense nuclear facility, the Secretary of Energy shall consult with a citizen advisory board established pursuant to subsection (c) or a similar advisory board already in existence as of September 23, 1996, for such facility, affected local governments (including any local future use redevelopment authorities), and other appropriate State agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2582_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>50-year planning period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) 50-year planning period A future use plan developed under this section shall cover a period of at least 50 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2582_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Not later than 60 days after completing development of a final plan for a site listed in subsection (b), the Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress a report on the plan. The report shall describe the plan and contain such findings and recommendations with respect to the site as the Secretary considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2582_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Savings provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>