<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2588" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2588/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2588/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2588"><akn:num>2588</akn:num><akn:heading>Public participation in planning for defense environmental cleanup</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2588. Public participation in planning for defense environmental cleanup
The Secretary of Energy shall consult with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Attorney General, Governors and attorneys general of affected States, appropriate representatives of affected Indian tribes, and interested members of the public in any planning conducted by the Secretary for defense environmental cleanup activities at Department of Energy defense nuclear facilities.
(Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLIV, § 4408, formerly Pub. L. 103–337, div. C, title XXXI, § 3160(e), Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 3095; renumbered Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLIV, § 4408, and amended Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(g)(9), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1765; Pub. L. 113–66, div. C, title XXXI, § 3146(e)(9), Dec. 26, 2013, 127 Stat. 1077.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly set out as a note under section 7274g of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to renumbering by Pub. L. 108–136.

Amendments2013—Pub. L. 113–66 substituted “defense environmental cleanup” for “environmental restoration and waste management at defense nuclear facilities” in section catchline and substituted “attorneys general” for “Attorneys General” and “defense environmental cleanup activities” for “environmental restoration and waste management” in text.
2003—Pub. L. 108–136, § 3141(g)(9)(C), substituted “Public participation in planning for environmental restoration and waste management at defense nuclear facilities” for “Public participation in planning” in section catchline.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>