<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2589" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2589/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2589/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2589"><akn:num>2589</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy of Department of Energy regarding future defense environmental management matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2589. Policy of Department of Energy regarding future defense environmental management matters(a) Policy required(1) Commencing not later than October 1, 2005, the Secretary of Energy shall have in effect a policy for carrying out future defense environmental management matters of the Department of Energy. The policy shall specify each officer within the Department with responsibilities for carrying out that policy and, for each such officer, the nature and extent of those responsibilities.

(2) In paragraph (1), the term “future defense environmental management matter” means any environmental cleanup project, decontamination and decommissioning project, waste management project, or related activity that arises out of the activities of the Department in carrying out programs necessary for national security and is to be commenced after November 24, 2003. However, such term does not include any such project or activity the responsibility for which has been assigned, as of November 24, 2003, to the Environmental Management program of the Department.


(b) Reflection in budgetFor fiscal year 2006 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall ensure that the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Energy budget for such fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31) reflect the policy required by subsection (a).


(c) ConsultationThe Secretary shall carry out this section in consultation with the Administrator for Nuclear Security and the Under Secretary of Energy for Energy, Science, and Environment.


(d) ReportThe Secretary shall include with the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Energy budget for fiscal year 2005 (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31) a report on the policy that the Secretary plans to have in effect under subsection (a) as of October 1, 2005. The report shall</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2589_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Policy required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2589_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reflection in budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reflection in budget For fiscal year 2006 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall ensure that the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Energy budget for such fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31) reflect the policy required by subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2589_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation The Secretary shall carry out this section in consultation with the Administrator for Nuclear Security and the Under Secretary of Energy for Energy, Science, and Environment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2589_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report The Secretary shall include with the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Energy budget for fiscal year 2005 (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31) a report on the policy that the Secretary plans to have in effect under subsection (a) as of October 1, 2005. The report shall specify the officers and responsibilities referred to in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>