<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2603" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2603/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2603/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2603"><akn:num>2603</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan for deactivation and decommissioning of nonoperational defense nuclear facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2603. Plan for deactivation and decommissioning of nonoperational defense nuclear facilities(a) In generalThe Secretary of Energy shall, every four years beginning in 2025, develop and subsequently carry out a plan for the activities of the Department of Energy relating to the deactivation and decommissioning of nonoperational defense nuclear facilities.


(b) ElementsThe plan required by subsection (a) shall include the following:(1) A list of nonoperational defense nuclear facilities, prioritized for deactivation and decommissioning based on the potential to reduce risks to human health, property, or the environment and to maximize cost savings.

(2) An assessment of the life cycle costs of each nonoperational defense nuclear facility during the period beginning on the date on which the plan is submitted under subsection (d) and ending on the earlier of—(A) the date that is 25 years after the date on which the plan is submitted; or

(B) the estimated date for deactivation and decommissioning of the facility.


(3) An estimate of the cost and time needed to deactivate and decommission each nonoperational defense nuclear facility.

(4) A schedule for when the Office of Environmental Management will accept each nonoperational defense nuclear facility for deactivation and decommissioning.

(5) An estimate of costs that could be avoided by—(A) accelerating the cleanup of nonoperational defense nuclear facilities; or

(B) other means, such as reusing such facilities for another purpose.



(c) Plan for transfer of responsibility for certain facilitiesThe Secretary shall, during 2025, develop and subsequently carry out a plan under which the Administrator shall transfer, by March 31, 2029, to the Assistant Secretary for Environmental Management the responsibility for decontaminating and decommissioning facilities of the Administration that the Secretary determines are nonoperational as of September 30, 2024.


(d) Submission to CongressNot later than March 31, 2025, an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2603_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Energy shall, every four years beginning in 2025, develop and subsequently carry out a plan for the activities of the Department of Energy relating to the deactivation and decommissioning of nonoperational defense nuclear facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2603_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Elements The plan required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2603_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan for transfer of responsibility for certain facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Plan for transfer of responsibility for certain facilities The Secretary shall, during 2025, develop and subsequently carry out a plan under which the Administrator shall transfer, by March 31, 2029, to the Assistant Secretary for Environmental Management the responsibility for decontaminating and decommissioning facilities of the Administration that the Secretary determines are nonoperational as of September 30, 2024.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2603_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Submission to Congress Not later than March 31, 2025, and every four years thereafter,,11 So in original. the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2603_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination The requirements of this section shall terminate after the submission to the appropriate congressional committees of the report required by subsection (d) to be submitted not later than March 31, 2033.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2603_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>