<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2622" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2622/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2622/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2622"><akn:num>2622</akn:num><akn:heading>Hanford waste tank cleanup program reforms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2622. Hanford waste tank cleanup program reforms(a) Establishment of Office of River ProtectionThe Secretary of Energy shall establish an office at the Hanford Reservation, Richland, Washington, to be known as the “Office of River Protection” (in this section referred to as the “Office”).


(b) Management and responsibilities of Office(1) The Office shall be headed by a senior official of the Department of Energy, who shall report to the Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environmental Management.

(2) The head of the Office shall be responsible for managing all aspects of the River Protection Project, Richland, Washington, including Hanford Tank Farm operations and the Waste Treatment Plant.

(3)(A) The Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environmental Management shall delegate in writing responsibility for the management of the River Protection Project, Richland, Washington, to the head of the Office.

(B) Such delegation shall include, at a minimum, authorities for contracting, financial management, safety, and general program management that are equivalent to the authorities of managers of other operations offices of the Department of Energy.

(C) The head of the Office shall, to the maximum extent possible, coordinate all activities of the Office with the manager of the Richland Operations Office of the Department of Energy.



(c) Department responsibilitiesThe Secretary shall provide the head of the Office with the resources and personnel necessary to carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (b)(2).


(d) NotificationThe Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environmental Management shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives written notification detailing any changes in the roles, responsibilities, and reporting relationships that involve the Office.


(e) TerminationThe Office shall terminate on September 30, 2024. The Office may be extended beyond that date if th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2622_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Office of River Protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Office of River Protection The Secretary of Energy shall establish an office at the Hanford Reservation, Richland, Washington, to be known as the “Office of River Protection” (in this section referred to as the “Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2622_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management and responsibilities of Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management and responsibilities of Office</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2622_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Department responsibilities The Secretary shall provide the head of the Office with the resources and personnel necessary to carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (b)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2622_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification The Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environmental Management shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives written notification detailing any changes in the roles, responsibilities, and reporting relationships that involve the Office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2622_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination The Office shall terminate on September 30, 2024. The Office may be extended beyond that date if the Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environmental Management determines in writing that termination would disrupt effective management of the Hanford Tank Farm operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>