<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2673" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2673/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2673/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2673"><akn:num>2673</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement to plan for declassification of Restricted Data and Formerly Restricted Data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2673. Supplement to plan for declassification of Restricted Data and Formerly Restricted Data(a) Supplement to planThe Secretary of Energy and the Archivist of the United States shall, after consultation with the members of the National Security Council and in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, develop a supplement to the plan required under subsection (a) of section 2672 of this title.


(b) Contents of supplementThe supplement shall provide for the application of that plan (including in particular the element of the plan required by subsection (b)(1) of section 2672 of this title) to all records subject to Executive Order No. 12958 that were determined before October 17, 1998, to be suitable for declassification.


(c) Limitation on declassification of recordsAll records referred to in subsection (b) shall be treated, for purposes of subsection (c) of section 2672 of this title, in the same manner as records referred to in subsection (a) of such section.


(d) Submission of supplementThe Secretary of Energy shall submit the supplement required under subsection (a) to the recipients of the plan referred to in subsection (d) of section 2672 of this title.


(Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLV, § 4523, formerly Pub. L. 106–65, div. C, title XXXI, § 3149, Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 938; renumbered Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLV, § 4523, and amended Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(h)(13), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1775.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextExecutive Order No. 12958, referred to in subsec. (b), which was formerly set out as a note under section 435 (now section 3161) of this title, was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 13526, § 6.2(g), Dec. 29, 2009, 75 F.R. 731.

Codification
Section was formerly set out as a note under section 435 of this title prior to renumbering by Pub. L. 108–136.

Amendments2003—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 108–136, § 3141(h)(13)(D)(i), substituted “subsection (a) of sectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2673_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement to plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Supplement to plan The Secretary of Energy and the Archivist of the United States shall, after consultation with the members of the National Security Council and in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, develop a supplement to the plan required under subsection (a) of section 2672 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2673_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of supplement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of supplement The supplement shall provide for the application of that plan (including in particular the element of the plan required by subsection (b)(1) of section 2672 of this title) to all records subject to Executive Order No. 12958 that were determined before October 17, 1998, to be suitable for declassification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2673_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on declassification of records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on declassification of records All records referred to in subsection (b) shall be treated, for purposes of subsection (c) of section 2672 of this title, in the same manner as records referred to in subsection (a) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2673_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of supplement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Submission of supplement The Secretary of Energy shall submit the supplement required under subsection (a) to the recipients of the plan referred to in subsection (d) of section 2672 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>