<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2702"><akn:num>2702</akn:num><akn:heading>Whistleblower protection program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2702. Whistleblower protection program(a) Program requiredThe Secretary of Energy shall establish a program to ensure that covered individuals may not be discharged, demoted, or otherwise discriminated against as a reprisal for making protected disclosures.


(b) Covered individualsFor purposes of this section, a covered individual is an individual who is an employee of the Department of Energy, or of a contractor of the Department, who is engaged in the defense activities of the Department.


(c) Protected disclosuresFor purposes of this section, a protected disclosure is a disclosure—(1) made by a covered individual who takes appropriate steps to protect the security of the information in accordance with guidance provided under this section;

(2) made to a person or entity specified in subsection (d); and

(3) of classified or other information that the covered individual reasonably believes to provide direct and specific evidence of any of the following:(A) A violation of law or Federal regulation.

(B) Gross mismanagement, a gross waste of funds, or abuse of authority.

(C) A false statement to Congress on an issue of material fact.



(d) Persons and entities to which disclosures may be madeA person or entity specified in this subsection is any of the following:(1) A member of a committee of Congress having primary responsibility for oversight of the department, agency, or element of the Government to which the disclosed information relates.

(2) An employee of Congress who is a staff member of such a committee and has an appropriate security clearance for access to information of the type disclosed.

(3) The Inspector General of the Department of Energy.

(4) The Federal Bureau of Investigation.

(5) Any other element of the Government designated by the Secretary as authorized to receive information of the type disclosed.


(e) Official capacity of persons to whom information is disclosedA member of, or an employee of Congress who is a staff member of, a com</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program required The Secretary of Energy shall establish a program to ensure that covered individuals may not be discharged, demoted, or otherwise discriminated against as a reprisal for making protected disclosures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Covered individuals For purposes of this section, a covered individual is an individual who is an employee of the Department of Energy, or of a contractor of the Department, who is engaged in the defense activities of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protected disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Protected disclosures For purposes of this section, a protected disclosure is a disclosure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons and entities to which disclosures may be made</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Persons and entities to which disclosures may be made A person or entity specified in this subsection is any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Official capacity of persons to whom information is disclosed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Official capacity of persons to whom information is disclosed A member of, or an employee of Congress who is a staff member of, a committee of Congress specified in subsection (d) who receives a protected disclosure under this section does so in that member or employee’s official capacity as such a member or employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance and guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Assistance and guidance The Secretary, acting through the Inspector General of the Department of Energy, shall provide assistance and guidance to each covered individual who seeks to make a protected disclosure under this section. Such assistance and guidance shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to ensure the security of any information disclosed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to covered individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notification to covered individuals The Secretary shall notify each covered individual of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Complaint by covered individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Complaint by covered individuals If a covered individual believes that that individual has been discharged, demoted, or otherwise discriminated against as a reprisal for making a protected disclosure under this section, the individual may submit a complaint relating to such matter to the Director of the Office of Hearings and Appeals of the Department of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2702_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation by Office of Hearings and Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Investigation by Office of Hearings and Appeals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>