<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2704"><akn:num>2704</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Energy defense nuclear facilities workforce restructuring plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2704. Department of Energy defense nuclear facilities workforce restructuring plan(a) In generalUpon determination that a change in the workforce at a defense nuclear facility is necessary, the Secretary of Energy shall develop a plan for restructuring the workforce for the defense nuclear facility that takes into account—(1) the reconfiguration of the defense nuclear facility; and

(2) the plan for the nuclear weapons stockpile that is the most recently prepared plan at the time of the development of the plan referred to in this subsection.


(b) Consultation(1) In developing a plan referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Labor, appropriate representatives of local and national collective-bargaining units of individuals employed at Department of Energy defense nuclear facilities, appropriate representatives of departments and agencies of State and local governments, appropriate representatives of State and local institutions of higher education, and appropriate representatives of community groups in communities affected by the restructuring plan.

(2) The Secretary shall determine appropriate representatives of the units, governments, institutions, and groups referred to in paragraph (1).


(c) ObjectivesIn preparing the plan required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall be guided by the following objectives:(1) Changes in the workforce at a Department of Energy defense nuclear facility—(A) should be accomplished so as to minimize social and economic impacts;

(B) should be made only after the provision of notice of such changes not later than 120 days before the commencement of such changes to such employees and the communities in which such facilities are located; and

(C) should be accomplished, when possible, through the use of retraining, early retirement, attrition, and other options that minimize layoffs.


(2) Employees whose employment in positions at such facilities is terminated shall, to the extent practic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Upon determination that a change in the workforce at a defense nuclear facility is necessary, the Secretary of Energy shall develop a plan for restructuring the workforce for the defense nuclear facility that takes into account—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Objectives In preparing the plan required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall be guided by the following objectives:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation The Secretary shall, subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, work on an ongoing basis with representatives of the Department of Labor, workforce bargaining units, and States and local communities in carrying out a plan required under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2704_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submittal to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Submittal to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2704_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Energy defense nuclear facility defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Department of Energy defense nuclear facility defined In this section, the term “Department of Energy defense nuclear facility” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>