<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2705" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2705/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2705/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2705"><akn:num>2705</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to provide certificate of commendation to Department of Energy and contractor employees fo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2705. Authority to provide certificate of commendation to Department of Energy and contractor employees for exemplary service in stockpile stewardship and security(a) Authority to present certificate of commendationThe Secretary of Energy may present a certificate of commendation to any current or former employee of the Department of Energy, and any current or former employee of a Department contractor, whose service to the Department in matters relating to stockpile stewardship and security assisted the Department in furthering the national security interests of the United States.


(b) CertificateThe certificate of commendation presented to a current or former employee under subsection (a) shall include an appropriate citation of the service of the current or former employee described in that subsection, including a citation for dedication, intellect, and sacrifice in furthering the national security interests of the United States by maintaining a strong, safe, and viable United States nuclear deterrent during the cold war or thereafter.


(c) Department of Energy definedFor purposes of this section, the term “Department of Energy” includes any predecessor agency of the Department of Energy.


(Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLVI, § 4605, formerly Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [div. C, title XXXI, § 3195], Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1654, 1654A–481; renumbered Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLVI, § 4605, by Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(i)(6), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1778; Pub. L. 113–66, div. C, title XXXI, § 3146(g)(5), Dec. 26, 2013, 127 Stat. 1079.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly set out as a note under section 2121 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to renumbering by Pub. L. 108–136.

Amendments2013—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 113–66 substituted “cold war” for “Cold War”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to present certificate of commendation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to present certificate of commendation The Secretary of Energy may present a certificate of commendation to any current or former employee of the Department of Energy, and any current or former employee of a Department contractor, whose service to the Department in matters relating to stockpile stewardship and security assisted the Department in furthering the national security interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certificate The certificate of commendation presented to a current or former employee under subsection (a) shall include an appropriate citation of the service of the current or former employee described in that subsection, including a citation for dedication, intellect, and sacrifice in furthering the national security interests of the United States by maintaining a strong, safe, and viable United States nuclear deterrent during the cold war or thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Energy defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Department of Energy defined For purposes of this section, the term “Department of Energy” includes any predecessor agency of the Department of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>