<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2733" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2733/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2733/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2733"><akn:num>2733</akn:num><akn:heading>Program to monitor Department of Energy workers exposed to hazardous and radioactive substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2733. Program to monitor Department of Energy workers exposed to hazardous and radioactive substances(a) In generalThe Secretary of Energy shall establish and carry out a program for the identification and on-going medical evaluation of current and former Department of Energy employees who are subject to significant health risks as a result of the exposure of such employees to hazardous or radioactive substances during such employment.


(b) Implementation of program(1) The Secretary shall, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Health and Human Services, issue regulations under which the Secretary shall implement the program. Such regulations shall, to the extent practicable, provide for a process to—(A) identify the hazardous substances and radioactive substances to which current and former Department of Energy employees may have been exposed as a result of such employment;

(B) identify employees referred to in subparagraph (A) who received a level of exposure identified under paragraph (2)(B);

(C) determine the appropriate number, scope, and frequency of medical evaluations and laboratory tests to be provided to employees who have received a level of exposure identified under paragraph (2)(B) to permit the Secretary to evaluate fully the extent, nature, and medical consequences of such exposure;

(D) make available the evaluations and tests referred to in subparagraph (C) to the employees referred to in such subparagraph;

(E) ensure that privacy is maintained with respect to medical information that personally identifies any such employee; and

(F) ensure that employee participation in the program is voluntary.


(2)(A) In determining the most appropriate means of carrying out the activities referred to in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services under the agreement referred to in subsection (c).

(B) The Secretary of Health and Human Services, with the assistance of the Dir</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Energy shall establish and carry out a program for the identification and on-going medical evaluation of current and former Department of Energy employees who are subject to significant health risks as a result of the exposure of such employees to hazardous or radioactive substances during such employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Implementation of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement with Secretary of Health and Human Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreement with Secretary of Health and Human Services Not later than April 23, 1993, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Health and Human Services relating to the establishment and conduct of the program required and regulations issued under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>