<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2750" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2750/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2750/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2750"><akn:num>2750</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of defense environmental cleanup funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2750. Transfer of defense environmental cleanup funds(a) Transfer authority for defense environmental cleanup fundsThe Secretary of Energy shall provide the manager of each field office of the Department of Energy with the authority to transfer defense environmental cleanup funds from a program or project under the jurisdiction of that office to another such program or project.


(b) Limitations(1) Number of transfersNot more than one transfer may be made to or from any program or project under subsection (a) in a fiscal year.


(2) Amounts transferredThe amount transferred to or from a program or project in any one transfer under subsection (a) may not exceed $5,000,000.


(3) Determination requiredA transfer may not be carried out by a manager of a field office under subsection (a) unless the manager determines that the transfer is necessary—(A) to address a risk to health, safety, or the environment; or

(B) to assure the most efficient use of defense environmental cleanup funds at the field office.


(4) Impermissible usesFunds transferred pursuant to subsection (a) may not be used for an item for which Congress has specifically denied funds or for a new program or project that has not been authorized by Congress.



(c) Exemption from reprogramming requirementsThe requirements of section 2742 of this title shall not apply to transfers of funds pursuant to subsection (a).


(d) NotificationThe Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environmental Management, shall notify Congress of any transfer of funds pursuant to subsection (a) not later than 30 days after such transfer occurs.


(e) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) The term “program or project” means, with respect to a field office of the Department of Energy, a program or project that is for defense environmental cleanup activities necessary for national security programs of the Department, that is being carried out by that office, and for which defense environmental cleanup funds ha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2750_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer authority for defense environmental cleanup funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer authority for defense environmental cleanup funds The Secretary of Energy shall provide the manager of each field office of the Department of Energy with the authority to transfer defense environmental cleanup funds from a program or project under the jurisdiction of that office to another such program or project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2750_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2750_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from reprogramming requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exemption from reprogramming requirements The requirements of section 2742 of this title shall not apply to transfers of funds pursuant to subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2750_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environmental Management, shall notify Congress of any transfer of funds pursuant to subsection (a) not later than 30 days after such transfer occurs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2750_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>