<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2785" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2785/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2785/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2785"><akn:num>2785</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of contractor performance evaluations leading to award fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2785. Publication of contractor performance evaluations leading to award fees(a) In generalThe Administrator shall take appropriate actions to make available to the public, to the maximum extent practicable, contractor performance evaluations conducted by the Administration of management and operating contractors of the nuclear security enterprise that results in the award of an award fee to the contractor concerned.


(b) FormatPerformance evaluations shall be made public under this section in a common format that facilitates comparisons of performance evaluations between and among similar management and operating contracts.


(Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLVIII, § 4805, as added Pub. L. 112–239, div. C, title XXXI, § 3117(a)(1), Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 2173.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 112–239, div. C, title XXXI, § 3117(b), Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 2173, provided that: “The amendments made by subsection (a) [enacting this section] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [Jan. 2, 2013], and shall apply with respect to contractor performance evaluations conducted by the National Nuclear Security Administration on or after that date.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2785_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Administrator shall take appropriate actions to make available to the public, to the maximum extent practicable, contractor performance evaluations conducted by the Administration of management and operating contractors of the nuclear security enterprise that results in the award of an award fee to the contractor concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2785_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Format</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Format Performance evaluations shall be made public under this section in a common format that facilitates comparisons of performance evaluations between and among similar management and operating contracts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>