<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2787" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2787/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2787/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2787"><akn:num>2787</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-benefit analyses for competition of management and operating contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2787. Cost-benefit analyses for competition of management and operating contracts(a) Briefings on requests for proposalsNot later than 7 days after issuing a request for proposals for a contract to manage and operate a facility of the Administration, the Administrator shall brief the congressional defense committees on the preliminary assessment of the Administrator of the costs and benefits of the competition for the contract, including a preliminary assessment of the matters described in subsection (c) with respect to the contract.


(b) Reports after transition to new contractsIf the Administrator awards a new contract to manage and operate a facility of the Administration, the Administrator shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that includes the matters described in subsection (c) with respect to the contract by not later than 30 days after the completion of the period required to transition to the contract.


(c) Matters describedThe matters described in this subsection, with respect to a contract, are the following:(1) A clear and complete description of the cost savings the Administrator expects to result from the competition for the contract over the life of the contract, including associated analyses, assumptions, and information sources used to determine such expected cost savings.

(2) A description of any key limitations or uncertainties that could affect such costs savings, including costs savings that are anticipated but not fully known.

(3) The costs of the competition for the contract, including the immediate costs of conducting the competition, the costs of the transition to the contract from the previous contract, and any increased costs over the life of the contract.

(4) A description of any disruptions or delays in mission activities or deliverables resulting from the competition for the contract.

(5) A clear and complete description of the benefits expected by the Administrator with respect to mission performance or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2787_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Briefings on requests for proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Briefings on requests for proposals Not later than 7 days after issuing a request for proposals for a contract to manage and operate a facility of the Administration, the Administrator shall brief the congressional defense committees on the preliminary assessment of the Administrator of the costs and benefits of the competition for the contract, including a preliminary assessment of the matters described in subsection (c) with respect to the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2787_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports after transition to new contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports after transition to new contracts If the Administrator awards a new contract to manage and operate a facility of the Administration, the Administrator shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that includes the matters described in subsection (c) with respect to the contract by not later than 30 days after the completion of the period required to transition to the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2787_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Matters described The matters described in this subsection, with respect to a contract, are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2787_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information quality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information quality Each briefing required by subsection (a) and report required by subsection (b) shall be prepared in accordance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2787_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of reports by Comptroller General of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review of reports by Comptroller General of the United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2787_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>