<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2791" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2791/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2791/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2791"><akn:num>2791</akn:num><akn:heading>Laboratory-directed research and development programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2791. Laboratory-directed research and development programs(a) AuthorityGovernment-owned, contractor-operated laboratories that are funded out of funds available to the Department of Energy for national security programs are authorized to carry out laboratory-directed research and development.


(b) RegulationsThe Secretary of Energy shall prescribe regulations for the conduct of laboratory-directed research and development at such laboratories.


(c) FundingOf the funds provided by the Department of Energy to a national security laboratory for national security activities, the Secretary shall provide a specific amount, of not less than 5 percent and not more than 7 percent of such funds, to be used by the laboratory for laboratory-directed research and development.


(d) “Laboratory-directed research and development” definedFor purposes of this section, the term “laboratory-directed research and development” means research and development work of a creative and innovative nature which, under the regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (b), is selected by the director of a laboratory for the purpose of maintaining the vitality of the laboratory in defense-related scientific disciplines.


(Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLVIII, § 4811, formerly Pub. L. 101–510, div. C, title XXXI, § 3132, Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1832; renumbered Pub. L. 107–314, div. D, title XLVIII, § 4811, and amended Pub. L. 108–136, div. C, title XXXI, § 3141(k)(6), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1784; Pub. L. 114–92, div. C, title XXXI, § 3115(a), Nov. 25, 2015, 129 Stat. 1193.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 7257a of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to renumbering by Pub. L. 108–136.

Amendments2015—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 114–92 substituted “to a national security laboratory” for “to such laboratories”, “of not less than 5 percent and not more than 7 percent” for “not to exceed 6 percent”, and “by the laboratory” for “by such laboratories</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2791_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority Government-owned, contractor-operated laboratories that are funded out of funds available to the Department of Energy for national security programs are authorized to carry out laboratory-directed research and development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2791_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations The Secretary of Energy shall prescribe regulations for the conduct of laboratory-directed research and development at such laboratories.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2791_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funding Of the funds provided by the Department of Energy to a national security laboratory for national security activities, the Secretary shall provide a specific amount, of not less than 5 percent and not more than 7 percent of such funds, to be used by the laboratory for laboratory-directed research and development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2791_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Laboratory-directed research and development” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Laboratory-directed research and development” defined For purposes of this section, the term “laboratory-directed research and development” means research and development work of a creative and innovative nature which, under the regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (b), is selected by the director of a laboratory for the purpose of maintaining the vitality of the laboratory in defense-related scientific disciplines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>