<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2811" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2811/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/2811/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2811"><akn:num>2811</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers of real property at certain Department of Energy facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2811. Transfers of real property at certain Department of Energy facilities(a) Transfer regulations(1) The Secretary of Energy shall prescribe regulations for the transfer by sale or lease of real property at Department of Energy defense nuclear facilities for the purpose of permitting the economic development of the property.

(2) The Secretary may not transfer real property under the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1) until—(A) the Secretary submits a notification of the proposed transfer to the congressional defense committees; and

(B) a period of 30 days has elapsed following the date on which the notification is submitted.



(b) Indemnification(1) Except as provided in paragraph (3) and subject to subsection (c), in the sale or lease of real property pursuant to the regulations prescribed under subsection (a), the Secretary may hold harmless and indemnify a person or entity described in paragraph (2) against any claim for injury to person or property that results from the release or threatened release of a hazardous substance or pollutant or contaminant as a result of Department of Energy activities at the defense nuclear facility on which the real property is located. Before entering into any agreement for such a sale or lease, the Secretary shall notify the person or entity that the Secretary has authority to provide indemnification to the person or entity under this subsection. The Secretary shall include in any agreement for such a sale or lease a provision stating whether indemnification is or is not provided.

(2) Paragraph (1) applies to the following persons and entities:(A) Any State that acquires ownership or control of real property of a defense nuclear facility.

(B) Any political subdivision of a State that acquires such ownership or control.

(C) Any other person or entity that acquires such ownership or control.

(D) Any successor, assignee, transferee, lender, or lessee of a person or entity described in subparagraphs (A) through (C)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2811_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2811_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indemnification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Indemnification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2811_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2811_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority of Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2811_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Relationship to other law Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting or modifying in any way section 9620(h) of title 42.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2811_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section, the terms “hazardous substance”, “release”, and “pollutant or contaminant” have the meanings provided by section 9601 of title 42.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>