<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3021"><akn:num>3021</akn:num><akn:heading>National Security Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3021. National Security Council(a) National Security CouncilThere is a council known as the National Security Council (in this section referred to as the “Council”).


(b) FunctionsConsistent with the direction of the President, the functions of the Council shall be to—(1) advise the President with respect to the integration of domestic, foreign, and military policies relating to the national security so as to enable the Armed Forces and the other departments and agencies of the United States Government to cooperate more effectively in matters involving the national security;

(2) assess and appraise the objectives, commitments, and risks of the United States in relation to the actual and potential military power of the United States, and make recommendations thereon to the President;

(3) make recommendations to the President concerning policies on matters of common interest to the departments and agencies of the United States Government concerned with the national security; and

(4) coordinate, without assuming operational authority, the United States Government response to malign foreign influence operations and campaigns.


(c) Membership(1) In generalThe Council consists of the President, the Vice President, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Director of the Office of Pandemic Preparedness and Response Policy and such other officers of the United States Government as the President may designate.


(2) Attendance and participation in meetingsThe President may designate such other officers of the United States Government as the President considers appropriate, including the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of National Drug Control Policy, the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and the National Cyber Director, to attend and participate in meetings of the Council.



(d) Presiding officersAt meetings of the Council, the President shall preside or, in the absence of the P</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Security Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National Security Council There is a council known as the National Security Council (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions Consistent with the direction of the President, the functions of the Council shall be to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presiding officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Presiding officers At meetings of the Council, the President shall preside or, in the absence of the President, a member of the Council designated by the President shall preside.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Advisor to the President on International Religious Freedom</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special Advisor to the President on International Religious Freedom It is the sense of Congress that there should be within the staff of the Council a Special Adviser to the President on International Religious Freedom, whose position should be comparable to that of a director within the Executive Office of the President. The Special Adviser should serve as a resource for executive branch officials, compiling and maintaining information on the facts and circumstances of violations of religious freedom (as defined in section 6402 of title 22), and making policy recommendations. The Special Adviser should serve as liaison with the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom, the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom, Congress and, as advisable, religious nongovernmental organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordinator for combating malign foreign influence operations and campaigns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coordinator for combating malign foreign influence operations and campaigns</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3021_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of malign foreign influence operations and campaigns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definition of malign foreign influence operations and campaigns In this section, the term “malign foreign influence operations and campaigns” means the coordinated, direct or indirect application of national diplomatic, informational, military, economic, business, corruption, educational, and other capabilities by hostile foreign powers to affect attitudes, behaviors, decisions, or outcomes within the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>