<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3030" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3030/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3030/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3030"><akn:num>3030</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of Science and Technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3030. Director of Science and Technology(a) Director of Science and TechnologyThere is a Director of Science and Technology within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence who shall be appointed by the Director of National Intelligence.


(b) Requirement relating to appointmentAn individual appointed as Director of Science and Technology shall have a professional background and experience appropriate for the duties of the Director of Science and Technology. In making such appointment, the Director of National Intelligence may give preference to an individual with experience outside of the United States Government.


(c) DutiesThe Director of Science and Technology shall—(1) act as the chief representative of the Director of National Intelligence for science and technology;

(2) chair the Director of National Intelligence Science and Technology Committee under subsection (d);

(3) assist the Director in formulating a long-term strategy for scientific advances in the field of intelligence;

(4) assist the Director on the science and technology elements of the budget of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence; and

(5) perform other such duties as may be prescribed by the Director of National Intelligence or specified by law.


(d) Director of National Intelligence Science and Technology Committee(1) There is within the Office of the Director of Science and Technology a Director of National Intelligence Science and Technology Committee.

(2) The Committee shall be composed of the principal science officers of the National Intelligence Program.

(3) The Committee shall—(A) coordinate advances in research and development related to intelligence; and

(B) perform such other functions as the Director of Science and Technology shall prescribe.



(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title I, § 103E, as added Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1011(a), Dec. 17, 2004, 118 Stat. 3659; amended Pub. L. 117–263, div. F, title LXVII, § 6703(b), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 3562.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of Science and Technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Director of Science and Technology There is a Director of Science and Technology within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence who shall be appointed by the Director of National Intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement relating to appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement relating to appointment An individual appointed as Director of Science and Technology shall have a professional background and experience appropriate for the duties of the Director of Science and Technology. In making such appointment, the Director of National Intelligence may give preference to an individual with experience outside of the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Director of Science and Technology shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of National Intelligence Science and Technology Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Director of National Intelligence Science and Technology Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>