<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3031" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3031/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3031/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3031"><akn:num>3031</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3031. Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center(a) Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security CenterThe Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center appointed under section 902 of the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002 (50 U.S.C. 3382) is a component of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.


(b) DutiesThe Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall perform the duties provided in the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002 and such other duties as may be prescribed by the Director of National Intelligence or specified by law.


(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title I, § 103F, as added Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1011(a), Dec. 17, 2004, 118 Stat. 3660; amended Pub. L. 115–31, div. N, title IV, § 401(e)(1), May 5, 2017, 131 Stat. 819.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002, referred to in subsec. (b), is title IX of Pub. L. 107–306, Nov. 27, 2002, 116 Stat. 2432. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 403–3f of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

AmendmentsPub. L. 115–31, § 401(e)(1)(A), substituted “Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center” for “National Counterintelligence Executive” in section catchline.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 115–31, § 401(e)(1)(B), substituted “Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center” for “National Counterintelligence Executive” in heading and “Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center appointed under section 902 of the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002 (50 U.S.C. 3382)” for “National Counterintelligence Executive under section 902 of the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002” in text.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 115–31, § 401(e)(1)(C), substituted “Director of the National Counterintelligenc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3031_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center The Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center appointed under section 902 of the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002 (50 U.S.C. 3382) is a component of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3031_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall perform the duties provided in the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002 and such other duties as may be prescribed by the Director of National Intelligence or specified by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>