<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3034d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3034d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3034d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3034d"><akn:num>3034d</akn:num><akn:heading>National Intelligence Management Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3034d. National Intelligence Management Council(a) EstablishmentThere is within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence a National Intelligence Management Council.


(b) Composition(1) The National Intelligence Management Council shall be composed of senior officials within the intelligence community and substantive experts from the public or private sector, who shall be appointed by, report to, and serve at the pleasure of, the Director of National Intelligence.

(2) The Director shall prescribe appropriate security requirements for personnel appointed from the private sector as a condition of service on the National Intelligence Management Council, or as contractors of the Council or employees of such contractors, to ensure the protection of intelligence sources and methods while avoiding, wherever possible, unduly intrusive requirements which the Director considers to be unnecessary for this purpose.


(c) Duties and responsibilitiesMembers of the National Intelligence Management Council shall work with each other and with other elements of the intelligence community to ensure proper coordination and to minimize duplication of effort, in addition to the following duties and responsibilities:(1) Provide integrated mission input to support the processes and activities of the intelligence community, including with respect to intelligence planning, programming, budgeting, and evaluation processes.

(2) Identify and pursue opportunities to integrate or coordinate collection and counterintelligence efforts.

(3) In concert with the responsibilities of the National Intelligence Council, ensure the integration and coordination of analytic and collection efforts.

(4) Develop and coordinate intelligence strategies in support of budget planning and programming activities.

(5) Advise the Director of National Intelligence on the development of the National Intelligence Priorities Framework of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (or any successo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3034d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence a National Intelligence Management Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3034d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Composition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3034d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties and responsibilities Members of the National Intelligence Management Council shall work with each other and with other elements of the intelligence community to ensure proper coordination and to minimize duplication of effort, in addition to the following duties and responsibilities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3034d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mission management of members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mission management of members Members of the National Intelligence Management Council, under the direction of the Director of National Intelligence, shall serve as mission managers to ensure integration among the elements of the intelligence community and across intelligence functions, disciplines, and activities for the purpose of achieving unity of effort and effect, including through the following responsibilities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3034d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff; availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Staff; availability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3034d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support from elements of the intelligence community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Support from elements of the intelligence community The heads of the elements of the intelligence community shall provide appropriate support to the National Intelligence Management Council, including with respect to intelligence activities, as required by the Director of National Intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>