<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3043a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3043a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3043a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3043a"><akn:num>3043a</akn:num><akn:heading>National intelligence strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3043a. National intelligence strategy(a) In generalBeginning in 2017, and once every 4 years thereafter, the Director of National Intelligence shall develop a comprehensive national intelligence strategy to meet national security objectives for the following 4-year period, or a longer period, if appropriate.


(b) RequirementsEach national intelligence strategy required by subsection (a) shall—(1) delineate a national intelligence strategy consistent with—(A) the most recent national security strategy report submitted pursuant to section 3043 of this title;

(B) the strategic plans of other relevant departments and agencies of the United States; and

(C) other relevant national-level plans;


(2) address matters related to national and military intelligence, including counterintelligence;

(3) identify the major national security missions that the intelligence community is currently pursuing and will pursue in the future to meet the anticipated security environment;

(4) describe how the intelligence community will utilize personnel, technology, partnerships, and other capabilities to pursue the major national security missions identified in paragraph (3);

(5) assess current, emerging, and future threats to the intelligence community, including threats from foreign intelligence and security services and insider threats;

(6) outline the organizational roles and missions of the elements of the intelligence community as part of an integrated enterprise to meet customer demands for intelligence products, services, and support;

(7) identify sources of strategic, institutional, programmatic, fiscal, and technological risk; and

(8) analyze factors that may affect the intelligence community’s performance in pursuing the major national security missions identified in paragraph (3) during the following 10-year period.


(c) Submission to CongressThe Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on each national inte</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3043a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Beginning in 2017, and once every 4 years thereafter, the Director of National Intelligence shall develop a comprehensive national intelligence strategy to meet national security objectives for the following 4-year period, or a longer period, if appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3043a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements Each national intelligence strategy required by subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3043a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission to Congress The Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on each national intelligence strategy required by subsection (a) not later than 45 days after the date of the completion of such strategy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>