<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3052" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3052/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3052/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3052"><akn:num>3052</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on establishment or operation of diplomatic intelligence support centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3052. Limitation on establishment or operation of diplomatic intelligence support centers(a) In general(1) A diplomatic intelligence support center may not be established, operated, or maintained without the prior approval of the Director of National Intelligence.

(2) The Director may only approve the establishment, operation, or maintenance of a diplomatic intelligence support center if the Director determines that the establishment, operation, or maintenance of such center is required to provide necessary intelligence support in furtherance of the national security interests of the United States.


(b) Prohibition of use of appropriationsAmounts appropriated pursuant to authorizations by law for intelligence and intelligence-related activities may not be obligated or expended for the establishment, operation, or maintenance of a diplomatic intelligence support center that is not approved by the Director of National Intelligence.


(c) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) The term “diplomatic intelligence support center” means an entity to which employees of the various elements of the intelligence community (as defined in section 3003(4) of this title) are detailed for the purpose of providing analytical intelligence support that—(A) consists of intelligence analyses on military or political matters and expertise to conduct limited assessments and dynamic taskings for a chief of mission; and

(B) is not intelligence support traditionally provided to a chief of mission by the Director of National Intelligence.


(2) The term “chief of mission” has the meaning given that term by section 3902(3) of title 22, and includes ambassadors at large and ministers of diplomatic missions of the United States, or persons appointed to lead United States offices abroad designated by the Secretary of State as diplomatic in nature.


(d) TerminationThis section shall cease to be effective on October 1, 2000.


(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title I, § 115, as added Pub. L. 106–120, title II</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3052_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3052_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of use of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition of use of appropriations Amounts appropriated pursuant to authorizations by law for intelligence and intelligence-related activities may not be obligated or expended for the establishment, operation, or maintenance of a diplomatic intelligence support center that is not approved by the Director of National Intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3052_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3052_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination This section shall cease to be effective on October 1, 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>