<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3056" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3056/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3056/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3056"><akn:num>3056</akn:num><akn:heading>National Counterterrorism Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3056. National Counterterrorism Center(a) Establishment of CenterThere is within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence a National Counterterrorism Center.


(b) Director of National Counterterrorism Center(1) There is a Director of the National Counterterrorism Center, who shall be the head of the National Counterterrorism Center, and who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.

(2) The Director of the National Counterterrorism Center may not simultaneously serve in any other capacity in the executive branch.


(c) Reporting(1) The Director of the National Counterterrorism Center shall report to the Director of National Intelligence with respect to matters described in paragraph (2) and the President with respect to matters described in paragraph (3).

(2) The matters described in this paragraph are as follows:(A) The budget and programs of the National Counterterrorism Center.

(B) The activities of the Directorate of Intelligence of the National Counterterrorism Center under subsection (i).

(C) The conduct of intelligence operations implemented by other elements of the intelligence community; and


(3) The matters described in this paragraph are the planning and progress of joint counterterrorism operations (other than intelligence operations).


(d) Primary missionsThe primary missions of the National Counterterrorism Center shall be as follows:(1) To serve as the primary organization in the United States Government for analyzing and integrating all intelligence possessed or acquired by the United States Government pertaining to terrorism and counterterrorism, excepting intelligence pertaining exclusively to domestic terrorists and domestic counterterrorism.

(2) To conduct strategic operational planning for counterterrorism activities, integrating all instruments of national power, including diplomatic, financial, military, intelligence, homeland security, and law enforcement activities within and a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Center There is within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence a National Counterterrorism Center.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of National Counterterrorism Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Director of National Counterterrorism Center</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Primary missions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Primary missions The primary missions of the National Counterterrorism Center shall be as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic counterterrorism intelligence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Domestic counterterrorism intelligence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and responsibilities of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Duties and responsibilities of Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation The Director of the National Counterterrorism Center may not direct the execution of counterterrorism operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolution of disputes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Resolution of disputes The Director of National Intelligence shall resolve disagreements between the National Counterterrorism Center and the head of a department, agency, or element of the United States Government on designations, assignments, plans, or responsibilities under this section. The head of such a department, agency, or element may appeal the resolution of the disagreement by the Director of National Intelligence to the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Directorate of Intelligence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Directorate of Intelligence The Director of the National Counterterrorism Center shall establish and maintain within the National Counterterrorism Center a Directorate of Intelligence which shall have primary responsibility within the United States Government for analysis of terrorism and terrorist organizations (except for purely domestic terrorism and domestic terrorist organizations) from all sources of intelligence, whether collected inside or outside the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Directorate of Strategic Operational Planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Directorate of Strategic Operational Planning</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>