<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3057" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3057/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3057/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3057"><akn:num>3057</akn:num><akn:heading>National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3057. National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center(a) Establishment(1) The President shall establish a National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, taking into account all appropriate government tools to—(A) prevent and halt the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies; and

(B) lead integration and mission management of all intelligence activities pertaining to biosecurity and foreign biological threats.


(2) The head of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center shall be the Director of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, who shall be appointed by the Director of National Intelligence.

(3) The National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center shall be located within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.

(4) The Director of the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center shall serve as the principal coordinator for the intelligence community, and as the principal advisor to the Director of National Intelligence, with respect to counterproliferation, biosecurity, and foreign biological threats.


(b) Missions and objectives(1) CounterproliferationIn establishing the National Counterproliferation and Biosecurity Center, the President shall address the following missions and objectives to prevent and halt the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies:(A) Establishing a primary organization within the United States Government for integrating all intelligence possessed or acquired by the United States pertaining to proliferation.

(B) Ensuring that appropriate agencies have full access to and receive all-source intelligence support needed to execute their counterproliferation plans or activities, and perform independent, alternative analyses.

(C) Coordinating the establishment of a central repository on known and suspected proliferation activities, incl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Missions and objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Missions and objectives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National security waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National security waiver The President may waive the requirements of this section, and any parts thereof, if the President determines that such requirements do not materially improve the ability of the United States Government to prevent and halt the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies. Such waiver shall be made in writing to Congress and shall include a description of how the missions and objectives in subsection (b) are being met.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that a central feature of counterproliferation activities, consistent with the President’s Proliferation Security Initiative, should include the physical interdiction, by air, sea, or land, of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, and related materials and technologies, and enhanced law enforcement activities to identify and disrupt proliferation networks, activities, organizations, and persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>