<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3071" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3071/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3071/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3071"><akn:num>3071</akn:num><akn:heading>National Security Agency voluntary separation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3071. National Security Agency voluntary separation(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “National Security Agency Voluntary Separation Act”.


(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) the term “Director” means the Director of the National Security Agency; and

(2) the term “employee” means an employee of the National Security Agency, serving under an appointment without time limitation, who has been currently employed by the National Security Agency for a continuous period of at least 12 months prior to the effective date of the program established under subsection (c), except that such term does not include—(A) a reemployed annuitant under subchapter III of chapter 83 or chapter 84 of title 5 or another retirement system for employees of the Government; or

(B) an employee having a disability on the basis of which such employee is or would be eligible for disability retirement under any of the retirement systems referred to in subparagraph (A).



(c) Establishment of programNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director, in his sole discretion, may establish a program under which employees may, after October 1, 2000, be eligible for early retirement, offered separation pay to separate from service voluntarily, or both.


(d) Early retirementAn employee who—(1) is at least 50 years of age and has completed 20 years of service; or

(2) has at least 25 years of service,


may, pursuant to regulations promulgated under this section, apply and be retired from the National Security Agency and receive benefits in accordance with chapter 83 or 84 of title 5 if the employee has not less than 10 years of service with the National Security Agency.

(e) Amount of separation pay and treatment for other purposes(1) AmountSeparation pay shall be paid in a lump sum and shall be equal to the lesser of—(A) an amount equal to the amount the employee would be entitled to receive under section 5595(c) of title 5 if the employee were entitled to payment un</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “National Security Agency Voluntary Separation Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of program Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director, in his sole discretion, may establish a program under which employees may, after October 1, 2000, be eligible for early retirement, offered separation pay to separate from service voluntarily, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Early retirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Early retirement An employee who— may, pursuant to regulations promulgated under this section, apply and be retired from the National Security Agency and receive benefits in accordance with chapter 83 or 84 of title 5 if the employee has not less than 10 years of service with the National Security Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of separation pay and treatment for other purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amount of separation pay and treatment for other purposes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reemployment restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reemployment restrictions An employee who receives separation pay under such program may not be reemployed by the National Security Agency for the 12-month period beginning on the effective date of the employee’s separation. An employee who receives separation pay under this section on the basis of a separation occurring on or after March 30, 1994, and accepts employment with the Government of the United States within 5 years after the date of the separation on which payment of the separation pay is based shall be required to repay the entire amount of the separation pay to the National Security Agency. If the employment is with an Executive agency (as defined by section 105 of title 5), the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may, at the request of the head of the agency, waive the repayment if the individual involved possesses unique abilities and is the only qualified applicant available for the position. If the employment is with an entity in the legislative branch, </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bar on certain employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Bar on certain employment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations Under this program, early retirement and separation pay may be offered only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations Before an employee may be eligible for early retirement, separation pay, or both, under this section, the Director shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of exercise of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Notification of exercise of authority The Director may not make an offer of early retirement, separation pay, or both, pursuant to this section until 15 days after submitting to the congressional intelligence committees a report describing the occupational groups or geographic locations, or other similar limitations or conditions, required by the Director under subsection (h), and including the proposed regulations issued pursuant to subsection (i).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>