<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3078" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3078/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3078/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3078"><akn:num>3078</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealing and savings provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3078. Repealing and savings provisions
All laws, orders, and regulations inconsistent with the provisions of this title 11 See References in Text note below. are repealed insofar as they are inconsistent with the powers, duties, and responsibilities enacted hereby: Provided, That the powers, duties, and responsibilities of the Secretary of Defense under this title 1 shall be administered in conformance with the policy and requirements for administration of budgetary and fiscal matters in the Government generally, including accounting and financial reporting, and that nothing in this title 1 shall be construed as eliminating or modifying the powers, duties, and responsibilities of any other department, agency, or officer of the Government in connection with such matters, but no such department, agency, or officer shall exercise any such powers, duties, or responsibilities in a manner that will render ineffective the provisions of this title.1
(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title III, § 312, formerly title IV, § 411, as added Aug. 10, 1949, ch. 412, § 11, 63 Stat. 590; renumbered title III, § 312, Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXVII, § 6742(b)(11), Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 2240.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis title, referred to in text, meant, when enacted, title IV of act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, which was added by section 11 of act Aug. 10, 1949, ch. 412, 63 Stat. 585, and which consisted of sections 401 to 411, this section being section 411. Section 11 of act Aug. 10, 1949—except for “§ 411”—was repealed by Pub. L. 87–651, § 307, Sept. 7, 1962, 76 Stat. 526. Although that repeal was executed by repealing title IV of act July 26, 1947 (except for this section), and the subsequent renumbering of section 411 of that Act as section 312 suggests that this section is now within title III, it is unclear whether the reference to “this title” should now be interpreted as referring to title III (classified to this subchapter) or whether it continues to refer to the no</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>