<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3091" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3091/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3091/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3091"><akn:num>3091</akn:num><akn:heading>General congressional oversight provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3091. General congressional oversight provisions(a) Reports to congressional committees of intelligence activities and anticipated activities(1) The President shall ensure that the congressional intelligence committees are kept fully and currently informed of the intelligence activities of the United States, including any significant anticipated intelligence activity as required by this subchapter.

(2) Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as requiring the approval of the congressional intelligence committees as a condition precedent to the initiation of any significant anticipated intelligence activity.


(b) Reports concerning illegal intelligence activitiesThe President shall ensure that any illegal intelligence activity is reported promptly to the congressional intelligence committees, as well as any corrective action that has been taken or is planned in connection with such illegal activity.


(c) Procedures for reporting informationThe President and the congressional intelligence committees shall each establish such written procedures as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.


(d) Procedures to protect from unauthorized disclosureThe House of Representatives and the Senate shall each establish, by rule or resolution of such House, procedures to protect from unauthorized disclosure all classified information, and all information relating to intelligence sources and methods, that is furnished to the congressional intelligence committees or to Members of Congress under this subchapter. Such procedures shall be established in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence. In accordance with such procedures, each of the congressional intelligence committees shall promptly call to the attention of its respective House, or to any appropriate committee or committees of its respective House, any matter relating to intelligence activities requiring the attention of such House or such committee or committees.


(e) Construc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to congressional committees of intelligence activities and anticipated activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports to congressional committees of intelligence activities and anticipated activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports concerning illegal intelligence activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports concerning illegal intelligence activities The President shall ensure that any illegal intelligence activity is reported promptly to the congressional intelligence committees, as well as any corrective action that has been taken or is planned in connection with such illegal activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for reporting information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Procedures for reporting information The President and the congressional intelligence committees shall each establish such written procedures as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures to protect from unauthorized disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Procedures to protect from unauthorized disclosure The House of Representatives and the Senate shall each establish, by rule or resolution of such House, procedures to protect from unauthorized disclosure all classified information, and all information relating to intelligence sources and methods, that is furnished to the congressional intelligence committees or to Members of Congress under this subchapter. Such procedures shall be established in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence. In accordance with such procedures, each of the congressional intelligence committees shall promptly call to the attention of its respective House, or to any appropriate committee or committees of its respective House, any matter relating to intelligence activities requiring the attention of such House or such committee or committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of authority conferred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Construction of authority conferred Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as authority to withhold information from the congressional intelligence committees on the grounds that providing the information to the congressional intelligence committees would constitute the unauthorized disclosure of classified information or information relating to intelligence sources and methods.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Intelligence activities” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Intelligence activities” defined As used in this section, the term “intelligence activities” includes covert actions as defined in section 3093(e) of this title, and includes financial intelligence activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>