<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3091a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3091a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3091a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3091a"><akn:num>3091a</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional oversight of controlled access programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3091a. Congressional oversight of controlled access programs(a) Periodic briefings(1) RequirementNot less frequently than semiannually or upon request by one of the appropriate congressional committees or a member of congressional leadership, the Director of National Intelligence shall provide to such committees and congressional leadership a briefing on each controlled access program in effect.


(2) ContentsEach briefing provided under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, the following:(A) A description of the activity of the controlled access programs during the period covered by the briefing.

(B) Documentation with respect to how the controlled access programs have achieved outcomes consistent with requirements documented by the Director and, as applicable, the Secretary of Defense.



(b) Limitations(1) EstablishmentA head of an element of the intelligence community may not establish a controlled access program, or a compartment or subcompartment therein, until the head notifies the appropriate congressional committees and congressional leadership of such controlled access program, compartment, or subcompartment, as the case may be.


(2) Transfers(A) LimitationExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), a head of an element of the intelligence community may not transfer a capability from a controlled access program, including from a compartment or subcompartment therein to a compartment or subcompartment of another controlled access program, to a special access program (as defined in section 3348(g) of this title), or to anything else outside the controlled access program, until the head submits to the appropriate congressional committees and congressional leadership notice of the intent of the head to make such transfer.


(B) ExceptionThe head of an element of the intelligence community may make a transfer described in subparagraph (A) without prior congressional notification if the head determines that doing so—(i) is required to mitigate an urgent cou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic briefings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Periodic briefings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on spending</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on spending Funds authorized to be appropriated for the National Intelligence Program may not be obligated or expended for any controlled access program, or a compartment or subcompartment therein, until the head of the element of the intelligence community responsible for the establishment of such program, compartment, or subcompartment, submits the notification required by subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3091a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>