<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3096" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3096/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3096/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3096"><akn:num>3096</akn:num><akn:heading>Specificity of National Intelligence Program budget amounts for counterterrorism, counterproliferati</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3096. Specificity of National Intelligence Program budget amounts for counterterrorism, counterproliferation, counternarcotics, and counterintelligence(a) In generalThe budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the budget of the President for a fiscal year that is submitted to Congress under section 1105(a) of title 31 shall set forth separately the aggregate amount requested for that fiscal year for the National Intelligence Program for each of the following:(1) Counterterrorism.

(2) Counterproliferation.

(3) Counternarcotics.

(4) Counterintelligence.


(b) Election of classified or unclassified formAmounts set forth under subsection (a) may be set forth in unclassified form or classified form, at the election of the Director of National Intelligence.


(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title V, § 506, as added Pub. L. 107–306, title III, § 311(a), Nov. 27, 2002, 116 Stat. 2390; amended Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1074(b)(1)(A), Dec. 17, 2004, 118 Stat. 3694; Pub. L. 112–87, title V, § 505(2), Jan. 3, 2012, 125 Stat. 1897.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 415a of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments2012—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 112–87 substituted “Director of National Intelligence.” for “Director of Central Intelligence.”
2004—Pub. L. 108–458, § 1074(b)(1)(A)(ii), struck out “Foreign” before “Intelligence” in section catchline.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 108–458, § 1074(b)(1)(A)(i), substituted “National Intelligence Program” for “National Foreign Intelligence Program”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2004 AmendmentFor Determination by President that amendment by Pub. L. 108–458 take effect on Apr. 21, 2005, see Memorandum of President of the United States, Apr. 21, 2005, 70 F.R. 23925, set out as a note under section 3001 of this title.
Amendment by Pub. L. 108–458 effective not later than six months after Dec. 17, 2004, except as </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3096_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the budget of the President for a fiscal year that is submitted to Congress under section 1105(a) of title 31 shall set forth separately the aggregate amount requested for that fiscal year for the National Intelligence Program for each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3096_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of classified or unclassified form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Election of classified or unclassified form Amounts set forth under subsection (a) may be set forth in unclassified form or classified form, at the election of the Director of National Intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>