<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3097" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3097/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3097/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3097"><akn:num>3097</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget treatment of costs of acquisition of major systems by the intelligence community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3097. Budget treatment of costs of acquisition of major systems by the intelligence community(a) Independent cost estimates(1) The Director of National Intelligence shall, in consultation with the head of each element of the intelligence community concerned, prepare an independent cost estimate of the full life-cycle cost of development, procurement, and operation of each major system to be acquired by the intelligence community.

(2)(A) Each independent cost estimate for a major system shall, to the maximum extent practicable, specify the amount required to be appropriated and obligated to develop, procure, and operate the major system in each fiscal year of the proposed period of development, procurement, and operation of the major system.

(B) For major system acquisitions requiring a service or capability from another acquisition or program to deliver the end-to-end functionality for the intelligence community end users, independent cost estimates shall include, to the maximum extent practicable, all estimated costs across all pertinent elements of the intelligence community. For collection programs, such cost estimates shall include the cost of new analyst training, new hardware and software for data exploitation and analysis, and any unique or additional costs for data processing, storing, and power, space, and cooling across the life cycle of the program. If such costs for processing, exploitation, dissemination, and storage are scheduled to be executed in other elements of the intelligence community, the independent cost estimate shall identify and annotate such costs for such other elements accordingly.


(3)(A) In the case of a program of the intelligence community that qualifies as a major system, an independent cost estimate shall be prepared before the submission to Congress of the budget of the President for the first fiscal year in which appropriated funds are anticipated to be obligated for the development or procurement of such major system.

(B) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3097_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent cost estimates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Independent cost estimates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3097_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation of independent cost estimates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preparation of independent cost estimates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3097_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization in budgets of President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Utilization in budgets of President</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3097_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of estimates in budget justification materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inclusion of estimates in budget justification materials The budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the budget of the President shall include the most current independent cost estimate under this section for each major system for which appropriations are requested in such budget for any fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3097_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>