<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3100" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3100/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3100/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3100"><akn:num>3100</akn:num><akn:heading>Intelligence community business system transformation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3100. Intelligence community business system transformation(a) Limitation on obligation of funds(1) Subject to paragraph (3), no funds appropriated to any element of the intelligence community may be obligated for an intelligence community business system transformation that will have a total cost in excess of $3,000,000 unless—(A) the Director of the Office of Business Transformation of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence makes a certification described in paragraph (2) with respect to such intelligence community business system transformation; and

(B) such certification is approved by the board established under subsection (f).


(2) The certification described in this paragraph for an intelligence community business system transformation is a certification made by the Director of the Office of Business Transformation of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence that the intelligence community business system transformation—(A) complies with the enterprise architecture under subsection (b) and such other policies and standards that the Director of National Intelligence considers appropriate; or

(B) is necessary—(i) to achieve a critical national security capability or address a critical requirement; or

(ii) to prevent a significant adverse effect on a project that is needed to achieve an essential capability, taking into consideration any alternative solutions for preventing such adverse effect.



(3) With respect to a fiscal year after fiscal year 2010, the amount referred to in paragraph (1) in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) shall be equal to the sum of—(A) the amount in effect under such paragraph (1) for the preceding fiscal year (determined after application of this paragraph), plus

(B) such amount multiplied by the annual percentage increase in the consumer price index (all items; U.S. city average) as of September of the previous fiscal year.



(b) Enterprise architecture for intelligence community business systems(1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on obligation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitation on obligation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enterprise architecture for intelligence community business systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enterprise architecture for intelligence community business systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities for intelligence community business system transformation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities for intelligence community business system transformation The Director of National Intelligence shall be responsible for the entire life cycle of an intelligence community business system transformation, including review, approval, and oversight of the planning, design, acquisition, deployment, operation, and maintenance of the business system transformation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intelligence community business system investment review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Intelligence community business system investment review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 112–277, title III, § 310(a)(3), Jan. 14, 2013, 126 Stat. 2475</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intelligence community business system transformation governance board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Intelligence community business system transformation governance board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to annual registration requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Relation to annual registration requirements Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter the requirements of section 8083 of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2005 (Public Law 108–287; 118 Stat. 989), with regard to information technology systems (as defined in subsection (d) of such section).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to defense business enterprise architecture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Relationship to defense business enterprise architecture Nothing in this section shall be construed to exempt funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense from the requirements of section 2222 of title 10 to the extent that such requirements are otherwise applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to Clinger-Cohen Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Relation to Clinger-Cohen Act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3100_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reports Not later than March 31 of each of the years 2011 through 2014, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on the compliance of the intelligence community with the requirements of this section. Each such report shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>