<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3106"><akn:num>3106</akn:num><akn:heading>Dates for submittal of various annual and semiannual reports to the congressional intelligence commi</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3106. Dates for submittal of various annual and semiannual reports to the congressional intelligence committees(a) Annual reportsThe date for the submittal to the congressional intelligence committees of the following annual reports shall be the date each year provided in subsection (c)(1):(1) The annual report of the Inspectors General of the intelligence community on proposed resources and activities of their offices required by section 416(h) of title 5.

(2) The annual report on certifications for immunity in interdiction of aircraft engaged in illicit drug trafficking required by section 2291–4(c)(2) of title 22.

(3) The annual report on activities under the David L. Boren National Security Education Act of 1991 (title VIII of Public Law 102–183; 50 U.S.C. 1901 et seq.) required by section 806(a) of that Act (50 U.S.C. 1906(a)).

(4) The annual report on hiring and retention of minority employees in the intelligence community required by section 3050(a) of this title.

(5) The annual report on financial intelligence on terrorist assets required by section 3055 of this title.

(6) An annual report submitted under section 3059(d)(1) of this title.


(b) Semiannual reportsThe dates for the submittal to the congressional intelligence committees of the following semiannual reports shall be the dates each year provided in subsection (c)(2):(1) The semiannual reports on decisions not to prosecute certain violations of law under the Classified Information Procedures Act (18 U.S.C. App.) as required by section 13 of that Act.

(2) The semiannual reports on the disclosure of information and consumer reports to the Federal Bureau of Investigation for counterintelligence purposes required by section 1681u(h)(2) of title 15.11 See References in Text note below.

(3) The semiannual provision of information on requests for financial information for foreign counterintelligence purposes required by section 3414(a)(5)(C) of title 12.


(c) Submittal dates for reports(1) Excep</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual reports The date for the submittal to the congressional intelligence committees of the following annual reports shall be the date each year provided in subsection (c)(1):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Semiannual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Semiannual reports The dates for the submittal to the congressional intelligence committees of the following semiannual reports shall be the dates each year provided in subsection (c)(2):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submittal dates for reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submittal dates for reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Postponement of submittal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Postponement of submittal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>