<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3126" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3126/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3126/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3126"><akn:num>3126</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3126. Definitions
For the purposes of this subchapter:(1) The term “classified information” means information or material designated and clearly marked or clearly represented, pursuant to the provisions of a statute or Executive order (or a regulation or order issued pursuant to a statute or Executive order), as requiring a specific degree of protection against unauthorized disclosure for reasons of national security.

(2) The term “authorized”, when used with respect to access to classified information, means having authority, right, or permission pursuant to the provisions of a statute, Executive order, directive of the head of any department or agency engaged in foreign intelligence or counterintelligence activities, order of any United States court, or provisions of any Rule of the House of Representatives or resolution of the Senate which assigns responsibility within the respective House of Congress for the oversight of intelligence activities.

(3) The term “disclose” means to communicate, provide, impart, transmit, transfer, convey, publish, or otherwise make available.

(4) The term “covert agent” means—(A) a present or retired officer or employee of an intelligence agency or a present or retired member of the Armed Forces assigned to duty with an intelligence agency whose identity as such an officer, employee, or member is classified information; or

(B) a United States citizen whose intelligence relationship to the United States is classified information, and—(i) who acts as an agent of, or informant or source of operational assistance to, an intelligence agency, or

(ii) who is at the time of the disclosure acting as an agent of, or informant to, the foreign counterintelligence or foreign counterterrorism components of the Federal Bureau of Investigation; or


(C) an individual, other than a United States citizen, whose past or present intelligence relationship to the United States is classified information and who is a present or former agent of, or a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “classified information” means information or material designated and clearly marked or clearly represented, pursuant to the provisions of a statute or Executive order (or a regulation or order issued pursuant to a statute or Executive order), as requiring a specific degree of protection against unauthorized disclosure for reasons of national security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “authorized”, when used with respect to access to classified information, means having authority, right, or permission pursuant to the provisions of a statute, Executive order, directive of the head of any department or agency engaged in foreign intelligence or counterintelligence activities, order of any United States court, or provisions of any Rule of the House of Representatives or resolution of the Senate which assigns responsibility within the respective House of Congress for the oversight of intelligence activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “disclose” means to communicate, provide, impart, transmit, transfer, convey, publish, or otherwise make available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “covert agent” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “intelligence agency” means the elements of the intelligence community, as that term is defined in section 3003(4) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “informant” means any individual who furnishes information to an intelligence agency in the course of a confidential relationship protecting the identity of such individual from public disclosure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The terms “officer” and “employee” have the meanings given such terms by section 2104 and 2105, respectively, of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “Armed Forces” means the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “United States”, when used in a geographic sense, means all areas under the territorial sovereignty of the United States and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3126_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “pattern of activities” requires a series of acts with a common purpose or objective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>