<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3174" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3174/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3174/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3174"><akn:num>3174</akn:num><akn:heading>Laws subject to stay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3174. Laws subject to stay
The President may use the authority of sections 3171 and 3172 of this title to stay the imposition of an economic, cultural, diplomatic, or other sanction or related action by the United States Government related to the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, their delivery systems, or advanced conventional weapons otherwise required to be imposed by the Chemical and Biological Weapons Control and Warfare Elimination Act of 1991 (title III of Public Law 102–182) [22 U.S.C. 5601 et seq.]; the Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Act of 1994 (title VIII of Public Law 103–236); title XVII of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 (Public Law 101–510) (relating to the nonproliferation of missile technology); the Iran-Iraq Arms Nonproliferation Act of 1992 (title XVI of Public Law 102–484); section 573 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1994 (Public Law 103–87); section 563 of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing Related Programs Appropriations Act, 1995 (Public Law 103–306); and comparable provisions.
(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title IX, § 904, as added Pub. L. 104–93, title III, § 303(a), Jan. 6, 1996, 109 Stat. 965.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Chemical and Biological Weapons Control and Warfare Elimination Act of 1991, referred to in text, is title III of Pub. L. 102–182, Dec. 4, 1991, 105 Stat. 1245, which is classified principally to chapter 65 (§ 5601 et seq.) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 5601 of Title 22 and Tables.
The Nuclear Proliferation Prevention Act of 1994, referred to in text, is title VIII of Pub. L. 103–236, Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 507. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 6301 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, and Tables.
Title XVII of the National Defense</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>