<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3191" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3191/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3191/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3191"><akn:num>3191</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarships and work-study for pursuit of graduate degrees in science and technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3191. Scholarships and work-study for pursuit of graduate degrees in science and technology(a) Program authorizedThe Director of National Intelligence may carry out a program to provide scholarships and work-study for individuals who are pursuing graduate degrees in fields of study in science and technology that are identified by the Director as appropriate to meet the future needs of the intelligence community for qualified scientists and engineers.


(b) AdministrationIf the Director of National Intelligence carries out the program under subsection (a), the Director of National Intelligence shall administer the program through the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.


(c) Identification of fields of studyIf the Director of National Intelligence carries out the program under subsection (a), the Director shall identify fields of study under subsection (a) in consultation with the other heads of the elements of the intelligence community.


(d) Eligibility for participationAn individual eligible to participate in the program is any individual who—(1) either—(A) is an employee of the intelligence community; or

(B) meets criteria for eligibility for employment in the intelligence community that are established by the Director of National Intelligence;


(2) is accepted in a graduate degree program in a field of study in science or technology identified under subsection (a); and

(3) is eligible for a security clearance at the level of Secret or above.


(e) RegulationsIf the Director of National Intelligence carries out the program under subsection (a), the Director shall prescribe regulations for purposes of the administration of this section.


(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title X, § 1001, as added Pub. L. 107–306, title III, § 331(a)(3), Nov. 27, 2002, 116 Stat. 2394; amended Pub. L. 108–458, title I, §§ 1071(a)(1)(MM), (3)(C)–(F), 1072(a)(8), Dec. 17, 2004, 118 Stat. 3689, 3690, 3692.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to sec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3191_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized The Director of National Intelligence may carry out a program to provide scholarships and work-study for individuals who are pursuing graduate degrees in fields of study in science and technology that are identified by the Director as appropriate to meet the future needs of the intelligence community for qualified scientists and engineers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3191_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration If the Director of National Intelligence carries out the program under subsection (a), the Director of National Intelligence shall administer the program through the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3191_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of fields of study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Identification of fields of study If the Director of National Intelligence carries out the program under subsection (a), the Director shall identify fields of study under subsection (a) in consultation with the other heads of the elements of the intelligence community.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3191_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility for participation An individual eligible to participate in the program is any individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3191_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations If the Director of National Intelligence carries out the program under subsection (a), the Director shall prescribe regulations for purposes of the administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>