<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3224" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3224/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3224/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3224"><akn:num>3224</akn:num><akn:heading>Intelligence officer training program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3224. Intelligence officer training program(a) Programs(1) The Director of National Intelligence may carry out grant programs in accordance with subsections (b) and (c) to enhance the recruitment and retention of an ethnically and culturally diverse intelligence community workforce with capabilities critical to the national security interests of the United States.

(2) In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director shall identify the skills necessary to meet current or emergent needs of the intelligence community and the educational disciplines that will provide individuals with such skills.


(b) Institutional grant program(1) The Director may provide grants to institutions of higher education to support the establishment or continued development of programs of study in educational disciplines identified under subsection (a)(2).

(2) A grant provided under paragraph (1) may, with respect to the educational disciplines identified under subsection (a)(2), be used for the following purposes:(A) Curriculum or program development.

(B) Faculty development.

(C) Laboratory equipment or improvements.

(D) Faculty research.



(c) Grant program for certain minority-serving colleges and universities(1) The Director may provide grants to historically black colleges and universities, Predominantly Black Institutions, Hispanic-serving institutions, and Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions to provide programs of study in educational disciplines identified under subsection (a)(2) or described in paragraph (2).

(2) A grant provided under paragraph (1) may be used to provide programs of study in the following educational disciplines:(A) Intermediate and advanced foreign languages deemed in the immediate interest of the intelligence community, including Farsi, Pashto, Middle Eastern, African, and South Asian dialects.

(B) Study abroad programs and cultural immersion programs.



(d) ApplicationAn institution of higher education seeking a grant u</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3224_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3224_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institutional grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Institutional grant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3224_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program for certain minority-serving colleges and universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant program for certain minority-serving colleges and universities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3224_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application An institution of higher education seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application describing the proposed use of the grant at such time and in such manner as the Director may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3224_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports An institution of higher education that receives a grant under this section shall submit to the Director regular reports regarding the use of such grant, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3224_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Director shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3224_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>