<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3227d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3227d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3227d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3227d"><akn:num>3227d</akn:num><akn:heading>National Intelligence University acceptance of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3227d. National Intelligence University acceptance of grants(a) AuthorityThe Director of National Intelligence may authorize the President of the National Intelligence University to accept qualifying research grants.


(b) Qualifying grantsA qualifying research grant under this section is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity referred to in subsection (c) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.


(c) Entities from which grants may be acceptedA qualifying research grant may be accepted under this section only from a Federal agency or from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.


(d) Administration of grant funds(1) Establishment of accountThe Director shall establish an account for administering funds received as qualifying research grants under this section.


(2) Use of fundsThe President of the University shall use the funds in the account established pursuant to paragraph (1) in accordance with applicable provisions of the regulations and the terms and conditions of the grants received.



(e) Related expensesSubject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the National Intelligence University may be used to pay expenses incurred by the University in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, the award of qualifying research grants.


(f) RegulationsThe Director of National Intelligence shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.


(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title X, § 1035, as added Pub. L. 118–159, div. F, title LXIII, § 6305(a), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2474.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3227d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority The Director of National Intelligence may authorize the President of the National Intelligence University to accept qualifying research grants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3227d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualifying grants A qualifying research grant under this section is a grant that is awarded on a competitive basis by an entity referred to in subsection (c) for a research project with a scientific, literary, or educational purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3227d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entities from which grants may be accepted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Entities from which grants may be accepted A qualifying research grant may be accepted under this section only from a Federal agency or from a corporation, fund, foundation, educational institution, or similar entity that is organized and operated primarily for scientific, literary, or educational purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3227d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration of grant funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3227d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Related expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Related expenses Subject to such limitations as may be provided in appropriations Acts, appropriations available for the National Intelligence University may be used to pay expenses incurred by the University in applying for, and otherwise pursuing, the award of qualifying research grants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3227d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Director of National Intelligence shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>