<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3232" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3232/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3232/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3232"><akn:num>3232</akn:num><akn:heading>Counterintelligence initiatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3232. Counterintelligence initiatives(a) Inspection processIn order to protect intelligence sources and methods from unauthorized disclosure, the Director of National Intelligence shall establish and implement an inspection process for all agencies and departments of the United States that handle classified information relating to the national security of the United States intended to assure that those agencies and departments maintain effective operational security practices and programs directed against counterintelligence activities.


(b) Annual review of dissemination listsThe Director of National Intelligence shall establish and implement a process for all elements of the intelligence community to review, on an annual basis, individuals included on distribution lists for access to classified information. Such process shall ensure that only individuals who have a particularized “need to know” (as determined by the Director) are continued on such distribution lists.


(c) Completion of financial disclosure statements required for access to certain classified informationThe Director of National Intelligence shall establish and implement a process by which each head of an element of the intelligence community directs that all employees of that element, in order to be granted access to classified information referred to in subsection (a) of section 1.3 of Executive Order No. 12968 (August 2, 1995; 60 Fed. Reg. 40245; [former] 50 U.S.C. 435 note [now 50 U.S.C. 3161 note]), submit financial disclosure forms as required under subsection (b) of such section.


(d) Arrangements to handle sensitive informationThe Director of National Intelligence shall establish, for all elements of the intelligence community, programs and procedures by which sensitive classified information relating to human intelligence is safeguarded against unauthorized disclosure by employees of those elements.


(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title XI, § 1102, as added Pub. L. 108–177, title III, § 341</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3232_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Inspection process In order to protect intelligence sources and methods from unauthorized disclosure, the Director of National Intelligence shall establish and implement an inspection process for all agencies and departments of the United States that handle classified information relating to the national security of the United States intended to assure that those agencies and departments maintain effective operational security practices and programs directed against counterintelligence activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3232_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual review of dissemination lists</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual review of dissemination lists The Director of National Intelligence shall establish and implement a process for all elements of the intelligence community to review, on an annual basis, individuals included on distribution lists for access to classified information. Such process shall ensure that only individuals who have a particularized “need to know” (as determined by the Director) are continued on such distribution lists.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3232_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Completion of financial disclosure statements required for access to certain classified information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Completion of financial disclosure statements required for access to certain classified information The Director of National Intelligence shall establish and implement a process by which each head of an element of the intelligence community directs that all employees of that element, in order to be granted access to classified information referred to in subsection (a) of section 1.3 of Executive Order No. 12968 (August 2, 1995; 60 Fed. Reg. 40245; [former] 50 U.S.C. 435 note [now 50 U.S.C. 3161 note]), submit financial disclosure forms as required under subsection (b) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3232_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Arrangements to handle sensitive information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Arrangements to handle sensitive information The Director of National Intelligence shall establish, for all elements of the intelligence community, programs and procedures by which sensitive classified information relating to human intelligence is safeguarded against unauthorized disclosure by employees of those elements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>