<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3243" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3243/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3243/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3243"><akn:num>3243</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic reports on technology strategy of intelligence community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3243. Periodic reports on technology strategy of intelligence community(a) ReportsOn a basis that is not less frequent than once every 4 years, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of such other agencies as the Director considers appropriate, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a comprehensive report on the technology strategy of the intelligence community, which shall be designed to support the maintenance of the leadership of the United States in critical and emerging technologies essential to the national security of the United States.


(b) ElementsEach report submitted under subsection (a) shall include the following:(1) An assessment of technologies critical to the national security of the United States, particularly those technologies with respect to which foreign countries that are adversarial to the United States have or are poised to match or surpass the technology leadership of the United States.

(2) A review of current technology policies of the intelligence community, including long-term goals.

(3) An identification of sectors and supply chains the Director determines to be of the greatest strategic importance to national security.

(4) An identification of opportunities to protect the leadership of the United States, and the allies and partners of the United States, in critical technologies, including through targeted export controls, investment screening, and counterintelligence activities.

(5) An identification of research and development areas the Director determines critical to the national security of the United States, including areas in which the private sector does not focus.

(6) Recommendations for growing talent in key critical and emerging technologies and enhancing the ability of the intelligence community to recruit and retain individuals with critical skills relating to such technologies.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports On a basis that is not less frequent than once every 4 years, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of such other agencies as the Director considers appropriate, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a comprehensive report on the technology strategy of the intelligence community, which shall be designed to support the maintenance of the leadership of the United States in critical and emerging technologies essential to the national security of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Elements Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of annex</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Form of annex Each annex submitted under subsection (b)(8) may be submitted in classified form.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>