<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3244" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3244/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3244/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3244"><akn:num>3244</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report on reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3244. Annual report on reporting requirements(a) Annual report requiredNot later than March 1 of each fiscal year, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report detailing all congressionally mandated reporting requirements applicable to the Office of the Director of National Intelligence for the upcoming fiscal year.


(b) ContentsEach report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include, for the fiscal year covered by the report and for each congressionally mandated reporting requirement detailed in the report:(1) A description of the reporting requirement.

(2) A citation to the provision of law (or other source of congressional directive) imposing the reporting requirement.

(3) Whether the reporting requirement is recurring, conditional, or subject to a termination provision.

(4) Whether the Director recommends repealing or modifying the requirement.


(c) FormEach report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) may be submitted in classified form.


(July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title XI, § 1114, as added Pub. L. 118–31, div. G, title III, § 7314(a), Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 1031; amended Pub. L. 118–159, div. F, title LXIX, § 6902(a)(5), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2517.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2024—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 118–159 inserted “the” before “Office of the Director”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3244_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report required Not later than March 1 of each fiscal year, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report detailing all congressionally mandated reporting requirements applicable to the Office of the Director of National Intelligence for the upcoming fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3244_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents Each report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include, for the fiscal year covered by the report and for each congressionally mandated reporting requirement detailed in the report:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3244_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Form Each report submitted pursuant to subsection (a) may be submitted in classified form.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>