<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3310" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3310/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3310/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3310"><akn:num>3310</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report on United States security arrangements and commitments with other nations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3310. Annual report on United States security arrangements and commitments with other nations(a) Report requirementsThe President shall submit to the congressional committees specified in subsection (d) each year a report (in both classified and unclassified form) on United States security arrangements with, and commitments to, other nations.


(b) Matters to be includedThe President shall include in each such report the following:(1) A description of—(A) each security arrangement with, or commitment to, other nations, whether based upon (i) a formal document (including a mutual defense treaty, a pre-positioning arrangement or agreement, or an access agreement), or (ii) an expressed policy; and

(B) the historical origins of each such arrangement or commitment.


(2) An evaluation of the ability of the United States to meet its commitments based on the projected reductions in the defense structure of the United States.

(3) A plan for meeting each of those commitments with the force structure projected for the future.

(4) An assessment of the need to continue, modify, or discontinue each of those arrangements and commitments in view of the changing international security situation.


(c) Deadline for reportThe President shall submit the report required by subsection (a) not later than February 1 of each year.


(d) Specified congressional committeesThe congressional committees referred to in subsection (a) are the following:(1) The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.

(2) The Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives.


(Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1457, Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1696; Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1502(c)(4)(C), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 507; Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1067(10), Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 774.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 404c of this title prior to editorial</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3310_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Report requirements The President shall submit to the congressional committees specified in subsection (d) each year a report (in both classified and unclassified form) on United States security arrangements with, and commitments to, other nations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3310_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters to be included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Matters to be included The President shall include in each such report the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3310_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline for report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deadline for report The President shall submit the report required by subsection (a) not later than February 1 of each year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3310_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specified congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Specified congressional committees The congressional committees referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>