<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3316b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3316b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3316b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3316b"><akn:num>3316b</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuity of operations plans for certain elements of the intelligence community in the case of a n</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3316b. Continuity of operations plans for certain elements of the intelligence community in the case of a national emergency(a) Definition of covered national emergencyIn this section, the term “covered national emergency” means the following:(1) A major disaster declared by the President under section 5170 of title 42.

(2) An emergency declared by the President under section 5191 of title 42.

(3) A national emergency declared by the President under the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.).

(4) A public health emergency declared under section 247d of title 42.


(b) In generalThe Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Reconnaissance Office, the Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Security Agency, and the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall each establish continuity of operations plans for use in the case of covered national emergencies for the element of the intelligence community concerned.


(c) Submission to Congress(1) Director of National Intelligence and Director of the Central Intelligence AgencyNot later than 7 days after the date on which a covered national emergency is declared, the Director of National Intelligence and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall each submit to the congressional intelligence committees the plan established under subsection (b) for that emergency for the element of the intelligence community concerned.


(2) Director of National Reconnaissance Office, Director of Defense Intelligence Agency, Director of National Security Agency, and Director of National Geospatial-Intelligence AgencyNot later than 7 days after the date on which a covered national emergency is declared, the Director of the National Reconnaissance Office, the Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Security Agency, and the Director of the National Geospatial-Inte</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3316b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of covered national emergency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of covered national emergency In this section, the term “covered national emergency” means the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3316b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In general The Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Reconnaissance Office, the Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Security Agency, and the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall each establish continuity of operations plans for use in the case of covered national emergencies for the element of the intelligence community concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3316b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3316b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Updates During a covered national emergency, the Director of National Intelligence, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Reconnaissance Office, the Director of the Defense Intelligence Agency, the Director of the National Security Agency, and the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall each submit any updates to the plans submitted under subsection (c)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>