<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3325" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3325/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3325/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3325"><akn:num>3325</akn:num><akn:heading>Reaffirmation of longstanding prohibition against drug trafficking by employees of the intelligence </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3325. Reaffirmation of longstanding prohibition against drug trafficking by employees of the intelligence community(a) FindingCongress finds that longstanding statutes, regulations, and policies of the United States prohibit employees, agents, and assets of the elements of the intelligence community, and of every other Federal department and agency, from engaging in the illegal manufacture, purchase, sale, transport, and distribution of drugs.


(b) Obligation of employees of intelligence communityAny employee of the intelligence community having knowledge of a fact or circumstance that reasonably indicates that an employee, agent, or asset of an element of the intelligence community is involved in any activity that violates a statute, regulation, or policy described in subsection (a) shall report such knowledge to an appropriate official.


(c) Intelligence community definedIn this section, the term “intelligence community” has the meaning given that term in section 3003(4) of this title.


(Pub. L. 106–120, title III, § 313, Dec. 3, 1999, 113 Stat. 1615.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 403–8 of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3325_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Finding Congress finds that longstanding statutes, regulations, and policies of the United States prohibit employees, agents, and assets of the elements of the intelligence community, and of every other Federal department and agency, from engaging in the illegal manufacture, purchase, sale, transport, and distribution of drugs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3325_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation of employees of intelligence community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Obligation of employees of intelligence community Any employee of the intelligence community having knowledge of a fact or circumstance that reasonably indicates that an employee, agent, or asset of an element of the intelligence community is involved in any activity that violates a statute, regulation, or policy described in subsection (a) shall report such knowledge to an appropriate official.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3325_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intelligence community defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Intelligence community defined In this section, the term “intelligence community” has the meaning given that term in section 3003(4) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>