<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3334k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3334k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3334k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3334k"><akn:num>3334k</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on protocols for certain intelligence community employees and dependents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3334k. Report on protocols for certain intelligence community employees and dependents(a) In generalBeginning not later than 180 days after March 15, 2022, the President shall develop, for uniform implementation across the elements of the intelligence community, each of the protocols described in subsections (c) through (f). Such protocols shall be subject to review and revision on a periodic basis, and any implementation of such protocols shall be conducted in accordance with applicable laws and current clinical and professional practices of the interagency medical community.


(b) PrivacyNo data collected pursuant to any protocol under this section may be used for research or analytical purposes without the written consent of the individual from whom such data was collected with respect to such use.


(c) Protocol on baseline medical testingThe protocol described in this subsection is a protocol for conducting voluntary baseline medical testing of covered employees, covered individuals, and the dependents of covered employees who are included on the overseas travel orders of the covered employee. Such protocol shall set forth the required elements of such baseline medical testing, such as—(1) standard lab collection and testing of relevant biofluids;

(2) the conduct of relevant visual and auditory examinations;

(3) the conduct of Acquired Brain Injury Tool assessments, or other relevant assessments for balance, eye motion, and cognition;

(4) the assessment of relevant medical histories; and

(5) the conduct of any other standard relevant medical or neurological examinations, testing, or assessments.


(d) Protocols on post-incident medical testingThe protocols described in this subsection are protocols to enable voluntary medical testing and the coordination of treatment for covered employees, covered individuals, and the dependents of covered employees, following a reported anomalous health incident, such as—(1) a protocol that sets forth elements, similar t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Beginning not later than 180 days after March 15, 2022, the President shall develop, for uniform implementation across the elements of the intelligence community, each of the protocols described in subsections (c) through (f). Such protocols shall be subject to review and revision on a periodic basis, and any implementation of such protocols shall be conducted in accordance with applicable laws and current clinical and professional practices of the interagency medical community.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Privacy No data collected pursuant to any protocol under this section may be used for research or analytical purposes without the written consent of the individual from whom such data was collected with respect to such use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protocol on baseline medical testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Protocol on baseline medical testing The protocol described in this subsection is a protocol for conducting voluntary baseline medical testing of covered employees, covered individuals, and the dependents of covered employees who are included on the overseas travel orders of the covered employee. Such protocol shall set forth the required elements of such baseline medical testing, such as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protocols on post-incident medical testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Protocols on post-incident medical testing The protocols described in this subsection are protocols to enable voluntary medical testing and the coordination of treatment for covered employees, covered individuals, and the dependents of covered employees, following a reported anomalous health incident, such as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334k_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protocol on information collection, storage, and safeguarding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Protocol on information collection, storage, and safeguarding The protocol described in this subsection is a protocol for the collection, storage, and safeguarding of information acquired as a result of the protocols described in subsections (c) and (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334k_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protocol on reporting mechanisms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Protocol on reporting mechanisms The protocol described in this subsection is a protocol for the reporting of matters relating to anomalous health incidents by covered employees, covered individuals, and the dependents of covered employees, including the development of a system for the adjudication of complaints regarding medical treatment received by such covered employees, covered individuals, and dependents of covered employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334k_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report and briefings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report and briefings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334k_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>