<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3334p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3334p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3334p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3334p"><akn:num>3334p</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased intelligence-related engineering, research, and development capabilities of minority insti</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3334p. Increased intelligence-related engineering, research, and development capabilities of minority institutions(a) Plan(1) RequirementThe Director of National Intelligence shall develop a plan to promote intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities at covered institutions for the purpose of contributing toward the research necessary to achieve the intelligence advantage of the United States.


(2) ElementsThe plan under paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) An assessment of opportunities to support engineering, research, and development at covered institutions in computer sciences, including artificial intelligence, quantum computing, and machine learning, and synthetic biology and an assessment of opportunities to support the associated workforce and physical research infrastructure of such institutions.

(B) An assessment of opportunities to enhance the ability of covered institutions—(i) to participate in intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities; and

(ii) to effectively compete for intelligence-related engineering, research and development contracts in support of the most urgent research requirements of the intelligence community.


(C) An assessment of the activities and investments the Director determines necessary—(i) to expand opportunities for covered institutions to partner with other research organizations and educational institutions that the intelligence community frequently partners with to conduct research; and

(ii) to increase participation of covered institutions in intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities.


(D) Recommendations identifying actions that may be taken by the Director, Congress, covered institutions, and other organizations to increase participation of such institutions in intelligence-related engineering, research, and development activities and contracts.

(E) Specific goals, incentives, and metrics to increase and measure the capacity</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334p_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334p_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities to support research and engineering capacity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities to support research and engineering capacity Subject to the availability of appropriations for such purpose, the Director may establish a program to award contracts, grants, or other agreements, on a competitive basis, and to perform other appropriate activities, for any of the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334p_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased partnerships between IARPA and covered institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Increased partnerships between IARPA and covered institutions The Director shall establish goals and incentives to encourage the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activity to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334p_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered institution defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Covered institution defined In this section, the term “covered institution” means the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>