<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3334e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3334e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3334e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3334e"><akn:num>3334e</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced procurement authority to manage supply chain risk</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3334e. Enhanced procurement authority to manage supply chain risk(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Covered agencyThe term “covered agency” means any element of the intelligence community other than an element within the Department of Defense.


(2) Covered item of supplyThe term “covered item of supply” means an item of information technology (as that term is defined in section 11101 of title 40) that is purchased for inclusion in a covered system, and the loss of integrity of which could result in a supply chain risk for a covered system.


(3) Covered procurementThe term “covered procurement” means—(A) a source selection for a covered system or a covered item of supply involving either a performance specification, as provided in section 3306(a)(3)(B) of title 41, or an evaluation factor, as provided in section 3306(b)(1) of such title, relating to supply chain risk;

(B) the consideration of proposals for and issuance of a task or delivery order for a covered system or a covered item of supply, as provided in section 4106(d)(3) of title 41, where the task or delivery order contract concerned includes a contract clause establishing a requirement relating to supply chain risk; or

(C) any contract action involving a contract for a covered system or a covered item of supply where such contract includes a clause establishing requirements relating to supply chain risk.


(4) Covered procurement actionThe term “covered procurement action” means any of the following actions, if the action takes place in the course of conducting a covered procurement:(A) The exclusion of a source that fails to meet qualifications standards established in accordance with the requirements of section 3311 of title 41 for the purpose of reducing supply chain risk in the acquisition of covered systems.

(B) The exclusion of a source that fails to achieve an acceptable rating with regard to an evaluation factor providing for the consideration of supply chain risk in the evaluation of proposa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority Subject to subsection (c) and in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, the head of a covered agency may, in conducting intelligence and intelligence-related activities—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination and notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination and notification The head of a covered agency may exercise the authority provided in subsection (b) only after—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Delegation The head of a covered agency may not delegate the authority provided in subsection (b) or the responsibility to make a determination under subsection (c) to an official below the level of the service acquisition executive for the agency concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Savings The authority under this section is in addition to any other authority under any other provision of law. The authority under this section shall not be construed to alter or effect the exercise of any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3334e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective date The requirements of this section shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after January 3, 2012, and shall apply to contracts that are awarded on or after such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>