<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3343" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3343/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3343/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3343"><akn:num>3343</akn:num><akn:heading>Security clearances; limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3343. Security clearances; limitations(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Controlled substanceThe term “controlled substance” has the meaning given that term in section 802 of title 21.


(2) Covered personThe term “covered person” means—(A) an officer or employee of a Federal agency;

(B) a member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps who is on active duty or is in an active status; and

(C) an officer or employee of a contractor of a Federal agency.


(3) Restricted DataThe term “Restricted Data” has the meaning given that term in section 2014 of title 42.


(4) Special access programThe term “special access program” has the meaning given that term in section 4.1 of Executive Order No. 12958 (60 Fed. Reg. 19825).



(b) ProhibitionAfter January 1, 2008, the head of a Federal agency may not grant or renew a security clearance for a covered person who is an unlawful user of a controlled substance or an addict (as defined in section 802(1) of title 21).


(c) Disqualification(1) In generalAfter January 1, 2008, absent an express written waiver granted in accordance with paragraph (2), the head of a Federal agency may not grant or renew a security clearance described in paragraph (3) for a covered person who—(A) has been convicted in any court of the United States of a crime, was sentenced to imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year, and was incarcerated as a result of that sentence for not less than 1 year;

(B) has been discharged or dismissed from the Armed Forces under dishonorable conditions; or

(C) is mentally incompetent, as determined by an adjudicating authority, based on an evaluation by a duly qualified mental health professional employed by, or acceptable to and approved by, the United States Government and in accordance with the adjudicative guidelines required by subsection (d).


(2) Waiver authorityIn a meritorious case, an exception to the disqualification in this subsection may be authorized if there are mitigating factors. Any such waiver </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3343_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3343_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition After January 1, 2008, the head of a Federal agency may not grant or renew a security clearance for a covered person who is an unlawful user of a controlled substance or an addict (as defined in section 802(1) of title 21).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3343_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disqualification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disqualification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3343_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjudicative guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adjudicative guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>