<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3345" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3345/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3345/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3345"><akn:num>3345</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on handling, retention, and storage of certain classified materials by the Department of </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3345. Limitation on handling, retention, and storage of certain classified materials by the Department of State(a) Certification regarding full compliance with requirementsThe Director of Central Intelligence shall certify to the appropriate committees of Congress whether or not each covered element of the Department of State is in full compliance with all applicable directives of the Director of Central Intelligence relating to the handling, retention, or storage of covered classified material.


(b) Limitation on certificationThe Director of Central Intelligence may not certify a covered element of the Department of State as being in full compliance with the directives referred to in subsection (a) if the covered element is currently subject to a waiver of compliance with respect to any such directive.


(c) Report on noncomplianceWhenever the Director of Central Intelligence determines that a covered element of the Department of State is not in full compliance with any directive referred to in subsection (a), the Director shall promptly notify the appropriate committees of Congress of such determination.


(d) Effects of certification of non-full compliance(1) Subject to subsection (e), effective as of January 1, 2001, a covered element of the Department of State may not retain or store covered classified material unless the Director has certified under subsection (a) as of such date that the covered element is in full compliance with the directives referred to in subsection (a).

(2) If the prohibition in paragraph (1) takes effect in accordance with that paragraph, the prohibition shall remain in effect until the date on which the Director certifies under subsection (a) that the covered element involved is in full compliance with the directives referred to in that subsection.


(e) Waiver by Director of Central Intelligence(1) The Director of Central Intelligence may waive the applicability of the prohibition in subsection (d) to an element of the Department </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification regarding full compliance with requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Certification regarding full compliance with requirements The Director of Central Intelligence shall certify to the appropriate committees of Congress whether or not each covered element of the Department of State is in full compliance with all applicable directives of the Director of Central Intelligence relating to the handling, retention, or storage of covered classified material.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on certification The Director of Central Intelligence may not certify a covered element of the Department of State as being in full compliance with the directives referred to in subsection (a) if the covered element is currently subject to a waiver of compliance with respect to any such directive.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on noncompliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report on noncompliance Whenever the Director of Central Intelligence determines that a covered element of the Department of State is not in full compliance with any directive referred to in subsection (a), the Director shall promptly notify the appropriate committees of Congress of such determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effects of certification of non-full compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effects of certification of non-full compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver by Director of Central Intelligence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Waiver by Director of Central Intelligence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>