<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3352g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3352g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3352g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3352g"><akn:num>3352g</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to authorize additional security clearances for certain contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3352g. Requirement to authorize additional security clearances for certain contractors(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Appropriate committees of CongressThe term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—(A) the congressional intelligence committees;

(B) the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and

(C) the Subcommittee on Defense of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.


(2) Covered contract or agreementThe term “covered contract or agreement”, with respect to an entity, means a contract or other agreement between that entity and an element of the intelligence community the performance of which requires a specified number of covered persons to hold a security clearance.


(3) Covered personThe term “covered person”, with respect to an entity, means a contractor or employee of that entity.



(b) Plan and study(1) In generalNo later than April 1, 2024, the Director of National Intelligence shall—(A) complete a study on the feasibility and advisability of implementing a program to authorize additional security clearances for certain contractors as described in subsection (c);

(B) develop a plan to implement the program described in subparagraph (A); and

(C) submit to the appropriate committees of Congress—(i) a report on the findings of the Director with respect to the study completed pursuant to subparagraph (A); and

(ii) the plan developed pursuant to subparagraph (B).



(2) Study elementsThe study completed pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) shall address the following:(A) For contracts agreed to after December 22, 2023, how private entities that contract with the intelligence community would make payments for additional clearances for their employees and how the intelligence community would receive payments.

(B) A list of and changes to provisions of law required in order to fully implement the program required by subsection (c) and achieve the intent indicated in subparagraph (A) of this parag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan and study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Plan and study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program to authorize additional security clearances for certain contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program to authorize additional security clearances for certain contractors Subject to the limitations described in subsection (d), the Director shall establish a program under which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations The limitations described in this subsection are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construed as requiring the head of an element of the intelligence community to grant any covered person access to classified information if a favorable determination of eligibility to access such classified information is not made with respect to such person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>