<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3352f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3352f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3352f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3352f"><akn:num>3352f</akn:num><akn:heading>Information-sharing program for positions of trust and security clearances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3352f. Information-sharing program for positions of trust and security clearances(a) Program required(1) In generalNot later than 90 days after December 20, 2019, the Security Executive Agent and the Suitability and Credentialing Executive Agent shall establish and implement a program to share between and among agencies of the Federal Government and industry partners of the Federal Government relevant background information regarding individuals applying for and currently occupying national security positions and positions of trust, in order to ensure the Federal Government maintains a trusted workforce.


(2) DesignationThe program established under paragraph (1) shall be known as the “Trusted Information Provider Program” (in this section referred to as the “Program”).



(b) Privacy safeguardsThe Security Executive Agent and the Suitability and Credentialing Executive Agent shall ensure that the Program includes such safeguards for privacy as the Security Executive Agent and the Suitability and Credentialing Executive Agent consider appropriate.


(c) Provision of information to the Federal GovernmentThe Program shall include requirements that enable investigative service providers and agencies of the Federal Government to leverage certain pre-employment information gathered through private-sector means during the employment or military recruiting process, and other relevant security or human resources information obtained during employment with or for the Federal Government, that satisfy Federal investigative standards, while safeguarding personnel privacy.


(d) Information and recordsThe information and records considered under the Program shall include the following:(1) Date and place of birth.

(2) Citizenship or immigration and naturalization information.

(3) Education records.

(4) Employment records.

(5) Employment or social references.

(6) Military service records.

(7) State and local law enforcement checks.

(8) Criminal history checks.

(9) Finan</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy safeguards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Privacy safeguards The Security Executive Agent and the Suitability and Credentialing Executive Agent shall ensure that the Program includes such safeguards for privacy as the Security Executive Agent and the Suitability and Credentialing Executive Agent consider appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of information to the Federal Government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provision of information to the Federal Government The Program shall include requirements that enable investigative service providers and agencies of the Federal Government to leverage certain pre-employment information gathered through private-sector means during the employment or military recruiting process, and other relevant security or human resources information obtained during employment with or for the Federal Government, that satisfy Federal investigative standards, while safeguarding personnel privacy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information and records The information and records considered under the Program shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Implementation plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan for pilot program on two-way information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Plan for pilot program on two-way information sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3352f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Review Not later than 1 year after December 20, 2019, the Security Executive Agent and the Suitability and Credentialing Executive Agent shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees and make available to appropriate industry partners a review of the plans submitted under subsections (e)(1) and (f)(1) and utility and effectiveness of the programs described in such plans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>