<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3352e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3352e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3352e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3352e"><akn:num>3352e</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic report on positions in the intelligence community that can be conducted without access to c</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3352e. Periodic report on positions in the intelligence community that can be conducted without access to classified information, networks, or facilities
Not later than 180 days after December 20, 2019, and biennially thereafter, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report that reviews the intelligence community for which positions can be conducted without access to classified information, networks, or facilities, or may only require a security clearance at the secret level. Such report shall take into account the potential effect of maintaining continuity of operations during a covered national emergency (as defined by section 3316b of this title) and the assessed needs of the intelligence community to maintain such continuity of operations.
(Pub. L. 116–92, div. E, title LXVI, § 6610, Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 2218; Pub. L. 117–103, div. X, title VIII, § 801, Mar. 15, 2022, 136 Stat. 1011.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2022—Pub. L. 117–103 substituted “December 20, 2019, and biennially thereafter,” for “December 20, 2019, and not less frequently than once every 5 years thereafter,” and inserted at end “Such report shall take into account the potential effect of maintaining continuity of operations during a covered national emergency (as defined by section 3316b of this title) and the assessed needs of the intelligence community to maintain such continuity of operations.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Definitions
For definitions of “congressional intelligence committees” and “intelligence community”, referred to in text, see section 5003 of div. E of Pub. L. 116–92, set out as a note under section 3003 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>