<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3355b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3355b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3355b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3355b"><akn:num>3355b</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification, collection, and review for declassification of information of archival value or extr</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3355b. Identification, collection, and review for declassification of information of archival value or extraordinary public interest(a) Briefings on agency declassification programs(1) As requested by the Board, or by the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate or the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, the head of any agency with the authority under an Executive order to classify information shall provide to the Board, the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, or the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, on an annual basis, a summary briefing and report on such agency’s progress and plans in the declassification of national security information. Such briefing shall cover the declassification goals set by statute, regulation, or policy, the agency’s progress with respect to such goals, and the agency’s planned goals and priorities for its declassification activities over the next 2 fiscal years. Agency briefings and reports shall give particular attention to progress on the declassification of records and materials that are of archival value or extraordinary public interest to the people of the United States.

(2)(A) The annual briefing and report under paragraph (1) for agencies within the Department of Defense, including the military departments and the elements of the intelligence community, shall be provided on a consolidated basis.

(B) In this paragraph, the term “elements of the intelligence community” means the elements of the intelligence community specified or designated under section 3003(4) of this title.



(b) Recommendations on agency declassification programs(1) Upon reviewing and discussing declassification plans and progress with an agency, the Board shall provide to the head of the agency the written recommendations of the Board as to how the agency’s declassification program could be improved. A copy of each recommendation shall also be submitted to t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Briefings on agency declassification programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Briefings on agency declassification programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations on agency declassification programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recommendations on agency declassification programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations on special searches for records of extraordinary public interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recommendations on special searches for records of extraordinary public interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>President’s declassification priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) President’s declassification priorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declassification reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Declassification reviews</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>