<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3355a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3355a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3355a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3355a"><akn:num>3355a</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Interest Declassification Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3355a. Public Interest Declassification Board(a) Establishment(1) There is established within the executive branch of the United States a board to be known as the “Public Interest Declassification Board” (in this subchapter referred to as the “Board”).

(2) The Board shall report directly to the President or, upon designation by the President, the Vice President, the Attorney General, or other designee of the President. The other designee of the President under this paragraph may not be an agency head or official authorized to classify information under Executive Order 13526, or any successor order.


(b) PurposesThe purposes of the Board are as follows:(1) To advise the President, the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and such other executive branch officials as the Board considers appropriate on the systematic, thorough, coordinated, and comprehensive identification, collection, review for declassification, and release to Congress, interested agencies, and the public of declassified records and materials (including donated historical materials) that are of archival value, including records and materials of extraordinary public interest.

(2) To promote the fullest possible public access to a thorough, accurate, and reliable documentary record of significant United States national security decisions and significant United States national security activities in order to—(A) support the oversight and legislative functions of Congress;

(B) support the policymaking role of the executive branch;

(C) respond to the interest of the public in national security matters; and

(D) promote reliable historical analysis and new avenues of historical study in national security matters.


(3) To provide recommendations to the President for the identification, collection, and review for declassification of information of extraordinary public interest that does not undermine the national security of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purposes The purposes of the Board are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson; Executive Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chairperson; Executive Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Meetings The Board shall meet as needed to accomplish its mission, consistent with the availability of funds, but shall meet in person not less frequently than on a quarterly basis. A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Security</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance; annual budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Guidance; annual budget</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3355a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Support The Information Security Oversight Office may support the activities of the Board under this subchapter. Such support shall be provided on a reimbursable basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>