<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3371" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3371/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3371/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3371"><akn:num>3371</akn:num><akn:heading>Required counterintelligence assessments, briefings, notifications, and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3371. Required counterintelligence assessments, briefings, notifications, and reports(a) Foreign counterintelligence and cybersecurity threats to Federal election campaigns(1) Reports required(A) In generalAs provided in subparagraph (B), with respect to an election for Federal office, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Under Secretary of Homeland Security for Intelligence and Analysis and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall make publicly available on an internet website an advisory report on foreign counterintelligence and cybersecurity threats to campaigns of candidates for Federal office. Each such report, consistent with the protection of sources and methods, shall include the following:(i) A description of foreign counterintelligence and cybersecurity threats to campaigns of candidates for Federal office.

(ii) A summary of best practices that campaigns of candidates for Federal office can employ in seeking to counter such threats.

(iii) An identification of publicly available resources, including United States Government resources, for countering such threats.


(B) Schedule for submittal(i) In generalExcept as provided by clause (ii), with respect to an election for Federal office, a report under this subsection shall be first made available not later than the date that is 1 year before the date of such election, and may be subsequently revised as the Director of National Intelligence determines appropriate.


(ii) 2020 electionsWith respect to an election for Federal office that occurs during 2020, the report under this subsection shall be first made available not later than the date that is 60 days after December 20, 2020, and may be subsequently revised as the Director of National Intelligence determines appropriate.



(C) Information to be includedA report under this subsection shall reflect the most current information available to the Director of National Intelligence regarding foreign counterintel</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3371_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign counterintelligence and cybersecurity threats to Federal election campaigns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Foreign counterintelligence and cybersecurity threats to Federal election campaigns</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3371_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3371_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of National Intelligence assessment of foreign interference in Federal elections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Director of National Intelligence assessment of foreign interference in Federal elections</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>