<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3381" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3381/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3381/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3381"><akn:num>3381</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of counterintelligence activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3381. Coordination of counterintelligence activities(a) Establishment of Counterintelligence Policy BoardThere is established within the executive branch of Government a National Counterintelligence Policy Board (in this section referred to as the “Board”). The Board shall report to the President through the National Security Council.


(b) ChairpersonThe Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center appointed under section 902 of the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002 (50 U.S.C. 3382) shall serve as the chairperson of the Board.


(c) MembershipThe membership of the National Counterintelligence Policy Board shall consist of the following:(1) The Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center.

(2) Senior personnel of departments and elements of the United States Government, appointed by the head of the department or element concerned, as follows:(A) The Department of Justice, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation.

(B) The Department of Defense, including the Joint Chiefs of Staff.

(C) The Department of State.

(D) The Department of Energy.

(E) The Central Intelligence Agency.

(F) Any other department, agency, or element of the United States Government specified by the President.



(d) Functions and discharge of functions(1) The Board shall—(A) serve as the principal mechanism for—(i) developing policies and procedures for the approval of the President to govern the conduct of counterintelligence activities; and

(ii) upon the direction of the President, resolving conflicts that arise between elements of the Government conducting such activities; and


(B) act as an interagency working group to—(i) ensure the discussion and review of matters relating to the implementation of the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002; and

(ii) provide advice to the Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center on priorities in the implementation of the National Counterintelligence Strategy produced</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3381_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Counterintelligence Policy Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Counterintelligence Policy Board There is established within the executive branch of Government a National Counterintelligence Policy Board (in this section referred to as the “Board”). The Board shall report to the President through the National Security Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3381_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Chairperson The Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center appointed under section 902 of the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002 (50 U.S.C. 3382) shall serve as the chairperson of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3381_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership The membership of the National Counterintelligence Policy Board shall consist of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3381_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions and discharge of functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Functions and discharge of functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3381_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of counterintelligence matters with Federal Bureau of Investigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination of counterintelligence matters with Federal Bureau of Investigation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>