<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3383" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3383/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3383/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3383"><akn:num>3383</akn:num><akn:heading>National Counterintelligence and Security Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3383. National Counterintelligence and Security Center(a) EstablishmentThere shall be a National Counterintelligence and Security Center.


(b) Head of CenterThe Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall be the head of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center.


(c) Location of CenterThe National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall be located in the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.


(d) MissionThe mission of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall include organizing and leading strategic planning for counterintelligence activities of the United States Government by integrating instruments of national power as needed to counter foreign intelligence activities.


(e) FunctionsSubject to the direction and control of the Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center, the functions of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall be as follows:(1) National threat identification and prioritization assessmentSubject to subsection (f), in consultation with appropriate department and agencies of the United States Government, and private sector entities, to produce a strategic planning assessment of the counterintelligence requirements of the United States to be known as the National Threat Identification and Prioritization Assessment.


(2) National Counterintelligence Strategy(A) Requirement to produceSubject to subsection (f), in consultation with appropriate department and agencies of the United States Government, and private sector entities, and based on the most current National Threat Identification and Prioritization Assessment under paragraph (1), to produce a strategy for the counterintelligence programs and activities of the United States Government to be known as the National Counterintelligence Strategy.


(B) Revision and requirementThe National Counterintelligence Strategy shall be revised or updated at least once every three years and shall </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There shall be a National Counterintelligence and Security Center.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Head of Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Head of Center The Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall be the head of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location of Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Location of Center The National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall be located in the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mission The mission of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall include organizing and leading strategic planning for counterintelligence activities of the United States Government by integrating instruments of national power as needed to counter foreign intelligence activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Functions Subject to the direction and control of the Director of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center, the functions of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall be as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements regarding National Threat Identification and Prioritization Assessment and National Counterintelligence Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional requirements regarding National Threat Identification and Prioritization Assessment and National Counterintelligence Strategy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Personnel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of activities under certain administrative laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Treatment of activities under certain administrative laws The files of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center shall be treated as operational files of the Central Intelligence Agency for purposes of section 701 of the National Security Act of 1947 (50 U.S.C. 3141) to the extent such files meet criteria under subsection (b) of that section for treatment of files as operational files of an element of the Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight by Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Oversight by Congress The location of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence shall not be construed as affecting access by Congress, or any committee of Congress, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3383_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Construction Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, or the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation as provided or specified under the National Security Act of 1947 or under other provisions of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>