<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3515" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3515/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3515/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3515"><akn:num>3515</akn:num><akn:heading>Security personnel at Agency installations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3515. Security personnel at Agency installations(a) Special policemen: functions and powers; regulations: promulgation and enforcement(1) The Director may authorize Agency personnel within the United States to perform the same functions as officers and agents of the Department of Homeland Security, as provided in section 1315(b)(2) of title 40, with the powers set forth in that section, except that such personnel shall perform such functions and exercise such powers—(A) within the Agency Headquarters Compound and the property controlled and occupied by the Federal Highway Administration located immediately adjacent to such Compound;

(B) in the streets, sidewalks, and the open areas within the zone beginning at the outside boundary of such Compound and property and extending outward 500 yards;

(C) within any other Agency installation and protected property;

(D) within an installation owned, or contracted to be occupied for a period of one year or longer, by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence; and

(E) in the streets, sidewalks, and open areas within the zone beginning at the outside boundary of any installation or property referred to in subparagraph (C) or (D) and extending outward 500 yards.


(2) The performance of functions and exercise of powers under subparagraph (B) or (E) of paragraph (1) shall be limited to those circumstances where such personnel can identify specific and articulable facts giving such personnel reason to believe that the performance of such functions and exercise of such powers is reasonable to protect against physical damage or injury, or threats of physical damage or injury, to Agency installations, property, or employees.

(3) Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude, or limit in any way, the authority of any Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency, or any other Federal police or Federal protective service.

(4) The rules and regulations enforced by such personnel shall be the rules and regu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3515_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special policemen: functions and powers; regulations: promulgation and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Special policemen: functions and powers; regulations: promulgation and enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3515_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for violations of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalties for violations of regulations The Director is authorized to establish penalties for violations of the rules or regulations promulgated by the Director under subsection (a) of this section. Such penalties shall not exceed the maximum penalty authorized for a Class B misdemeanor under section 3559 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3515_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Identification Agency personnel designated by the Director under subsection (a) of this section shall be clearly identifiable as United States Government security personnel while engaged in the performance of the functions to which subsection (a) of this section refers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3515_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of certain CIA personnel from tort liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Protection of certain CIA personnel from tort liability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>