<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3517" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3517/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3517/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3517"><akn:num>3517</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspector General for Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3517. Inspector General for Agency(a) Purpose; establishmentIn order to—(1) create an objective and effective office, appropriately accountable to Congress, to initiate and conduct independently inspections, investigations, and audits relating to programs and operations of the Agency;

(2) provide leadership and recommend policies designed to promote economy, efficiency, and effectiveness in the administration of such programs and operations, and detect fraud and abuse in such programs and operations;

(3) provide a means for keeping the Director fully and currently informed about problems and deficiencies relating to the administration of such programs and operations, and the necessity for and the progress of corrective actions; and

(4) in the manner prescribed by this section, ensure that the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence and the House Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence (hereafter in this section referred to collectively as the “intelligence committees”) are kept similarly informed of significant problems and deficiencies as well as the necessity for and the progress of corrective actions,


there is hereby established in the Agency an Office of Inspector General (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Office”).

(b) Appointment; supervision; removal(1) There shall be at the head of the Office an Inspector General who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. This appointment shall be made without regard to political affiliation and shall be on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigation. Such appointment shall also be made on the basis of compliance with the security standards of the Agency and prior experience in the field of foreign intelligence.

(2) The Inspector General shall report directly to and be under the general supervision of the Director.

(3) The Director may proh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3517_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose; establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose; establishment In order to— there is hereby established in the Agency an Office of Inspector General (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3517_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment; supervision; removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment; supervision; removal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3517_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties and responsibilities It shall be the duty and responsibility of the Inspector General appointed under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3517_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Semiannual reports; immediate reports of serious or flagrant problems; reports of functional problems; reports to Congress on urgent concerns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Semiannual reports; immediate reports of serious or flagrant problems; reports of functional problems; reports to Congress on urgent concerns</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3517_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities of Inspector General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorities of Inspector General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3517_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate budget account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Separate budget account</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3517_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transfer There shall be transferred to the Office the office of the Agency referred to as the “Office of Inspector General.” The personnel, assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, and other funds employed, held, used, arising from, or available to such “Office of Inspector General” are hereby transferred to the Office established pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3517_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on website</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Information on website</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>