<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3519a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3519a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3519a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3519a"><akn:num>3519a</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation pay program for voluntary separation from service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3519a. Separation pay program for voluntary separation from service(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) the term “Director” means the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency; and

(2) the term “employee” means an employee of the Central Intelligence Agency, serving under an appointment without time limitation, who has been currently employed for a continuous period of at least 12 months, except that such term does not include—(A) a reemployed annuitant under subchapter III of chapter 83 or chapter 84 of title 5 or another retirement system for employees of the Government; or

(B) an employee having a disability on the basis of which such employee is or would be eligible for disability retirement under any of the retirement systems referred to in subparagraph (A).



(b) Establishment of programIn order to avoid or minimize the need for involuntary separations due to downsizing, reorganization, transfer of function, or other similar action, the Director may establish a program under which employees may be offered separation pay to separate from service voluntarily (whether by retirement or resignation). An employee who receives separation pay under such program may not be reemployed by the Central Intelligence Agency for the 12-month period beginning on the effective date of the employee’s separation. An employee who receives separation pay under this section on the basis of a separation occurring on or after March 30, 1994, and accepts employment with the Government of the United States within 5 years after the date of the separation on which payment of the separation pay is based shall be required to repay the entire amount of the separation pay to the Central Intelligence Agency. If the employment is with an Executive agency (as defined by section 105 of title 5), the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may, at the request of the head of the agency, waive the repayment if the individual involved possesses unique abilities and is the onl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3519a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3519a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of program In order to avoid or minimize the need for involuntary separations due to downsizing, reorganization, transfer of function, or other similar action, the Director may establish a program under which employees may be offered separation pay to separate from service voluntarily (whether by retirement or resignation). An employee who receives separation pay under such program may not be reemployed by the Central Intelligence Agency for the 12-month period beginning on the effective date of the employee’s separation. An employee who receives separation pay under this section on the basis of a separation occurring on or after March 30, 1994, and accepts employment with the Government of the United States within 5 years after the date of the separation on which payment of the separation pay is based shall be required to repay the entire amount of the separation pay to the Central Intelligence Agency. If the employment is with an Executive agency (as defined by sect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3519a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bar on certain employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Bar on certain employment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3519a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations Under this program, separation pay may be offered only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3519a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount and treatment for other purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amount and treatment for other purposes Such separation pay—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3519a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Director shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3519a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>