<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3520" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3520/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3520/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3520"><akn:num>3520</akn:num><akn:heading>General Counsel of Central Intelligence Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3520. General Counsel of Central Intelligence Agency(a) AppointmentThere is a General Counsel of the Central Intelligence Agency, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(b) Chief legal officerThe General Counsel is the chief legal officer of the Central Intelligence Agency.


(c) FunctionsThe General Counsel of the Central Intelligence Agency shall perform such functions as the Director may prescribe.


(June 20, 1949, ch. 227, § 20, as added Pub. L. 104–293, title VIII, § 813(a), Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3483; amended Pub. L. 108–458, title I, § 1071(b)(2)(D), Dec. 17, 2004, 118 Stat. 3690.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 403t of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments2004—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 108–458 struck out “of Central Intelligence” after “Director”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2004 AmendmentFor Determination by President that amendment by Pub. L. 108–458 take effect on Apr. 21, 2005, see Memorandum of President of the United States, Apr. 21, 2005, 70 F.R. 23925, set out as a note under section 3001 of this title.
Amendment by Pub. L. 108–458 effective not later than six months after Dec. 17, 2004, except as otherwise expressly provided, see section 1097(a) of Pub. L. 108–458, set out in an Effective Date of 2004 Amendment; Transition Provisions note under section 3001 of this title.

Applicability of Appointment RequirementsPub. L. 104–293, title VIII, § 813(b), Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3483, provided that: 
“The requirement established by section 20 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [50 U.S.C. 3520], as added by subsection (a), for the appointment by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, of an individual to the position of General Counsel of the Central Intelligence Agency shall apply as follows:
“(1) To any vacancy in such position t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3520_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment There is a General Counsel of the Central Intelligence Agency, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3520_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief legal officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Chief legal officer The General Counsel is the chief legal officer of the Central Intelligence Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3520_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions The General Counsel of the Central Intelligence Agency shall perform such functions as the Director may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>