<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3521" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3521/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3521/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3521"><akn:num>3521</akn:num><akn:heading>Central services program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3521. Central services program(a) In generalThe Director may carry out a program under which elements of the Agency provide items and services on a reimbursable basis to other elements of the Agency, nonappropriated fund entities or instrumentalities associated or affiliated with the Agency, and other Government agencies. The Director shall carry out the program in accordance with the provisions of this section.


(b) Participation of Agency elements(1) In order to carry out the program, the Director shall—(A) designate the elements of the Agency that are to provide items or services under the program (in this section referred to as “central service providers”);

(B) specify the items or services to be provided under the program by such providers;

(C) assign to such providers for purposes of the program such inventories, equipment, and other assets (including equipment on order) as the Director determines necessary to permit such providers to provide items or services under the program; and

(D) authorize such providers to make known their services to the entities specified in subsection (a) through Government communication channels.


(2) The designation of elements and the specification of items and services under paragraph (1) shall be subject to the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.

(3) The authority in paragraph (1)(D) does not include the authority to distribute gifts or promotional items.


(c) Central Services Working Capital Fund(1) There is established a fund to be known as the Central Services Working Capital Fund (in this section referred to as the “Fund”). The purpose of the Fund is to provide sums for activities under the program.

(2) There shall be deposited in the Fund the following:(A) Amounts appropriated to the Fund.

(B) Amounts credited to the Fund from payments received by central service providers under subsection (e).

(C) Fees imposed and collected under subsection (f)(1).

(D) Amounts received in payment </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3521_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director may carry out a program under which elements of the Agency provide items and services on a reimbursable basis to other elements of the Agency, nonappropriated fund entities or instrumentalities associated or affiliated with the Agency, and other Government agencies. The Director shall carry out the program in accordance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3521_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation of Agency elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Participation of Agency elements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3521_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Central Services Working Capital Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Central Services Working Capital Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3521_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on amount of orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on amount of orders The total value of all orders for items or services to be provided under the program in any fiscal year may not exceed an amount specified in advance by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3521_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment for items and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment for items and services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3521_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3521_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Termination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>