<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3523" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3523/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3523/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3523"><akn:num>3523</akn:num><akn:heading>Intelligence operations and cover enhancement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3523. Intelligence operations and cover enhancement authority(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “designated employee” means an employee designated by the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency under subsection (b); and

(2) the term “Federal retirement system” includes the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and the Federal Employees’ Retirement System (including the Thrift Savings Plan).


(b) In general(1) AuthorityNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may exercise the authorities under this section in order to—(A) protect from unauthorized disclosure—(i) intelligence operations;

(ii) the identities of undercover intelligence officers;

(iii) intelligence sources and methods; or

(iv) intelligence cover mechanisms; or


(B) meet the special requirements of work related to collection of foreign intelligence or other authorized activities of the Agency.


(2) Designation of employeesThe Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may designate any employee of the Agency who is under nonofficial cover to be an employee to whom this section applies. Such designation may be made with respect to any or all authorities exercised under this section.



(c) CompensationThe Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may pay a designated employee salary, allowances, and other benefits in an amount and in a manner consistent with the nonofficial cover of that employee, without regard to any limitation that is otherwise applicable to a Federal employee. A designated employee may accept, utilize, and, to the extent authorized by regulations prescribed under subsection (i), retain any salary, allowances, and other benefits provided under this section.


(d) Retirement benefits(1) In generalThe Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may establish and administer a nonofficial cover employee retirement system for designated employees (and the spouse, former spouses, and survivors </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may pay a designated employee salary, allowances, and other benefits in an amount and in a manner consistent with the nonofficial cover of that employee, without regard to any limitation that is otherwise applicable to a Federal employee. A designated employee may accept, utilize, and, to the extent authorized by regulations prescribed under subsection (i), retain any salary, allowances, and other benefits provided under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Retirement benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health insurance benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Health insurance benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life insurance benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Life insurance benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from certain requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exemption from certain requirements The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may exempt a designated employee from mandatory compliance with any Federal regulation, rule, standardized administrative policy, process, or procedure that the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency determines—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxation and social security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Taxation and social security</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. The regulations shall ensure that the combination of salary, allowances, and benefits that an employee designated under this section may retain does not significantly exceed, except to the extent determined by the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency to be necessary to exercise the authority in subsection (b), the combination of salary, allowances, and benefits otherwise received by Federal employees not designated under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3523_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of decisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Finality of decisions Any determinations authorized by this section to be made by the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency or the Director’s designee shall be final and conclusive and shall not be subject to review by any court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>