<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3531" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3531/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3531/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3531"><akn:num>3531</akn:num><akn:heading>Sexual assault and sexual harassment within the Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3531. Sexual assault and sexual harassment within the Agency(a) Responsibilities of DirectorThe Director shall carry out the following responsibilities:(1) Establishing professional and uniform training for employees assigned to working with all aspects of the response of the Agency to allegations of sexual assault and sexual harassment.

(2) Developing and implementing policies and procedures to protect the confidentiality of employees who report sexual assault or sexual harassment and to mitigate negative effects on the reputation or career of such an employee as a result of such a report.

(3) Developing and implementing documented standards for—(A) appropriate mitigation and protection measures for individuals who make allegations of a sexual assault or sexual harassment to be put in place while an investigation proceeds;

(B) appropriate employee consequences to be imposed based on the findings of an inquiry or investigation into a substantiated allegation of sexual assault or sexual harassment;

(C) appropriate career path protection for all employees involved in an incident resulting in a reported allegation of sexual assault or sexual harassment while an administrative or criminal investigation or review of the allegation is pending; and

(D) mitigation measures to protect employees and mission execution while such allegations are being addressed.


(4) Articulating and enforcing norms, expectations, practices, and policies, including with respect to employee promotions and assignments, that are published for the workforce and designed to promote a healthy workplace culture that is inhospitable to sexual assault and sexual harassment.

(5) Developing and issuing workforce messaging to inform Agency employees of policies, procedures, resources, and points of contact to obtain information related to, or to report, sexual assault or sexual harassment globally.

(6) Developing and implementing sexual assault and sexual harassment training for all Agency employ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Responsibilities of Director The Director shall carry out the following responsibilities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Semiannual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Semiannual report Not less frequently than once every 180 days, the Director shall submit to the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives a report on the activities of all Agency offices responsible for preventing, investigating, adjudicating, and addressing claims of sexual assault or sexual harassment. The Director shall personally review, approve, and submit each report under this subsection on a nondelegable basis. Each such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>