<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3532" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3532/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3532/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3532"><akn:num>3532</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting and investigation of allegations of sexual assault and sexual harassment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3532. Reporting and investigation of allegations of sexual assault and sexual harassment(a) Policies relating to restricted and unrestricted reporting of sexual assault and sexual harassment(1) In generalThe Director shall develop and implement policies, regulations, personnel training, and workforce education to establish and provide information about restricted reports and unrestricted reports of allegations of sexual assault and sexual harassment within the Agency in accordance with this subsection.


(2) Workforce educationWorkforce education developed under paragraph (1) shall be designed to clearly inform Agency employees of the differences between restricted and unrestricted reporting of allegations of sexual assault and sexual harassment, and which individual or office within the Agency is responsible for receiving each type of report.


(3) Relationship to the Sexual Harassment/Assault Response and Prevention OfficeTo the extent consistent with preserving a victim’s complete autonomy, the policies, regulations, training, and messaging described in this subsection shall—(A) encourage Agency employees to make restricted or unrestricted reports of sexual assault and sexual harassment to the Sexual Harassment/Assault Response and Prevention Office;

(B) encourage Agency employees to use the Sexual Harassment/Assault Response and Prevention Office as the primary point of contact and entry point for Agency employees to make restricted or unrestricted reports of sexual assault and sexual harassment;

(C) encourage Agency employees to seek the victim advocacy services of the Sexual Harassment/Assault Response and Prevention Office after reporting an allegation of sexual assault or sexual harassment, to the extent consistent with the victim’s election; and

(D) encourage Agency employees and individuals who receive disclosures of sexual assault and sexual harassment to provide the report to, and receive guidance from, the Sexual Harassment/Assault Response and Pre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policies relating to restricted and unrestricted reporting of sexual assault and sexual harassment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Policies relating to restricted and unrestricted reporting of sexual assault and sexual harassment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Election Any person making a report containing an allegation of a sexual assault or sexual harassment shall elect whether to make a restricted report or an unrestricted report. Once an election is made to make an unrestricted report, such election may not be changed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unrestricted reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Unrestricted reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restricted reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Restricted reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privileged communications with Agency employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Privileged communications with Agency employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incident reports when victim or alleged perpetrator is an Agency employee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Incident reports when victim or alleged perpetrator is an Agency employee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common perpetrator notice requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Common perpetrator notice requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Applicability The policies developed pursuant to this section shall apply to each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3532_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Relationship to the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity In the case of a restricted report of sexual harassment, such report shall not result in a referral to the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, unless the victim elects to change the report from a restricted report to an unrestricted report. In the case of an unrestricted report, the Special Victim Investigator, the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity, law enforcement, or any other appropriate investigative body, or any appropriate combination thereof, may investigate the unrestricted report, as appropriate. Policies and procedures developed pursuant to this section are intended to offer victims options in addition to the process described in part 1614 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>