<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3614" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3614/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3614/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3614"><akn:num>3614</akn:num><akn:heading>Louis Stokes Educational Scholarship Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3614. Louis Stokes Educational Scholarship Program(a) EstablishmentThe purpose of this section is to establish an undergraduate and graduate training program, which may lead to a baccalaureate or graduate degree, to facilitate the recruitment of individuals, particularly minority high school students, with a demonstrated capability to develop skills critical to the mission of the National Security Agency, including mathematics, computer science, engineering, and foreign languages.


(b) Assignment for trainingThe Secretary of Defense is authorized, in his discretion, to assign civilians who may or may not be employees of the National Security Agency as students at accredited professional, technical, and other institutions of higher learning for training at the undergraduate or graduate level in skills critical to effective performance of the mission of the Agency.


(c) Payment of expensesThe National Security Agency may pay, directly or by reimbursement to program participants, expenses incident to assignments under subsection (b), in any fiscal year only to the extent that appropriated funds are available for such purpose.


(d) Eligibility(1) To be eligible for assignment under subsection (b), a program participant must agree in writing—(A) to continue in the service of the Agency for the period of the assignment and to complete the educational course of training for which the program participant is assigned;

(B) to continue in the service of the Agency following completion of the assignment for a period of one-and-a-half years for each year of the assignment or part thereof;

(C) to reimburse the United States for the total cost of education (excluding the program participant’s pay and allowances) provided under this section to the program participant if, prior to the program participant’s completing the educational course of training for which the program participant is assigned, the assignment or the program participant’s employment with the Agency is termi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The purpose of this section is to establish an undergraduate and graduate training program, which may lead to a baccalaureate or graduate degree, to facilitate the recruitment of individuals, particularly minority high school students, with a demonstrated capability to develop skills critical to the mission of the National Security Agency, including mathematics, computer science, engineering, and foreign languages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment for training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assignment for training The Secretary of Defense is authorized, in his discretion, to assign civilians who may or may not be employees of the National Security Agency as students at accredited professional, technical, and other institutions of higher learning for training at the undergraduate or graduate level in skills critical to effective performance of the mission of the Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of expenses The National Security Agency may pay, directly or by reimbursement to program participants, expenses incident to assignments under subsection (b), in any fiscal year only to the extent that appropriated funds are available for such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recruitment of individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recruitment of individuals Agency efforts to recruit individuals at educational institutions for participation in the undergraduate and graduate training program established by this section shall be made openly and according to the common practices of universities and employers recruiting at such institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicability of other laws Chapter 41 of title 5 and subsections (a) and (b) of section 3324 of title 31 shall not apply with respect to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary of Defense may issue such regulations as may be necessary to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program name</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Program name The undergraduate and graduate training program established under this section shall be known as the Louis Stokes Educational Scholarship Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>