<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3711"><akn:num>3711</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to carry out Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3711. Authority to carry out Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Program(a) AuthorityThe Secretary of Defense may carry out a program, referred to as the “Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Program”, with respect to foreign countries to do the following:(1) Facilitate the elimination and the safe and secure transportation and storage of chemical, biological, or other weapons, weapons components, weapons-related materials, and associated delivery vehicles.

(2) Facilitate—(A) the safe and secure transportation and storage of nuclear weapons, nuclear weapons-usable or high-threat radiological materials, nuclear weapons components, and associated delivery vehicles; and

(B) the elimination of nuclear weapons, nuclear weapons components, and nuclear weapons delivery vehicles.


(3) Prevent the proliferation of nuclear and chemical weapons, weapons components, and weapons-related materials, technology, and expertise.

(4) Prevent the proliferation of biological weapons, weapons components, and weapons-related materials, technology, and expertise, which may include activities that facilitate detection and reporting of highly pathogenic diseases or other diseases that are associated with or that could be used as an early warning mechanism for disease outbreaks that could affect the Armed Forces of the United States or allies of the United States, regardless of whether such diseases are caused by biological weapons.

(5) Prevent the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction-related materials, including materials, equipment, and technology that could be used for the design, development, production, or use of nuclear, chemical, and biological weapons and the means of delivery of such weapons.

(6) Carry out military-to-military and defense contacts for advancing the mission of the Program, subject to subsection (f).


(b) Concurrence of Secretary of StateThe authority under subsection (a) to carry out the Program is subject to any concurren</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority The Secretary of Defense may carry out a program, referred to as the “Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Program”, with respect to foreign countries to do the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concurrence of Secretary of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Concurrence of Secretary of State The authority under subsection (a) to carry out the Program is subject to any concurrence of the Secretary of State or other appropriate agency head required under section 3712 or 3713 of this title (unless such concurrence is otherwise exempted pursuant to section 3751 of this title with respect to activities or determinations carried out or made before December 19, 2014).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Scope of authority The authority to carry out the Program in subsection (a) includes authority to provide equipment, goods, and services, but does not include authority to provide funds directly for a project or activity carried out under the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Type of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Type of program The Program carried out under subsection (a) may involve assistance in planning and in resolving technical problems associated with weapons destruction and proliferation. The Program may also involve the funding of critical short-term requirements relating to weapons destruction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3711_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reimbursement of other agencies The Secretary of Defense may reimburse heads of other departments and agencies of the Federal Government under this section for costs of the participation of the respective departments and agencies in the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3711_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military-to-military and defense contacts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Military-to-military and defense contacts The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the military-to-military and defense contacts carried out under subsection (a)(6)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3711_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior notice to Congress of obligation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prior notice to Congress of obligation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>