<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3743" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3743/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3743/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3743"><akn:num>3743</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports on activities and assistance under Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Progra</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3743. Reports on activities and assistance under Department of Defense Cooperative Threat Reduction Program(a) Annual reportIn any year in which the President submits to Congress, under section 1105 of title 31, the budget for a fiscal year that requests funds for the Department of Defense for activities or assistance under the Program, the Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the activities and assistance carried out under the Program.


(b) DeadlineEach report under subsection (a) shall be submitted not later than the first Monday in February of a year.


(c) Matters includedEach report under subsection (a) shall include the following:(1) An estimate of the total amount that will be required to be expended by the United States during the fiscal year covered by the budget described in subsection (a) in order to achieve the objectives of the Program.

(2) A five-year plan setting forth the amount of funds and other resources proposed to be provided by the United States for the Program during the period covered by the plan, including the purpose for which such funds and resources will be used.

(3) A description of the activities and assistance carried out under the Program during the fiscal year preceding the submission of the report, including—(A) the funds notified, obligated, and expended for such activities and assistance and the purposes for which such funds were notified, obligated, and expended for such fiscal year and cumulatively for the Program;

(B) a description of the participation, if any, of each department and agency of the Federal Government in such activities and assistance;

(C) a description of such activities and assistance, including the forms of assistance provided;

(D) a description of the United States private sector partici</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3743_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report In any year in which the President submits to Congress, under section 1105 of title 31, the budget for a fiscal year that requests funds for the Department of Defense for activities or assistance under the Program, the Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the activities and assistance carried out under the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3743_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deadline Each report under subsection (a) shall be submitted not later than the first Monday in February of a year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3743_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Matters included Each report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3743_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination date The requirement to submit the report under subsection (a) shall terminate on January 1, 2030.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>