<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3803"><akn:num>3803</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons liable for training and service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3803. Persons liable for training and service(a) Age limits; training in National Security Training Corps; physical and mental fitness; adequate training facilities; assignment to stations and units; training period; medical specialist categoriesExcept as otherwise provided in this chapter, every person required to register pursuant to section 3802 of this chapter who is between the ages of eighteen years and six months and twenty-six years, at the time fixed for his registration, or who attains the age of eighteen years and six months after having been required to register pursuant to section 3802 of this title, or who is otherwise liable as provided in section 3806(h) of this title, shall be liable for training and service in the Armed Forces of the United States: Provided, That each registrant shall be immediately liable for classification and examination, and shall, as soon as practicable following his registration, be so classified and examined, both physically and mentally, in order to determine his availability for induction for training and service in the Armed Forces: Provided further, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, any registrant who has failed or refused to report for induction shall continue to remain liable for induction and when available shall be immediately inducted. The President is authorized, from time to time, whether or not a state of war exists, to select and induct into the Armed Forces of the United States for training and service in the manner provided in this chapter (including but not limited to selection and induction by age group or age groups) such number of persons as may be required to provide and maintain the strength of the Armed Forces.
At such time as the period of active service in the Armed Forces required under this chapter of persons who have not attained the nineteenth anniversary of the day of their birth has been reduced or eliminated pursuant to the provisions of subsection (k), and except as otherwise</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Age limits; training in National Security Training Corps; physical and mental fitness; adequate training facilities; assignment to stations and units; training period; medical specialist categories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Age limits; training in National Security Training Corps; physical and mental fitness; adequate training facilities; assignment to stations and units; training period; medical specialist categories Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, every person required to register pursuant to section 3802 of this chapter who is between the ages of eighteen years and six months and twenty-six years, at the time fixed for his registration, or who attains the age of eighteen years and six months after having been required to register pursuant to section 3802 of this title, or who is otherwise liable as provided in section 3806(h) of this title, shall be liable for training and service in the Armed Forces of the United States: Provided, That each registrant shall be immediately liable for classification and examination, and shall, as soon as practicable following his registration, be so classified and examined, both physically and mentally, in order to determine his availability for induct</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Length of service; release of individuals accepted into Army National Guard, Air National Guard, and other Reserve components</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Length of service; release of individuals accepted into Army National Guard, Air National Guard, and other Reserve components Each person inducted into the Armed Forces under the provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall serve on active training and service for a period of twenty-four consecutive months, unless sooner released, transferred, or discharged in accordance with procedures prescribed by the Secretary of Defense (or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the United States Coast Guard) or as otherwise prescribed by subsection (d). The Secretaries of the Army, Navy, and Air Force, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense (and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the United States Coast Guard), may provide, by regulations which shall be as nearly uniform as practicable, for the release from training and service in the armed forces prior to serving the periods required by this subsection of individuals who volunteered for and are accept</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity to enlist in Regular Army; voluntary induction; volunteers under 18 years old</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Opportunity to enlist in Regular Army; voluntary induction; volunteers under 18 years old</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to Reserve component; period of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer to Reserve component; period of service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pay and allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Pay and allowances With respect to the persons inducted for training and service under this chapter there shall be paid, allowed, and extended the same pay, allowances, pensions, disability and death compensation, and other benefits as are provided by law in the case of other enlisted men of like grades and length of service of that component of the armed forces to which they are assigned. Section 3 of the Act of July 25, 1947 (Public Law 239, Eightieth Congress), is amended by deleting therefrom the following: “Act of March 7, 1942 (56 Stat. 143 to 148, ch. 166), as amended”. The Act of March 7, 1942 (56 Stat. 143 to 148), as amended, is made applicable to persons inducted into the armed forces pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional compensation from civilian sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional compensation from civilian sources Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person who is inducted into the armed forces under this Act and who, before being inducted, was receiving compensation from any person may, while serving under that induction, receive compensation from that person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Occupational deferment recommendations by National Security Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Occupational deferment recommendations by National Security Council The National Security Council shall periodically advise the Director of the Selective Service System and coordinate with him the work of such State and local volunteer advisory committees which the Director of Selective Service may establish, with respect to the identification, selection, and deferment of needed professional and scientific personnel and those engaged in, and preparing for, critical skills and other essential occupations. In the performance of its duties under this subsection the National Security Council shall consider the needs of both the Armed Forces and the civilian segment of the population.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. June 19, 1951, ch. 144, title I, § 1(h), 65 Stat. 80</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (j) Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) , (j) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of periods of service; establishment of National Security Training Corps; composition; service; pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) Reduction of periods of service; establishment of National Security Training Corps; composition; service; pay</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>