<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3809" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3809/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3809/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3809"><akn:num>3809</akn:num><akn:heading>Selective Service System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3809. Selective Service System(a) Establishment; construction; appointment of Director; termination and reestablishment of Office of Selective Service Records(1) There is established in the executive branch of the Government an agency to be known as the Selective Service System, and a Director of Selective Service who shall be the head thereof.

(2) The Selective Service System shall include a national headquarters, at least one State headquarters in each State, Territory, and possession of the United States, and in the District of Columbia, and the local boards, appeal boards, and other agencies provided for in subsection (b)(3) of this section.

(3) The Director shall be appointed by the President.

(4) The functions of the Office of Selective Service Records (established by the Act of March 31, 1947) and of the Director of the Office of Selective Service Records are transferred to the Selective Service System and the Director of Selective Service, respectively. The personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances (available or to be made available) of appropriations, allocations, and other funds of the Office of Selective Service Records are transferred to the Selective Service System. The Office of Selective Service Records shall cease to exist upon the taking effect of the provisions of this chapter: Provided, That, effective upon the termination of this chapter and notwithstanding such termination in other respects, (A) the said Office of Selective Service Records is reestablished on the same basis and with the same functions as obtained prior to June 24, 1948, (B) said reestablished Office shall be responsible for liquidating any other outstanding affairs of the Selective Service System, and (C) the personnel, property, records, and unexpended balances (available or to be made available) of appropriations, allocations, and other funds of the Selective Service System shall be transferred to such reestablished Office of Selective Service Records.


(b) A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3809_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; construction; appointment of Director; termination and reestablishment of Office of Selective Service Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; construction; appointment of Director; termination and reestablishment of Office of Selective Service Records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3809_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrative provisions The President is authorized to undertake the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3809_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of President’s authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Delegation of President’s authority The President is authorized to delegate any authority vested in him under this chapter, and to provide for the subdelegation of any such authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3809_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of gifts and voluntary services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acceptance of gifts and voluntary services In the administration of this chapter, gifts of supplies, equipment, and voluntary services may be accepted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3809_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of armed forces personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assignment of armed forces personnel The total number of armed forces personnel assigned to the Selective Service System under subsection (b)(2) at any time may not be less than the number of such personnel determined by the Director of Selective Service to be necessary, but not to exceed 745 persons, except that the President may assign additional armed forces personnel to the Selective Service System during a time of war or a national emergency declared by Congress or the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3809_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement of travel claims, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Settlement of travel claims, etc. The Director is authorized to make final settlement of individual claims, for amounts not exceeding $500, for travel and other expenses of uncompensated personnel of the Office of Selective Service Records, or the Selective Service System, incurred while in the performance of official duties, without regard to other provisions of law governing the travel of civilian employees of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3809_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports to Congress The Director of Selective Service shall submit to the Congress annually a written report covering the operation of the Selective Service System and such report shall include, by States, information as to the number of persons registered under this Act; the number of persons inducted in to the military service under this Act; and the number of deferments granted under this Act and the basis for such deferments; and such other specific kinds of information as the Congress may from time to time request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3809_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of System after institution of all volunteer program for meeting manpower needs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Maintenance of System after institution of all volunteer program for meeting manpower needs The Selective Service system 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. shall be maintained as an active standby organization, with (1) a complete registration and classification structure capable of immediate operation in the event of a national emergency (including a structure for registration and classification of persons qualified for practice or employment in a health care occupation essential to the maintenance of the Armed Forces), and (2) personnel adequate to reinstitute immediately the full operation of the System, including military reservists who are trained to operate such System and who can be ordered to active duty for such purpose in the event of a national emergency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>