<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3813" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3813/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3813/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3813"><akn:num>3813</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of requirements of this chapter; voluntary enlistments unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3813. Notice of requirements of this chapter; voluntary enlistments unaffected(a) Deeming of notice upon publicationEvery person shall be deemed to have notice of the requirements of this chapter upon publication by the President of a proclamation or other public notice fixing a time for any registration under section 3802 of this title.


(b) Duty to inform local board of current address and changes in statusIt shall be the duty of every registrant to keep his local board informed as to his current address and changes in status as required by such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the President.


(c) Separability of provisionsIf any provision of this chapter, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of the chapter, and the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.


(d) Voluntary enlistments or reenlistments; absence of affectExcept as provided in section 3803(c) of this title, nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to repeal, amend, or suspend the laws now in force authorizing voluntary enlistment or reenlistment in the Armed Forces of the United States, including the reserve components thereof, except that no person shall be accepted for enlistment after he has been issued an order to report for induction unless authorized by the Director and the Secretary of Defense and except that, whenever the Congress or the President has declared that the national interest is imperiled, voluntary enlistment or reenlistment in such forces, and their reserve components, may be suspended by the President to such extent as he may deem necessary in the interest of national defense.


(e) Furnishing of names and addresses to Secretary of Defense or Secretary of Homeland SecurityIn order to assist the Armed Forces in recruiting individuals for voluntary service in the Armed Forces, the Director shall, upon the request of the Secretary of Defense or the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3813_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deeming of notice upon publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deeming of notice upon publication Every person shall be deemed to have notice of the requirements of this chapter upon publication by the President of a proclamation or other public notice fixing a time for any registration under section 3802 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3813_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty to inform local board of current address and changes in status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duty to inform local board of current address and changes in status It shall be the duty of every registrant to keep his local board informed as to his current address and changes in status as required by such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3813_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separability of provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Separability of provisions If any provision of this chapter, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance, is held invalid, the remainder of the chapter, and the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3813_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary enlistments or reenlistments; absence of affect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Voluntary enlistments or reenlistments; absence of affect Except as provided in section 3803(c) of this title, nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to repeal, amend, or suspend the laws now in force authorizing voluntary enlistment or reenlistment in the Armed Forces of the United States, including the reserve components thereof, except that no person shall be accepted for enlistment after he has been issued an order to report for induction unless authorized by the Director and the Secretary of Defense and except that, whenever the Congress or the President has declared that the national interest is imperiled, voluntary enlistment or reenlistment in such forces, and their reserve components, may be suspended by the President to such extent as he may deem necessary in the interest of national defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3813_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing of names and addresses to Secretary of Defense or Secretary of Homeland Security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Furnishing of names and addresses to Secretary of Defense or Secretary of Homeland Security In order to assist the Armed Forces in recruiting individuals for voluntary service in the Armed Forces, the Director shall, upon the request of the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security, furnish to the Secretary the names and addresses of individuals registered under this Act. Names and addresses furnished pursuant to the preceding sentence may be used by the Secretary of Defense or Secretary of Homeland Security only for recruiting purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>