<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3814" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3814/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3814/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3814"><akn:num>3814</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3814. Definitions
When used in this chapter—(a) The term “between the ages of eighteen and twenty-six” shall refer to men who have attained the eighteenth anniversary of the day of their birth and who have not attained the twenty-sixth anniversary of the day of their birth; and other terms designating different age groups shall be construed in a similar manner.

(b) The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, shall be deemed to mean the several States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam.

(c) The term “armed forces” shall be deemed to include the Army, the Navy, the Marine Corps, the Air Force, and the Coast Guard.

(d) The term “district court of the United States” shall be deemed to include the courts of the United States for the Territories and possessions of the United States.

(e) The term “local board” shall be deemed to include an intercounty local board in the case of any registrant who is subject to the jurisdiction of an intercounty local board.

(f) The term “Director” shall be deemed to mean the Director of the Selective Service System.

(g)(1) The term “duly ordained minister of religion” means a person who has been ordained, in accordance with the ceremonial, ritual, or discipline of a church, religious sect, or organization established on the basis of a community of faith and belief, doctrines and practices of a religious character, to preach and to teach the doctrines of such church, sect, or organization and to administer the rites and ceremonies thereof in public worship, and who as his regular and customary vocation preaches and teaches the principles of religion and administers the ordinances of public worship as embodied in the creed or principles of such church, sect, or organization.

(2) The term “regular minister of religion” means one who as his customary vocation preaches and teaches the principles of religion of a church, a religious sect, or organization of which he is a member, without</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3814_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The term “between the ages of eighteen and twenty-six” shall refer to men who have attained the eighteenth anniversary of the day of their birth and who have not attained the twenty-sixth anniversary of the day of their birth; and other terms designating different age groups shall be construed in a similar manner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3814_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, shall be deemed to mean the several States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3814_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term “armed forces” shall be deemed to include the Army, the Navy, the Marine Corps, the Air Force, and the Coast Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3814_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term “district court of the United States” shall be deemed to include the courts of the United States for the Territories and possessions of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3814_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The term “local board” shall be deemed to include an intercounty local board in the case of any registrant who is subject to the jurisdiction of an intercounty local board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3814_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The term “Director” shall be deemed to mean the Director of the Selective Service System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3814_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3814_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The term “organized unit”, when used with respect to a reserve component, shall be deemed to mean a unit in which the members thereof are required satisfactorily to participate in scheduled drills and training periods as prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3814_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The term “reserve components of the armed forces” shall, unless the context otherwise requires, be deemed to include the federally recognized National Guard of the United States, the federally recognized Air National Guard of the United States, the Officers’ Reserve Corps, the Regular Army Reserve, the Air Force Reserve, the Enlisted Reserve Corps, the Navy Reserve, the Marine Corps Reserve, and the Coast Guard Reserve, and shall include, in addition to the foregoing, the Public Health Service Reserve when serving with the armed forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>