<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3818" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3818/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3818/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3818"><akn:num>3818</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3818. Effective date
This chapter shall become effective immediately; except that unless the President, or the Congress by concurrent resolution, declares a national emergency after June 24, 1948, no person shall be inducted or ordered into active service without his consent under this chapter within ninety days after June 24, 1948.
(June 24, 1948, ch. 625, title I, § 20, 62 Stat. 627; Sept. 27, 1950, ch. 1059, § 1(14), 64 Stat. 1074; Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, § 53, 70A Stat. 641.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title I of act June 24, 1948, ch. 625, 62 Stat. 604, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title I to the Code, see Tables.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 470 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments1956—Act Aug. 10, 1956, repealed provisions requiring the Secretaries of the Army, Navy, and the Treasury to initiate and carry forward intensified voluntary enlistment campaigns for the Army, Air Force, Navy, Marine Corps, and the Coast Guard.
1950—Act Sept. 27, 1950, struck out “and” after “Air Force” and inserted “and the Secretary of the Treasury, for the Coast Guard” after “Marine Corps”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>