<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3911" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3911/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3911/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3911"><akn:num>3911</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3911. Definitions
For the purposes of this chapter:(1) ServicememberThe term “servicemember” means a member of the uniformed services, as that term is defined in section 101(a)(5) of title 10.


(2) Military serviceThe term “military service” means—(A) in the case of a servicemember who is a member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard—(i) active duty, as defined in section 101(d)(1) of title 10, and

(ii) in the case of a member of the National Guard, includes service under a call to active service authorized by the President or the Secretary of Defense for a period of more than 30 consecutive days under section 502(f) of title 32 for purposes of responding to a national emergency declared by the President and supported by Federal funds;


(B) in the case of a servicemember who is a commissioned officer of the Public Health Service or the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, active service; and

(C) any period during which a servicemember is absent from duty on account of sickness, wounds, leave, or other lawful cause.


(3) Period of military serviceThe term “period of military service” means the period beginning on the date on which a servicemember enters military service and ending on the date on which the servicemember is released from military service or dies while in military service.


(4) DependentThe term “dependent”, with respect to a servicemember, means—(A) the servicemember’s spouse;

(B) the servicemember’s child (as defined in section 101(4) of title 38); or

(C) an individual for whom the servicemember provided more than one-half of the individual’s support for 180 days immediately preceding an application for relief under this chapter.


(5) CourtThe term “court” means a court or an administrative agency of the United States or of any State (including any political subdivision of a State), whether or not a court or administrative agency of record.


(6) StateThe term “State” includes—(A) a commonwealt</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3911_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Servicemember</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Servicemember The term “servicemember” means a member of the uniformed services, as that term is defined in section 101(a)(5) of title 10.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3911_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Military service The term “military service” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3911_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of military service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Period of military service The term “period of military service” means the period beginning on the date on which a servicemember enters military service and ending on the date on which the servicemember is released from military service or dies while in military service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3911_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dependent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Dependent The term “dependent”, with respect to a servicemember, means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3911_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Court The term “court” means a court or an administrative agency of the United States or of any State (including any political subdivision of a State), whether or not a court or administrative agency of record.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3911_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) State The term “State” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3911_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary concerned</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Secretary concerned The term “Secretary concerned”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3911_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motor vehicle</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Motor vehicle The term “motor vehicle” has the meaning given that term in section 30102(a)(6) of title 49.11 See References in Text note below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3911_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judgment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Judgment The term “judgment” means any judgment, decree, order, or ruling, final or temporary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>