<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3932" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3932/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3932/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3932"><akn:num>3932</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of proceedings when servicemember has notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3932. Stay of proceedings when servicemember has notice(a) Applicability of sectionThis section applies to any civil action or proceeding, including any child custody proceeding, in which the plaintiff or defendant at the time of filing an application under this section—(1) is in military service or is within 90 days after termination of or release from military service; and

(2) has received notice of the action or proceeding.


(b) Stay of proceedings(1) Authority for stayAt any stage before final judgment in a civil action or proceeding in which a servicemember described in subsection (a) is a party, the court may on its own motion and shall, upon application by the servicemember, stay the action for a period of not less than 90 days, if the conditions in paragraph (2) are met.


(2) Conditions for stayAn application for a stay under paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) A letter or other communication setting forth facts stating the manner in which current military duty requirements materially affect the servicemember’s ability to appear and stating a date when the servicemember will be available to appear.

(B) A letter or other communication from the servicemember’s commanding officer stating that the servicemember’s current military duty prevents appearance and that military leave is not authorized for the servicemember at the time of the letter.



(c) Application not a waiver of defensesAn application for a stay under this section does not constitute an appearance for jurisdictional purposes and does not constitute a waiver of any substantive or procedural defense (including a defense relating to lack of personal jurisdiction).


(d) Additional stay(1) ApplicationA servicemember who is granted a stay of a civil action or proceeding under subsection (b) may apply for an additional stay based on continuing material affect of military duty on the servicemember’s ability to appear. Such an application may be made by the servicemember at the time of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3932_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability of section This section applies to any civil action or proceeding, including any child custody proceeding, in which the plaintiff or defendant at the time of filing an application under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3932_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Stay of proceedings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3932_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application not a waiver of defenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application not a waiver of defenses An application for a stay under this section does not constitute an appearance for jurisdictional purposes and does not constitute a waiver of any substantive or procedural defense (including a defense relating to lack of personal jurisdiction).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3932_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional stay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional stay</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3932_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with section 3931</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination with section 3931 A servicemember who applies for a stay under this section and is unsuccessful may not seek the protections afforded by section 3931 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3932_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability to section 3951</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Inapplicability to section 3951 The protections of this section do not apply to section 3951 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>