<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3934" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3934/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3934/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3934"><akn:num>3934</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay or vacation of execution of judgments, attachments, and garnishments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3934. Stay or vacation of execution of judgments, attachments, and garnishments(a) Court action upon material affect determinationIf a servicemember, in the opinion of the court, is materially affected by reason of military service in complying with a court judgment or order, the court may on its own motion and shall on application by the servicemember—(1) stay the execution of any judgment or order entered against the servicemember; and

(2) vacate or stay an attachment or garnishment of property, money, or debts in the possession of the servicemember or a third party, whether before or after judgment.


(b) ApplicabilityThis section applies to an action or proceeding commenced in a court against a servicemember before or during the period of the servicemember’s military service or within 90 days after such service terminates.


(Oct. 17, 1940, ch. 888, title II, § 204, as added Pub. L. 108–189, § 1, Dec. 19, 2003, 117 Stat. 2843.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 524 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 204 of act Oct. 17, 1940, ch. 888, art. II, 54 Stat. 1181, related to duration and term of stays and codefendants not in service, prior to the general amendment of this Act by Pub. L. 108–189. See section 3935 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable to any case not final before Dec. 19, 2003, see section 3 of Pub. L. 108–189, set out as a note under section 3901 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3934_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court action upon material affect determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Court action upon material affect determination If a servicemember, in the opinion of the court, is materially affected by reason of military service in complying with a court judgment or order, the court may on its own motion and shall on application by the servicemember—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3934_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicability This section applies to an action or proceeding commenced in a court against a servicemember before or during the period of the servicemember’s military service or within 90 days after such service terminates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>