<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3937" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3937/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3937/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3937"><akn:num>3937</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum rate of interest on debts incurred before military service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3937. Maximum rate of interest on debts incurred before military service(a) Interest rate limitation(1) Limitation to 6 percentAn obligation or liability bearing interest at a rate in excess of 6 percent per year that is incurred by a servicemember, or the servicemember and the servicemember’s spouse jointly, before the servicemember enters military service shall not bear interest at a rate in excess of 6 percent—(A) during the period of military service and one year thereafter, in the case of an obligation or liability consisting of a mortgage, trust deed, or other security in the nature of a mortgage; or

(B) during the period of military service, in the case of any other obligation or liability.


(2) Forgiveness of interest in excess of 6 percentInterest at a rate in excess of 6 percent per year that would otherwise be incurred but for the prohibition in paragraph (1) is forgiven.


(3) Prevention of acceleration of principalThe amount of any periodic payment due from a servicemember under the terms of the instrument that created an obligation or liability covered by this section shall be reduced by the amount of the interest forgiven under paragraph (2) that is allocable to the period for which such payment is made.



(b) Implementation of limitation(1) Proof of military service(A) In generalNot later than 180 days after the date of a servicemember’s termination or release from military service, in order for an obligation or liability of the servicemember to be subject to the interest rate limitation in subsection (a), the servicemember shall provide to the creditor written notice and a copy of—(i) the military orders calling the servicemember to military service and any orders further extending military service; or

(ii) any other appropriate indicator of military service, including a certified letter from a commanding officer.


(B) Independent verification by creditor(i) In generalA creditor may use, in lieu of notice and documentation under subparagraph </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3937_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest rate limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Interest rate limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3937_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Implementation of limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3937_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creditor protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Creditor protection A court may grant a creditor relief from the limitations of this section if, in the opinion of the court, the ability of the servicemember to pay interest upon the obligation or liability at a rate in excess of 6 percent per year is not materially affected by reason of the servicemember’s military service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3937_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3937_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Penalty Whoever knowingly violates subsection (a) shall be fined as provided in title 18, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>