<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3973" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3973/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/3973/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3973"><akn:num>3973</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for insurance protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3973. Application for insurance protection(a) Application procedureAn application for protection under this subchapter shall—(1) be in writing and signed by the insured, the insured’s legal representative, or the insured’s beneficiary, as the case may be;

(2) identify the policy and the insurer; and

(3) include an acknowledgement that the insured’s rights under the policy are subject to and modified by the provisions of this subchapter.


(b) Additional requirementsThe Secretary of Veterans Affairs may require additional information from the applicant, the insured and the insurer to determine if the policy is entitled to protection under this subchapter.


(c) Notice to the Secretary by the insurerUpon receipt of the application of the insured, the insurer shall furnish a report concerning the policy to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs as required by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(d) Policy modificationUpon application for protection under this subchapter, the insured and the insurer shall have constructively agreed to any policy modification necessary to give this title full force and effect.


(Oct. 17, 1940, ch. 888, title IV, § 403, as added Pub. L. 108–189, § 1, Dec. 19, 2003, 117 Stat. 2852.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 543 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 403 of act Oct. 17, 1940, ch. 888, art. IV, 54 Stat. 1184; Oct. 6, 1942, ch. 581, § 13, 56 Stat. 775; Pub. L. 102–12, § 9(14), Mar. 18, 1991, 105 Stat. 40, related to determination of policies entitled to protection, notice to parties, and lapse of policies for nonpayment of premiums, prior to the general amendment of this Act by Pub. L. 108–189. See section 3974 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable to any case not final before Dec. 19, 2003, see section 3 of Pub. L. 108–189, set out as a n</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3973_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application procedure An application for protection under this subchapter shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3973_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional requirements The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may require additional information from the applicant, the insured and the insurer to determine if the policy is entitled to protection under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3973_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to the Secretary by the insurer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice to the Secretary by the insurer Upon receipt of the application of the insured, the insurer shall furnish a report concerning the policy to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs as required by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3973_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy modification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Policy modification Upon application for protection under this subchapter, the insured and the insurer shall have constructively agreed to any policy modification necessary to give this title full force and effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>