<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4026" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4026/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4026/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4026"><akn:num>4026</akn:num><akn:heading>Business or trade obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4026. Business or trade obligations(a) Availability of non-business assets to satisfy obligationsIf the trade or business (without regard to the form in which such trade or business is carried out) of a servicemember has an obligation or liability for which the servicemember is personally liable, the assets of the servicemember not held in connection with the trade or business may not be available for satisfaction of the obligation or liability during the servicemember’s military service.


(b) Relief to obligorsUpon application to a court by the holder of an obligation or liability covered by this section, relief granted by this section to a servicemember may be modified as justice and equity require.


(Oct. 17, 1940, ch. 888, title VII, § 706, as added Pub. L. 108–189, § 1, Dec. 19, 2003, 117 Stat. 2865.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 596 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable to any case not final before Dec. 19, 2003, see section 3 of Pub. L. 108–189, set out as a note under section 3901 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4026_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of non-business assets to satisfy obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Availability of non-business assets to satisfy obligations If the trade or business (without regard to the form in which such trade or business is carried out) of a servicemember has an obligation or liability for which the servicemember is personally liable, the assets of the servicemember not held in connection with the trade or business may not be available for satisfaction of the obligation or liability during the servicemember’s military service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4026_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relief to obligors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relief to obligors Upon application to a court by the holder of an obligation or liability covered by this section, relief granted by this section to a servicemember may be modified as justice and equity require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>