<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4101"><akn:num>4101</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4101. Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States(a) Employment of personnel; use of other facilities and servicesThe Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”) may, in accordance with the provisions of the civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, appoint and fix the compensation of such officers, attorneys, and employees, and may make such expenditures, as may be necessary to carry out its functions. Officers and employees of any other department or agency of the Government may, with the consent of the head of such department or agency, be assigned to assist the Commission in carrying out its functions. The Commission may, with the consent of the head of any other department or agency of the Government, utilize the facilities and services of such department or agency in carrying out the functions of the Commission.


(b) Rules and regulations; delegation of functions; time limit on filing of claimsThe Commission may prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary to enable it to carry out its functions, and may delegate functions to any member, officer, or employee of the Commission. The Commission shall give public notice of the time when, and the limit of time within which, claims may be filed, which notice shall be published in the Federal Register. The limit of time within which claims may be filed with the Commission shall in no event be later than March 31, 1952. The Commission shall take immediate action to advise all persons entitled to file claims under the provisions of this subchapter administered by the Commission of their rights under such provisions, and to assist them in the preparation and filing of their claims.


(c) Subpenas; issuance; contempt; witness fees; administration of oaths(1) For the purpose of any hearing, examination, or investigation under this subchapter, the Commission and those employees designated by the Com</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of personnel; use of other facilities and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employment of personnel; use of other facilities and services The Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States (hereinafter referred to as the “Commission”) may, in accordance with the provisions of the civil-service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, appoint and fix the compensation of such officers, attorneys, and employees, and may make such expenditures, as may be necessary to carry out its functions. Officers and employees of any other department or agency of the Government may, with the consent of the head of such department or agency, be assigned to assist the Commission in carrying out its functions. The Commission may, with the consent of the head of any other department or agency of the Government, utilize the facilities and services of such department or agency in carrying out the functions of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations; delegation of functions; time limit on filing of claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rules and regulations; delegation of functions; time limit on filing of claims The Commission may prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary to enable it to carry out its functions, and may delegate functions to any member, officer, or employee of the Commission. The Commission shall give public notice of the time when, and the limit of time within which, claims may be filed, which notice shall be published in the Federal Register. The limit of time within which claims may be filed with the Commission shall in no event be later than March 31, 1952. The Commission shall take immediate action to advise all persons entitled to file claims under the provisions of this subchapter administered by the Commission of their rights under such provisions, and to assist them in the preparation and filing of their claims.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpenas; issuance; contempt; witness fees; administration of oaths</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subpenas; issuance; contempt; witness fees; administration of oaths</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>