<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4215" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4215/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4215/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4215"><akn:num>4215</akn:num><akn:heading>Restitution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4215. Restitution(a) Location and payment of eligible individuals(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (7), the Attorney General shall, subject to the availability of funds appropriated to the Fund for such purpose, pay out of the Fund to each eligible individual the sum of $20,000, unless such individual refuses, in the manner described in paragraph (5), to accept the payment.


(2) Location of eligible individualsThe Attorney General shall identify and locate, without requiring any application for payment and using records already in the possession of the United States Government, each eligible individual. The Attorney General should use funds and resources available to the Attorney General, including those described in subsection (c), to attempt to complete such identification and location within 12 months after August 10, 1988. Any eligible individual may notify the Attorney General that such individual is an eligible individual, and may provide documentation therefor. The Attorney General shall designate an officer or employee to whom such notification and documentation may be sent, shall maintain a list of all individuals who submit such notification and documentation, and shall, subject to the availability of funds appropriated for such purpose, encourage, through a public awareness campaign, each eligible individual to submit his or her current address to such officer or employee. To the extent that resources referred to in the second sentence of this paragraph are not sufficient to complete the identification and location of all eligible individuals, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for such purpose. In any case, the identification and location of all eligible individuals shall be completed within 12 months after the appropriation of funds under the preceding sentence. Failure to be identified and located by the end of the 12-month period specified in the preceding sentence shall not preclude an eligible individual from r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4215_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location and payment of eligible individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Location and payment of eligible individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4215_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Order of payments The Attorney General shall endeavor to make payments under this section to eligible individuals in the order of date of birth (with the oldest individual on August 10, 1988 (or, if applicable, that individual’s survivors under paragraph (8)) receiving full payment first), until all eligible individuals have received payment in full.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4215_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resources for locating eligible individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Resources for locating eligible individuals In attempting to locate any eligible individual, the Attorney General may use any facility or resource of any public or nonprofit organization or any other record, document, or information that may be made available to the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4215_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs not paid from the Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative costs not paid from the Fund No costs incurred by the Attorney General in carrying out this section shall be paid from the Fund or set off against, or otherwise deducted from, any payment under this section to any eligible individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4215_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of duties of Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of duties of Attorney General The duties of the Attorney General under this section shall cease 180 days after the Fund terminates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4215_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification of treatment of payments under other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Clarification of treatment of payments under other laws Amounts paid to an eligible individual under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4215_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of United States limited to amount in Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Liability of United States limited to amount in Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4215_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>