<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4237" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4237/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4237/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4237"><akn:num>4237</akn:num><akn:heading>Attu Island restitution program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4237. Attu Island restitution program(a) Purpose of sectionIn accordance with section 1132(c) of title 16, the public lands on Attu Island, Alaska, within the National Wildlife Refuge System have been designated as wilderness by section 702(1) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (94 Stat. 2417; 16 U.S.C. 1132 note). In order to make restitution for the loss of traditional Aleut lands and village properties on Attu Island, while preserving the present designation of Attu Island lands as part of the National Wilderness Preservation System, compensation to the Aleut people, in lieu of the conveyance of Attu Island, shall be provided in accordance with this section.


(b) Acreage determinationNot later than 90 days after August 10, 1988, the Secretary shall, in accordance with this subsection, determine the total acreage of land on Attu Island, Alaska, that, at the beginning of World War II, was subject to traditional use by the Aleut villagers of that island for subsistence and other purposes. In making such acreage determination, the Secretary shall establish a base acreage of not less than 35,000 acres within that part of eastern Attu Island traditionally used by the Aleut people, and shall, from the best available information, including information that may be submitted by representatives of the Aleut people, identify any such additional acreage on Attu Island that was subject to such use. The combination of such base acreage and such additional acreage shall constitute the acreage determination upon which payment to the Corporation under this section is based. The Secretary shall promptly notify the Corporation of the results of the acreage determination made under this subsection.


(c) Valuation(1) Determination of valueNot later than 120 days after August 10, 1988, the Secretary shall determine the value of the Attu Island acreage determined under subsection (b), except that—(A) such acreage may not be valued at less than $350 per acre nor m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4237_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose of section In accordance with section 1132(c) of title 16, the public lands on Attu Island, Alaska, within the National Wildlife Refuge System have been designated as wilderness by section 702(1) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (94 Stat. 2417; 16 U.S.C. 1132 note). In order to make restitution for the loss of traditional Aleut lands and village properties on Attu Island, while preserving the present designation of Attu Island lands as part of the National Wilderness Preservation System, compensation to the Aleut people, in lieu of the conveyance of Attu Island, shall be provided in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4237_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acreage determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acreage determination Not later than 90 days after August 10, 1988, the Secretary shall, in accordance with this subsection, determine the total acreage of land on Attu Island, Alaska, that, at the beginning of World War II, was subject to traditional use by the Aleut villagers of that island for subsistence and other purposes. In making such acreage determination, the Secretary shall establish a base acreage of not less than 35,000 acres within that part of eastern Attu Island traditionally used by the Aleut people, and shall, from the best available information, including information that may be submitted by representatives of the Aleut people, identify any such additional acreage on Attu Island that was subject to such use. The combination of such base acreage and such additional acreage shall constitute the acreage determination upon which payment to the Corporation under this section is based. The Secretary shall promptly notify the Corporation of the results of the acreage de</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4237_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Valuation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4237_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>In lieu compensation payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In lieu compensation payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4237_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Village site conveyance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Village site conveyance The Secretary may convey to the Corporation all right, title, and interest of the United States to the surface estate of the traditional Aleut village site on Attu Island, Alaska (consisting of approximately 10 acres) and to the surface estate of a parcel of land consisting of all land outside such village that is within 660 feet of any point on the boundary of such village. The conveyance may be made under the authority contained in section 1613(h)(1) of title 43, except that after August 10, 1988, no site on Attu Island, Alaska, other than such traditional Aleut village site and such parcel of land, may be conveyed to the Corporation under such section 1613(h)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4237_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 to the Secretary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>