<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4302"><akn:num>4302</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4302. Definitions
The word “enemy,” as used herein, shall be deemed to mean, for the purposes of such trading and of this chapter—(a) Any individual, partnership, or other body of individuals, of any nationality, resident within the territory (including that occupied by the military and naval forces) of any nation with which the United States is at war, or resident outside the United States and doing business within such territory, and any corporation incorporated within such territory of any nation with which the United States is at war or incorporated within any country other than the United States and doing business within such territory.

(b) The government of any nation with which the United States is at war, or any political or municipal subdivision thereof, or any officer, official, agent, or agency thereof.

(c) Such other individuals, or body or class of individuals, as may be natives, citizens, or subjects of any nation with which the United States is at war, other than citizens of the United States, wherever resident or wherever doing business, as the President, if he shall find the safety of the United States or the successful prosecution of the war shall so require, may, by proclamation, include within the term “enemy.”The words “ally of enemy,” as used herein, shall be deemed to mean—


(a) Any individual, partnership, or other body of individuals, of any nationality, resident within the territory (including that occupied by the military and naval forces) of any nation which is an ally of a nation with which the United States is at war, or resident outside the United States and doing business within such territory, and any corporation incorporated within such territory of such ally nation, or incorporated within any country other than the United States and doing business within such territory.

(b) The government of any nation which is an ally of a nation with which the United States is at war, or any political or municipal subdivision of such ally n</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any individual, partnership, or other body of individuals, of any nationality, resident within the territory (including that occupied by the military and naval forces) of any nation with which the United States is at war, or resident outside the United States and doing business within such territory, and any corporation incorporated within such territory of any nation with which the United States is at war or incorporated within any country other than the United States and doing business within such territory.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The government of any nation with which the United States is at war, or any political or municipal subdivision thereof, or any officer, official, agent, or agency thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Such other individuals, or body or class of individuals, as may be natives, citizens, or subjects of any nation with which the United States is at war, other than citizens of the United States, wherever resident or wherever doing business, as the President, if he shall find the safety of the United States or the successful prosecution of the war shall so require, may, by proclamation, include within the term “enemy.”The words “ally of enemy,” as used herein, shall be deemed to mean—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any individual, partnership, or other body of individuals, of any nationality, resident within the territory (including that occupied by the military and naval forces) of any nation which is an ally of a nation with which the United States is at war, or resident outside the United States and doing business within such territory, and any corporation incorporated within such territory of such ally nation, or incorporated within any country other than the United States and doing business within such territory.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The government of any nation which is an ally of a nation with which the United States is at war, or any political or municipal subdivision of such ally nation, or any officer, official, agent, or agency thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Such other individuals, or body or class of individuals, as may be natives, citizens, or subjects of any nation which is an ally of a nation with which the United States is at war, other than citizens of the United States, wherever resident or wherever doing business, as the President, if he shall find the safety of the United States or the successful prosecution of the war shall so require, may, by proclamation, include within the term “ally of enemy.”The word “person,” as used herein, shall be deemed to mean an individual, partnership, association, company, or other unincorporated body of individuals, or corporation or body politic.
The words “United States,” as used herein, shall be deemed to mean all land and water, continental or insular, in any way within the jurisdiction of the United States or occupied by the military or naval forces thereof.
The words “the beginning of the war,” as used herein, shall be deemed to mean midnight ending the day on which Congress has declared </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pay, satisfy, compromise, or give security for the payment or satisfaction of any debt or obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Draw, accept, pay, present for acceptance or payment, or indorse any negotiable instrument or chose in action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enter into, carry on, complete, or perform any contract, agreement, or obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Buy or sell, loan or extend credit, trade in, deal with, exchange, transmit, transfer, assign, or otherwise dispose of, or receive any form of property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>