<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4306"><akn:num>4306</akn:num><akn:heading>Alien Property Custodian; general powers and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4306. Alien Property Custodian; general powers and duties
The President is authorized to appoint, prescribe the duties of, and fix the salary of an official to be known as the alien property custodian, who shall be empowered to receive all money and property in the United States due or belonging to an enemy, or ally of enemy, which may be paid, conveyed, transferred, assigned, or delivered to said custodian under the provisions of this chapter; and to hold, administer, and account for the same under the general direction of the President and as provided in this chapter. The President may further employ in the District of Columbia and elsewhere and fix the compensation of such clerks, attorneys, investigators, accountants, and other employees as he may find necessary for the due administration of the provisions of this chapter; Provided, That such clerks, investigators, accountants, and other employees shall be appointed from lists of eligibles to be supplied by the Civil Service Commission 11 See Transfer of Functions note below. and in accordance with the civil-service law.
(Oct. 6, 1917, ch. 106, § 6, 40 Stat. 415; Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 235, June 6, 1972, 86 Stat. 214; Pub. L. 94–273, § 11(5), Apr. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 378; Pub. L. 100–418, title II, § 2501(b), Aug. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 1371.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning act Oct. 6, 1917, ch. 106, 40 Stat. 411, known as the Trading with the enemy Act, also known as the Trading with the Enemy Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 4301 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 6 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.
Provisions that limited the salary of the alien property custodian to not more than $5,000 per annum have been omitted as obsolet</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>