<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4336" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4336/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4336/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4336"><akn:num>4336</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of properties or interests of Germany and Japan and their nationals; proceeds covered into</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4336. Retention of properties or interests of Germany and Japan and their nationals; proceeds covered into Treasury; ex gratia payment to Switzerland(a) Retention of properties or interests of Germany and Japan and their nationalsNo property or interest therein of Germany, Japan, or any national of either such country vested in or transferred to any officer or agency of the Government at any time after December 17, 1941, pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, shall be returned to former owners thereof or their successors in interest, and the United States shall not pay compensation for any such property or interest therein. The net proceeds remaining upon the completion of administration, liquidation, and disposition pursuant to the provisions of this chapter of any such property or interest therein shall be covered into the Treasury at the earliest practicable date. Nothing in this section shall be construed to repeal or otherwise affect the operation of the provisions of section 4329, 4337, 4338, 4339 or 4340 of this title or of the Philippine Property Act of 1946 [22 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.].


(b) Cover into Treasury of sums received by Attorney GeneralThe Attorney General shall cover into the Treasury, to the credit of miscellaneous receipts, all sums from property vested in or transferred to the Attorney General under this chapter—(1) which the Attorney General receives after August 23, 1988, or

(2) which the Attorney General received before that date and which, as of that date, the Attorney General had not covered into the Treasury for deposit in the War Claims Fund, other than any such sums which the Attorney General determines in his or her discretion are the subject matter of any judicial action or proceeding.


(c) Ex gratia payment to Government of SwitzerlandNotwithstanding any of the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Attorney General is authorized to pay from property vested in or transferred to the Attorney General under t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of properties or interests of Germany and Japan and their nationals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Retention of properties or interests of Germany and Japan and their nationals No property or interest therein of Germany, Japan, or any national of either such country vested in or transferred to any officer or agency of the Government at any time after December 17, 1941, pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, shall be returned to former owners thereof or their successors in interest, and the United States shall not pay compensation for any such property or interest therein. The net proceeds remaining upon the completion of administration, liquidation, and disposition pursuant to the provisions of this chapter of any such property or interest therein shall be covered into the Treasury at the earliest practicable date. Nothing in this section shall be construed to repeal or otherwise affect the operation of the provisions of section 4329, 4337, 4338, 4339 or 4340 of this title or of the Philippine Property Act of 1946 [22 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cover into Treasury of sums received by Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cover into Treasury of sums received by Attorney General The Attorney General shall cover into the Treasury, to the credit of miscellaneous receipts, all sums from property vested in or transferred to the Attorney General under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex gratia payment to Government of Switzerland</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ex gratia payment to Government of Switzerland Notwithstanding any of the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Attorney General is authorized to pay from property vested in or transferred to the Attorney General under this chapter, the sum of $20,000 as an ex gratia payment to the Government of Switzerland in accordance with the terms of the agreement entered into by that Government and the Government of the United States on March 12, 1980.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>