<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4516" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4516/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4516/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4516"><akn:num>4516</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of energy as a strategic and critical material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4516. Designation of energy as a strategic and critical material
For purposes of this chapter, “energy” shall be designated as a “strategic and critical material” after June 30, 1980: Provided, That no provision of this chapter shall, by virtue of such designation 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. grant any new direct or indirect authority to the President for the mandatory allocation or pricing of any fuel or feedstock (including, but not limited to, crude oil, residual fuel oil, any refined petroleum product, natural gas, or coal) or electricity or any other form of energy.
(Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932, title I, § 106, as added Pub. L. 96–294, title I, § 103, June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 617; amended Pub. L. 111–67, § 5, Sept. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 2009.)

Termination of SectionFor termination of section, see section 4564(a) of this title.

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning act Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932, 64 Stat. 798, known as the Defense Production Act of 1950, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 4501 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 2076 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments2009—Pub. L. 111–67 substituted “such designation” for “such designation—” and “energy.” for “energy; or”, struck out par. (1) designation before “grant any new direct or indirect authority to the President for”, and struck out par. (2) which read as follows: “grant any new direct or indirect authority to the President to engage in the production of energy in any manner whatsoever (such as oil and gas exploration and development, or any energy facility construction), except as expressly provided in sections 305 and 306 [of act Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932] for synthetic fuel production.”

Statutory Notes and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>