<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4534" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4534/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4534/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4534"><akn:num>4534</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Production Act Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4534. Defense Production Act Fund(a) Establishment of FundThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a separate fund to be known as the “Defense Production Act Fund” (in this section referred to as the “Fund”).


(b) Moneys in FundThere shall be credited to the Fund—(1) all moneys appropriated for the Fund, as authorized by section 4561 of this title; and

(2) all moneys received by the Fund on transactions entered into pursuant to section 4533 of this title.


(c) Use of FundThe Fund shall be available to carry out the provisions and purposes of this subchapter, subject to the limitations set forth in this chapter and in appropriations Acts.


(d) Duration of FundMoneys in the Fund shall remain available until expended.


(e) Fund balanceThe Fund balance at the close of each fiscal year shall not exceed $750,000,000, excluding any moneys appropriated to the Fund during that fiscal year or obligated funds. If, at the close of any fiscal year, the Fund balance exceeds $750,000,000, the amount in excess of $750,000,000 shall be paid into the general fund of the Treasury.


(f) Fund managerThe President shall designate a Fund manager. The duties of the Fund manager shall include—(1) determining the liability of the Fund in accordance with subsection (g);

(2) ensuring the visibility and accountability of transactions engaged in through the Fund; and

(3) reporting to the Congress each year regarding activities of the Fund during the previous fiscal year.


(g) Liabilities against FundWhen any agreement entered into pursuant to this subchapter after December 31, 1991, imposes any contingent liability upon the United States, such liability shall be considered an obligation against the Fund.


(Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932, title III, § 304, as added Pub. L. 111–67, § 7, Sept. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 2017.)

Termination of SectionFor termination of section, see section 4564(a) of this title.

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4534_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Fund There is established in the Treasury of the United States a separate fund to be known as the “Defense Production Act Fund” (in this section referred to as the “Fund”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4534_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Moneys in Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Moneys in Fund There shall be credited to the Fund—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4534_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of Fund The Fund shall be available to carry out the provisions and purposes of this subchapter, subject to the limitations set forth in this chapter and in appropriations Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4534_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duration of Fund Moneys in the Fund shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4534_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund balance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fund balance The Fund balance at the close of each fiscal year shall not exceed $750,000,000, excluding any moneys appropriated to the Fund during that fiscal year or obligated funds. If, at the close of any fiscal year, the Fund balance exceeds $750,000,000, the amount in excess of $750,000,000 shall be paid into the general fund of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4534_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund manager</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fund manager The President shall designate a Fund manager. The duties of the Fund manager shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4534_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liabilities against Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Liabilities against Fund When any agreement entered into pursuant to this subchapter after December 31, 1991, imposes any contingent liability upon the United States, such liability shall be considered an obligation against the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>