<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4551" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4551/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4551/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4551"><akn:num>4551</akn:num><akn:heading>Small business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4551. Small business(a) ParticipationSmall business concerns shall be given the maximum practicable opportunity to participate as contractors, and subcontractors at various tiers, in all programs to maintain and strengthen the Nation’s industrial base and technology base undertaken pursuant to this chapter.


(b) Administration of chapterIn administering the programs, implementing regulations, policies, and procedures under this chapter, requests, applications, or appeals from small business concerns shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be expeditiously handled.


(c) Advisory committee participationRepresentatives of small business concerns shall be afforded the maximum opportunity to participate in such advisory committees as may be established pursuant to this chapter.


(d) InformationInformation about this chapter and activities undertaken in accordance with this chapter shall be made available to small business concerns.


(e) Allocations under section 4511Whenever the President makes a determination to exercise any authority to allocate any material pursuant to section 4511 of this title, small business concerns shall be accorded, to the extent practicable, a fair share of such material, in proportion to the share received by such business concerns under normal conditions, giving such special consideration as may be possible to emerging small business concerns.


(Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932, title VII, § 701, 64 Stat. 815; July 31, 1951, ch. 275, title I, § 108, 65 Stat. 138; June 30, 1953, ch. 171, § 7, 67 Stat. 130; Aug. 9, 1955, ch. 655, §§ 4, 5, 69 Stat. 580; Pub. L. 96–294, title I, § 105(c), June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 633; Pub. L. 102–558, title I, § 131, Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 4209.)

Termination of SectionFor termination of section, see section 4564(a) of this title.

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning act Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932, 64 Stat. 798, known as the Defense Production </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4551_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Participation Small business concerns shall be given the maximum practicable opportunity to participate as contractors, and subcontractors at various tiers, in all programs to maintain and strengthen the Nation’s industrial base and technology base undertaken pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4551_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration of chapter In administering the programs, implementing regulations, policies, and procedures under this chapter, requests, applications, or appeals from small business concerns shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be expeditiously handled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4551_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory committee participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Advisory committee participation Representatives of small business concerns shall be afforded the maximum opportunity to participate in such advisory committees as may be established pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4551_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information Information about this chapter and activities undertaken in accordance with this chapter shall be made available to small business concerns.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4551_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations under section 4511</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allocations under section 4511 Whenever the President makes a determination to exercise any authority to allocate any material pursuant to section 4511 of this title, small business concerns shall be accorded, to the extent practicable, a fair share of such material, in proportion to the share received by such business concerns under normal conditions, giving such special consideration as may be possible to emerging small business concerns.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>