<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4554" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4554/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4554/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4554"><akn:num>4554</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4554. Regulations and orders(a) In generalSubject to section 4559 of this title and subsection (b), the President may prescribe such regulations and issue such orders as the President may determine to be appropriate to carry out this chapter.


(b) Procurement regulationsAny procurement regulation, procedure, or form issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall be issued pursuant to section 25 of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act [now 41 U.S.C. 1302, 1303], and shall conform to any governmentwide procurement policy or regulation issued pursuant to section 6 or 25 of that Act [see 41 U.S.C. 1121 et seq., 1302, 1303].


(Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932, title VII, § 704, 64 Stat. 816; July 31, 1951, ch. 275, title I, § 109(c), 65 Stat. 139; Pub. L. 102–558, title I, § 134, Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 4212.)

Termination of SectionFor termination of section, see section 4564(a) of this title.

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning act Sept. 8, 1950, ch. 932, 64 Stat. 798, known as the Defense Production Act of 1950, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 4501 of this title and Tables.
Sections 6 and 25 of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act, referred to in subsec. (b), were sections 6 and 25 of Pub. L. 93–400, which were classified to sections 405 and 421, respectively, of former Title 41, Public Contracts, and were repealed and largely restated in subchapter II (§ 1121 et seq.) of chapter 11 and as sections 1302 and 1303 of Title 41, Public Contracts, by Pub. L. 111–350, §§ 3, 7(b), Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 3677, 3855.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 2154 of the former Appendix to this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments1992—Pub. L. 102–558 amended section generally, substituting present provisions for provisions authorizing promulgation </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4554_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to section 4559 of this title and subsection (b), the President may prescribe such regulations and issue such orders as the President may determine to be appropriate to carry out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4554_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procurement regulations Any procurement regulation, procedure, or form issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall be issued pursuant to section 25 of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act [now 41 U.S.C. 1302, 1303], and shall conform to any governmentwide procurement policy or regulation issued pursuant to section 6 or 25 of that Act [see 41 U.S.C. 1121 et seq., 1302, 1303].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>