<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4567" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4567/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4567/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4567"><akn:num>4567</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Production Act Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4567. Defense Production Act Committee(a) Committee establishedThere is established the Defense Production Act Committee (in this section referred to as the “Committee”), which shall coordinate and plan for on 11 So in original. The word “on” probably should not appear. the effective use of the priorities and allocations authorities under this chapter by the departments, agencies, and independent establishments of the Federal Government to which the President has delegated authority under this chapter.


(b) Membership(1) In general.—The members of the Committee shall be—(A) the head of each Federal agency to which the President has delegated authority under this chapter; and

(B) the Chairperson of the Council of Economic Advisors.


(2) The Chairperson of the Committee shall be the head of the agency to which the President has delegated primary responsibility for government-wide coordination of the authorities in this chapter.


(c) Coordination of Committee activitiesThe Chairperson shall appoint one person to coordinate all of the activities of the Committee, and such person shall—(1) be a full-time employee of the Federal Government;

(2) report to the Chairperson; and

(3) carry out such activities relating to the Committee as the Chairperson may determine appropriate.


(d) ReportThe Committee shall issue a report each year by March 31 to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report signed by the Chairperson that contains—(1) a description of the contingency planning by each department, agency, or independent establishment of the Federal Government to which the President has delegated authority under this chapter for events that might require the use of the priorities and allocations authorities;

(2) recommendations for the effective use of the priorities and allocations authorities in this chapter in a manner consistent with the statement of policy under</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee established</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Committee established There is established the Defense Production Act Committee (in this section referred to as the “Committee”), which shall coordinate and plan for on 11 So in original. The word “on” probably should not appear. the effective use of the priorities and allocations authorities under this chapter by the departments, agencies, and independent establishments of the Federal Government to which the President has delegated authority under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of Committee activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination of Committee activities The Chairperson shall appoint one person to coordinate all of the activities of the Committee, and such person shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report The Committee shall issue a report each year by March 31 to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report signed by the Chairperson that contains—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chapter 10 of title 5 The provisions of chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>