<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4568" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4568/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4568/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4568"><akn:num>4568</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report on impact of offsets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4568. Annual report on impact of offsets(a) Report required(1) In generalThe President shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, a detailed annual report on the impact of offsets on the defense preparedness, industrial competitiveness, employment, and trade of the United States.


(2) Duties of the Secretary of CommerceThe Secretary of Commerce (hereafter in this subsection referred to as the “Secretary”) shall—(A) prepare the report required by paragraph (1);

(B) consult with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of State, and the United States Trade Representative in connection with the preparation of such report; and

(C) function as the President’s Executive Agent for carrying out this section.



(b) Interagency studies and related data(1) Purpose of reportEach report required under subsection (a) shall identify the cumulative effects of offset agreements on—(A) the full range of domestic defense productive capability (with special attention paid to the firms serving as lower-tier subcontractors or suppliers); and

(B) the domestic defense technology base as a consequence of the technology transfers associated with such offset agreements.


(2) Use of dataData developed or compiled by any agency while conducting any interagency study or other independent study or analysis shall be made available to the Secretary to facilitate the execution of the Secretary’s responsibilities with respect to trade offset and countertrade policy development.



(c) Notice of offset agreements(1) In generalIf a United States firm enters into a contract for the sale of a weapon system or defense-related item to a foreign country or foreign firm and such contract is subject to an offset agreement exceeding $5,000,000 in value, such firm shall furnish to the official designated in the regulations promulgated pursuant to paragraph (2) in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4568_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Report required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4568_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency studies and related data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interagency studies and related data</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4568_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of offset agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice of offset agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4568_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contents of report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4568_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of annual report in negotiations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Utilization of annual report in negotiations The findings and recommendations of the reports required by subsection (a), and any interagency reports and analyses shall be considered by representatives of the United States during bilateral and multilateral negotiations to minimize the adverse effects of offsets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>