<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4612" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4612/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4612/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4612"><akn:num>4612</akn:num><akn:heading>Missile proliferation control violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4612. Missile proliferation control violations(a) Violations by United States persons(1) Sanctions(A) If the President determines that a United States person knowingly—(i) exports, transfers, or otherwise engages in the trade of any item on the MTCR Annex, in violation of the provisions of section 38 (22 U.S.C. 2778) or chapter 7 of the Arms Export Control Act [22 U.S.C. 2797 et seq.], section 4604 or 4605 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, or any regulations or orders issued under any such provisions,

(ii) conspires to or attempts to engage in such export, transfer, or trade, or

(iii) facilitates such export, transfer, or trade by any other person,


then the President shall impose the applicable sanctions described in subparagraph (B).

(B) The sanctions which apply to a United States person under subparagraph (A) are the following:(i) If the item on the MTCR Annex involved in the export, transfer, or trade is missile equipment or technology within category II of the MTCR Annex, then the President shall deny to such United States person, for a period of 2 years, licenses for the transfer of missile equipment or technology controlled under this chapter.

(ii) If the item on the MTCR Annex involved in the export, transfer, or trade is missile equipment or technology within category I of the MTCR Annex, then the President shall deny to such United States person, for a period of not less than 2 years, all licenses for items the export of which is controlled under this chapter.



(2) Discretionary sanctionsIn the case of any determination referred to in paragraph (1), the Secretary may pursue any other appropriate penalties under section 4610 1 of this title.


(3) WaiverThe President may waive the imposition of sanctions under paragraph (1) on a person with respect to a product or service if the President certifies to the Congress that—(A) the product or service is essential to the national security of the United States; and

(B) such person is </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4612_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations by United States persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Violations by United States persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4612_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers of missile equipment or technology by foreign persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfers of missile equipment or technology by foreign persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4612_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section and subsections (k) and (l) of section 4605 1 of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>