<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4815" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4815/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4815/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4815"><akn:num>4815</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4815. Licensing(a) In generalThe Secretary shall, consistent with delegations as described in section 4814 of this title, establish a procedure to license or otherwise authorize the export, reexport, and in-country transfer of items controlled under this subchapter in order to carry out the policy set forth in section 4811 of this title and the requirements set forth in section 4812(b) of this title. The procedure shall ensure that—(1) license applications and other requests for authorization are considered and decisions made with the participation of appropriate Federal agencies, as appropriate; and

(2) licensing decisions are made in an expeditious manner, with transparency to applicants on the status of license and other authorization processing and the reason for denying any license or request for authorization.


(b) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that the Secretary should make best efforts to ensure that an accurate, consistent, and timely evaluation and processing of licenses or other requests for authorization to export, reexport, or in-country transfer items controlled under this subchapter is generally accomplished within 30 days from the date of such license request.


(c) FeesNo fee may be charged in connection with the submission, processing, or consideration of any application for a license or other authorization or other request made in connection with any regulation in effect under the authority of this subchapter.


(d) Additional procedural requirements(1) In generalThe procedure required under subsection (a) shall provide for the assessment of the impact of a proposed export of an item on the United States defense industrial base and the denial of an application for a license or a request for an authorization of any export that would have a significant negative impact on such defense industrial base, as described in paragraph (3).


(2) Information from applicantThe procedure required under subsection (a) shall also require an app</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4815_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall, consistent with delegations as described in section 4814 of this title, establish a procedure to license or otherwise authorize the export, reexport, and in-country transfer of items controlled under this subchapter in order to carry out the policy set forth in section 4811 of this title and the requirements set forth in section 4812(b) of this title. The procedure shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4815_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary should make best efforts to ensure that an accurate, consistent, and timely evaluation and processing of licenses or other requests for authorization to export, reexport, or in-country transfer items controlled under this subchapter is generally accomplished within 30 days from the date of such license request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4815_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fees No fee may be charged in connection with the submission, processing, or consideration of any application for a license or other authorization or other request made in connection with any regulation in effect under the authority of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4815_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional procedural requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional procedural requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4815_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>