<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4825" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4825/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4825/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4825"><akn:num>4825</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4825. Effect on other acts(a) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this subchapter, nothing contained in this subchapter shall be construed to modify, repeal, supersede, or otherwise affect the provisions of any other laws authorizing control over the export or reexport of any item.


(b) Coordination of controls(1) In generalThe authority granted to the President under this subchapter shall be exercised in such manner so as to achieve effective coordination with the authority exercised under section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2778) and all other export control and sanctions authorities exercised by Federal departments and agencies, particularly the Department of State, the Department of the Treasury, and the Department of Energy.


(2) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that in order to achieve effective coordination described in paragraph (1), such Federal departments and agencies—(A) should continuously work to create enforceable regulations with respect to the export, reexport, and in-country transfer by United States and foreign persons of commodities, software, technology, and services to various end uses and end users for foreign policy and national security reasons;

(B) should regularly work to reduce complexity in the system, including complexity caused merely by the existence of structural, definitional, and other non-policy based differences between and among different export control and sanctions systems; and

(C) should coordinate controls on items exported, reexported, or in-country transferred in connection with a foreign military sale under chapter 2 of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2761 et seq.) or a commercial sale under section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act [22 U.S.C. 2778] to reduce as much unnecessary administrative burden as possible that is a result of differences between the exercise of those two authorities.



(c) Nonproliferation controlsNothing in this subchapter shall be construed to super</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4825_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, nothing contained in this subchapter shall be construed to modify, repeal, supersede, or otherwise affect the provisions of any other laws authorizing control over the export or reexport of any item.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4825_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of controls</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination of controls</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4825_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonproliferation controls</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nonproliferation controls Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to supersede the procedures published by the President pursuant to section 2139a(c) of title 42.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>