<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4851" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4851/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/4851/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4851"><akn:num>4851</akn:num><akn:heading>Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4851. Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security(a) Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and SecurityThe President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, an Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, who shall carry out—(1) all functions of the Secretary under this chapter; and

(2) all functions delegated to the Under Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.


(b) ReferenceOn and after August 13, 2018, any reference in any law or regulation to the Under Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration shall be deemed to be a reference to the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security.


(c) Omitted

(d) Continuation in officeThe individual serving as Under Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration on the day before August 13, 2018, may serve as the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security on and after that date without the need for renomination or reappointment.


(Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title XVII, § 1781, Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 2238; Pub. L. 116–6, div. H, title II, § 205(a), Feb. 15, 2019, 133 Stat. 476.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle B (§§ 1741–1781) of title XVII of div. A of Pub. L. 115–232, Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 2208, known as the Export Control Reform Act of 2018, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of subtitle B to the Code, see section 1741 of Pub. L. 115–232, set out as a Short Title note under section 4801 of this title and Tables.
The date of the enactment of this Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), probably means the date of enactment of Pub. L. 115–232, which enacted this section and was approved Aug. 13, 2018.

Codification
Section is comprised of section 1781 of Pub. L. 115–232. Subsec. (c) of section 1781 of Pub. L. 115–232 amended section 5314 of Titl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security The President shall appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, an Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, who shall carry out—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reference On and after August 13, 2018, any reference in any law or regulation to the Under Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration shall be deemed to be a reference to the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation in office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Continuation in office The individual serving as Under Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration on the day before August 13, 2018, may serve as the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security on and after that date without the need for renomination or reappointment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>