<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/811...826" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/811...826/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/811...826/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_811___826"><akn:num>811...826</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 92–128, § 2(a), Sept. 25, 1971, 85 Stat. 348</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 811 to 826. Repealed. Pub. L. 92–128, § 2(a), Sept. 25, 1971, 85 Stat. 348

Section 811, act Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1024, title II, § 101, 64 Stat. 1019, related to Congressional finding of necessity.


Section 812, act Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1024, title II, § 102, 64 Stat. 1021, related to declaration of “internal security emergency” by the President, events warranting the declaration, and period of existence.


Section 813, act Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1024, title II, § 103, 64 Stat. 1021, related to detention during emergency and to release.


Section 814, act Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1024, title II, § 104, 64 Stat. 1022, related to procedure for apprehension and detention, providing in subsecs. (a) to (h), respectively, for warrants and applications; service of warrants and apprehension, and copies for persons apprehended; places of confinement, provision for transportation, food, shelter, etc., and supervision; preliminary hearing, rights of detainee, evidence, orders and reports of hearing officer, and appointment of preliminary hearing officers; receipt of additional information upon request of detainee, and revocation or modification of detention order; presentation of evidence in case of Board or court review and right to withhold certain information; regulations by Attorney General and exclusion of forced labor and confinement with criminals; and bimonthly reports to President and Congress during emergency.


Section 815, act Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1024, title II, § 105, 64 Stat. 1023, related to the Detention Review Board, providing in subsecs. (a) to (d), respectively, for creation of Board, membership, terms, designation of Chairman, and removal; Board divisions, vacancies, powers of remaining members, quorums, official seal, and judicial notice thereof; reports to Congress and its contents; and dissolution upon termination of emergency, release of detainees, conclusion of proceedings, and subsequent establishment.


Section 816, act Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1024, title II,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>