<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/98g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/98g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/98g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_98g"><akn:num>98g</akn:num><akn:heading>Materials development and research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 98g. Materials development and research(a) Development, mining, preparation, treatment, and utilization of ores and other mineral substances(1) The President shall make scientific, technologic, and economic investigations concerning the development, mining, preparation, treatment, and utilization of ores and other mineral substances that (A) are found in the United States, its territories or possessions, or in a reliable source 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. (B) are essential to the national defense, industrial, and essential civilian needs of the United States, and (C) are found in known domestic sources in inadequate quantities or grades.

(2) Such investigations shall be carried out in order to develop new sources of strategic and critical materials, develop substitutes, or conserve domestic sources and reliable sources of supply for such strategic and critical materials.

(3) Investigations under paragraph (1) may be carried out on public lands and, with the consent of the owner, on privately owned lands for the purpose of exploring and determining the extent and quality of deposits of such minerals, the most suitable methods of mining and beneficiating such minerals, and the cost at which the minerals or metals may be produced.


(b) Development of sources of supplies of agricultural materials; use of agricultural commodities for manufacture of materialsThe President shall make scientific, technologic, and economic investigations of the feasibility of developing domestic sources of supplies of any agricultural material or for using agricultural commodities for the manufacture of any material determined pursuant to section 98b(a) of this title to be a strategic and critical material or substitutes therefor.


(c) Development of sources of supply of other materials; development or use of alternative methods for refining or processing materials in stockpileThe President shall make scientific, technologic, and economic investigations c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development, mining, preparation, treatment, and utilization of ores and other mineral substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development, mining, preparation, treatment, and utilization of ores and other mineral substances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of sources of supplies of agricultural materials; use of agricultural commodities for manufacture of materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development of sources of supplies of agricultural materials; use of agricultural commodities for manufacture of materials The President shall make scientific, technologic, and economic investigations of the feasibility of developing domestic sources of supplies of any agricultural material or for using agricultural commodities for the manufacture of any material determined pursuant to section 98b(a) of this title to be a strategic and critical material or substitutes therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of sources of supply of other materials; development or use of alternative methods for refining or processing materials in stockpile</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Development of sources of supply of other materials; development or use of alternative methods for refining or processing materials in stockpile The President shall make scientific, technologic, and economic investigations concerning the feasibility of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and contracts to encourage conservation of strategic and critical materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grants and contracts to encourage conservation of strategic and critical materials The President shall encourage the conservation of domestic sources of any material determined pursuant to section 98b(a) of this title to be a strategic and critical material by making grants or awarding contracts for research regarding the development of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>