<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/98h–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/98h–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/50/98h–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_98h_5"><akn:num>98h–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Biennial report on stockpile requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 98h–5. Biennial report on stockpile requirements(a) In generalNot later than January 15 of every other year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on stockpile requirements. Each such report shall include—(1) the Secretary’s recommendations with respect to stockpile requirements; and

(2) the matters required under subsection (b).


(b) National emergency planning assumptionsEach report under this section shall set forth the national emergency planning assumptions used by the Secretary in making the Secretary’s recommendations under subsection (a)(1) with respect to stockpile requirements. The Secretary shall base the national emergency planning assumptions on a military conflict scenario consistent with the scenario used by the Secretary in budgeting and defense planning purposes. The assumptions to be set forth include assumptions relating to each of the following:(1) The length and intensity of the assumed military conflict.

(2) The military force structure to be mobilized.

(3) The losses anticipated from enemy action.

(4) The military, industrial, and essential civilian requirements to support the national emergency.

(5) The availability of supplies of strategic and critical materials from foreign sources during the mobilization period, the military conflict, and the subsequent period of replenishment, taking into consideration possible shipping losses.

(6) The domestic production of strategic and critical materials during the mobilization period, the military conflict, and the subsequent period of replenishment, taking into consideration possible shipping losses.

(7) Civilian austerity measures required during the mobilization period and military conflict.


(c) Period within which to replace or replenish materialsThe stockpile requirements shall be based on those strategic and critical materials necessary for the United States to replenish or replace, within three years of the end of the military conflict scenario required under su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98h_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than January 15 of every other year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on stockpile requirements. Each such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98h_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National emergency planning assumptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National emergency planning assumptions Each report under this section shall set forth the national emergency planning assumptions used by the Secretary in making the Secretary’s recommendations under subsection (a)(1) with respect to stockpile requirements. The Secretary shall base the national emergency planning assumptions on a military conflict scenario consistent with the scenario used by the Secretary in budgeting and defense planning purposes. The assumptions to be set forth include assumptions relating to each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98h_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period within which to replace or replenish materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Period within which to replace or replenish materials The stockpile requirements shall be based on those strategic and critical materials necessary for the United States to replenish or replace, within three years of the end of the military conflict scenario required under subsection (b), all munitions, combat support items, and weapons systems that would be required after such a military conflict.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98h_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of alternative mobilization periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect of alternative mobilization periods The Secretary shall also include in each report under this section an examination of the effect that alternative mobilization periods under the military conflict scenario required under subsection (b), as well as a range of other military conflict scenarios addressing potentially more serious threats to national security, would have on the Secretary’s recommendations under subsection (a)(1) with respect to stockpile requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98h_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans of President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Plans of President The President shall submit with each report under this section a statement of the plans of the President for meeting the recommendations of the Secretary set forth in the report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_98h_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Briefings on shortfalls in stockpile</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Briefings on shortfalls in stockpile</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>