<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20304"><akn:num>20304</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for collection and delivery of marked absentee ballots of absent overseas uniformed servi</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20304. Procedures for collection and delivery of marked absentee ballots of absent overseas uniformed services voters(a) Establishment of proceduresThe Presidential designee shall establish procedures for collecting marked absentee ballots of absent overseas uniformed services voters in regularly scheduled general elections for Federal office, including absentee ballots prepared by States and the Federal write-in absentee ballot prescribed under section 20303 of this title, and for delivering such marked absentee ballots to the appropriate election officials.


(b) Delivery to appropriate election officials(1) In generalUnder the procedures established under this section, the Presidential designee shall implement procedures that facilitate the delivery of marked absentee ballots of absent overseas uniformed services voters for regularly scheduled general elections for Federal office to the appropriate election officials, in accordance with this section, not later than the date by which an absentee ballot must be received in order to be counted in the election.


(2) Cooperation and coordination with the United States Postal ServiceThe Presidential designee shall carry out this section in cooperation and coordination with the United States Postal Service, and shall provide expedited mail delivery service for all such marked absentee ballots of absent uniformed services voters that are collected on or before the deadline described in paragraph (3) and then transferred to the United States Postal Service.


(3) Deadline described(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the deadline described in this paragraph is noon (in the location in which the ballot is collected) on the seventh day preceding the date of the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office.


(B) Authority to establish alternative deadline for certain locationsIf the Presidential designee determines that the deadline described in subparagraph (A) is not sufficient to ensure tim</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of procedures The Presidential designee shall establish procedures for collecting marked absentee ballots of absent overseas uniformed services voters in regularly scheduled general elections for Federal office, including absentee ballots prepared by States and the Federal write-in absentee ballot prescribed under section 20303 of this title, and for delivering such marked absentee ballots to the appropriate election officials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery to appropriate election officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Delivery to appropriate election officials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach for absent overseas uniformed services voters on procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Outreach for absent overseas uniformed services voters on procedures The Presidential designee shall take appropriate actions to inform individuals who are anticipated to be absent overseas uniformed services voters in a regularly scheduled general election for Federal office to which this section applies of the procedures for the collection and delivery of marked absentee ballots established pursuant to this section, including the manner in which such voters may utilize such procedures for the submittal of marked absentee ballots pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20304_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Absent overseas uniformed services voter defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Absent overseas uniformed services voter defined In this section, the term “absent overseas uniformed services voter” means an overseas voter described in section 20310(5)(A) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20304_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Presidential designee such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>