<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20924" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20924/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20924/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20924"><akn:num>20924</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20924. Staff(a) Executive Director, General Counsel, and other staff(1) Executive DirectorThe Commission shall have an Executive Director, who shall be paid at a rate not to exceed the rate of basic pay for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5.


(2) Term of service for Executive DirectorThe Executive Director shall serve for a term of 4 years. An Executive Director may serve for a longer period only if reappointed for an additional term or terms by a vote of the Commission.


(3) Procedure for appointment(A) In generalWhen a vacancy exists in the position of the Executive Director, the Standards Board and the Board of Advisors shall each appoint a search committee to recommend at least three nominees for the position.


(B) Requiring consideration of nomineesExcept as provided in subparagraph (C), the Commission shall consider the nominees recommended by the Standards Board and the Board of Advisors in appointing the Executive Director.


(C) Interim service of General CounselIf a vacancy exists in the position of the Executive Director, the General Counsel of the Commission shall serve as the acting Executive Director until the Commission appoints a new Executive Director in accordance with this paragraph.


(D) Special rules for interim Executive Director(i) Convening of search committeesThe Standards Board and the Board of Advisors shall each appoint a search committee and recommend nominees for the position of Executive Director in accordance with subparagraph (A) as soon as practicable after the appointment of their members.


(ii) Interim initial appointmentNotwithstanding subparagraph (B), the Commission may appoint an individual to serve as an interim Executive Director prior to the recommendation of nominees for the position by the Standards Board or the Board of Advisors, except that such individual’s term of service may not exceed 6 months. Nothing in the previous sentence may be construed to prohibit the individual serving a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20924_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Director, General Counsel, and other staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Executive Director, General Counsel, and other staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20924_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Experts and consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Experts and consultants Subject to rules prescribed by the Commission, the Executive Director may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5 by a vote of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20924_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff of Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Staff of Federal agencies Upon request of the Commission, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its duties under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20924_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Arranging for assistance for Board of Advisors and Standards Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Arranging for assistance for Board of Advisors and Standards Board At the request of the Board of Advisors or the Standards Board, the Commission may enter into such arrangements as the Commission considers appropriate to make personnel available to assist the Boards with carrying out their duties under this subchapter (including contracts with private individuals for providing temporary personnel services or the temporary detailing of personnel of the Commission).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20924_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with Board of Advisors and Standards Board on certain matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation with Board of Advisors and Standards Board on certain matters In preparing the program goals, long-term plans, mission statements, and related matters for the Commission, the Executive Director and staff of the Commission shall consult with the Board of Advisors and the Standards Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>