<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20923" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20923/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20923/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20923"><akn:num>20923</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership and appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20923. Membership and appointment(a) Membership(1) In generalThe Commission shall have four members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(2) RecommendationsBefore the initial appointment of the members of the Commission and before the appointment of any individual to fill a vacancy on the Commission, the Majority Leader of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Minority Leader of the Senate, and the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives shall each submit to the President a candidate recommendation with respect to each vacancy on the Commission affiliated with the political party of the Member of Congress involved.


(3) QualificationsEach member of the Commission shall have experience with or expertise in election administration or the study of elections.


(4) Date of appointmentThe appointments of the members of the Commission shall be made not later than 120 days after October 29, 2002.



(b) Term of service(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), members shall serve for a term of 4 years and may be reappointed for not more than one additional term.


(2) Terms of initial appointeesAs designated by the President at the time of nomination, of the members first appointed—(A) two of the members (not more than one of whom may be affiliated with the same political party) shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and

(B) two of the members (not more than one of whom may be affiliated with the same political party) shall be appointed for a term of 4 years.


(3) Vacancies(A) In generalA vacancy on the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made and shall be subject to any conditions which applied with respect to the original appointment.


(B) Expired termsA member of the Commission shall serve on the Commission after the expiration of the member’s term until the successor of such member has taken office as a member of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20923_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20923_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Term of service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20923_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair and vice chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chair and vice chair</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20923_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>