<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20961" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20961/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/20961/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20961"><akn:num>20961</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Guidelines Development Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20961. Technical Guidelines Development Committee(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established the Technical Guidelines Development Committee (hereafter in this subpart referred to as the “Development Committee”).


(b) Duties(1) In generalThe Development Committee shall assist the Executive Director of the Commission in the development of the voluntary voting system guidelines.


(2) Deadline for initial set of recommendationsThe Development Committee shall provide its first set of recommendations under this section to the Executive Director of the Commission not later than 9 months after all of its members have been appointed.



(c) Membership(1) In generalThe Development Committee shall be composed of the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (who shall serve as its chair), together with a group of 14 other individuals appointed jointly by the Commission and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, consisting of the following:(A) An equal number of each of the following:(i) Members of the Standards Board.

(ii) Members of the Board of Advisors.

(iii) Members of the Architectural and Transportation Barrier Compliance Board under section 792 of title 29.


(B) A representative of the American National Standards Institute.

(C) A representative of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers.

(D) Two representatives of the National Association of State Election Directors selected by such Association who are not members of the Standards Board or Board of Advisors, and who are not of the same political party.

(E) Other individuals with technical and scientific expertise relating to voting systems and voting equipment.


(2) QuorumA majority of the members of the Development Committee shall constitute a quorum, except that the Development Committee may not conduct any business prior to the appointment of all of its members.



(d) No compensation for serviceMembers of the Development Committee shall not </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20961_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established the Technical Guidelines Development Committee (hereafter in this subpart referred to as the “Development Committee”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20961_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20961_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20961_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No compensation for service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No compensation for service Members of the Development Committee shall not receive any compensation for their service, but shall be paid travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Development Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20961_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical support from National Institute of Standards and Technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical support from National Institute of Standards and Technology</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20961_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of recommendations in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Publication of recommendations in Federal Register At the time the Commission adopts any voluntary voting system guideline pursuant to section 20962 of this title, the Development Committee shall cause to have published in the Federal Register the recommendations it provided under this section to the Executive Director of the Commission concerning the guideline adopted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>