<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/21003" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/21003/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/21003/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21003"><akn:num>21003</akn:num><akn:heading>Condition for receipt of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21003. Condition for receipt of funds(a) In generalA State is eligible to receive a requirements payment for a fiscal year if the chief executive officer of the State, or designee, in consultation and coordination with the chief State election official, has filed with the Commission a statement certifying that the State is in compliance with the requirements referred to in subsection (b). A State may meet the requirement of the previous sentence by filing with the Commission a statement which reads as follows: “______ hereby certifies that it is in compliance with the requirements referred to in section 253(b) of the Help America Vote Act of 2002.” (with the blank to be filled in with the name of the State involved).


(b) State plan requirement; certification of compliance with applicable laws and requirementsThe requirements referred to in this subsection are as follows:(1) The State has filed with the Commission a State plan covering the fiscal year which the State certifies—(A) contains each of the elements described in section 21004(a) of this title (or, for purposes of determining the eligibility of a State to receive a requirements payment appropriated pursuant to the authorization provided under section 21007(a)(4) of this title, contains the element described in paragraph (14) of such section) with respect to the fiscal year;

(B) is developed in accordance with section 21005 of this title; and

(C) meets the public notice and comment requirements of section 21006 of this title.


(2)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), the State has filed with the Commission a plan for the implementation of the uniform, nondiscriminatory administrative complaint procedures required under section 21112 of this title (or has included such a plan in the State plan filed under paragraph (1)), and has such procedures in place for purposes of meeting the requirements of such section. If the State does not include such an implementation plan in the State plan filed under paragraph </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21003_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A State is eligible to receive a requirements payment for a fiscal year if the chief executive officer of the State, or designee, in consultation and coordination with the chief State election official, has filed with the Commission a statement certifying that the State is in compliance with the requirements referred to in subsection (b). A State may meet the requirement of the previous sentence by filing with the Commission a statement which reads as follows: “______ hereby certifies that it is in compliance with the requirements referred to in section 253(b) of the Help America Vote Act of 2002.” (with the blank to be filled in with the name of the State involved).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21003_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan requirement; certification of compliance with applicable laws and requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State plan requirement; certification of compliance with applicable laws and requirements The requirements referred to in this subsection are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21003_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methods of compliance left to discretion of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Methods of compliance left to discretion of State The specific choices on the methods of complying with the elements of a State plan shall be left to the discretion of the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21003_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing for filing of certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Timing for filing of certification A State may not file a statement of certification under subsection (a) until the expiration of the 45-day period (or, in the case of a fiscal year other than the first fiscal year for which a requirements payment is made to the State under this part, the 30-day period) which begins on the date notice of the State plan under this part is published in the Federal Register pursuant to section 21005(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21003_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief State election official defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chief State election official defined In this part, the “chief State election official” of a State is the individual designated by the State under section 10 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (42 U.S.C. 1973gg–8) [now 52 U.S.C. 20509] to be responsible for coordination of the State’s responsibilities under such Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>