<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/21025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/21025/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/21025/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21025"><akn:num>21025</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21025. Reports(a) Reports by recipientsNot later than the 11 So in original. 6 months after the end of each fiscal year for which an eligible State or eligible unit of local government received a payment under this subpart, the State or unit shall submit a report to the Secretary on the activities conducted with the funds provided during the year, and shall include in the report a list of expenditures made with respect to each category of activities described in section 21021(b) of this title.


(b) Report by Secretary to CommitteesWith respect to each fiscal year for which the Secretary makes payments under this subpart, the Secretary shall submit a report on the activities carried out under this subpart to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.


(Pub. L. 107–252, title II, § 265, Oct. 29, 2002, 116 Stat. 1699.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 15425 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21025_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports by recipients Not later than the 11 So in original. 6 months after the end of each fiscal year for which an eligible State or eligible unit of local government received a payment under this subpart, the State or unit shall submit a report to the Secretary on the activities conducted with the funds provided during the year, and shall include in the report a list of expenditures made with respect to each category of activities described in section 21021(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21025_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report by Secretary to Committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report by Secretary to Committees With respect to each fiscal year for which the Secretary makes payments under this subpart, the Secretary shall submit a report on the activities carried out under this subpart to the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>