<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/21142" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/21142/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/21142/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21142"><akn:num>21142</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits and repayment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21142. Audits and repayment of funds(a) Recordkeeping requirementEach recipient of a grant or other payment made under this chapter shall keep such records with respect to the payment as are consistent with sound accounting principles, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of funds, the total cost of the project or undertaking for which such funds are used, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.


(b) Audits and examinations(1) Audits and examinationsExcept as provided in paragraph (4), each office making a grant or other payment under this chapter, or any duly authorized representative of such office, may audit or examine any recipient of the grant or payment and shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipient which in the opinion of the entity may be related or pertinent to the grant or payment.


(2) Recipients of assistance subject to provisions of sectionThe provisions of this section shall apply to all recipients of grants or other payments under this chapter, whether by direct grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under this chapter or by subgrant or subcontract from primary grantees or contractors under this chapter.


(3) Special rule for payments by General Services AdministrationWith respect to any grant or payment made under this chapter by the Administrator of General Services, the Election Assistance Commission shall be deemed to be the office making the grant or payment for purposes of this section.


(4) Special ruleIn the case of grants or payments made under section 21001 of this title, audits and examinations conducted under paragraph (1) shall be performed on a regular basis (as determined by the Commission).


(5) Special rules for audits by the CommissionIn addition to the audits described in paragrap</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21142_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recordkeeping requirement Each recipient of a grant or other payment made under this chapter shall keep such records with respect to the payment as are consistent with sound accounting principles, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of funds, the total cost of the project or undertaking for which such funds are used, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21142_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits and examinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Audits and examinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21142_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recoupment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recoupment of funds If the Comptroller General determines as a result of an audit conducted under subsection (b) prior to November 26, 2014, that— the recipient shall pay to the office which made the grant or payment involved a portion of the funds provided which reflects the proportion of the requirements with which the recipient is not in compliance, or the extent to which the payment is in excess, under the program involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>