<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30109" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30109/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30109/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30109"><akn:num>30109</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30109. Enforcement(a) Administrative and judicial practice and procedure(1) Any person who believes a violation of this Act or of chapter 95 or chapter 96 of title 26 has occurred, may file a complaint with the Commission. Such complaint shall be in writing, signed and sworn to by the person filing such complaint, shall be notarized, and shall be made under penalty of perjury and subject to the provisions of section 1001 of title 18. Within 5 days after receipt of a complaint, the Commission shall notify, in writing, any person alleged in the complaint to have committed such a violation. Before the Commission conducts any vote on the complaint, other than a vote to dismiss, any person so notified shall have the opportunity to demonstrate, in writing, to the Commission within 15 days after notification that no action should be taken against such person on the basis of the complaint. The Commission may not conduct any investigation or take any other action under this section solely on the basis of a complaint of a person whose identity is not disclosed to the Commission.

(2) If the Commission, upon receiving a complaint under paragraph (1) or on the basis of information ascertained in the normal course of carrying out its supervisory responsibilities, determines, by an affirmative vote of 4 of its members, that it has reason to believe that a person has committed, or is about to commit, a violation of this Act or chapter 95 or chapter 96 of title 26, the Commission shall, through its chairman or vice chairman, notify the person of the alleged violation. Such notification shall set forth the factual basis for such alleged violation. The Commission shall make an investigation of such alleged violation, which may include a field investigation or audit, in accordance with the provisions of this section.

(3) The general counsel of the Commission shall notify the respondent of any recommendation to the Commission by the general counsel to proceed to a vote on probable c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30109_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative and judicial practice and procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administrative and judicial practice and procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30109_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to persons not filing required reports prior to institution of enforcement action; publication of identity of persons and unfiled reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice to persons not filing required reports prior to institution of enforcement action; publication of identity of persons and unfiled reports Before taking any action under subsection (a) against any person who has failed to file a report required under section 30104(a)(2)(A)(iii) of this title for the calendar quarter immediately preceding the election involved, or in accordance with section 30104(a)(2)(A)(i) of this title, the Commission shall notify the person of such failure to file the required reports. If a satisfactory response is not received within 4 business days after the date of notification, the Commission shall, pursuant to section 30111(a)(7) of this title, publish before the election the name of the person and the report or reports such person has failed to file.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30109_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by Attorney General of apparent violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports by Attorney General of apparent violations Whenever the Commission refers an apparent violation to the Attorney General, the Attorney General shall report to the Commission any action taken by the Attorney General regarding the apparent violation. Each report shall be transmitted within 60 days after the date the Commission refers an apparent violation, and every 30 days thereafter until the final disposition of the apparent violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30109_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties; defenses; mitigation of offenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Penalties; defenses; mitigation of offenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>