<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30104"><akn:num>30104</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30104. Reporting requirements(a) Receipts and disbursements by treasurers of political committees; filing requirements(1) Each treasurer of a political committee shall file reports of receipts and disbursements in accordance with the provisions of this subsection. The treasurer shall sign each such report.

(2) If the political committee is the principal campaign committee of a candidate for the House of Representatives or for the Senate—(A) in any calendar year during which there is 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “a”. regularly scheduled election for which such candidate is seeking election, or nomination for election, the treasurer shall file the following reports:(i) a pre-election report, which shall be filed no later than the 12th day before (or posted by any of the following: registered mail, certified mail, priority mail having a delivery confirmation, or express mail having a delivery confirmation, or delivered to an overnight delivery service with an on-line tracking system, if posted or delivered no later than the 15th day before) any election in which such candidate is seeking election, or nomination for election, and which shall be complete as of the 20th day before such election;

(ii) a post-general election report, which shall be filed no later than the 30th day after any general election in which such candidate has sought election, and which shall be complete as of the 20th day after such general election; and

(iii) additional quarterly reports, which shall be filed no later than the 15th day after the last day of each calendar quarter, and which shall be complete as of the last day of each calendar quarter: except that the report for the quarter ending December 31 shall be filed no later than January 31 of the following calendar year; and


(B) in any other calendar year the treasurer shall file quarterly reports, which shall be filed not later than the 15th day after the last day of each calendar quarter, and which shall be co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipts and disbursements by treasurers of political committees; filing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Receipts and disbursements by treasurers of political committees; filing requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of reports Each report under this section shall disclose—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statements by other than political committees; filing; contents; indices of expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statements by other than political committees; filing; contents; indices of expenditures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing by facsimile device or electronic mail</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Filing by facsimile device or electronic mail</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30104_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Political committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Political committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30104_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of electioneering communications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosure of electioneering communications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30104_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for reporting certain expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Time for reporting certain expenditures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30104_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports from Inaugural Committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports from Inaugural Committees The Federal Election Commission shall make any report filed by an Inaugural Committee under section 510 of title 36 accessible to the public at the offices of the Commission and on the Internet not later than 48 hours after the report is received by the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30104_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of bundled contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Disclosure of bundled contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>