<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30102"><akn:num>30102</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization of political committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30102. Organization of political committees(a) Treasurer; vacancy; official authorizationsEvery political committee shall have a treasurer. No contribution or expenditure shall be accepted or made by or on behalf of a political committee during any period in which the office of treasurer is vacant. No expenditure shall be made for or on behalf of a political committee without the authorization of the treasurer or his or her designated agent.


(b) Account of contributions; segregated funds(1) Every person who receives a contribution for an authorized political committee shall, no later than 10 days after receiving such contribution, forward to the treasurer such contribution, and if the amount of the contribution is in excess of $50 the name and address of the person making the contribution and the date of receipt.

(2) Every person who receives a contribution for a political committee which is not an authorized committee shall—(A) if the amount of the contribution is $50 or less, forward to the treasurer such contribution no later than 30 days after receiving the contribution; and

(B) if the amount of the contribution is in excess of $50, forward to the treasurer such contribution, the name and address of the person making the contribution, and the date of receipt of the contribution, no later than 10 days after receiving the contribution.


(3) All funds of a political committee shall be segregated from, and may not be commingled with, the personal funds of any individual.


(c) RecordkeepingThe treasurer of a political committee shall keep an account of—(1) all contributions received by or on behalf of such political committee;

(2) the name and address of any person who makes any contribution in excess of $50, together with the date and amount of such contribution by any person;

(3) the identification of any person who makes a contribution or contributions aggregating more than $200 during a calendar year, together with the date and amount of any such contri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treasurer; vacancy; official authorizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Treasurer; vacancy; official authorizations Every political committee shall have a treasurer. No contribution or expenditure shall be accepted or made by or on behalf of a political committee during any period in which the office of treasurer is vacant. No expenditure shall be made for or on behalf of a political committee without the authorization of the treasurer or his or her designated agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Account of contributions; segregated funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Account of contributions; segregated funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recordkeeping The treasurer of a political committee shall keep an account of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of records and copies of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preservation of records and copies of reports The treasurer shall preserve all records required to be kept by this section and copies of all reports required to be filed by this subchapter for 3 years after the report is filed. For any report filed in electronic format under section 30104(a)(11) of this title, the treasurer shall retain a machine-readable copy of the report as the copy preserved under the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30102_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal and additional campaign committees; designations, status of candidate, authorized committees, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Principal and additional campaign committees; designations, status of candidate, authorized committees, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30102_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing with and receipt of designations, statements, and reports by principal campaign committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Filing with and receipt of designations, statements, and reports by principal campaign committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30102_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing with the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Filing with the Commission All designations, statements, and reports required to be filed under this Act shall be filed with the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30102_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Campaign depositories; designations, maintenance of accounts, etc.; petty cash fund for disbursements; record of disbursements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Campaign depositories; designations, maintenance of accounts, etc.; petty cash fund for disbursements; record of disbursements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30102_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and records, compliance with requirements based on best efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reports and records, compliance with requirements based on best efforts When the treasurer of a political committee shows that best efforts have been used to obtain, maintain, and submit the information required by this Act for the political committee, any report or any records of such committee shall be considered in compliance with this Act or chapter 95 or chapter 96 of title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>