<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30106"><akn:num>30106</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Election Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30106. Federal Election Commission(a) Establishment; membership; term of office; vacancies; qualifications; compensation; chairman and vice chairman(1) There is established a commission to be known as the Federal Election Commission. The Commission is composed of the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives or their designees, ex officio and without the right to vote, and 6 members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. No more than 3 members of the Commission appointed under this paragraph may be affiliated with the same political party.

(2)(A) Members of the Commission shall serve for a single term of 6 years, except that of the members first appointed—(i) two of the members, not affiliated with the same political party, shall be appointed for terms ending on April 30, 1977;

(ii) two of the members, not affiliated with the same political party, shall be appointed for terms ending on April 30, 1979; and

(iii) two of the members, not affiliated with the same political party, shall be appointed for terms ending on April 30, 1981.


(B) A member of the Commission may serve on the Commission after the expiration of his or her term until his or her successor has taken office as a member of the Commission.

(C) An individual appointed to fill a vacancy occurring other than by the expiration of a term of office shall be appointed only for the unexpired term of the member he or she succeeds.

(D) Any vacancy occurring in the membership of the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as in the case of the original appointment.


(3) Members shall be chosen on the basis of their experience, integrity, impartiality, and good judgment and members (other than the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives) shall be individuals who, at the time appointed to the Commission, are not elected or appointed officers or employees in the executive, legislative, or judicial branch of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; membership; term of office; vacancies; qualifications; compensation; chairman and vice chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; membership; term of office; vacancies; qualifications; compensation; chairman and vice chairman</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration, enforcement, and formulation of policy; exclusive jurisdiction of civil enforcement; Congressional authorities or functions with respect to elections for Federal office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration, enforcement, and formulation of policy; exclusive jurisdiction of civil enforcement; Congressional authorities or functions with respect to elections for Federal office</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting requirements; delegation of authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Voting requirements; delegation of authorities All decisions of the Commission with respect to the exercise of its duties and powers under the provisions of this Act shall be made by a majority vote of the members of the Commission. A member of the Commission may not delegate to any person his or her vote or any decisionmaking authority or duty vested in the Commission by the provisions of this Act, except that the affirmative vote of 4 members of the Commission shall be required in order for the Commission to take any action in accordance with paragraph (6), (7), (8), or (9) of section 30107(a) of this title or with chapter 95 or chapter 96 of title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Meetings The Commission shall meet at least once each month and also at the call of any member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules for conduct of activities; judicial notice of seal; principal office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rules for conduct of activities; judicial notice of seal; principal office The Commission shall prepare written rules for the conduct of its activities, shall have an official seal which shall be judicially noticed, and shall have its principal office in or near the District of Columbia (but it may meet or exercise any of its powers anywhere in the United States).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff director and general counsel; appointment and compensation; appointment and compensation of personnel and procurement of intermittent services by staff director; use of assistance, personnel, and facilities of Federal agencies and departments; counsel for defense of actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Staff director and general counsel; appointment and compensation; appointment and compensation of personnel and procurement of intermittent services by staff director; use of assistance, personnel, and facilities of Federal agencies and departments; counsel for defense of actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>