<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/52/30111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30111"><akn:num>30111</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30111. Administrative provisions(a) Duties of CommissionThe Commission shall—(1) prescribe forms necessary to implement this Act;

(2) prepare, publish, and furnish to all persons required to file reports and statements under this Act a manual recommending uniform methods of bookkeeping and reporting;

(3) develop a filing, coding, and cross-indexing system consistent with the purposes of this Act;

(4) within 48 hours after the time of the receipt by the Commission of reports and statements filed with it, make them available for public inspection, and copying, at the expense of the person requesting such copying, except that any information copied from such reports or statements may not be sold or used by any person for the purpose of soliciting contributions or for commercial purposes, other than using the name and address of any political committee to solicit contributions from such committee. A political committee may submit 10 pseudonyms on each report filed in order to protect against the illegal use of names and addresses of contributors, provided such committee attaches a list of such pseudonyms to the appropriate report. The Secretary or the Commission shall exclude these lists from the public record;

(5) keep such designations, reports, and statements for a period of 10 years from the date of receipt, except that designations, reports, and statements that relate solely to candidates for the House of Representatives shall be kept for 5 years from the date of their receipt;

(6)(A) compile and maintain a cumulative index of designations, reports, and statements filed under this Act, which index shall be published at regular intervals and made available for purchase directly or by mail;

(B) compile, maintain, and revise a separate cumulative index of reports and statements filed by multi-candidate committees, including in such index a list of multi-candidate committees; and

(C) compile and maintain a list of multi-candidate committees, which shall be rev</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Duties of Commission The Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits and field investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Audits and field investigations The Commission may conduct audits and field investigations of any political committee required to file a report under section 30104 of this title. All audits and field investigations concerning the verification for, and receipt and use of, any payments received by a candidate or committee under chapter 95 or chapter 96 of title 26 shall be given priority. Prior to conducting any audit under this subsection, the Commission shall perform an internal review of reports filed by selected committees to determine if the reports filed by a particular committee meet the threshold requirements for substantial compliance with the Act. Such thresholds for compliance shall be established by the Commission. The Commission may, upon an affirmative vote of 4 of its members, conduct an audit and field investigation of any committee which does meet the threshold requirements established by the Commission. Such audit shall be commenced within 30 days of such vote, exce</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30111_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory provisions applicable to forms and information-gathering activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statutory provisions applicable to forms and information-gathering activities Any forms prescribed by the Commission under subsection (a)(1), and any information-gathering activities of the Commission under this Act, shall not be subject to the provisions of section 3512 11 See References in Text note below. of title 44.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30111_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules, regulations, or forms; issuance, procedures applicable, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rules, regulations, or forms; issuance, procedures applicable, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30111_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of protection for good faith reliance upon rules or regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Scope of protection for good faith reliance upon rules or regulations Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person who relies upon any rule or regulation prescribed by the Commission in accordance with the provisions of this section and who acts in good faith in accordance with such rule or regulation shall not, as a result of such act, be subject to any sanction provided by this Act or by chapter 95 or chapter 96 of title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30111_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of rules, regulations, and forms by Commission and Internal Revenue Service; report to Congress on cooperative efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Promulgation of rules, regulations, and forms by Commission and Internal Revenue Service; report to Congress on cooperative efforts In prescribing such rules, regulations, and forms under this section, the Commission and the Internal Revenue Service shall consult and work together to promulgate rules, regulations, and forms which are mutually consistent. The Commission shall report to the Congress annually on the steps it has taken to comply with this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>