<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1008" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1008/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1008/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1008"><akn:num>1008</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of costs of telecommunications carriers to comply with capability requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1008. Payment of costs of telecommunications carriers to comply with capability requirements(a) Equipment, facilities, and services deployed on or before January 1, 1995The Attorney General may, subject to the availability of appropriations, agree to pay telecommunications carriers for all reasonable costs directly associated with the modifications performed by carriers in connection with equipment, facilities, and services installed or deployed on or before January 1, 1995, to establish the capabilities necessary to comply with section 1002 of this title.


(b) Equipment, facilities, and services deployed after January 1, 1995(1) Determinations of reasonably achievableThe Commission, on petition from a telecommunications carrier or any other interested person, and after notice to the Attorney General, shall determine whether compliance with the assistance capability requirements of section 1002 of this title is reasonably achievable with respect to any equipment, facility, or service installed or deployed after January 1, 1995. The Commission shall make such determination within 1 year after the date such petition is filed. In making such determination, the Commission shall determine whether compliance would impose significant difficulty or expense on the carrier or on the users of the carrier’s systems and shall consider the following factors:(A) The effect on public safety and national security.

(B) The effect on rates for basic residential telephone service.

(C) The need to protect the privacy and security of communications not authorized to be intercepted.

(D) The need to achieve the capability assistance requirements of section 1002 of this title by cost-effective methods.

(E) The effect on the nature and cost of the equipment, facility, or service at issue.

(F) The effect on the operation of the equipment, facility, or service at issue.

(G) The policy of the United States to encourage the provision of new technologies and services to the public.

(H) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1008_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equipment, facilities, and services deployed on or before January 1, 1995</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Equipment, facilities, and services deployed on or before The Attorney General may, subject to the availability of appropriations, agree to pay telecommunications carriers for all reasonable costs directly associated with the modifications performed by carriers in connection with equipment, facilities, and services installed or deployed on or before January 1, 1995, to establish the capabilities necessary to comply with section 1002 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1008_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equipment, facilities, and services deployed after January 1, 1995</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Equipment, facilities, and services deployed after</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1008_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds for payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocation of funds for payment The Attorney General shall allocate funds appropriated to carry out this subchapter in accordance with law enforcement priorities determined by the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1008_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to make payment with respect to equipment, facilities, and services deployed on or before January 1, 1995</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Failure to make payment with respect to equipment, facilities, and services deployed on or before If a carrier has requested payment in accordance with procedures promulgated pursuant to subsection (e), and the Attorney General has not agreed to pay the telecommunications carrier for all reasonable costs directly associated with modifications necessary to bring any equipment, facility, or service deployed on or before January 1, 1995, into compliance with the assistance capability requirements of section 1002 of this title, such equipment, facility, or service shall be considered to be in compliance with the assistance capability requirements of section 1002 of this title until the equipment, facility, or service is replaced or significantly upgraded or otherwise undergoes major modification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1008_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost control regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cost control regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>