<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1021"><akn:num>1021</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Justice Telecommunications Carrier Compliance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1021. Department of Justice Telecommunications Carrier Compliance Fund(a) Establishment of FundThere is hereby established in the United States Treasury a fund to be known as the Department of Justice Telecommunications Carrier Compliance Fund (hereafter referred to as “the Fund”), which shall be available without fiscal year limitation to the Attorney General for making payments to telecommunications carriers, equipment manufacturers, and providers of telecommunications support services pursuant to section 1008 of this title.


(b) Deposits to FundNotwithstanding any other provision of law, any agency of the United States with law enforcement or intelligence responsibilities may deposit as offsetting collections to the Fund any unobligated balances that are available until expended, upon compliance with any Congressional notification requirements for reprogrammings of funds applicable to the appropriation from which the deposit is to be made.


(c) Termination(1) The Attorney General may terminate the Fund at such time as the Attorney General determines that the Fund is no longer necessary.

(2) Any balance in the Fund at the time of its termination shall be deposited in the General Fund of the Treasury.

(3) A decision of the Attorney General to terminate the Fund shall not be subject to judicial review.


(d) Availability of funds for expenditureFunds shall not be available for obligation unless an implementation plan as set forth in subsection (e) is submitted to each member of the Committees on the Judiciary and Appropriations of both the House of Representatives and the Senate and the Congress does not by law block or prevent the obligation of such funds. Such funds shall be treated as a reprogramming of funds under section 605 of the Department of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997, and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that secti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Fund There is hereby established in the United States Treasury a fund to be known as the Department of Justice Telecommunications Carrier Compliance Fund (hereafter referred to as “the Fund”), which shall be available without fiscal year limitation to the Attorney General for making payments to telecommunications carriers, equipment manufacturers, and providers of telecommunications support services pursuant to section 1008 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits to Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deposits to Fund Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any agency of the United States with law enforcement or intelligence responsibilities may deposit as offsetting collections to the Fund any unobligated balances that are available until expended, upon compliance with any Congressional notification requirements for reprogrammings of funds applicable to the appropriation from which the deposit is to be made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Termination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds for expenditure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of funds for expenditure Funds shall not be available for obligation unless an implementation plan as set forth in subsection (e) is submitted to each member of the Committees on the Judiciary and Appropriations of both the House of Representatives and the Senate and the Congress does not by law block or prevent the obligation of such funds. Such funds shall be treated as a reprogramming of funds under section 605 of the Department of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1997, and shall not be available for obligation or expenditure except in compliance with the procedures set forth in that section and this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Implementation plan The implementation plan shall include:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual report to Congress The Attorney General shall submit to the Congress each year a report specifically detailing all deposits and expenditures made pursuant to subchapter I 22 See References in Text note below. of this chapter in each fiscal year. This report shall be submitted to each member of the Committees on the Judiciary and Appropriations of both the House of Representatives and the Senate, and to the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives and to the majority and minority leaders of the Senate, no later than 60 days after the end of each fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>