<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1307"><akn:num>1307</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Internet Connectivity and Growth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1307. Office of Internet Connectivity and Growth(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Advancing Critical Connectivity Expands Service, Small Business Resources, Opportunities, Access, and Data Based on Assessed Need and Demand Act” or the “ACCESS BROADBAND Act”.


(b) EstablishmentNot later than 180 days after December 27, 2020, the Assistant Secretary shall establish the Office of Internet Connectivity and Growth within the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.


(c) Duties(1) OutreachThe Office shall—(A) connect with communities that need access to high-speed internet and improved digital inclusion efforts through various forms of outreach and communication techniques;

(B) hold regional workshops across the country to share best practices and effective strategies for promoting broadband access and adoption;

(C) develop targeted broadband training and presentations for various demographic communities through various media;

(D) develop and distribute publications (including toolkits, primers, manuals, and white papers) providing guidance, strategies, and insights to communities as the communities develop strategies to expand broadband access and adoption; and

(E) as applicable in carrying out subparagraphs (A) through (D), coordinate with State agencies that provide similar broadband investments, outreach, and coordination through Federal programs.


(2) Tracking of Federal dollars(A) Broadband infrastructureThe Office shall track the construction and use of and access to any broadband infrastructure built using any Federal support in a central database.


(B) Accounting mechanismThe Office shall develop a streamlined accounting mechanism by which any agency offering a Federal broadband support program and the Commission for any Universal Service Fund Program shall provide the information described in subparagraph (A) in a standardized and efficient fashion.


(C) ReportNot later than 1 year after December 27, 2020, and every y</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Advancing Critical Connectivity Expands Service, Small Business Resources, Opportunities, Access, and Data Based on Assessed Need and Demand Act” or the “ACCESS BROADBAND Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment Not later than 180 days after December 27, 2020, the Assistant Secretary shall establish the Office of Internet Connectivity and Growth within the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to current broadband activities of NTIA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Relation to current broadband activities of NTIA The Assistant Secretary shall assign to the Office all activities performed by the National Telecommunications and Information Administration as of December 27, 2020, that are similar to the activities required to be conducted by the Office under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Streamlined applications for support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Streamlined applications for support</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1307_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination of support</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1307_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1307_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction Nothing in this section is intended to alter or amend any provision of section 254 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>