<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1424" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1424/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1424/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1424"><akn:num>1424</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the First Responder Network Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1424. Establishment of the First Responder Network Authority(a) EstablishmentThere is established as an independent authority within the NTIA the “First Responder Network Authority” or “FirstNet”.


(b) Board(1) In generalThe First Responder Network Authority shall be headed by a Board, which shall consist of—(A) the Secretary of Homeland Security;

(B) the Attorney General of the United States;

(C) the Director of the Office of Management and Budget; and

(D) 12 individuals appointed by the Secretary of Commerce in accordance with paragraph (2).


(2) Appointments(A) In generalIn making appointments under paragraph (1)(D), the Secretary of Commerce shall—(i) appoint not fewer than 3 individuals to represent the collective interests of the States, localities, tribes, and territories;

(ii) seek to ensure geographic and regional representation of the United States in such appointments;

(iii) seek to ensure rural and urban representation in such appointments; and

(iv) appoint not fewer than 3 individuals who have served as public safety professionals.


(B) Required qualifications(i) In generalEach member appointed under paragraph (1)(D) should meet not less than 1 of the following criteria:(I) Public safety experienceKnowledge and experience in the use of Federal, State, local, or tribal public safety or emergency response.


(II) Technical expertiseTechnical expertise and fluency regarding broadband communications, including public safety communications.


(III) Network expertiseExpertise in building, deploying, and operating commercial telecommunications networks.


(IV) Financial expertiseExpertise in financing and funding telecommunications networks.



(ii) Expertise to be representedIn making appointments under paragraph (1)(D), the Secretary of Commerce shall appoint—(I) not fewer than 1 individual who satisfies the requirement under subclause (II) of clause (i);

(II) not fewer than 1 individual who satisfies the requirement under subclause (III) of clau</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1424_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established as an independent authority within the NTIA the “First Responder Network Authority” or “FirstNet”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1424_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1424_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms of appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1424_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chair</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1424_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Meetings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1424_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Quorum Eight members of the Board shall constitute a quorum, including at least 6 of the members appointed under subsection (b)(1)(D).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1424_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>