<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1426" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1426/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1426/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1426"><akn:num>1426</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers, duties, and responsibilities of the First Responder Network Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1426. Powers, duties, and responsibilities of the First Responder Network Authority(a) General powersThe First Responder Network Authority shall have the authority to do the following:(1) To exercise, through the actions of its Board, all powers specifically granted by the provisions of this subchapter, and such incidental powers as shall be necessary.

(2) To hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the First Responder Network Authority considers necessary to carry out its responsibilities and duties.

(3) To obtain grants and funds from and make contracts with individuals, private companies, organizations, institutions, and Federal, State, regional, and local agencies.

(4) To accept, hold, administer, and utilize gifts, donations, and bequests of property, both real and personal, for the purposes of aiding or facilitating the work of the First Responder Network Authority.

(5) To spend funds under paragraph (3) in a manner authorized by the Board, but only for purposes that will advance or enhance public safety communications consistent with this chapter.

(6) To take such other actions as the First Responder Network Authority (through the Board) may from time to time determine necessary, appropriate, or advisable to accomplish the purposes of this chapter.


(b) Duty and responsibility to deploy and operate a nationwide public safety broadband network(1) In generalThe First Responder Network Authority shall hold the single public safety wireless license granted under section 1421 of this title and take all actions necessary to ensure the building, deployment, and operation of the nationwide public safety broadband network, in consultation with Federal, State, tribal, and local public safety entities, the Director of NIST, the Commission, and the public safety advisory committee established in section 1425(a) of this title, including by, at a minimum—(A) ensuring nationwide standards for use and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General powers The First Responder Network Authority shall have the authority to do the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty and responsibility to deploy and operate a nationwide public safety broadband network</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duty and responsibility to deploy and operate a nationwide public safety broadband network</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other specific duties and responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other specific duties and responsibilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from certain laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemption from certain laws Any action taken or decisions made by the First Responder Network Authority shall be exempt from the requirements of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Network Construction Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Network Construction Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Termination of Authority The authority of the First Responder Network Authority shall terminate on the date that is 15 years after February 22, 2012.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) GAO report Not later than 10 years after February 22, 2012, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on what action Congress should take regarding the 15-year sunset of authority under subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>