<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1441" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1441/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1441/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1441"><akn:num>1441</akn:num><akn:heading>State and Local Implementation Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1441. State and Local Implementation Fund(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the State and Local Implementation Fund.


(b) Amounts available for State and Local Implementation Grant ProgramAny amounts borrowed under subsection (c)(1) and any amounts in the State and Local Implementation Fund that are not necessary to reimburse the general fund of the Treasury for such borrowed amounts shall be available to the Assistant Secretary to implement section 1442 of this title.


(c) Borrowing authority(1) In generalPrior to the end of fiscal year 2022, the Assistant Secretary may borrow from the general fund of the Treasury such sums as may be necessary, but not to exceed $135,000,000, to implement section 1442 of this title.


(2) ReimbursementThe Assistant Secretary shall reimburse the general fund of the Treasury, without interest, for any amounts borrowed under paragraph (1) as funds are deposited into the State and Local Implementation Fund.



(d) Transfer of unused fundsIf there is a balance remaining in the State and Local Implementation Fund on September 30, 2022, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer such balance to the general fund of the Treasury, where such balance shall be dedicated for the sole purpose of deficit reduction.


(Pub. L. 112–96, title VI, § 6301, Feb. 22, 2012, 126 Stat. 218.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the State and Local Implementation Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts available for State and Local Implementation Grant Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amounts available for State and Local Implementation Grant Program Any amounts borrowed under subsection (c)(1) and any amounts in the State and Local Implementation Fund that are not necessary to reimburse the general fund of the Treasury for such borrowed amounts shall be available to the Assistant Secretary to implement section 1442 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Borrowing authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Borrowing authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of unused funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer of unused funds If there is a balance remaining in the State and Local Implementation Fund on September 30, 2022, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer such balance to the general fund of the Treasury, where such balance shall be dedicated for the sole purpose of deficit reduction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>