<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1508" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1508/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1508/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1508"><akn:num>1508</akn:num><akn:heading>National plan for unlicensed spectrum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1508. National plan for unlicensed spectrum(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Spectrum Relocation FundThe term “Spectrum Relocation Fund” means the Fund established under section 928 of this title.


(2) Unlicensed or licensed by rule operationsThe term “unlicensed or licensed by rule operations” means the use of spectrum on a non-exclusive basis under—(A) part 15 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations; or

(B) licensing by rule under part 96 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations.



(b) National planNot later than 18 months after March 23, 2018, the Commission, in consultation with the NTIA, shall develop a national plan for making additional radio frequency bands available for unlicensed or licensed by rule operations.


(c) RequirementsThe plan developed under this section shall—(1) identify an approach that ensures that consumers have access to additional spectrum to conduct unlicensed or licensed by rule operations in a range of radio frequencies to meet consumer demand;

(2) recommend specific actions by the Commission and the NTIA to permit unlicensed or licensed by rule operations in additional radio frequency ranges that the Commission finds—(A) are consistent with the statement of policy under section 1507(a) of this title;

(B) will—(i) expand opportunities for unlicensed or licensed by rule operations in a spectrum band; or

(ii) otherwise improve spectrum utilization and intensity of use of bands where unlicensed or licensed by rule operations are already permitted;


(C) will not cause harmful interference to Federal or non-Federal users of such bands; and

(D) will not significantly impact homeland security or national security communications systems; and


(3) examine additional ways, with respect to existing and planned databases or spectrum access systems designed to promote spectrum sharing and access to spectrum for unlicensed or licensed by rule operations—(A) to improve accuracy and efficacy;

(B) to reduce burdens on consumers, manufact</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National plan Not later than 18 months after March 23, 2018, the Commission, in consultation with the NTIA, shall develop a national plan for making additional radio frequency bands available for unlicensed or licensed by rule operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements The plan developed under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Spectrum Relocation Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Spectrum Relocation Fund To be included as an appendix as part of the plan developed under this section, the NTIA, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall share with the Commission recommendations about how to reform the Spectrum Relocation Fund—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule of construction Nothing in this section confers any additional rights on unlicensed users or users licensed by rule under part 96 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, to protection from harmful interference.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>