<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1511" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1511/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1511/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1511"><akn:num>1511</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1511. Rules of construction(a) Ranges of frequenciesEach range of frequencies described in this chapter shall be construed to be inclusive of the upper and lower frequencies in the range.


(b) Assessment of electromagnetic spectrum reallocationNothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect any requirement under section 156 of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (47 U.S.C. 921 note), as added by section 1062(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000.


(Pub. L. 115–141, div. P, title VI, § 621, Mar. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 1115.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title VI of div. P of Pub. L. 115–141, Mar. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 1097, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title VI to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1501 of this title and Tables.
Section 156 of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act, as added by section 1062(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000, referred to in subsec. (b), is section 156 of title I of Pub. L. 102–538, as added by Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title X, § 1062(a), Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 767, formerly set out as a note under section 921 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ranges of frequencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Ranges of frequencies Each range of frequencies described in this chapter shall be construed to be inclusive of the upper and lower frequencies in the range.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1511_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of electromagnetic spectrum reallocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assessment of electromagnetic spectrum reallocation Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect any requirement under section 156 of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (47 U.S.C. 921 note), as added by section 1062(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>