<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/153" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/153/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/153/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_153"><akn:num>153</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 153. Definitions
For the purposes of this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires—(1) Advanced communications servicesThe term “advanced communications services” means—(A) interconnected VoIP service;

(B) non-interconnected VoIP service;

(C) electronic messaging service;

(D) interoperable video conferencing service; and

(E) any audio or video communications service used by inmates for the purpose of communicating with individuals outside the correctional institution where the inmate is held, regardless of technology used.


(2) AffiliateThe term “affiliate” means a person that (directly or indirectly) owns or controls, is owned or controlled by, or is under common ownership or control with, another person. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “own” means to own an equity interest (or the equivalent thereof) of more than 10 percent.


(3) Amateur stationThe term “amateur station” means a radio station operated by a duly authorized person interested in radio technique solely with a personal aim and without pecuniary interest.


(4) AT&amp;T Consent DecreeThe term “AT&amp;T Consent Decree” means the order entered August 24, 1982, in the antitrust action styled United States v. Western Electric, Civil Action No. 82–0192, in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, and includes any judgment or order with respect to such action entered on or after August 24, 1982.


(5) Bell operating companyThe term “Bell operating company”—(A) means any of the following companies: Bell Telephone Company of Nevada, Illinois Bell Telephone Company, Indiana Bell Telephone Company, Incorporated, Michigan Bell Telephone Company, New England Telephone and Telegraph Company, New Jersey Bell Telephone Company, New York Telephone Company, U S West Communications Company, South Central Bell Telephone Company, Southern Bell Telephone and Telegraph Company, Southwestern Bell Telephone Company, The Bell Telephone Company of Pennsylvania, The Chesapeake and Potomac Tele</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced communications services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Advanced communications services The term “advanced communications services” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affiliate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Affiliate The term “affiliate” means a person that (directly or indirectly) owns or controls, is owned or controlled by, or is under common ownership or control with, another person. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “own” means to own an equity interest (or the equivalent thereof) of more than 10 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amateur station</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Amateur station The term “amateur station” means a radio station operated by a duly authorized person interested in radio technique solely with a personal aim and without pecuniary interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>AT&amp;T Consent Decree</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) AT&amp;T Consent Decree The term “AT&amp;T Consent Decree” means the order entered August 24, 1982, in the antitrust action styled United States v. Western Electric, Civil Action No. 82–0192, in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, and includes any judgment or order with respect to such action entered on or after August 24, 1982.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bell operating company</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Bell operating company The term “Bell operating company”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Broadcast station</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Broadcast station The term “broadcast station”, “broadcasting station”, or “radio broadcast station” means a radio station equipped to engage in broadcasting as herein defined.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Broadcasting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Broadcasting The term “broadcasting” means the dissemination of radio communications intended to be received by the public, directly or by the intermediary of relay stations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cable service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Cable service The term “cable service” has the meaning given such term in section 522 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cable system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Cable system The term “cable system” has the meaning given such term in section 522 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_153_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chain broadcasting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Chain broadcasting The term “chain broadcasting” means simultaneous broadcasting of an identical program by two or more connected stations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>