<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/154" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/154/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/154/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_154"><akn:num>154</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Communications Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 154. Federal Communications Commission(a) Number of commissioners; appointmentThe Federal Communications Commission (in this chapter referred to as the “Commission”) shall be composed of five commissioners appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, one of whom the President shall designate as chairman.


(b) Qualifications(1) Each member of the Commission shall be a citizen of the United States.

(2)(A) No member of the Commission or person employed by the Commission shall—(i) be financially interested in any company or other entity engaged in the manufacture or sale of telecommunications equipment which is subject to regulation by the Commission;

(ii) be financially interested in any company or other entity engaged in the business of communication by wire or radio or in the use of the electromagnetic spectrum;

(iii) be financially interested in any company or other entity which controls any company or other entity specified in clause (i) or clause (ii), or which derives a significant portion of its total income from ownership of stocks, bonds, or other securities of any such company or other entity; or

(iv) be employed by, hold any official relation to, or own any stocks, bonds, or other securities of, any person significantly regulated by the Commission under this chapter;


except that the prohibitions established in this subparagraph shall apply only to financial interests in any company or other entity which has a significant interest in communications, manufacturing, or sales activities which are subject to regulation by the Commission.

(B)(i) The Commission shall have authority to waive, from time to time, the application of the prohibitions established in subparagraph (A) to persons employed by the Commission if the Commission determines that the financial interests of a person which are involved in a particular case are minimal, except that such waiver authority shall be subject to the provisions of section 208 of ti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number of commissioners; appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Number of commissioners; appointment The Federal Communications Commission (in this chapter referred to as the “Commission”) shall be composed of five commissioners appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, one of whom the President shall designate as chairman.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of office; vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms of office; vacancies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of Commission members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation of Commission members Each Commissioner shall receive an annual salary at the annual rate payable from time to time for level IV of the Executive Schedule, payable in monthly installments. The Chairman of the Commission, during the period of his service as Chairman, shall receive an annual salary at the annual rate payable from time to time for level III of the Executive Schedule.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal office; special sessions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Principal office; special sessions The principal office of the Commission shall be in the District of Columbia, where its general sessions shall be held; but whenever the convenience of the public or of the parties may be promoted or delay or expense prevented thereby, the Commission may hold special sessions in any part of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees and assistants; compensation of members of Field Engineering and Monitoring Bureau; use of amateur volunteers for certain purposes; commercial radio operator examinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employees and assistants; compensation of members of Field Engineering and Monitoring Bureau; use of amateur volunteers for certain purposes; commercial radio operator examinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Expenditures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum; seal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Quorum; seal Three members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum thereof. The Commission shall have an official seal which shall be judicially noticed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Duties and powers The Commission may perform any and all acts, make such rules and regulations, and issue such orders, not inconsistent with this chapter, as may be necessary in the execution of its functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_154_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conduct of proceedings; hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Conduct of proceedings; hearings The Commission may conduct its proceedings in such manner as will best conduce to the proper dispatch of business and to the ends of justice. No commissioner shall participate in any hearing or proceeding in which he has a pecuniary interest. Any party may appear before the Commission and be heard in person or by attorney. Every vote and official act of the Commission shall be entered of record, and its proceedings shall be public upon the request of any party interested. The Commission is authorized to withhold publication of records or proceedings containing secret information affecting the national defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>