<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/159a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/159a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/159a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_159a"><akn:num>159a</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions applicable to application and regulatory fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 159a. Provisions applicable to application and regulatory fees(a) Judicial review prohibitedAny adjustment or amendment to a schedule of fees under subsection (b) or (c) of section 158 of this title or subsection (c) or (d) of section 159 of this title is not subject to judicial review.


(b) Notice to CongressThe Commission shall transmit to Congress notification—(1) of any adjustment under section 158(b) or 159(c) of this title immediately upon the adoption of such adjustment; and

(2) of any amendment under section 158(c) or 159(d) of this title not later than 90 days before the effective date of such amendment.


(c) Enforcement(1) Penalties for late paymentThe Commission shall by rule prescribe an additional penalty for late payment of fees under section 158 or 159 of this title. Such additional penalty shall be 25 percent of the amount of the fee that was not paid in a timely manner.


(2) Interest on unpaid fees and penaltiesThe Commission shall charge interest, at a rate determined under section 3717 of title 31, on a fee under section 158 or 159 of this title or an additional penalty under this subsection that is not paid in a timely manner. Such section 3717 shall not otherwise apply with respect to such a fee or penalty.


(3) Dismissal of applications or filingsThe Commission may dismiss any application or other filing for failure to pay in a timely manner any fee under section 158 or 159 of this title or any interest or additional penalty under this subsection.


(4) Revocations(A) In generalIn addition to or in lieu of the penalties and dismissals authorized by this subsection, the Commission may revoke any instrument of authorization held by any licensee that has not paid in a timely manner a regulatory fee assessed under section 159 of this title or any related interest or penalty.


(B) NoticeRevocation action may be taken by the Commission under this paragraph after notice of the Commission’s intent to take such action is sent to the licensee by </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_159a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Judicial review prohibited Any adjustment or amendment to a schedule of fees under subsection (b) or (c) of section 158 of this title or subsection (c) or (d) of section 159 of this title is not subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_159a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice to Congress The Commission shall transmit to Congress notification—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_159a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_159a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver, reduction, and deferment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver, reduction, and deferment The Commission may waive, reduce, or defer payment of a fee under section 158 or 159 of this title or an interest charge or penalty under this section in any specific instance for good cause shown, where such action would promote the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_159a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment rules The Commission shall by rule permit payment—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_159a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounting system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Accounting system The Commission shall develop accounting systems necessary to make the amendments authorized by sections 158(c) and 159(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>