<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1603" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1603/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1603/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1603"><akn:num>1603</akn:num><akn:heading>Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Reimbursement Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1603. Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Reimbursement Program(a) In generalThe Commission shall establish a reimbursement program, to be known as the “Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Reimbursement Program”, to make reimbursements to providers of advanced communications service to replace covered communications equipment or services.


(b) EligibilityThe Commission may not make a reimbursement under the Program to a provider of advanced communications service unless the provider—(1) has 10,000,000 or fewer customers; and

(2) makes all of the certifications required by subsection (d)(4).


(c) Use of funds(1) In generalA recipient of a reimbursement under the Program shall use reimbursement funds solely for the purposes of—(A) permanently removing covered communications equipment or services purchased, rented, leased, or otherwise obtained—(i) as defined in the Report and Order of the Commission in the matter of Protecting Against National Security Threats to the Communications Supply Chain Through FCC Programs (FCC 19–121; WC Docket No. 18–89; adopted November 22, 2019) (in this section referred to as the “Report and Order”); or

(ii) as determined to be covered by both the process of the Report and Order and the Designation Orders of the Commission on June 30, 2020 (DA 20–690; PS Docket No. 19–351; adopted June 30, 2020) (DA 20–691; PS Docket No. 19–352; adopted June 30, 2020) (in this section collectively referred to as the “Designation Orders”);


(B) replacing the covered communications equipment or services removed as described in subparagraph (A) with communications equipment or services that are not covered communications equipment or services; and

(C) disposing of the covered communications equipment or services removed as described in subparagraph (A) in accordance with the requirements under subsection (d)(7).


(2) LimitationsA recipient of a reimbursement under the Program may not—(A) use reimbursement funds to remove, replace, or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Commission shall establish a reimbursement program, to be known as the “Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Reimbursement Program”, to make reimbursements to providers of advanced communications service to replace covered communications equipment or services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility The Commission may not make a reimbursement under the Program to a provider of advanced communications service unless the provider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Measures to avoid waste, fraud, and abuse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Measures to avoid waste, fraud, and abuse</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of removal of equipment or service from list</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect of removal of equipment or service from list</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rulemaking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction regarding timing of reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction regarding timing of reimbursement Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Commission from making a reimbursement under the Program to a provider of advanced communications service before the provider incurs the cost of the permanent removal, replacement, and disposal of the covered communications equipment or service for which the application of the provider has been approved under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Education efforts The Commission shall engage in education efforts with providers of advanced communications service to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1603_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate from Federal universal service programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Separate from Federal universal service programs The Program shall be separate from any Federal universal service program established under section 254 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>