<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1704"><akn:num>1704</akn:num><akn:heading>Broadband Deployment Locations Map</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1704. Broadband Deployment Locations Map(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Broadband infrastructureThe term “broadband infrastructure” means any cables, fiber optics, wiring, or other permanent (integral to the structure) infrastructure, including wireless infrastructure, that—(A) is capable of providing access to internet connections in individual locations; and

(B) is an advanced telecommunications capability, as defined in section 1302(d) of this title.


(2) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Federal Communications Commission.


(3) Deployment Locations MapThe term “Deployment Locations Map” means the mapping tool required to be established under subsection (b).



(b) Establishment of Deployment Locations MapNot later than 18 months after November 15, 2021, the Commission shall, in consultation with all relevant Federal agencies, establish an online mapping tool to provide a locations overview of the overall geographic footprint of each broadband infrastructure deployment project funded by the Federal Government.


(c) RequirementsThe Deployment Locations Map shall be—(1) the centralized, authoritative source of information on funding made available by the Federal Government for broadband infrastructure deployment in the United States; and

(2) made publicly available on the website of the Commission.


(d) FunctionsIn establishing the Deployment Locations Map, the Commission shall ensure that the Deployment Locations Map—(1) compiles data related to Federal funding for broadband infrastructure deployment provided by the Commission, the National Telecommunications and Information Administration, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Institute of Museum and Library Sciences, and any other Federal agency that provides such data relating to broadband infrastructure deployment funding to the Commission, including funding under—(A) thi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Deployment Locations Map</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of Deployment Locations Map Not later than 18 months after November 15, 2021, the Commission shall, in consultation with all relevant Federal agencies, establish an online mapping tool to provide a locations overview of the overall geographic footprint of each broadband infrastructure deployment project funded by the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements The Deployment Locations Map shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Functions In establishing the Deployment Locations Map, the Commission shall ensure that the Deployment Locations Map—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic updates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Periodic updates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>No effect on programmatic missions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No effect on programmatic missions Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the programmatic missions of Federal agencies providing funding for broadband infrastructure development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonduplication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nonduplication The requirements in this section shall be consistent with and avoid duplication with the provisions of section 903 of division FF of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (Public Law 116–260) [47 U.S.C. 1307].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding Of the amounts appropriated to carry out this division under this Act, $10,000,000 shall be made available to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>