<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1752" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1752/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/1752/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1752"><akn:num>1752</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefit for broadband service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1752. Benefit for broadband service(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Broadband internet access serviceThe term “broadband internet access service” has the meaning given such term in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.


(2) Broadband providerThe term “broadband provider” means a provider of broadband internet access service.


(3) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Federal Communications Commission.


(4) Connected deviceThe term “connected device” means a laptop or desktop computer or a tablet.


(5) Designated as an eligible telecommunications carrierThe term “designated as an eligible telecommunications carrier”, with respect to a broadband provider, means the broadband provider is designated as an eligible telecommunications carrier under section 214(e) of the Communications Act of 1934 (47 U.S.C. 214(e)).


(6) Eligible householdThe term “eligible household” means, regardless of whether the household or any member of the household receives support under subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), and regardless of whether any member of the household has any past or present arrearages with a broadband provider, a household in which—(A) at least one member of the household meets the qualifications in subsection (a) or (b) of section 54.409 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation) except that such subsection (a), including for purposes of such subsection (b), shall be applied by substituting “200 percent” for “135 percent”;

(B) at least one member of the household has applied for and been approved to receive benefits under the free and reduced price lunch program under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.) or the school breakfast program under section 1773 of title 42;

(C) at least one member of the household has received a Federal Pell Grant under section 1070a of title 20 in the current a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affordable Connectivity Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Affordable Connectivity Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility of providers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall affect the collection, distribution, or administration of the Lifeline Assistance Program governed by the rules set forth in subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Part 54 regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Part 54 regulations Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the Commission from providing that the regulations in part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation, shall apply in whole or in part to the Affordable Connectivity Program, shall not apply in whole or in part to such Program, or shall be modified in whole or in part for purposes of application to such Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Enforcement A violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section shall be treated as a violation of the Communications Act of 1934 (47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.) or a regulation promulgated under such Act. The Commission shall enforce this section and the regulations promulgated under this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Communications Act of 1934 were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affordable Connectivity Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Affordable Connectivity Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safe harbor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Safe harbor The Commission may not enforce a violation of this section under section 501, 502, or 503 of the Communications Act of 1934 (47 U.S.C. 501; 502; 503), or any rules of the Commission promulgated under such sections of such Act, if a participating provider demonstrates to the Commission that such provider relied in good faith on information provided to such provider to make the verification required by subsection (b)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>