<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/222" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/222/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/222/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_222"><akn:num>222</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy of customer information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 222. Privacy of customer information(a) In generalEvery telecommunications carrier has a duty to protect the confidentiality of proprietary information of, and relating to, other telecommunication carriers, equipment manufacturers, and customers, including telecommunication carriers reselling telecommunications services provided by a telecommunications carrier.


(b) Confidentiality of carrier informationA telecommunications carrier that receives or obtains proprietary information from another carrier for purposes of providing any telecommunications service shall use such information only for such purpose, and shall not use such information for its own marketing efforts.


(c) Confidentiality of customer proprietary network information(1) Privacy requirements for telecommunications carriersExcept as required by law or with the approval of the customer, a telecommunications carrier that receives or obtains customer proprietary network information by virtue of its provision of a telecommunications service shall only use, disclose, or permit access to individually identifiable customer proprietary network information in its provision of (A) the telecommunications service from which such information is derived, or (B) services necessary to, or used in, the provision of such telecommunications service, including the publishing of directories.


(2) Disclosure on request by customersA telecommunications carrier shall disclose customer proprietary network information, upon affirmative written request by the customer, to any person designated by the customer.


(3) Aggregate customer informationA telecommunications carrier that receives or obtains customer proprietary network information by virtue of its provision of a telecommunications service may use, disclose, or permit access to aggregate customer information other than for the purposes described in paragraph (1). A local exchange carrier may use, disclose, or permit access to aggregate customer information other tha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Every telecommunications carrier has a duty to protect the confidentiality of proprietary information of, and relating to, other telecommunication carriers, equipment manufacturers, and customers, including telecommunication carriers reselling telecommunications services provided by a telecommunications carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of carrier information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Confidentiality of carrier information A telecommunications carrier that receives or obtains proprietary information from another carrier for purposes of providing any telecommunications service shall use such information only for such purpose, and shall not use such information for its own marketing efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of customer proprietary network information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Confidentiality of customer proprietary network information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exceptions Nothing in this section prohibits a telecommunications carrier from using, disclosing, or permitting access to customer proprietary network information obtained from its customers, either directly or indirectly through its agents—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subscriber list information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subscriber list information Notwithstanding subsections (b), (c), and (d), a telecommunications carrier that provides telephone exchange service shall provide subscriber list information gathered in its capacity as a provider of such service on a timely and unbundled basis, under nondiscriminatory and reasonable rates, terms, and conditions, to any person upon request for the purpose of publishing directories in any format.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to use location information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authority to use location information For purposes of subsection (c)(1), without the express prior authorization of the customer, a customer shall not be considered to have approved the use or disclosure of or access to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subscriber listed and unlisted information for emergency services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subscriber listed and unlisted information for emergency services Notwithstanding subsections (b), (c), and (d), a telecommunications carrier that provides telephone exchange service or a provider of IP-enabled voice service (as such term is defined in section 615b of this title) shall provide information described in subsection (i)(3)(A) 11 So in original. Probably should be subsection “(h)(3)(A)”. (including information pertaining to subscribers whose information is unlisted or unpublished) that is in its possession or control (including information pertaining to subscribers of other carriers) on a timely and unbundled basis, under nondiscriminatory and reasonable rates, terms, and conditions to providers of emergency services, and providers of emergency support services, solely for purposes of delivering or assisting in the delivery of emergency services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>