<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/226" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/226/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/226/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_226"><akn:num>226</akn:num><akn:heading>Telephone operator services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 226. Telephone operator services(a) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) The term “access code” means a sequence of numbers that, when dialed, connect the caller to the provider of operator services associated with that sequence.

(2) The term “aggregator” means any person that, in the ordinary course of its operations, makes telephones available to the public or to transient users of its premises, for interstate telephone calls using a provider of operator services.

(3) The term “call splashing” means the transfer of a telephone call from one provider of operator services to another such provider in such a manner that the subsequent provider is unable or unwilling to determine the location of the origination of the call and, because of such inability or unwillingness, is prevented from billing the call on the basis of such location.

(4) The term “consumer” means a person initiating any interstate telephone call using operator services.

(5) The term “equal access” has the meaning given that term in Appendix B of the Modification of Final Judgment entered August 24, 1982, in United States v. Western Electric, Civil Action No. 82–0192 (United States District Court, District of Columbia), as amended by the Court in its orders issued prior to October 17, 1990.

(6) The term “equal access code” means an access code that allows the public to obtain an equal access connection to the carrier associated with that code.

(7) The term “operator services” means any interstate telecommunications service initiated from an aggregator location that includes, as a component, any automatic or live assistance to a consumer to arrange for billing or completion, or both, of an interstate telephone call through a method other than—(A) automatic completion with billing to the telephone from which the call originated; or

(B) completion through an access code used by the consumer, with billing to an account previously established with the carrier by the consumer.


(8) The term “pre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for providers of operator services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements for providers of operator services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for aggregators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for aggregators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rulemaking required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) General rulemaking required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate rulemaking on access and compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Separate rulemaking on access and compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technological capability of equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Technological capability of equipment Any equipment and software manufactured or imported more than 18 months after October 17, 1990, and installed by any aggregator shall be technologically capable of providing consumers with access to interstate providers of operator services through the use of equal access codes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fraud</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fraud In any proceeding to carry out the provisions of this section, the Commission shall require such actions or measures as are necessary to ensure that aggregators are not exposed to undue risk of fraud.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations of rate compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Determinations of rate compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Statutory construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter the obligations, powers, or duties of common carriers or the Commission under the other sections of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>