<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/231" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/231/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/231/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_231"><akn:num>231</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction of access by minors to materials commercially distributed by means of World Wide Web tha</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 231. Restriction of access by minors to materials commercially distributed by means of World Wide Web that are harmful to minors(a) Requirement to restrict access(1) Prohibited conductWhoever knowingly and with knowledge of the character of the material, in interstate or foreign commerce by means of the World Wide Web, makes any communication for commercial purposes that is available to any minor and that includes any material that is harmful to minors shall be fined not more than $50,000, imprisoned not more than 6 months, or both.


(2) Intentional violationsIn addition to the penalties under paragraph (1), whoever intentionally violates such paragraph shall be subject to a fine of not more than $50,000 for each violation. For purposes of this paragraph, each day of violation shall constitute a separate violation.


(3) Civil penaltyIn addition to the penalties under paragraphs (1) and (2), whoever violates paragraph (1) shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $50,000 for each violation. For purposes of this paragraph, each day of violation shall constitute a separate violation.



(b) Inapplicability of carriers and other service providersFor purposes of subsection (a), a person shall not be considered to make any communication for commercial purposes to the extent that such person is—(1) a telecommunications carrier engaged in the provision of a telecommunications service;

(2) a person engaged in the business of providing an Internet access service;

(3) a person engaged in the business of providing an Internet information location tool; or

(4) similarly engaged in the transmission, storage, retrieval, hosting, formatting, or translation (or any combination thereof) of a communication made by another person, without selection or alteration of the content of the communication, except that such person’s deletion of a particular communication or material made by another person in a manner consistent with subsection (c) or section 230 of this title </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to restrict access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement to restrict access</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of carriers and other service providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inapplicability of carriers and other service providers For purposes of subsection (a), a person shall not be considered to make any communication for commercial purposes to the extent that such person is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affirmative defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Affirmative defense</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy protection requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Privacy protection requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this subsection,11 So in original. Probably should be “section,”. the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>