<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/251" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/251/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/251/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_251"><akn:num>251</akn:num><akn:heading>Interconnection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 251. Interconnection(a) General duty of telecommunications carriersEach telecommunications carrier has the duty—(1) to interconnect directly or indirectly with the facilities and equipment of other telecommunications carriers; and

(2) not to install network features, functions, or capabilities that do not comply with the guidelines and standards established pursuant to section 255 or 256 of this title.


(b) Obligations of all local exchange carriersEach local exchange carrier has the following duties:(1) ResaleThe duty not to prohibit, and not to impose unreasonable or discriminatory conditions or limitations on, the resale of its telecommunications services.


(2) Number portabilityThe duty to provide, to the extent technically feasible, number portability in accordance with requirements prescribed by the Commission.


(3) Dialing parityThe duty to provide dialing parity to competing providers of telephone exchange service and telephone toll service, and the duty to permit all such providers to have nondiscriminatory access to telephone numbers, operator services, directory assistance, and directory listing, with no unreasonable dialing delays.


(4) Access to rights-of-wayThe duty to afford access to the poles, ducts, conduits, and rights-of-way of such carrier to competing providers of telecommunications services on rates, terms, and conditions that are consistent with section 224 of this title.


(5) Reciprocal compensationThe duty to establish reciprocal compensation arrangements for the transport and termination of telecommunications.



(c) Additional obligations of incumbent local exchange carriersIn addition to the duties contained in subsection (b), each incumbent local exchange carrier has the following duties:(1) Duty to negotiateThe duty to negotiate in good faith in accordance with section 252 of this title the particular terms and conditions of agreements to fulfill the duties described in paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (b) and this subs</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General duty of telecommunications carriers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General duty of telecommunications carriers Each telecommunications carrier has the duty—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations of all local exchange carriers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Obligations of all local exchange carriers Each local exchange carrier has the following duties:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional obligations of incumbent local exchange carriers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional obligations of incumbent local exchange carriers In addition to the duties contained in subsection (b), each incumbent local exchange carrier has the following duties:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Numbering administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Numbering administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions, suspensions, and modifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemptions, suspensions, and modifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued enforcement of exchange access and interconnection requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Continued enforcement of exchange access and interconnection requirements On and after February 8, 1996, each local exchange carrier, to the extent that it provides wireline services, shall provide exchange access, information access, and exchange services for such access to interexchange carriers and information service providers in accordance with the same equal access and nondiscriminatory interconnection restrictions and obligations (including receipt of compensation) that apply to such carrier on the date immediately preceding February 8, 1996, under any court order, consent decree, or regulation, order, or policy of the Commission, until such restrictions and obligations are explicitly superseded by regulations prescribed by the Commission after February 8, 1996. During the period beginning on February 8, 1996, and until such restrictions and obligations are so superseded, such restrictions and obligations shall be enforceable in the same manner as regulations of the Commissi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Incumbent local exchange carrier” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Incumbent local exchange carrier” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Savings provision Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or otherwise affect the Commission’s authority under section 201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>