<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/260" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/260/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/260/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_260"><akn:num>260</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of telemessaging service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 260. Provision of telemessaging service(a) Nondiscrimination safeguardsAny local exchange carrier subject to the requirements of section 251(c) of this title that provides telemessaging service—(1) shall not subsidize its telemessaging service directly or indirectly from its telephone exchange service or its exchange access; and

(2) shall not prefer or discriminate in favor of its telemessaging service operations in its provision of telecommunications services.


(b) Expedited consideration of complaintsThe Commission shall establish procedures for the receipt and review of complaints concerning violations of subsection (a) or the regulations thereunder that result in material financial harm to a provider of telemessaging service. Such procedures shall ensure that the Commission will make a final determination with respect to any such complaint within 120 days after receipt of the complaint. If the complaint contains an appropriate showing that the alleged violation occurred, the Commission shall, within 60 days after receipt of the complaint, order the local exchange carrier and any affiliates to cease engaging in such violation pending such final determination.


(c) “Telemessaging service” definedAs used in this section, the term “telemessaging service” means voice mail and voice storage and retrieval services, any live operator services used to record, transcribe, or relay messages (other than telecommunications relay services), and any ancillary services offered in combination with these services.


(June 19, 1934, ch. 652, title II, § 260, as added Pub. L. 104–104, title I, § 101(a), Feb. 8, 1996, 110 Stat. 79.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_260_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination safeguards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nondiscrimination safeguards Any local exchange carrier subject to the requirements of section 251(c) of this title that provides telemessaging service—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_260_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited consideration of complaints</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expedited consideration of complaints The Commission shall establish procedures for the receipt and review of complaints concerning violations of subsection (a) or the regulations thereunder that result in material financial harm to a provider of telemessaging service. Such procedures shall ensure that the Commission will make a final determination with respect to any such complaint within 120 days after receipt of the complaint. If the complaint contains an appropriate showing that the alleged violation occurred, the Commission shall, within 60 days after receipt of the complaint, order the local exchange carrier and any affiliates to cease engaging in such violation pending such final determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_260_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Telemessaging service” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Telemessaging service” defined As used in this section, the term “telemessaging service” means voice mail and voice storage and retrieval services, any live operator services used to record, transcribe, or relay messages (other than telecommunications relay services), and any ancillary services offered in combination with these services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>