<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/262" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/262/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/262/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_262"><akn:num>262</akn:num><akn:heading>Ensuring the integrity of voice communications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 262. Ensuring the integrity of voice communications(a) Registration and compliance by intermediate providersAn intermediate provider that offers or holds itself out as offering the capability to transmit covered voice communications from one destination to another and that charges any rate to any other entity (including an affiliated entity) for the transmission shall—(1) register with the Commission; and

(2) comply with the service quality standards for such transmission to be established by the Commission under subsection (c)(1)(B).


(b) Required use of registered intermediate providersA covered provider may not use an intermediate provider to transmit covered voice communications unless such intermediate provider is registered under subsection (a)(1).


(c) Commission rules(1) In general(A) RegistryNot later than 180 days after February 26, 2018, the Commission shall promulgate rules to establish a registry to record registrations under subsection (a)(1).


(B) Service quality standardsNot later than 1 year after February 26, 2018, the Commission shall promulgate rules to establish service quality standards for the transmission of covered voice communications by intermediate providers.



(2) RequirementsIn promulgating the rules required by paragraph (1), the Commission shall—(A) ensure the integrity of the transmission of covered voice communications to all customers in the United States; and

(B) prevent unjust or unreasonable discrimination among areas of the United States in the delivery of covered voice communications.



(d) Public availability of registryThe Commission shall make the registry established under subsection (c)(1)(A) publicly available on the website of the Commission.


(e) Scope of applicationThe requirements of this section shall apply regardless of the format by which any communication or service is provided, the protocol or format by which the transmission of such communication or service is achieved, or the regulatory classificatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration and compliance by intermediate providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Registration and compliance by intermediate providers An intermediate provider that offers or holds itself out as offering the capability to transmit covered voice communications from one destination to another and that charges any rate to any other entity (including an affiliated entity) for the transmission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required use of registered intermediate providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required use of registered intermediate providers A covered provider may not use an intermediate provider to transmit covered voice communications unless such intermediate provider is registered under subsection (a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Commission rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public availability of registry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public availability of registry The Commission shall make the registry established under subsection (c)(1)(A) publicly available on the website of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Scope of application The requirements of this section shall apply regardless of the format by which any communication or service is provided, the protocol or format by which the transmission of such communication or service is achieved, or the regulatory classification of such communication or service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the regulatory classification of any communication or service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect on other laws Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt or expand the authority of a State public utility commission or other relevant State agency to collect data, or investigate and enforce State law and regulations, regarding the completion of intrastate voice communications, regardless of the format by which any communication or service is provided, the protocol or format by which the transmission of such communication or service is achieved, or the regulatory classification of such communication or service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exception The requirement under subsection (a)(2) to comply with the service quality standards established under subsection (c)(1)(B) shall not apply to a covered provider that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>