<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/271" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/271/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/271/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_271"><akn:num>271</akn:num><akn:heading>Bell operating company entry into interLATA services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 271. Bell operating company entry into interLATA services(a) General limitationNeither a Bell operating company, nor any affiliate of a Bell operating company, may provide interLATA services except as provided in this section.


(b) InterLATA services to which this section applies(1) In-region servicesA Bell operating company, or any affiliate of that Bell operating company, may provide interLATA services originating in any of its in-region States (as defined in subsection (i)) if the Commission approves the application of such company for such State under subsection (d)(3).


(2) Out-of-region servicesA Bell operating company, or any affiliate of that Bell operating company, may provide interLATA services originating outside its in-region States after February 8, 1996, subject to subsection (j).


(3) Incidental interLATA servicesA Bell operating company, or any affiliate of a Bell operating company, may provide incidental interLATA services (as defined in subsection (g)) originating in any State after February 8, 1996.


(4) TerminationNothing in this section prohibits a Bell operating company or any of its affiliates from providing termination for interLATA services, subject to subsection (j).



(c) Requirements for providing certain in-region interLATA services(1) Agreement or statementA Bell operating company meets the requirements of this paragraph if it meets the requirements of subparagraph (A) or subparagraph (B) of this paragraph for each State for which the authorization is sought.(A) Presence of a facilities-based competitorA Bell operating company meets the requirements of this subparagraph if it has entered into one or more binding agreements that have been approved under section 252 of this title specifying the terms and conditions under which the Bell operating company is providing access and interconnection to its network facilities for the network facilities of one or more unaffiliated competing providers of telephone exchange service (as define</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General limitation Neither a Bell operating company, nor any affiliate of a Bell operating company, may provide interLATA services except as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>InterLATA services to which this section applies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) InterLATA services to which this section applies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for providing certain in-region interLATA services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for providing certain in-region interLATA services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for previously authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exception for previously authorized activities Neither subsection (a) nor section 273 of this title shall prohibit a Bell operating company or affiliate from engaging, at any time after February 8, 1996, in any activity to the extent authorized by, and subject to the terms and conditions contained in, an order entered by the United States District Court for the District of Columbia pursuant to section VII or VIII(C) of the AT&amp;T Consent Decree if such order was entered on or before February 8, 1996, to the extent such order is not reversed or vacated on appeal. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit, or to impose terms or conditions on, an activity in which a Bell operating company is otherwise authorized to engage under any other provision of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Incidental interLATA services” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) “Incidental interLATA services” defined For purposes of this section, the term “incidental interLATA services” means the interLATA provision by a Bell operating company or its affiliate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations The provisions of subsection (g) are intended to be narrowly construed. The interLATA services provided under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of subsection (g)(1) are limited to those interLATA transmissions incidental to the provision by a Bell operating company or its affiliate of video, audio, and other programming services that the company or its affiliate is engaged in providing to the public. The Commission shall ensure that the provision of services authorized under subsection (g) by a Bell operating company or its affiliate will not adversely affect telephone exchange service ratepayers or competition in any telecommunications market.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Additional definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain service applications treated as in-region service applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Certain service applications treated as in-region service applications For purposes of this section, a Bell operating company application to provide 800 service, private line service, or their equivalents that— shall be considered an in-region service subject to the requirements of subsection (b)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>