<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/274" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/274/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/274/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_274"><akn:num>274</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic publishing by Bell operating companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 274. Electronic publishing by Bell operating companies(a) LimitationsNo Bell operating company or any affiliate may engage in the provision of electronic publishing that is disseminated by means of such Bell operating company’s or any of its affiliates’ basic telephone service, except that nothing in this section shall prohibit a separated affiliate or electronic publishing joint venture operated in accordance with this section from engaging in the provision of electronic publishing.


(b) Separated affiliate or electronic publishing joint venture requirementsA separated affiliate or electronic publishing joint venture shall be operated independently from the Bell operating company. Such separated affiliate or joint venture and the Bell operating company with which it is affiliated shall—(1) maintain separate books, records, and accounts and prepare separate financial statements;

(2) not incur debt in a manner that would permit a creditor of the separated affiliate or joint venture upon default to have recourse to the assets of the Bell operating company;

(3) carry out transactions (A) in a manner consistent with such independence, (B) pursuant to written contracts or tariffs that are filed with the Commission and made publicly available, and (C) in a manner that is auditable in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards;

(4) value any assets that are transferred directly or indirectly from the Bell operating company to a separated affiliate or joint venture, and record any transactions by which such assets are transferred, in accordance with such regulations as may be prescribed by the Commission or a State commission to prevent improper cross subsidies;

(5) between a separated affiliate and a Bell operating company—(A) have no officers, directors, and employees in common after the effective date of this section; and

(B) own no property in common;


(6) not use for the marketing of any product or service of the separated affiliate or joint venture</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitations No Bell operating company or any affiliate may engage in the provision of electronic publishing that is disseminated by means of such Bell operating company’s or any of its affiliates’ basic telephone service, except that nothing in this section shall prohibit a separated affiliate or electronic publishing joint venture operated in accordance with this section from engaging in the provision of electronic publishing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separated affiliate or electronic publishing joint venture requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Separated affiliate or electronic publishing joint venture requirements A separated affiliate or electronic publishing joint venture shall be operated independently from the Bell operating company. Such separated affiliate or joint venture and the Bell operating company with which it is affiliated shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint marketing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Joint marketing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bell operating company requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Bell operating company requirement A Bell operating company under common ownership or control with a separated affiliate or electronic publishing joint venture shall provide network access and interconnections for basic telephone service to electronic publishers at just and reasonable rates that are tariffed (so long as rates for such services are subject to regulation) and that are not higher on a per-unit basis than those charged for such services to any other electronic publisher or any separated affiliate engaged in electronic publishing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private right of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Private right of action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separated affiliate reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Separated affiliate reporting requirement Any separated affiliate under this section shall file with the Commission annual reports in a form substantially equivalent to the Form 10–K required by regulations of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effective dates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Electronic publishing” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Electronic publishing” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Additional definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>