<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/275" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/275/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/275/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_275"><akn:num>275</akn:num><akn:heading>Alarm monitoring services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 275. Alarm monitoring services(a) Delayed entry into alarm monitoring(1) ProhibitionNo Bell operating company or affiliate thereof shall engage in the provision of alarm monitoring services before the date which is 5 years after February 8, 1996.


(2) Existing activitiesParagraph (1) does not prohibit or limit the provision, directly or through an affiliate, of alarm monitoring services by a Bell operating company that was engaged in providing alarm monitoring services as of November 30, 1995, directly or through an affiliate. Such Bell operating company or affiliate may not acquire any equity interest in, or obtain financial control of, any unaffiliated alarm monitoring service entity after November 30, 1995, and until 5 years after February 8, 1996, except that this sentence shall not prohibit an exchange of customers for the customers of an unaffiliated alarm monitoring service entity.



(b) NondiscriminationAn incumbent local exchange carrier (as defined in section 251(h) of this title) engaged in the provision of alarm monitoring services shall—(1) provide nonaffiliated entities, upon reasonable request, with the network services it provides to its own alarm monitoring operations, on nondiscriminatory terms and conditions; and

(2) not subsidize its alarm monitoring services either directly or indirectly from telephone exchange service operations.


(c) Expedited consideration of complaintsThe Commission shall establish procedures for the receipt and review of complaints concerning violations of subsection (b) or the regulations thereunder that result in material financial harm to a provider of alarm monitoring service. Such procedures shall ensure that the Commission will make a final determination with respect to any such complaint within 120 days after receipt of the complaint. If the complaint contains an appropriate showing that the alleged violation occurred, as determined by the Commission in accordance with such regulations, the Commission shall, wi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_275_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delayed entry into alarm monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Delayed entry into alarm monitoring</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_275_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nondiscrimination An incumbent local exchange carrier (as defined in section 251(h) of this title) engaged in the provision of alarm monitoring services shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_275_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited consideration of complaints</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expedited consideration of complaints The Commission shall establish procedures for the receipt and review of complaints concerning violations of subsection (b) or the regulations thereunder that result in material financial harm to a provider of alarm monitoring service. Such procedures shall ensure that the Commission will make a final determination with respect to any such complaint within 120 days after receipt of the complaint. If the complaint contains an appropriate showing that the alleged violation occurred, as determined by the Commission in accordance with such regulations, the Commission shall, within 60 days after receipt of the complaint, order the incumbent local exchange carrier (as defined in section 251(h) of this title) and its affiliates to cease engaging in such violation pending such final determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_275_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of data A local exchange carrier may not record or use in any fashion the occurrence or contents of calls received by providers of alarm monitoring services for the purposes of marketing such services on behalf of such local exchange carrier, or any other entity. Any regulations necessary to enforce this subsection shall be issued initially within 6 months after February 8, 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_275_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Alarm monitoring service” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Alarm monitoring service” defined The term “alarm monitoring service” means a service that uses a device located at a residence, place of business, or other fixed premises— but does not include a service that uses a medical monitoring device attached to an individual for the automatic surveillance of an ongoing medical condition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>