<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/302a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/302a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/302a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_302a"><akn:num>302a</akn:num><akn:heading>Devices which interfere with radio reception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 302a. Devices which interfere with radio reception(a) RegulationsThe Commission may, consistent with the public interest, convenience, and necessity, make reasonable regulations (1) governing the interference potential of devices which in their operation are capable of emitting radio frequency energy by radiation, conduction, or other means in sufficient degree to cause harmful interference to radio communications; and (2) establishing minimum performance standards for home electronic equipment and systems to reduce their susceptibility to interference from radio frequency energy. Such regulations shall be applicable to the manufacture, import, sale, offer for sale, or shipment of such devices and home electronic equipment and systems, and to the use of such devices.


(b) RestrictionsNo person shall manufacture, import, sell, offer for sale, or ship devices or home electronic equipment and systems, or use devices, which fail to comply with regulations promulgated pursuant to this section.


(c) ExceptionsThe provisions of this section shall not be applicable to carriers transporting such devices or home electronic equipment and systems without trading in them, to devices or home electronic equipment and systems manufactured solely for export, to the manufacture, assembly, or installation of devices or home electronic equipment and systems for its own use by a public utility engaged in providing electric service, or to devices or home electronic equipment and systems for use by the Government of the United States or any agency thereof. Devices and home electronic equipment and systems for use by the Government of the United States or any agency thereof shall be developed, procured, or otherwise acquired, including offshore procurement, under United States Government criteria, standards, or specifications designed to achieve the objectives of reducing interference to radio reception and to home electronic equipment and systems, taking into account the unique needs </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations The Commission may, consistent with the public interest, convenience, and necessity, make reasonable regulations (1) governing the interference potential of devices which in their operation are capable of emitting radio frequency energy by radiation, conduction, or other means in sufficient degree to cause harmful interference to radio communications; and (2) establishing minimum performance standards for home electronic equipment and systems to reduce their susceptibility to interference from radio frequency energy. Such regulations shall be applicable to the manufacture, import, sale, offer for sale, or shipment of such devices and home electronic equipment and systems, and to the use of such devices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Restrictions No person shall manufacture, import, sell, offer for sale, or ship devices or home electronic equipment and systems, or use devices, which fail to comply with regulations promulgated pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions The provisions of this section shall not be applicable to carriers transporting such devices or home electronic equipment and systems without trading in them, to devices or home electronic equipment and systems manufactured solely for export, to the manufacture, assembly, or installation of devices or home electronic equipment and systems for its own use by a public utility engaged in providing electric service, or to devices or home electronic equipment and systems for use by the Government of the United States or any agency thereof. Devices and home electronic equipment and systems for use by the Government of the United States or any agency thereof shall be developed, procured, or otherwise acquired, including offshore procurement, under United States Government criteria, standards, or specifications designed to achieve the objectives of reducing interference to radio reception and to home electronic equipment and systems, taking into account the unique needs of natio</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cellular telecommunications receivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cellular telecommunications receivers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of equipment testing and certification to private laboratories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Delegation of equipment testing and certification to private laboratories The Commission may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local enforcement of FCC regulations on use of citizens band radio equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) State and local enforcement of FCC regulations on use of citizens band radio equipment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>