<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/303a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/303a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/303a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_303a"><akn:num>303a</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for children’s television programming</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 303a. Standards for children’s television programming(a) EstablishmentThe Commission shall, within 30 days after October 18, 1990, initiate a rulemaking proceeding to prescribe standards applicable to commercial television broadcast licensees with respect to the time devoted to commercial matter in conjunction with children’s television programming. The Commission shall, within 180 days after October 18, 1990, complete the rulemaking proceeding and prescribe final standards that meet the requirements of subsection (b).


(b) Advertising duration limitationsExcept as provided in subsection (c), the standards prescribed under subsection (a) shall include the requirement that each commercial television broadcast licensee shall limit the duration of advertising in children’s television programming to not more than 10.5 minutes per hour on weekends and not more than 12 minutes per hour on weekdays.


(c) Review of advertising duration limitations; modificationAfter January 1, 1993, the Commission—(1) may review and evaluate the advertising duration limitations required by subsection (b); and

(2) may, after notice and public comment and a demonstration of the need for modification of such limitations, modify such limitations in accordance with the public interest.


(d) “Commercial television broadcast licensee” definedAs used in this section, the term “commercial television broadcast licensee” includes a cable operator, as defined in section 522 of this title.


(Pub. L. 101–437, title I, § 102, Oct. 17, 1990, 104 Stat. 996.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Children’s Television Act of 1990, and not as part of the Communications Act of 1934 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Congressional FindingsPub. L. 101–437, title I, § 101, Oct. 17, 1990, 104 Stat. 996, provided that: 
“The Congress finds that—
“(1) it has been clearly demonstrated that television can assist children to learn important informat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_303a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Commission shall, within 30 days after October 18, 1990, initiate a rulemaking proceeding to prescribe standards applicable to commercial television broadcast licensees with respect to the time devoted to commercial matter in conjunction with children’s television programming. The Commission shall, within 180 days after October 18, 1990, complete the rulemaking proceeding and prescribe final standards that meet the requirements of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_303a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advertising duration limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advertising duration limitations Except as provided in subsection (c), the standards prescribed under subsection (a) shall include the requirement that each commercial television broadcast licensee shall limit the duration of advertising in children’s television programming to not more than 10.5 minutes per hour on weekends and not more than 12 minutes per hour on weekdays.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_303a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of advertising duration limitations; modification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review of advertising duration limitations; modification After January 1, 1993, the Commission—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_303a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Commercial television broadcast licensee” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Commercial television broadcast licensee” defined As used in this section, the term “commercial television broadcast licensee” includes a cable operator, as defined in section 522 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>