<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_307"><akn:num>307</akn:num><akn:heading>Licenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 307. Licenses(a) GrantThe Commission, if public convenience, interest, or necessity will be served thereby, subject to the limitations of this chapter, shall grant to any applicant therefor a station license provided for by this chapter.


(b) Allocation of facilitiesIn considering applications for licenses, and modifications and renewals thereof, when and insofar as there is demand for the same, the Commission shall make such distribution of licenses, frequencies, hours of operation, and of power among the several States and communities as to provide a fair, efficient, and equitable distribution of radio service to each of the same.


(c) Terms of licenses(1) Initial and renewal licensesEach license granted for the operation of a broadcasting station shall be for a term of not to exceed 8 years. Upon application therefor, a renewal of such license may be granted from time to time for a term of not to exceed 8 years from the date of expiration of the preceding license, if the Commission finds that public interest, convenience, and necessity would be served thereby. Consistent with the foregoing provisions of this subsection, the Commission may by rule prescribe the period or periods for which licenses shall be granted and renewed for particular classes of stations, but the Commission may not adopt or follow any rule which would preclude it, in any case involving a station of a particular class, from granting or renewing a license for a shorter period than that prescribed for stations of such class if, in its judgment, the public interest, convenience, or necessity would be served by such action.


(2) Materials in applicationIn order to expedite action on applications for renewal of broadcasting station licenses and in order to avoid needless expense to applicants for such renewals, the Commission shall not require any such applicant to file any information which previously has been furnished to the Commission or which is not directly material to the consideration</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant The Commission, if public convenience, interest, or necessity will be served thereby, subject to the limitations of this chapter, shall grant to any applicant therefor a station license provided for by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocation of facilities In considering applications for licenses, and modifications and renewals thereof, when and insofar as there is demand for the same, the Commission shall make such distribution of licenses, frequencies, hours of operation, and of power among the several States and communities as to provide a fair, efficient, and equitable distribution of radio service to each of the same.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of licenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms of licenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Renewals No renewal of an existing station license in the broadcast or the common carrier services shall be granted more than thirty days prior to the expiration of the original license.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of certain radio stations without individual licenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Operation of certain radio stations without individual licenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Areas in Alaska without access to over the air broadcasts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Areas in Alaska without access to over the air broadcasts Notwithstanding any other provision of law, (1) any holder of a broadcast license may broadcast to an area of Alaska that otherwise does not have access to over the air broadcasts via translator, microwave, or other alternative signal delivery even if another holder of a broadcast license begins broadcasting to such area, (2) any holder of a broadcast license who has broadcast to an area of Alaska that did not have access to over the air broadcasts via translator, microwave, or other alternative signal delivery may continue providing such service even if another holder of a broadcast license begins broadcasting to such area, and shall not be fined or subject to any other penalty, forfeiture, or revocation related to providing such service including any fine, penalty, forfeiture, or revocation for continuing to operate notwithstanding orders to the contrary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>