<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/338" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/338/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/338/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_338"><akn:num>338</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage of local television signals by satellite carriers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 338. Carriage of local television signals by satellite carriers(a) Carriage obligations(1) In generalEach satellite carrier providing, under section 122 of title 17, secondary transmissions to subscribers located within the local market of a television broadcast station of a primary transmission made by that station shall carry upon request the signals of all television broadcast stations located within that local market, subject to section 325(b) of this title.


(2) Remedies for failure to carryIn addition to the remedies available to television broadcast stations under section 501(f) of title 17, the Commission may use the Commission’s authority under this chapter to assure compliance with the obligations of this subsection, but in no instance shall a Commission enforcement proceeding be required as a predicate to the pursuit of a remedy available under such section 501(f).


(3) Low power station carriage optionalNo low power television station whose signals are provided under section 119(a)(14) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 17 shall be entitled to insist on carriage under this section, regardless of whether the satellite carrier provides secondary transmissions of the primary transmissions of other stations in the same local market pursuant to section 122 of such title, nor shall any such carriage be considered in connection with the requirements of subsection (c) of this section.


(4) Carriage of signals of local stations in certain marketsA satellite carrier that offers multichannel video programming distribution service in the United States to more than 5,000,000 subscribers shall (A) within 1 year after December 8, 2004, retransmit the signals originating as analog signals of each television broadcast station located in any local market within a State that is not part of the contiguous United States, and (B) within 30 months after December 8, 2004, retransmit the signals originating as digital signals of each such station. The retransmis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Carriage obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Good signal required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Good signal required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duplication not required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duplication not required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Channel positioning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Channel positioning No satellite carrier shall be required to provide the signal of a local television broadcast station to subscribers in that station’s local market on any particular channel number or to provide the signals in any particular order, except that the satellite carrier shall retransmit the signal of the local television broadcast stations to subscribers in the stations’ local market on contiguous channels and provide access to such station’s signals at a nondiscriminatory price and in a nondiscriminatory manner on any navigational device, on-screen program guide, or menu.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation for carriage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Compensation for carriage A satellite carrier shall not accept or request monetary payment or other valuable consideration in exchange either for carriage of local television broadcast stations in fulfillment of the requirements of this section or for channel positioning rights provided to such stations under this section, except that any such station may be required to bear the costs associated with delivering a good quality signal to the local receive facility of the satellite carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Remedies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage of local stations on a single reception antenna</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Carriage of local stations on a single reception antenna</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional notices to subscribers, networks, and stations concerning signal carriage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Additional notices to subscribers, networks, and stations concerning signal carriage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy rights of satellite subscribers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Privacy rights of satellite subscribers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_338_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations by Commission Within 1 year after November 29, 1999, the Commission shall issue regulations implementing this section following a rulemaking proceeding. The regulations prescribed under this section shall include requirements on satellite carriers that are comparable to the requirements on cable operators under sections 534(b)(3) and (4) and 535(g)(1) and (2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>