<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/339" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/339/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/339/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_339"><akn:num>339</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage of distant television stations by satellite carriers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 339. Carriage of distant television stations by satellite carriers(a) Provisions relating to carriage of distant signals(1) Carriage permitted(A) In generalSubject to section 119 of title 17, any satellite carrier shall be permitted to provide the signals of no more than two network stations in a single day for each television network to any household not located within the local markets of those network stations.


(B) Additional serviceIn addition to signals provided under subparagraph (A), any satellite carrier may also provide service under the statutory license of section 122 of title 17, to the local market within which such household is located. The service provided under section 122 of such title may be in addition to the two signals provided under section 119 of such title.



(2) Replacement of distant signals with local signalsNotwithstanding any other provision of paragraph (1), the following rules shall apply after December 8, 2004:(A) Rules for grandfathered subscribers(i) For those receiving distant signalsIn the case of a subscriber of a satellite carrier who is eligible to receive the signal of a network station solely by reason of section 119(e) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 17 (in this subparagraph referred to as a “distant signal”), and who, as of October 1, 2009, is receiving the distant signal of that network station, the following shall apply:(I) In a case in which the satellite carrier makes available to the subscriber the signal of a local network station affiliated with the same television network pursuant to section 338 of this title, the carrier may only provide the secondary transmissions of the distant signal of a station affiliated with the same network to that subscriber—(aa) if, within 60 days after receiving the notice of the satellite carrier under section 338(h)(1) of this title, the subscriber elects to retain the distant signal; but

(bb) only until such time as the subscriber elects to receive such local sign</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_339_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to carriage of distant signals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Provisions relating to carriage of distant signals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_339_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of network nonduplication, syndicated exclusivity, and sports blackout to satellite retransmission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Extension of network nonduplication, syndicated exclusivity, and sports blackout to satellite retransmission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_339_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for retransmission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility for retransmission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_339_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For the purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>