<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/345" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/345/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/345/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_345"><akn:num>345</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of survivors of domestic violence, human trafficking, and related crimes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 345. Protection of survivors of domestic violence, human trafficking, and related crimes(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) AbuserThe term “abuser” means an individual who has committed or allegedly committed a covered act against—(A) an individual who seeks relief under subsection (b); or

(B) an individual in the care of an individual who seeks relief under subsection (b).


(2) Covered act(A) In generalThe term “covered act” means conduct that constitutes—(i) a crime described in section 12291(a)of title 34, including domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, stalking, and sex trafficking;

(ii) an act or practice described in paragraph (11) or (12) of section 7102 of title 22 (relating to severe forms of trafficking in persons and sex trafficking, respectively); or

(iii) an act under State law, Tribal law, or the Uniform Code of Military Justice that is similar to an offense described in clause (i) or (ii).


(B) Conviction not requiredNothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to require a criminal conviction or any other determination of a court in order for conduct to constitute a covered act.



(3) Covered providerThe term “covered provider” means a provider of a private mobile service or commercial mobile service, as those terms are defined in section 332(d) of this title.


(4) Primary account holderThe term “primary account holder” means an individual who is a party to a mobile service contract with a covered provider.


(5) Shared mobile service contractThe term “shared mobile service contract”—(A) means a mobile service contract for an account that includes not less than 2 consumers; and

(B) does not include enterprise services offered by a covered provider.


(6) SurvivorThe term “survivor” means an individual who is not less than 18 years old and—(A) against whom a covered act has been committed or allegedly committed; or

(B) who cares for another individual against whom a covered act has been committed or allegedly committed (provi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_345_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_345_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation of lines from shared mobile service contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Separation of lines from shared mobile service contract</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_345_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Line separation request</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Line separation request</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_345_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidential and secure treatment of personal information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Confidential and secure treatment of personal information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_345_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of information to consumers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability of information to consumers A covered provider shall make information about the options and process described in subsections (b) and (c) readily available to consumers—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_345_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical infeasibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Technical infeasibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_345_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Liability protection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>