<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/390" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/390/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/390/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_390"><akn:num>390</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 390. Declaration of purpose
The purpose of this subpart is to assist, through matching grants, in the planning and construction of public telecommunications facilities in order to achieve the following objectives: (1) extend delivery of public telecommunications services to as many citizens of the United States as possible by the most efficient and economical means, including the use of broadcast and nonbroadcast technologies; (2) increase public telecommunications services and facilities available to, operated by, and owned by minorities and women; and (3) strengthen the capability of existing public television and radio stations to provide public telecommunications services to the public.
(June 19, 1934, ch. 652, title III, § 390, as added Pub. L. 87–447, May 1, 1962, 76 Stat. 64; amended Pub. L. 90–129, title I, § 103(a), title II, § 201(2), Nov. 7, 1967, 81 Stat. 365, 367; Pub. L. 94–309, § 2(c), June 5, 1976, 90 Stat. 683; Pub. L. 95–567, title I, § 101, Nov. 2, 1978, 92 Stat. 2405.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1978—Pub. L. 95–567 expanded scope of section to authorize construction financing for telecommunications facilities other than television and radio broadcasting, and assistance in the planning, as well as the construction, of such facilities, and substituted provisions relating to the objectives of this subpart for former provision relating to the demonstration of the use of telecommunication technologies for the distribution of information.
1976—Pub. L. 94–309 designated existing phrase relating to assistance in the construction of noncommercial educational broadcasting facilities as cl. (1) and added cl. (2).
1967—Pub. L. 90–129 inserted “noncommercial” and “or radio” and substituted “subpart” for “part”, respectively.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1978 AmendmentPub. L. 95–567, title IV, § 403, Nov. 2, 1978, 92 Stat. 2424, provided that: “The provisions of this Act [enacting section 395 of this title, amending this sectio</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>