<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/394" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/394/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/394/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_394"><akn:num>394</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of National Endowment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 394. Establishment of National Endowment(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section to enhance the education of children through the creation and production of television programming specifically directed toward the development of fundamental intellectual skills.


(b) Establishment; contracts and grants(1) There is established, under the direction of the Secretary, a National Endowment for Children’s Educational Television. In administering the National Endowment, the Secretary is authorized to—(A) contract with the Corporation for the production of educational television programming for children; and

(B) make grants directly to persons proposing to create and produce educational television programming for children.


The Secretary shall consult with the Advisory Council on Children’s Educational Television in the making of the grants or the awarding of contracts for the purpose of making the grants.

(2) Contracts and grants under this section shall be made on the condition that the programming shall—(A) during the first two years after its production, be made available only to public television licensees and permittees and noncommercial television licensees and permittees; and

(B) thereafter be made available to any commercial television licensee or permittee or cable television system operator, at a charge established by the Secretary that will assure the maximum practicable distribution of such programming, so long as such licensee, permittee, or operator does not interrupt the programming with commercial advertisements.


The Secretary may, consistent with the purpose and provisions of this section, permit the programming to be distributed to persons using other media, establish conditions relating to such distribution, and apply those conditions to any contract or grant made under this section. The Secretary may waive the requirements of subparagraph (A) if the Secretary finds that neither public television licensees and permittees nor noncommercial tele</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_394_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this section to enhance the education of children through the creation and production of television programming specifically directed toward the development of fundamental intellectual skills.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_394_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; contracts and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment; contracts and grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_394_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for contracts and grants; applications for contracts and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria for contracts and grants; applications for contracts and grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_394_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of grants Upon approving any application for a grant under subsection (b)(1)(B), the Secretary shall make a grant to the applicant in an amount determined by the Secretary, except that such amounts shall not exceed 75 percent of the amount determined by the Secretary to be the reasonable and necessary cost of the project for which the grant is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_394_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council on Children’s Educational Television</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Advisory Council on Children’s Educational Television</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_394_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping relating to grants; audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Recordkeeping relating to grants; audits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_394_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Issuance of rules and regulations The Secretary is authorized to make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section, including those relating to the order of priority in approving applications for projects under this section or to determining the amounts of contracts and grants for such projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_394_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations; availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations; availability There are authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for fiscal year 1991, $4,000,000 for fiscal year 1992, $5,000,000 for fiscal year 1993, and $6,000,000 for fiscal year 1994 to be used by the Secretary to carry out the provisions of this section. Sums appropriated under this subsection for any fiscal year shall remain available for contracts and grants for projects for which applications approved under this section have been submitted wtihin 11 So in original. Probably should be “within”. one year after the last day of such fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_394_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>