<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/396" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/396/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/396/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_396"><akn:num>396</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporation for Public Broadcasting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 396. Corporation for Public Broadcasting(a) Congressional declaration of policyThe Congress hereby finds and declares that—(1) it is in the public interest to encourage the growth and development of public radio and television broadcasting, including the use of such media for instructional, educational, and cultural purposes;

(2) it is in the public interest to encourage the growth and development of nonbroadcast telecommunications technologies for the delivery of public telecommunications services;

(3) expansion and development of public telecommunications and of diversity of its programming depend on freedom, imagination, and initiative on both local and national levels;

(4) the encouragement and support of public telecommunications, while matters of importance for private and local development, are also of appropriate and important concern to the Federal Government;

(5) it furthers the general welfare to encourage public telecommunications services which will be responsive to the interests of people both in particular localities and throughout the United States, which will constitute an expression of diversity and excellence, and which will constitute a source of alternative telecommunications services for all the citizens of the Nation;

(6) it is in the public interest to encourage the development of programming that involves creative risks and that addresses the needs of unserved and underserved audiences, particularly children and minorities;

(7) it is necessary and appropriate for the Federal Government to complement, assist, and support a national policy that will most effectively make public telecommunications services available to all citizens of the United States;

(8) public television and radio stations and public telecommunications services constitute valuable local community resources for utilizing electronic media to address national concerns and solve local problems through community programs and outreach programs;

(9) it is in the public i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional declaration of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional declaration of policy The Congress hereby finds and declares that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Corporation; application of District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of Corporation; application of District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act There is authorized to be established a nonprofit corporation, to be known as the “Corporation for Public Broadcasting”, which will not be an agency or establishment of the United States Government. The Corporation shall be subject to the provisions of this section, and, to the extent consistent with this section, to the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors; functions, duties, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Board of Directors; functions, duties, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of Chairman and Vice Chairman; compensation of Board members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Election of Chairman and Vice Chairman; compensation of Board members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers and employees; term of office, compensation, qualifications, and removal; political party affiliation, political test or qualification when taking personnel actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Officers and employees; term of office, compensation, qualifications, and removal; political party affiliation, political test or qualification when taking personnel actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonprofit and nonpolitical nature of Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nonprofit and nonpolitical nature of Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes and activities of Corporation; powers under District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Purposes and activities of Corporation; powers under District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free or reduced rate interconnection service; access to facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Free or reduced rate interconnection service; access to facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 115–141, div. P, title IV, § 402(i)(8)(A), Mar. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 1090</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_396_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repeal, alteration, or amendment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Repeal, alteration, or amendment The right to repeal, alter, or amend this section at any time is expressly reserved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>