<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/397" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/397/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/397/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_397"><akn:num>397</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 397. Definitions
For the purposes of this part—(1) The term “construction” (as applied to public telecommunications facilities) means acquisition (including acquisition by lease), installation, and modernization of public telecommunications facilities and planning and preparatory steps incidental to any such acquisition, installation, or modernization.

(2) The term “Corporation” means the Corporation for Public Broadcasting authorized to be established in subpart D.

(3) The term “interconnection” means the use of microwave equipment, boosters, translators, repeaters, communication space satellites, or other apparatus or equipment for the transmission and distribution of television or radio programs to public telecommunications entities.

(4) The term “interconnection system” means any system of interconnection facilities used for the distribution of programs to public telecommunications entities.

(5) The term “meeting” means the deliberations of at least the number of members of a governing or advisory body, or any committee thereof, required to take action on behalf of such body or committee where such deliberations determine or result in the joint conduct or disposition of the governing or advisory body’s business, or the committee’s business, as the case may be, but only to the extent that such deliberations relate to public broadcasting.

(6) The terms “noncommercial educational broadcast station” and “public broadcast station” mean a television or radio broadcast station which—(A) under the rules and regulations of the Commission in effect on November 2, 1978, is eligible to be licensed by the Commission as a noncommercial educational radio or television broadcast station and which is owned and operated by a public agency or nonprofit private foundation, corporation, or association; or

(B) is owned and operated by a municipality and which transmits only noncommercial programs for education purposes.


(7) The term “noncommercial telecommunications entity”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “construction” (as applied to public telecommunications facilities) means acquisition (including acquisition by lease), installation, and modernization of public telecommunications facilities and planning and preparatory steps incidental to any such acquisition, installation, or modernization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “Corporation” means the Corporation for Public Broadcasting authorized to be established in subpart D.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “interconnection” means the use of microwave equipment, boosters, translators, repeaters, communication space satellites, or other apparatus or equipment for the transmission and distribution of television or radio programs to public telecommunications entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “interconnection system” means any system of interconnection facilities used for the distribution of programs to public telecommunications entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “meeting” means the deliberations of at least the number of members of a governing or advisory body, or any committee thereof, required to take action on behalf of such body or committee where such deliberations determine or result in the joint conduct or disposition of the governing or advisory body’s business, or the committee’s business, as the case may be, but only to the extent that such deliberations relate to public broadcasting.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The terms “noncommercial educational broadcast station” and “public broadcast station” mean a television or radio broadcast station which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “noncommercial telecommunications entity” means any enterprise which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “nonprofit” (as applied to any foundation, corporation, or association) means a foundation, corporation, or association, no part of the net earnings of which inures, or may lawfully inure, to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “non-Federal financial support” means the total value of cash and the fair market value of property and services (including, to the extent provided in the second sentence of this paragraph, the personal services of volunteers) received— Such term includes the fair market value of personal services of volunteers, as computed using the valuation standards established by the Corporation, but only, with respect to such an entity in a fiscal year, to the extent that the value of the services does not exceed 5 percent of the total non-Federal financial support of the entity in such fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_397_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “preoperational expenses” means all nonconstruction costs incurred by new telecommunications entities before the date on which they begin providing service to the public, and all nonconstruction costs associated with expansion of existing entities before the date on which such expanded capacity is activated, except that such expenses shall not include any portion of the salaries of any personnel employed by an operating public telecommunications entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>