<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/399a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/399a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/399a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_399a"><akn:num>399a</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of business or institutional logograms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 399a. Use of business or institutional logograms(a) “Business or institutional logogram” definedFor purposes of this section, the term “business or institutional logogram” means any aural or visual letters or words, or any symbol or sign, which is used for the exclusive purpose of identifying any corporation, company, or other organization, and which is not used for the purpose of promoting the products, services, or facilities of such corporation, company, or other organization.


(b) Permitted usesEach public television station and each public radio station shall be authorized to broadcast announcements which include the use of any business or institutional logogram and which include a reference to the location of the corporation, company, or other organization involved, except that such announcements may not interrupt regular programming.


(c) Authority of Commission not limitedThe provisions of this section shall not be construed to limit the authority of the Commission to prescribe regulations relating to the manner in which logograms may be used to identify corporations, companies, or other organizations.


(June 19, 1934, ch. 652, title III, § 399A, as added Pub. L. 97–35, title XII, § 1230, Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 730.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Business or institutional logogram” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Business or institutional logogram” defined For purposes of this section, the term “business or institutional logogram” means any aural or visual letters or words, or any symbol or sign, which is used for the exclusive purpose of identifying any corporation, company, or other organization, and which is not used for the purpose of promoting the products, services, or facilities of such corporation, company, or other organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permitted uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Permitted uses Each public television station and each public radio station shall be authorized to broadcast announcements which include the use of any business or institutional logogram and which include a reference to the location of the corporation, company, or other organization involved, except that such announcements may not interrupt regular programming.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Commission not limited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority of Commission not limited The provisions of this section shall not be construed to limit the authority of the Commission to prescribe regulations relating to the manner in which logograms may be used to identify corporations, companies, or other organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>