<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/51...63" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/51...63/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/51...63/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_51___63"><akn:num>51...63</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Feb. 23, 1927, ch. 169, § 39, 44 Stat. 1174</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 51 to 63. Repealed. Feb. 23, 1927, ch. 169, § 39, 44 Stat. 1174

Section 51, act Aug. 13, 1912, ch. 287, § 1, 37 Stat. 302, required license for operation of apparatus for radio communication and transmission of radiograms or signals, revocable for cause, described its interstate, foreign and local aspects, exempted the United States from its requirement and provided for special call letters for every Government station and penalties and forfeiture of offending apparatus. See sections 301, 305, 312, 501, and 503 of this title.


Section 52, act Aug. 13, 1912, ch. 287, § 2, 37 Stat. 303, related to form of license, United States citizenship of licensee, and contents of license, including statement of restrictions, ownership, location, purpose, wave length, and hours for work of station, subjection to rules and regulations and to closing by the President in time of war, public peril or disaster or Government use or control with payment of just compensation. See sections 307 to 309 of this title.


Section 53, act Aug. 13, 1912, ch. 287, § 3, 37 Stat. 303, required that operators of radio apparatus be licensed, provided for one year period of suspension of license for noncompliance with rules and regulations, declared the employment of unlicensed operators to be unlawful and provided penalty therefor and authorized the issuance of temporary permits in emergencies by collector of customs to operators on a vessel. See sections 308 and 318 of this title.


Section 54, act Aug. 13, 1912, ch. 287, § 4, 37 Stat. 304, subjected private and commercial stations to certain specific regulations, provided for enforcement and waiver of regulations, for grant of special temporary licenses to conduct radio tests and experiments, and prescribed general penalty for violation of regulations and reduction and remittance of such penalty and suspension or revocation of license. The Regulations, numbered First-Nineteenth, related to: (1) normal wave length; (2) other wave lengths; (3) us</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>