<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/511" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/511/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/511/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_511"><akn:num>511</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced penalties for pirate radio broadcasting; enforcement sweeps; reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 511. Enhanced penalties for pirate radio broadcasting; enforcement sweeps; reporting(a) Increased general penaltyAny person who willfully and knowingly does or causes or suffers to be done any pirate radio broadcasting shall be subject to a fine of not more than $2,000,000.


(b) Violation of this chapter, rules, or regulationsAny person who willfully and knowingly violates this chapter or any rule, regulation, restriction, or condition made or imposed by the Commission under authority of this chapter, or any rule, regulation, restriction, or condition made or imposed by any international radio or wire communications treaty or convention, or regulations annexed thereto, to which the United States is party, relating to pirate radio broadcasting shall, in addition to any other penalties provided by law, be subject to a fine of not more than $100,000 for each day during which such offense occurs, in accordance with the limit described in subsection (a).


(c) Annual reportNot later than 1 year after January 24, 2020, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report summarizing the implementation of this section and associated enforcement activities for the previous fiscal year, which may include the efforts by the Commission to enlist the cooperation of Federal, State, and local law enforcement personnel (including United States attorneys and the United States Marshals Service) for service of process, collection of fines or forfeitures, seizures of equipment, and enforcement of orders.


(d) Enforcement sweeps(1) Annual sweepsNot less than once each year, the Commission shall assign appropriate enforcement personnel to focus specific and sustained attention on the elimination of pirate radio broadcasting within the top 5 radio markets identified as prevalent for such broadcasts. Such effort shall include identif</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased general penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Increased general penalty Any person who willfully and knowingly does or causes or suffers to be done any pirate radio broadcasting shall be subject to a fine of not more than $2,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violation of this chapter, rules, or regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Violation of this chapter, rules, or regulations Any person who willfully and knowingly violates this chapter or any rule, regulation, restriction, or condition made or imposed by the Commission under authority of this chapter, or any rule, regulation, restriction, or condition made or imposed by any international radio or wire communications treaty or convention, or regulations annexed thereto, to which the United States is party, relating to pirate radio broadcasting shall, in addition to any other penalties provided by law, be subject to a fine of not more than $100,000 for each day during which such offense occurs, in accordance with the limit described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual report Not later than 1 year after January 24, 2020, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report summarizing the implementation of this section and associated enforcement activities for the previous fiscal year, which may include the efforts by the Commission to enlist the cooperation of Federal, State, and local law enforcement personnel (including United States attorneys and the United States Marshals Service) for service of process, collection of fines or forfeitures, seizures of equipment, and enforcement of orders.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement sweeps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement sweeps</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local government authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State and local government authority The Commission may not preempt any State or local law prohibiting pirate radio broadcasting.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of commission rules required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Revision of commission rules required The Commission shall revise its rules to require that, absent good cause, in any case alleging a violation of subsection (a) or (b), the Commission shall proceed directly to issue a notice of apparent liability without first issuing a notice of unlicensed operation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pirate radio broadcasting database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Pirate radio broadcasting database</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of pirate radio broadcasting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definition of pirate radio broadcasting In this section, the term “pirate radio broadcasting” means the transmission of communications on spectrum frequencies between 535 and 1705 kilohertz, inclusive, or 87.7 and 108 megahertz, inclusive, without a license issued by the Commission, but does not include unlicensed operations in compliance with part 15 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>