<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/532" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/532/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/532/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_532"><akn:num>532</akn:num><akn:heading>Cable channels for commercial use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 532. Cable channels for commercial use(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to promote competition in the delivery of diverse sources of video programming and to assure that the widest possible diversity of information sources are made available to the public from cable systems in a manner consistent with growth and development of cable systems.


(b) Designation of channel capacity for commercial use(1) A cable operator shall designate channel capacity for commercial use by persons unaffiliated with the operator in accordance with the following requirements:(A) An operator of any cable system with 36 or more (but not more than 54) activated channels shall designate 10 percent of such channels which are not otherwise required for use (or the use of which is not prohibited) by Federal law or regulation.

(B) An operator of any cable system with 55 or more (but not more than 100) activated channels shall designate 15 percent of such channels which are not otherwise required for use (or the use of which is not prohibited) by Federal law or regulation.

(C) An operator of any cable system with more than 100 activated channels shall designate 15 percent of all such channels.

(D) An operator of any cable system with fewer than 36 activated channels shall not be required to designate channel capacity for commercial use by persons unaffiliated with the operator, unless the cable system is required to provide such channel capacity under the terms of a franchise in effect on October 30, 1984.

(E) An operator of any cable system in operation on October 30, 1984, shall not be required to remove any service actually being provided on July 1, 1984, in order to comply with this section, but shall make channel capacity available for commercial use as such capacity becomes available until such time as the cable operator is in full compliance with this section.


(2) Any Federal agency, State, or franchising authority may not require any cable system to designate channel capa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to promote competition in the delivery of diverse sources of video programming and to assure that the widest possible diversity of information sources are made available to the public from cable systems in a manner consistent with growth and development of cable systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of channel capacity for commercial use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation of channel capacity for commercial use</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of channel capacity by unaffiliated persons; editorial control; restriction on service; rules on rates, terms, and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of channel capacity by unaffiliated persons; editorial control; restriction on service; rules on rates, terms, and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of action in district court; relief; factors not to be considered by court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Right of action in district court; relief; factors not to be considered by court Any person aggrieved by the failure or refusal of a cable operator to make channel capacity available for use pursuant to this section may bring an action in the district court of the United States for the judicial district in which the cable system is located to compel that such capacity be made available. If the court finds that the channel capacity sought by such person has not been made available in accordance with this section, or finds that the price, terms, or conditions established by the cable operator are unreasonable, the court may order such system to make available to such person the channel capacity sought, and further determine the appropriate price, terms, or conditions for such use consistent with subsection (c), and may award actual damages if it deems such relief appropriate. In any such action, the court shall not consider any price, term, or condition established between an operato</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition to Commission; relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Petition to Commission; relief</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumption of reasonableness and good faith</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Presumption of reasonableness and good faith In any action brought under this section in any Federal district court or before the Commission, there shall be a presumption that the price, terms, and conditions for use of channel capacity designated pursuant to subsection (b) are reasonable and in good faith unless shown by clear and convincing evidence to the contrary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Promulgation of rules Notwithstanding sections 541(c) and 543(a) of this title, at such time as cable systems with 36 or more activated channels are available to 70 percent of households within the United States and are subscribed to by 70 percent of the households to which such systems are available, the Commission may promulgate any additional rules necessary to provide diversity of information sources. Any rules promulgated by the Commission pursuant to this subsection shall not preempt authority expressly granted to franchising authorities under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cable service unprotected by Constitution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cable service unprotected by Constitution Any cable service offered pursuant to this section shall not be provided, or shall be provided subject to conditions, if such cable service in the judgment of the franchising authority or the cable operator is obscene, or is in conflict with community standards in that it is lewd, lascivious, filthy, or indecent or is otherwise unprotected by the Constitution of the United States. This subsection shall permit a cable operator to enforce prospectively a written and published policy of prohibiting programming that the cable operator reasonably believes describes or depicts sexual or excretory activities or organs in a patently offensive manner as measured by contemporary community standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programming from qualified minority or educational programming sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Programming from qualified minority or educational programming sources</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_532_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Single channel access to indecent programming</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Single channel access to indecent programming</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>