<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/533" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/533/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/533/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_533"><akn:num>533</akn:num><akn:heading>Ownership restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 533. Ownership restrictions(a) Cable operator holding license for multichannel distribution or offering satellite serviceIt shall be unlawful for a cable operator to hold a license for multichannel multipoint distribution service, or to offer satellite master antenna television service separate and apart from any franchised cable service, in any portion of the franchise area served by that cable operator’s cable system. The Commission—(1) shall waive the requirements of this paragraph for all existing multichannel multipoint distribution services and satellite master antenna television services which are owned by a cable operator on October 5, 1992;

(2) may waive the requirements of this paragraph to the extent the Commission determines is necessary to ensure that all significant portions of a franchise area are able to obtain video programming; and

(3) shall not apply the requirements of this subsection to any cable operator in any franchise area in which a cable operator is subject to effective competition as determined under section 543(l) of this title.


(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 104–104, title III, § 302(b)(1), Feb. 8, 1996, 110 Stat. 124

(c) Promulgation of rulesThe Commission may prescribe rules with respect to the ownership or control of cable systems by persons who own or control other media of mass communications which serve the same community served by a cable system.


(d) Regulation of ownership by States or franchising authoritiesAny State or franchising authority may not prohibit the ownership or control of a cable system by any person because of such person’s ownership or control of any other media of mass communications or other media interests. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent any State or franchising authority from prohibiting the ownership or control of a cable system in a jurisdiction by any person (1) because of such person’s ownership or control of any other cable system in such jurisdiction; or (2) in circumstances in w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_533_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cable operator holding license for multichannel distribution or offering satellite service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cable operator holding license for multichannel distribution or offering satellite service It shall be unlawful for a cable operator to hold a license for multichannel multipoint distribution service, or to offer satellite master antenna television service separate and apart from any franchised cable service, in any portion of the franchise area served by that cable operator’s cable system. The Commission—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_533_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–104, title III, § 302(b)(1), Feb. 8, 1996, 110 Stat. 124</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_533_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Promulgation of rules The Commission may prescribe rules with respect to the ownership or control of cable systems by persons who own or control other media of mass communications which serve the same community served by a cable system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_533_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of ownership by States or franchising authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulation of ownership by States or franchising authorities Any State or franchising authority may not prohibit the ownership or control of a cable system by any person because of such person’s ownership or control of any other media of mass communications or other media interests. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent any State or franchising authority from prohibiting the ownership or control of a cable system in a jurisdiction by any person (1) because of such person’s ownership or control of any other cable system in such jurisdiction; or (2) in circumstances in which the State or franchising authority determines that the acquisition of such a cable system may eliminate or reduce competition in the delivery of cable service in such jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_533_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Holding of ownership interests or exercise of editorial control by States or franchising authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Holding of ownership interests or exercise of editorial control by States or franchising authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_533_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancement of effective competition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Enhancement of effective competition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_533_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Combination of interests under prior law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Combination of interests under prior law This section shall not apply to prohibit any combination of any interests held by any person on July 1, 1984, to the extent of the interests so held as of such date, if the holding of such interests was not inconsistent with any applicable Federal or State law or regulations in effect on that date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_533_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Media of mass communications” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Media of mass communications” defined For purposes of this section, the term “media of mass communications” shall have the meaning given such term under section 309(i)(3)(C)(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>