<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/534" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/534/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/534/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_534"><akn:num>534</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage of local commercial television signals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 534. Carriage of local commercial television signals(a) Carriage obligationsEach cable operator shall carry, on the cable system of that operator, the signals of local commercial television stations and qualified low power stations as provided by this section. Carriage of additional broadcast television signals on such system shall be at the discretion of such operator, subject to section 325(b) of this title.


(b) Signals required(1) In general(A) A cable operator of a cable system with 12 or fewer usable activated channels shall carry the signals of at least three local commercial television stations, except that if such a system has 300 or fewer subscribers, it shall not be subject to any requirements under this section so long as such system does not delete from carriage by that system any signal of a broadcast television station.

(B) A cable operator of a cable system with more than 12 usable activated channels shall carry the signals of local commercial television stations, up to one-third of the aggregate number of usable activated channels of such system.


(2) Selection of signalsWhenever the number of local commercial television stations exceeds the maximum number of signals a cable system is required to carry under paragraph (1), the cable operator shall have discretion in selecting which such stations shall be carried on its cable system, except that—(A) under no circumstances shall a cable operator carry a qualified low power station in lieu of a local commercial television station; and

(B) if the cable operator elects to carry an affiliate of a broadcast network (as such term is defined by the Commission by regulation), such cable operator shall carry the affiliate of such broadcast network whose city of license reference point, as defined in section 76.53 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (in effect on January 1, 1991), or any successor regulation thereto, is closest to the principal headend of the cable system.


(3) Content to be carried</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Carriage obligations Each cable operator shall carry, on the cable system of that operator, the signals of local commercial television stations and qualified low power stations as provided by this section. Carriage of additional broadcast television signals on such system shall be at the discretion of such operator, subject to section 325(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Signals required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Signals required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low power station carriage obligation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Low power station carriage obligation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Remedies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Input selector switch rules abolished</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Input selector switch rules abolished No cable operator shall be required—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations by Commission Within 180 days after October 5, 1992, the Commission shall, following a rulemaking proceeding, issue regulations implementing the requirements imposed by this section. Such implementing regulations shall include necessary revisions to update section 76.51 of title 47 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales presentations and program length commercials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sales presentations and program length commercials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>