<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/535" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/535/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/535/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_535"><akn:num>535</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage of noncommercial educational television</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 535. Carriage of noncommercial educational television(a) Carriage obligationsIn addition to the carriage requirements set forth in section 534 of this title, each cable operator of a cable system shall carry the signals of qualified noncommercial educational television stations in accordance with the provisions of this section.


(b) Requirements to carry qualified stations(1) General requirement to carry each qualified stationSubject to paragraphs (2) and (3) and subsection (e), each cable operator shall carry, on the cable system of that cable operator, any qualified local noncommercial educational television station requesting carriage.


(2) Systems with 12 or fewer channels(A) Notwithstanding paragraph (1), a cable operator of a cable system with 12 or fewer usable activated channels shall be required to carry the signal of one qualified local noncommercial educational television station; except that a cable operator of such a system shall comply with subsection (c) and may, in its discretion, carry the signals of other qualified noncommercial educational television stations.

(B) In the case of a cable system described in subparagraph (A) which operates beyond the presence of any qualified local noncommercial educational television station—(i) the cable operator shall import and carry on that system the signal of one qualified noncommercial educational television station;

(ii) the selection for carriage of such a signal shall be at the election of the cable operator; and

(iii) in order to satisfy the requirements for carriage specified in this subsection, the cable operator of the system shall not be required to remove any other programming service actually provided to subscribers on March 29, 1990; except that such cable operator shall use the first channel available to satisfy the requirements of this subparagraph.



(3) Systems with 13 to 36 channels(A) Subject to subsection (c), a cable operator of a cable system with 13 to 36 usable activated channel</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Carriage obligations In addition to the carriage requirements set forth in section 534 of this title, each cable operator of a cable system shall carry the signals of qualified noncommercial educational television stations in accordance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements to carry qualified stations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements to carry qualified stations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued carriage of existing stations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Continued carriage of existing stations Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, all cable operators shall continue to provide carriage to all qualified local noncommercial educational television stations whose signals were carried on their systems as of March 29, 1990. The requirements of this subsection may be waived with respect to a particular cable operator and a particular such station, upon the written consent of the cable operator and the station.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Placement of additional signals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Placement of additional signals A cable operator required to add the signals of qualified local noncommercial educational television stations to a cable system under this section may do so, subject to approval by the franchising authority pursuant to section 531 of this title, by placing such additional stations on public, educational, or governmental channels not in use for their designated purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Systems with more than 36 channels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Systems with more than 36 channels A cable operator of a cable system with a capacity of more than 36 usable activated channels which is required to carry the signals of three qualified local noncommercial educational television stations shall not be required to carry the signals of additional such stations the programming of which substantially duplicates the programming broadcast by another qualified local noncommercial educational television station requesting carriage. Substantial duplication shall be defined by the Commission in a manner that promotes access to distinctive noncommercial educational television services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of nonduplication rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Waiver of nonduplication rights A qualified local noncommercial educational television station whose signal is carried by a cable operator shall not assert any network nonduplication rights it may have pursuant to section 76.92 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, to require the deletion of programs aired on other qualified local noncommercial educational television stations whose signals are carried by that cable operator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of carriage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Conditions of carriage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of signals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Availability of signals Signals carried in fulfillment of the carriage obligations of a cable operator under this section shall be available to every subscriber as part of the cable system’s lowest priced service tier that includes the retransmission of local commercial television broadcast signals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment for carriage prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Payment for carriage prohibited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_535_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Remedies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>