<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/537a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/537a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/537a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_537a"><akn:num>537a</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage of certain programming</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 537a. Carriage of certain programming(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “local commercial television station” has the meaning given the term in section 534(h) of this title;

(2) the term “multichannel video programming distributor” has the meaning given the term in section 522 of this title;

(3) the term “qualified noncommercial educational television station” has the meaning given the term in section 535(l) of this title;

(4) the term “retransmission consent” means the authority granted to a multichannel video programming distributor under section 325(b) of this title to retransmit the signal of a television broadcast station; and

(5) the term “television broadcast station” has the meaning given the term in section 76.66(a) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations.


(b) Carriage of certain contentNotwithstanding any other provision of law, a multichannel video programming distributor may not be directly or indirectly required, including as a condition of obtaining retransmission consent, to—(1) carry non-incidental video content from a local commercial television station, qualified noncommercial educational television station, or television broadcast station to the extent that such content is owned, controlled, or financed (in whole or in part) by the Government of the Russian Federation; or

(2) lease, or otherwise make available, channel capacity to any person for the provision of video programming that is owned, controlled, or financed (in whole or in part) by the Government of the Russian Federation.


(c) Rule of constructionNothing in this section may be construed as applying to the editorial use by a local commercial television station, qualified noncommercial educational television station, or television broadcast station of programming that is owned, controlled, or financed (in whole or in part) by the Government of the Russian Federation.


(Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1093, Dec. 12, 2017, 131 Stat. 1611.)

Editorial Notes
Codificat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_537a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_537a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carriage of certain content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Carriage of certain content Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a multichannel video programming distributor may not be directly or indirectly required, including as a condition of obtaining retransmission consent, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_537a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construed as applying to the editorial use by a local commercial television station, qualified noncommercial educational television station, or television broadcast station of programming that is owned, controlled, or financed (in whole or in part) by the Government of the Russian Federation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>