<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/541" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/541/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/541/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_541"><akn:num>541</akn:num><akn:heading>General franchise requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 541. General franchise requirements(a) Authority to award franchises; public rights-of-way and easements; equal access to service; time for provision of service; assurances(1) A franchising authority may award, in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter, 1 or more franchises within its jurisdiction; except that a franchising authority may not grant an exclusive franchise and may not unreasonably refuse to award an additional competitive franchise. Any applicant whose application for a second franchise has been denied by a final decision of the franchising authority may appeal such final decision pursuant to the provisions of section 555 of this title for failure to comply with this subsection.

(2) Any franchise shall be construed to authorize the construction of a cable system over public rights-of-way, and through easements, which is within the area to be served by the cable system and which have been dedicated for compatible uses, except that in using such easements the cable operator shall ensure—(A) that the safety, functioning, and appearance of the property and the convenience and safety of other persons not be adversely affected by the installation or construction of facilities necessary for a cable system;

(B) that the cost of the installation, construction, operation, or removal of such facilities be borne by the cable operator or subscriber, or a combination of both; and

(C) that the owner of the property be justly compensated by the cable operator for any damages caused by the installation, construction, operation, or removal of such facilities by the cable operator.


(3) In awarding a franchise or franchises, a franchising authority shall assure that access to cable service is not denied to any group of potential residential cable subscribers because of the income of the residents of the local area in which such group resides.

(4) In awarding a franchise, the franchising authority—(A) shall allow the applicant’s cable system a reasonable</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_541_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to award franchises; public rights-of-way and easements; equal access to service; time for provision of service; assurances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to award franchises; public rights-of-way and easements; equal access to service; time for provision of service; assurances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_541_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>No cable service without franchise; exception under prior law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No cable service without franchise; exception under prior law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_541_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of cable system as common carrier or utility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Status of cable system as common carrier or utility Any cable system shall not be subject to regulation as a common carrier or utility by reason of providing any cable service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_541_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Informational tariffs; regulation by States; “State” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Informational tariffs; regulation by States; “State” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_541_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State regulation of facilities serving subscribers in multiple dwelling units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State regulation of facilities serving subscribers in multiple dwelling units Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to affect the authority of any State to license or otherwise regulate any facility or combination of facilities which serves only subscribers in one or more multiple unit dwellings under common ownership, control, or management and which does not use any public right-of-way.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_541_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local or municipal authority as multichannel video programming distributor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Local or municipal authority as multichannel video programming distributor No provision of this chapter shall be construed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>