<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/542" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/542/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/542/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_542"><akn:num>542</akn:num><akn:heading>Franchise fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 542. Franchise fees(a) Payment under terms of franchiseSubject to the limitation of subsection (b), any cable operator may be required under the terms of any franchise to pay a franchise fee.


(b) Amount of fees per annumFor any twelve-month period, the franchise fees paid by a cable operator with respect to any cable system shall not exceed 5 percent of such cable operator’s gross revenues derived in such period from the operation of the cable system to provide cable services. For purposes of this section, the 12-month period shall be the 12-month period applicable under the franchise for accounting purposes. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a franchising authority and a cable operator from agreeing that franchise fees which lawfully could be collected for any such 12-month period shall be paid on a prepaid or deferred basis; except that the sum of the fees paid during the term of the franchise may not exceed the amount, including the time value of money, which would have lawfully been collected if such fees had been paid per annum.


(c) Itemization of subscriber billsEach cable operator may identify, consistent with the regulations prescribed by the Commission pursuant to section 543 of this title, as a separate line item on each regular bill of each subscriber, each of the following:(1) The amount of the total bill assessed as a franchise fee and the identity of the franchising authority to which the fee is paid.

(2) The amount of the total bill assessed to satisfy any requirements imposed on the cable operator by the franchise agreement to support public, educational, or governmental channels or the use of such channels.

(3) The amount of any other fee, tax, assessment, or charge of any kind imposed by any governmental authority on the transaction between the operator and the subscriber.


(d) Court actions; reflection of costs in rate structuresIn any court action under subsection (c), the franchising authority shall demonstrate that the rate str</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment under terms of franchise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payment under terms of franchise Subject to the limitation of subsection (b), any cable operator may be required under the terms of any franchise to pay a franchise fee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of fees per annum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of fees per annum For any twelve-month period, the franchise fees paid by a cable operator with respect to any cable system shall not exceed 5 percent of such cable operator’s gross revenues derived in such period from the operation of the cable system to provide cable services. For purposes of this section, the 12-month period shall be the 12-month period applicable under the franchise for accounting purposes. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a franchising authority and a cable operator from agreeing that franchise fees which lawfully could be collected for any such 12-month period shall be paid on a prepaid or deferred basis; except that the sum of the fees paid during the term of the franchise may not exceed the amount, including the time value of money, which would have lawfully been collected if such fees had been paid per annum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Itemization of subscriber bills</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Itemization of subscriber bills Each cable operator may identify, consistent with the regulations prescribed by the Commission pursuant to section 543 of this title, as a separate line item on each regular bill of each subscriber, each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court actions; reflection of costs in rate structures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Court actions; reflection of costs in rate structures In any court action under subsection (c), the franchising authority shall demonstrate that the rate structure reflects all costs of the franchise fees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decreases passed through to subscribers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Decreases passed through to subscribers Any cable operator shall pass through to subscribers the amount of any decrease in a franchise fee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Itemization of franchise fee in bill</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Itemization of franchise fee in bill A cable operator may designate that portion of a subscriber’s bill attributable to the franchise fee as a separate item on the bill.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Franchise fee” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) “Franchise fee” defined For the purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uncompensated services; taxes, fees and other assessments; limitation on fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Uncompensated services; taxes, fees and other assessments; limitation on fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory authority of Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulatory authority of Federal agencies Any Federal agency may not regulate the amount of the franchise fees paid by a cable operator, or regulate the use of funds derived from such fees, except as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>