<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/543" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/543/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/543/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_543"><akn:num>543</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 543. Regulation of rates(a) Competition preference; local and Federal regulation(1) In generalNo Federal agency or State may regulate the rates for the provision of cable service except to the extent provided under this section and section 532 of this title. Any franchising authority may regulate the rates for the provision of cable service, or any other communications service provided over a cable system to cable subscribers, but only to the extent provided under this section. No Federal agency, State, or franchising authority may regulate the rates for cable service of a cable system that is owned or operated by a local government or franchising authority within whose jurisdiction that cable system is located and that is the only cable system located within such jurisdiction.


(2) Preference for competitionIf the Commission finds that a cable system is subject to effective competition, the rates for the provision of cable service by such system shall not be subject to regulation by the Commission or by a State or franchising authority under this section. If the Commission finds that a cable system is not subject to effective competition—(A) the rates for the provision of basic cable service shall be subject to regulation by a franchising authority, or by the Commission if the Commission exercises jurisdiction pursuant to paragraph (6), in accordance with the regulations prescribed by the Commission under subsection (b); and

(B) the rates for cable programming services shall be subject to regulation by the Commission under subsection (c).


(3) Qualification of franchising authorityA franchising authority that seeks to exercise the regulatory jurisdiction permitted under paragraph (2)(A) shall file with the Commission a written certification that—(A) the franchising authority will adopt and administer regulations with respect to the rates subject to regulation under this section that are consistent with the regulations prescribed by the Commission under subsect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competition preference; local and Federal regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Competition preference; local and Federal regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of basic service tier rate regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of basic service tier rate regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of unreasonable rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulation of unreasonable rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniform rate structure required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Uniform rate structure required A cable operator shall have a rate structure, for the provision of cable service, that is uniform throughout the geographic area in which cable service is provided over its cable system. This subsection does not apply to (1) a cable operator with respect to the provision of cable service over its cable system in any geographic area in which the video programming services offered by the operator in that area are subject to effective competition, or (2) any video programming offered on a per channel or per program basis. Bulk discounts to multiple dwelling units shall not be subject to this subsection, except that a cable operator of a cable system that is not subject to effective competition may not charge predatory prices to a multiple dwelling unit. Upon a prima facie showing by a complainant that there are reasonable grounds to believe that the discounted price is predatory, the cable system shall have the burden of showing that its discounted pric</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discrimination; services for the hearing impaired</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Discrimination; services for the hearing impaired Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as prohibiting any Federal agency, State, or a franchising authority from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negative option billing prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Negative option billing prohibited A cable operator shall not charge a subscriber for any service or equipment that the subscriber has not affirmatively requested by name. For purposes of this subsection, a subscriber’s failure to refuse a cable operator’s proposal to provide such service or equipment shall not be deemed to be an affirmative request for such service or equipment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Collection of information The Commission shall, by regulation, require cable operators to file with the Commission or a franchising authority, as appropriate, within one year after October 5, 1992, and annually thereafter, such financial information as may be needed for purposes of administering and enforcing this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of evasions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prevention of evasions Within 180 days after October 5, 1992, the Commission shall, by regulation, establish standards, guidelines, and procedures to prevent evasions, including evasions that result from retiering, of the requirements of this section and shall, thereafter, periodically review and revise such standards, guidelines, and procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small system burdens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Small system burdens In developing and prescribing regulations pursuant to this section, the Commission shall design such regulations to reduce the administrative burdens and cost of compliance for cable systems that have 1,000 or fewer subscribers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_543_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate regulation agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Rate regulation agreements During the term of an agreement made before July 1, 1990, by a franchising authority and a cable operator providing for the regulation of basic cable service rates, where there was not effective competition under Commission rules in effect on that date, nothing in this section (or the regulations thereunder) shall abridge the ability of such franchising authority to regulate rates in accordance with such an agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>