<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/551" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/551/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/551/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_551"><akn:num>551</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of subscriber privacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 551. Protection of subscriber privacy(a) Notice to subscriber regarding personally identifiable information; definitions(1) At the time of entering into an agreement to provide any cable service or other service to a subscriber and at least once a year thereafter, a cable operator shall provide notice in the form of a separate, written statement to such subscriber which clearly and conspicuously informs the subscriber of—(A) the nature of personally identifiable information collected or to be collected with respect to the subscriber and the nature of the use of such information;

(B) the nature, frequency, and purpose of any disclosure which may be made of such information, including an identification of the types of persons to whom the disclosure may be made;

(C) the period during which such information will be maintained by the cable operator;

(D) the times and place at which the subscriber may have access to such information in accordance with subsection (d); and

(E) the limitations provided by this section with respect to the collection and disclosure of information by a cable operator and the right of the subscriber under subsections (f) and (h) to enforce such limitations.


In the case of subscribers who have entered into such an agreement before the effective date of this section, such notice shall be provided within 180 days of such date and at least once a year thereafter.

(2) For purposes of this section, other than subsection (h)—(A) the term “personally identifiable information” does not include any record of aggregate data which does not identify particular persons;

(B) the term “other service” includes any wire or radio communications service provided using any of the facilities of a cable operator that are used in the provision of cable service; and

(C) the term “cable operator” includes, in addition to persons within the definition of cable operator in section 522 of this title, any person who (i) is owned or controlled by, or under common o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_551_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to subscriber regarding personally identifiable information; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice to subscriber regarding personally identifiable information; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_551_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of personally identifiable information using cable system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Collection of personally identifiable information using cable system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_551_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of personally identifiable information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disclosure of personally identifiable information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_551_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subscriber access to information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subscriber access to information A cable subscriber shall be provided access to all personally identifiable information regarding that subscriber which is collected and maintained by a cable operator. Such information shall be made available to the subscriber at reasonable times and at a convenient place designated by such cable operator. A cable subscriber shall be provided reasonable opportunity to correct any error in such information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_551_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Destruction of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Destruction of information A cable operator shall destroy personally identifiable information if the information is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was collected and there are no pending requests or orders for access to such information under subsection (d) or pursuant to a court order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_551_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil action in United States district court; damages; attorney’s fees and costs; nonexclusive nature of remedy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Civil action in United States district court; damages; attorney’s fees and costs; nonexclusive nature of remedy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_551_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation by States or franchising authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulation by States or franchising authorities Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to prohibit any State or any franchising authority from enacting or enforcing laws consistent with this section for the protection of subscriber privacy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_551_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of information to governmental entity pursuant to court order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Disclosure of information to governmental entity pursuant to court order Except as provided in subsection (c)(2)(D), a governmental entity may obtain personally identifiable information concerning a cable subscriber pursuant to a court order only if, in the court proceeding relevant to such court order—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>