<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/554" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/554/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/554/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_554"><akn:num>554</akn:num><akn:heading>Equal employment opportunity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 554. Equal employment opportunity(a) Entities within scope of coverageThis section shall apply to any corporation, partnership, association, joint-stock company, or trust engaged primarily in the management or operation of any cable system.


(b) Discrimination prohibitedEqual opportunity in employment shall be afforded by each entity specified in subsection (a), and no person shall be discriminated against in employment by such entity because of race, color, religion, national origin, age, or sex.


(c) Equal opportunity programs; establishment; maintenance; execution; termsAny entity specified in subsection (a) shall establish, maintain, and execute a positive continuing program of specific practices designed to ensure equal opportunity in every aspect of its employment policies and practices. Under the terms of its program, each such entity shall—(1) define the responsibility of each level of management to ensure a positive application and vigorous enforcement of its policy of equal opportunity, and establish a procedure to review and control managerial and supervisory performance;

(2) inform its employees and recognized employee organizations of the equal employment opportunity policy and program and enlist their cooperation;

(3) communicate its equal employment opportunity policy and program and its employment needs to sources of qualified applicants without regard to race, color, religion, national origin, age, or sex, and solicit their recruitment assistance on a continuing basis;

(4) conduct a continuing program to exclude every form of prejudice or discrimination based on race, color, religion, national origin, age, or sex, from its personnel policies and practices and working conditions; and

(5) conduct a continuing review of job structure and employment practices and adopt positive recruitment, training, job design, and other measures needed to ensure genuine equality of opportunity to participate fully in all its organizational units, occupations, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_554_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entities within scope of coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Entities within scope of coverage This section shall apply to any corporation, partnership, association, joint-stock company, or trust engaged primarily in the management or operation of any cable system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_554_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discrimination prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Discrimination prohibited Equal opportunity in employment shall be afforded by each entity specified in subsection (a), and no person shall be discriminated against in employment by such entity because of race, color, religion, national origin, age, or sex.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_554_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equal opportunity programs; establishment; maintenance; execution; terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Equal opportunity programs; establishment; maintenance; execution; terms Any entity specified in subsection (a) shall establish, maintain, and execute a positive continuing program of specific practices designed to ensure equal opportunity in every aspect of its employment policies and practices. Under the terms of its program, each such entity shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_554_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of rules; required provisions; annual statistical report; notice and comment on amendments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Revision of rules; required provisions; annual statistical report; notice and comment on amendments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_554_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual certification of compliance; periodic investigation of employment practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual certification of compliance; periodic investigation of employment practices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_554_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantial failure to comply; penalties; notice to public and franchising authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Substantial failure to comply; penalties; notice to public and franchising authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_554_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discrimination complaints; investigation; enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Discrimination complaints; investigation; enforcement Employees or applicants for employment who believe they have been discriminated against in violation of the requirements of this section, or rules under this section, or any other interested person, may file a complaint with the Commission. A complaint by any such person shall be in writing, and shall be signed and sworn to by that person. The regulations under subsection (d)(1) shall specify a program, under authorities otherwise available to the Commission, for the investigation of complaints and violations, and for the enforcement of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_554_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Cable operator” defined; owners of multiple unit dwellings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Cable operator” defined; owners of multiple unit dwellings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_554_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory powers of States and franchising authorities; nonexclusive nature of remedies and enforcement provisions; covered franchises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulatory powers of States and franchising authorities; nonexclusive nature of remedies and enforcement provisions; covered franchises</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>