<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/573" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/573/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/573/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_573"><akn:num>573</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of open video systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 573. Establishment of open video systems(a) Open video systems(1) Certificates of complianceA local exchange carrier may provide cable service to its cable service subscribers in its telephone service area through an open video system that complies with this section. To the extent permitted by such regulations as the Commission may prescribe consistent with the public interest, convenience, and necessity, an operator of a cable system or any other person may provide video programming through an open video system that complies with this section. An operator of an open video system shall qualify for reduced regulatory burdens under subsection (c) of this section if the operator of such system certifies to the Commission that such carrier complies with the Commission’s regulations under subsection (b) and the Commission approves such certification. The Commission shall publish notice of the receipt of any such certification and shall act to approve or disapprove any such certification within 10 days after receipt of such certification.


(2) Dispute resolutionThe Commission shall have the authority to resolve disputes under this section and the regulations prescribed thereunder. Any such dispute shall be resolved within 180 days after notice of such dispute is submitted to the Commission. At that time or subsequently in a separate damages proceeding, the Commission may, in the case of any violation of this section, require carriage, award damages to any person denied carriage, or any combination of such sanctions. Any aggrieved party may seek any other remedy available under this chapter.



(b) Commission actions(1) Regulations requiredWithin 6 months after February 8, 1996, the Commission shall complete all actions necessary (including any reconsideration) to prescribe regulations that—(A) except as required pursuant to section 531, 534, or 535 of this title, prohibit an operator of an open video system from discriminating among video programming providers with reg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_573_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Open video systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Open video systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_573_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commission actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_573_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduced regulatory burdens for open video systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reduced regulatory burdens for open video systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_573_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Telephone service area” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Telephone service area” defined For purposes of this section, the term “telephone service area” when used in connection with a common carrier subject in whole or in part to subchapter II of this chapter means the area within which such carrier is offering telephone exchange service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>