<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/610" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/610/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/610/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_610"><akn:num>610</akn:num><akn:heading>Telephone service for disabled</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 610. Telephone service for disabled(a) Establishment of regulationsThe Commission shall establish such regulations as are necessary to ensure reasonable access to telephone service by persons with impaired hearing.


(b) Hearing aid compatibility requirements(1) Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3) and subsection (c), the Commission shall require that customer premises equipment described in this paragraph provide internal means for effective use with hearing aids that are designed to be compatible with telephones which meet established technical standards for hearing aid compatibility. Customer premises equipment described in this paragraph are the following:(A) All essential telephones.

(B) All telephones manufactured in the United States (other than for export) more than one year after August 16, 1988, or imported for use in the United States more than one year after such date.

(C) All customer premises equipment used with advanced communications services that is designed to provide 2-way voice communication via a built-in speaker intended to be held to the ear in a manner functionally equivalent to a telephone, subject to the regulations prescribed by the Commission under subsection (e).


(2)(A) The regulations prescribed by the Commission under paragraph (1) shall exempt from the requirements established pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C) of paragraph (1) only—(i) telephones used with public mobile services;

(ii) telephones used with private radio services; and

(iii) secure telephones.


(B) The Commission shall periodically assess the appropriateness of continuing in effect the exemptions for telephones and other customer premises equipment described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph. The Commission shall revoke or otherwise limit any such exemption if the Commission determines that—(i) such revocation or limitation is in the public interest;

(ii) continuation of the exemption without such revocation or limitation would have an adverse e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of regulations The Commission shall establish such regulations as are necessary to ensure reasonable access to telephone service by persons with impaired hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing aid compatibility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hearing aid compatibility requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical standards The Commission shall establish or approve such technical standards as are required to enforce this section. A telephone or other customer premises equipment that is compliant with relevant technical standards developed through a public participation process and in consultation with interested consumer stakeholders (designated by the Commission for the purposes of this section) will be considered hearing aid compatible for purposes of this section, until such time as the Commission may determine otherwise. The Commission shall consult with the public, including people with hearing loss, in establishing or approving such technical standards. The Commission may delegate this authority to an employee pursuant to section 155(c) of this title. The Commission shall remain the final arbiter as to whether the standards meet the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling of packaging materials for equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Labeling of packaging materials for equipment The Commission shall establish such requirements for the labeling of packaging materials for equipment as are needed to provide adequate information to consumers on the compatibility between telephones and hearing aids.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs and benefits; encouragement of use of currently available technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Costs and benefits; encouragement of use of currently available technology In any rulemaking to implement the provisions of this section, the Commission shall specifically consider the costs and benefits to all telephone users, including persons with and without hearing loss. The Commission shall ensure that regulations adopted to implement this section encourage the use of currently available technology and do not discourage or impair the development of improved technology. In implementing the provisions of subsection (b)(1)(C), the Commission shall use appropriate timetables or benchmarks to the extent necessary (1) due to technical feasibility, or (2) to ensure the marketability or availability of new technologies to users.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review of regulations; retrofitting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Periodic review of regulations; retrofitting The Commission shall periodically review the regulations established pursuant to this section. Except for coin-operated telephones and telephones provided for emergency use, the Commission may not require the retrofitting of equipment to achieve the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of reasonable and prudent costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Recovery of reasonable and prudent costs Any common carrier or connecting carrier may provide specialized terminal equipment needed by persons whose hearing, speech, vision, or mobility is impaired. The State commission may allow the carrier to recover in its tariffs for regulated service reasonable and prudent costs not charged directly to users of such equipment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction Nothing in the Twenty-First Century Communications and Video Accessibility Act of 2010 shall be construed to modify the Commission’s regulations set forth in section 20.19 of title 47 of the Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on October 8, 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>