<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/613" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/613/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/613/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_613"><akn:num>613</akn:num><akn:heading>Video programming accessibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 613. Video programming accessibility(a) Repealed. Pub. L. 115–141, div. P, title IV, § 402(i)(11), Mar. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 1090

(b) Accountability criteriaWithin 18 months after February 8, 1996, the Commission shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to implement this section. Such regulations shall ensure that—(1) video programming first published or exhibited after the effective date of such regulations is fully accessible through the provision of closed captions, except as provided in subsection (d); and

(2) video programming providers or owners maximize the accessibility of video programming first published or exhibited prior to the effective date of such regulations through the provision of closed captions, except as provided in subsection (d).


(c) Deadlines for captioning(1) In generalThe regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (b) shall include an appropriate schedule of deadlines for the provision of closed captioning of video programming once published or exhibited on television.


(2) Deadlines for programming delivered using Internet protocol(A) Regulations on closed captioning on video programming delivered using Internet protocolNot later than 6 months after the submission of the report to the Commission required by subsection (e)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of the Twenty-First Century Communications and Video Accessibility Act of 2010, the Commission shall revise its regulations to require the provision of closed captioning on video programming delivered using Internet protocol that was published or exhibited on television with captions after the effective date of such regulations.


(B) ScheduleThe regulations prescribed under this paragraph shall include an appropriate schedule of deadlines for the provision of closed captioning, taking into account whether such programming is prerecorded and edited for Internet distribution, or whether such programming is live or near-live and not edited for Internet distribution.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 115–141, div. P, title IV, § 402(i)(11), Mar. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 1090</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Accountability criteria Within 18 months after February 8, 1996, the Commission shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to implement this section. Such regulations shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadlines for captioning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deadlines for captioning</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemptions Notwithstanding subsection (b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Undue burden</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Undue burden The term “undue burden” means significant difficulty or expense. In determining whether the closed captions necessary to comply with the requirements of this paragraph would result in an undue economic burden, the factors to be considered include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Video description</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Video description</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Emergency information Not later than 1 year after the Advisory Committee report under subsection (e)(2) 1 is submitted to the Commission, the Commission shall complete a proceeding to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions For purposes of this section, section 303 of this title, and section 330 of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>22 So in original. No subsec. (i) has been enacted. Private rights of actions prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize any private right of action to enforce any requirement of this section or any regulation thereunder. The Commission shall have exclusive jurisdiction with respect to any complaint under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>