<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/615b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/615b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/615b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_615b"><akn:num>615b</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 615b. Definitions
As used in this Act:(1) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Transportation.


(2) StateThe term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, or any territory or possession of the United States.


(3) Public safety answering point; PSAPThe term “public safety answering point” or “PSAP” means a facility that has been designated to receive 9–1–1 calls and route them to emergency service personnel.


(4) Wireless carrierThe term “wireless carrier” means a provider of commercial mobile services or any other radio communications service that the Federal Communications Commission requires to provide wireless 9–1–1 service.


(5) Enhanced wireless 9–1–1 serviceThe term “enhanced wireless 9–1–1 service” means any enhanced 9–1–1 service so designated by the Federal Communications Commission in the proceeding entitled “Revision of the Commission’s Rules to Ensure Compatibility with Enhanced 9–1–1 Emergency Calling Systems” (CC Docket No. 94–102; RM–8143), or any successor proceeding.


(6) Wireless 9–1–1 serviceThe term “wireless 9–1–1 service” means any 9–1–1 service provided by a wireless carrier, including enhanced wireless 9–1–1 service.


(7) Emergency dispatch providersThe term “emergency dispatch providers” shall include governmental and nongovernmental providers of emergency dispatch services.


(8) 11 So in original. Two pars. (8) have been enacted. IP-enabled voice serviceThe term “IP-enabled voice service” has the meaning given the term “interconnected VoIP service” by section 9.3 of the Federal Communications Commission’s regulations (47 CFR 9.3).


(8) 1 Other emergency communications serviceThe term “other emergency communications service” means the provision of emergency information to a public safety answering point via wire or radio communications, and may include 9–1–1 and enhanced 9–1–1 service.


(9) Other emergency communications service providerThe term “other emergency communications service prov</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) State The term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, or any territory or possession of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public safety answering point; PSAP</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Public safety answering point; PSAP The term “public safety answering point” or “PSAP” means a facility that has been designated to receive 9–1–1 calls and route them to emergency service personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wireless carrier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Wireless carrier The term “wireless carrier” means a provider of commercial mobile services or any other radio communications service that the Federal Communications Commission requires to provide wireless 9–1–1 service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced wireless 9–1–1 service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Enhanced wireless 9–1–1 service The term “enhanced wireless 9–1–1 service” means any enhanced 9–1–1 service so designated by the Federal Communications Commission in the proceeding entitled “Revision of the Commission’s Rules to Ensure Compatibility with Enhanced 9–1–1 Emergency Calling Systems” (CC Docket No. 94–102; RM–8143), or any successor proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wireless 9–1–1 service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Wireless 9–1–1 service The term “wireless 9–1–1 service” means any 9–1–1 service provided by a wireless carrier, including enhanced wireless 9–1–1 service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency dispatch providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Emergency dispatch providers The term “emergency dispatch providers” shall include governmental and nongovernmental providers of emergency dispatch services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. Two pars. (8) have been enacted. IP-enabled voice service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “IP-enabled voice service” has the meaning given the term “interconnected VoIP service” by section 9.3 of the Federal Communications Commission’s regulations (47 CFR 9.3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>1 Other emergency communications service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “other emergency communications service” means the provision of emergency information to a public safety answering point via wire or radio communications, and may include 9–1–1 and enhanced 9–1–1 service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615b_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other emergency communications service provider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Other emergency communications service provider The term “other emergency communications service provider” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>