<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/617" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/617/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/617/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_617"><akn:num>617</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to advanced communications services and equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 617. Access to advanced communications services and equipment(a) Manufacturing(1) In generalWith respect to equipment manufactured after the effective date of the regulations established pursuant to subsection (e), and subject to those regulations, a manufacturer of equipment used for advanced communications services, including end user equipment, network equipment, and software, shall ensure that the equipment and software that such manufacturer offers for sale or otherwise distributes in interstate commerce shall be accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities, unless the requirements of this subsection are not achievable.


(2) Industry flexibilityA manufacturer of equipment may satisfy the requirements of paragraph (1) with respect to such equipment by—(A) ensuring that the equipment that such manufacturer offers is accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities without the use of third party applications, peripheral devices, software, hardware, or customer premises equipment; or

(B) if such manufacturer chooses, using third party applications, peripheral devices, software, hardware, or customer premises equipment that is available to the consumer at nominal cost and that individuals with disabilities can access.



(b) Service providers(1) In generalWith respect to services provided after the effective date of the regulations established pursuant to subsection (e), and subject to those regulations, a provider of advanced communications services shall ensure that such services offered by such provider in or affecting interstate commerce are accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities, unless the requirements of this subsection are not achievable.


(2) Industry flexibilityA provider of services may satisfy the requirements of paragraph (1) with respect to such services by—(A) ensuring that the services that such provider offers are accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities without the use of third party ap</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Manufacturing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Service providers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compatibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compatibility Whenever the requirements of subsections 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (a) or (b) are not achievable, a manufacturer or provider shall ensure that its equipment or service is compatible with existing peripheral devices or specialized customer premises equipment commonly used by individuals with disabilities to achieve access, unless the requirement of this subsection is not achievable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Network features, functions, and capabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Network features, functions, and capabilities Each provider of advanced communications services has the duty not to install network features, functions, or capabilities that impede accessibility or usability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services and equipment subject to section 255 of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Services and equipment subject to The requirements of this section shall not apply to any equipment or services, including interconnected VoIP service, that are subject to the requirements of section 255 of this title on the day before October 8, 2010. Such services and equipment shall remain subject to the requirements of section 255 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Achievable defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Achievable defined For purposes of this section and section 619 of this title, the term “achievable” means with reasonable effort or expense, as determined by the Commission. In determining whether the requirements of a provision are achievable, the Commission shall consider the following factors:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission flexibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Commission flexibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customized equipment or services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Customized equipment or services The provisions of this section shall not apply to customized equipment or services that are not offered directly to the public, or to such classes of users as to be effectively available directly to the public, regardless of the facilities used.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_617_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Rule of construction This section shall not be construed to require a manufacturer of equipment used for advanced communications or a provider of advanced communications services to make every feature and function of every device or service accessible for every disability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>