<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/644" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/644/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/644/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_644"><akn:num>644</akn:num><akn:heading>Improving data accuracy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 644. Improving data accuracy(a) AuditsThe Commission shall conduct regular audits of information submitted to the Commission by providers under section 642(b)(2) of this title to ensure that the providers are complying with this subchapter.


(b) Crowdsourcing(1) In generalThe Commission shall develop a process through which entities or individuals in the United States may submit specific information about the deployment and availability of broadband internet access service in the United States on an ongoing basis so that the information may be used to verify and supplement information provided by providers of broadband internet access service for inclusion in the maps created under section 642(c)(1) of this title.


(2) CollaborationAs part of the efforts of the Commission to facilitate the ability of entities and individuals to submit information under paragraph (1), the Commission shall—(A) prioritize the consideration of data provided by data collection applications used by consumers that the Commission has determined—(i) are highly reliable; and

(ii) have proven methodologies for determining network coverage and network performance; and


(B) coordinate with the Postmaster General, the heads of other Federal agencies that operate delivery fleet vehicles, and the Director of the Bureau of the Census for assistance with data collection whenever coordination could feasibly yield more specific geographic data.



(c) Technical assistance to Indian Tribes(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the Commission shall hold workshops for Tribal Governments in each of the 12 Bureau of Indian Affairs regions to provide technical assistance with the collection and submission of data under section 642(a)(2) of this title.


(2) Annual reviewEach year, the Commission, in consultation with Indian Tribes, shall review the need for continued workshops required under paragraph (1).



(d) Technical assistance to small service providersThe Commission shall establish a process t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Audits The Commission shall conduct regular audits of information submitted to the Commission by providers under section 642(b)(2) of this title to ensure that the providers are complying with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crowdsourcing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Crowdsourcing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance to Indian Tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical assistance to Indian Tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance to small service providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance to small service providers The Commission shall establish a process through which a provider that has fewer than 100,000 active broadband internet access service connections may request and receive assistance from the Commission with respect to geographic information system data processing to ensure that the provider is able to comply with the requirements under section 642(b) of this title in a timely and accurate manner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance to State, local, and Tribal governments and consumers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance to State, local, and Tribal governments and consumers The Commission shall provide technical assistance to consumers and State, local, and Tribal governmental entities with respect to the challenge process established under section 642(b)(5) of this title, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_644_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO Assessment of Fabric source data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) GAO Assessment of Fabric source data</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>