<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/721" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/721/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/721/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_721"><akn:num>721</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 721. Implementation of policy
In order to achieve the objectives and to carry out the purposes of this chapter—(a) the President shall—(1) to (7) omitted.


(b) omitted.

(c) the Federal Communications Commission, in its administration of the provisions of the Communications Act of 1934, as amended [47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.], and as supplemented by this chapter, shall—(1) to (10) omitted;

(11) make rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this chapter.


(Pub. L. 87–624, title II, § 201, Aug. 31, 1962, 76 Stat. 421; Pub. L. 103–414, title III, § 304(b)(1), Oct. 25, 1994, 108 Stat. 4297.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Communications Act of 1934, as amended, referred to in subsec. (c), is act June 19, 1934, ch. 652, 48 Stat. 1064, which is classified principally to chapter 5 (§ 151 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 609 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Subsecs. (a)(1), (5), (6), (b), and (c)(1), (3) to (5), (8) to (10) of this section ceased to be effective Mar. 17, 2000, pursuant to section 765d(1) of this title. Prior to being omitted, subsec. (a)(1), (5) and (6) directed the President to aid in a national program to establish and operate a commercial communications satellite system, to insure arrangements were made for foreign participation in the establishment and use of the system, and to insure availability and utilization of the system for general governmental purposes, subsec. (b) directed the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to give technical advice to the Commission and to cooperate with, assist, and provide services to the corporation, and subsec. (c)(1), (3) to (5), (8) to (10) directed the Federal Communications Commission to insure effective competition in procurement of services, to require establishment of communication to a particular foreign point when advised by the Secretary of State, to insure technical compatibility of the system with satellite termina</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) the President shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) omitted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) the Federal Communications Commission, in its administration of the provisions of the Communications Act of 1934, as amended [47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.], and as supplemented by this chapter, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>