<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/761" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/761/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/761/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_761"><akn:num>761</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Communications Commission licensing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 761. Federal Communications Commission licensing(a) Licensing for separated entities(1) Competition testThe Commission may not issue a license or construction permit to any separated entity, or renew or permit the assignment or use of any such license or permit, or authorize the use by any entity subject to United States jurisdiction of any space segment owned, leased, or operated by any separated entity, unless the Commission determines that such issuance, renewal, assignment, or use will not harm competition in the telecommunications market of the United States. If the Commission does not make such a determination, it shall deny or revoke authority to use space segment owned, leased, or operated by the separated entity to provide services to, from, or within the United States.


(2) Criteria for competition testIn making the determination required by paragraph (1), the Commission shall use the licensing criteria in sections 763 and 763b 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, and shall not make such a determination unless the Commission determines that the privatization of any separated entity is consistent with such criteria.



(b) Licensing for INTELSAT, Inmarsat, and successor entities(1) Competition test(A) In generalIn considering the application of INTELSAT, Inmarsat, or their successor entities for a license or construction permit, or for the renewal or assignment or use of any such license or permit, or in considering the request of any entity subject to United States jurisdiction for authorization to use any space segment owned, leased, or operated by INTELSAT, Inmarsat, or their successor entities, to provide non-core services to, from, or within the United States, the Commission shall determine whether—(i) after April 1, 2001, in the case of INTELSAT and its successor entities, INTELSAT and any successor entities have been privatized in a manner that will harm competition in the telecommunications markets of the United States; or

(ii) a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing for separated entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Licensing for separated entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing for INTELSAT, Inmarsat, and successor entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Licensing for INTELSAT, Inmarsat, and successor entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional considerations in determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional considerations in determinations In making its determinations and licensing decisions under subsections (a) and (b), the Commission shall construe such subsections in a manner consistent with the United States obligations and commitments for satellite services under the Fourth Protocol to the General Agreement on Trade in Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent facilities competition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Independent facilities competition Nothing in this section shall be construed as precluding COMSAT from investing in or owning satellites or other facilities independent from INTELSAT and Inmarsat, and successor or separated entities, or from providing services through reselling capacity over the facilities of satellite systems independent from INTELSAT and Inmarsat, and successor or separated entities. This subsection shall not be construed as restricting the types of contracts which can be executed or services which may be provided by COMSAT over the independent satellites or facilities described in this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>