<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/763" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/763/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/763/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_763"><akn:num>763</akn:num><akn:heading>General criteria to ensure a pro-competitive privatization of INTELSAT and Inmarsat</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 763. General criteria to ensure a pro-competitive privatization of INTELSAT and Inmarsat
The President and the Commission shall secure a pro-competitive privatization of INTELSAT and Inmarsat that meets the criteria set forth in this section and sections 763a through 763c 11 See References in Text note below. of this title. In securing such privatizations, the following criteria shall be applied as licensing criteria for purposes of part A:(1) Dates for privatizationPrivatization shall be obtained in accordance with the criteria of this subchapter of—(A) INTELSAT as soon as practicable, but no later than April 1, 2001; and

(B) Inmarsat as soon as practicable, but no later than July 1, 2000.


(2) IndependenceThe privatized successor entities and separated entities of INTELSAT and Inmarsat shall operate as independent commercial entities, and have a pro-competitive ownership structure. The successor entities and separated entities of INTELSAT and Inmarsat shall conduct an initial public offering in accordance with paragraph (5) to achieve such independence. Such offering shall substantially dilute the aggregate ownership of such entities by such signatories or former signatories. In determining whether a public offering attains such substantial dilution, the Commission shall take into account the purposes and intent, privatization criteria, and other provisions of this subchapter, as well as market conditions. No intergovernmental organization, including INTELSAT or Inmarsat, shall have—(A) an ownership interest in INTELSAT or the successor or separated entities of INTELSAT; or

(B) more than minimal ownership interest in Inmarsat or the successor or separated entities of Inmarsat.


(3) Termination of privileges and immunitiesThe preferential treatment of INTELSAT and Inmarsat shall not be extended to any successor entity or separated entity of INTELSAT or Inmarsat. Such preferential treatment includes—(A) privileged or immune treatment by national governments;

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_763_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dates for privatization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Dates for privatization Privatization shall be obtained in accordance with the criteria of this subchapter of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_763_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Independence The privatized successor entities and separated entities of INTELSAT and Inmarsat shall operate as independent commercial entities, and have a pro-competitive ownership structure. The successor entities and separated entities of INTELSAT and Inmarsat shall conduct an initial public offering in accordance with paragraph (5) to achieve such independence. Such offering shall substantially dilute the aggregate ownership of such entities by such signatories or former signatories. In determining whether a public offering attains such substantial dilution, the Commission shall take into account the purposes and intent, privatization criteria, and other provisions of this subchapter, as well as market conditions. No intergovernmental organization, including INTELSAT or Inmarsat, shall have—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_763_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of privileges and immunities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Termination of privileges and immunities The preferential treatment of INTELSAT and Inmarsat shall not be extended to any successor entity or separated entity of INTELSAT or Inmarsat. Such preferential treatment includes— Access to new, or renewal of access to, orbital locations shall be subject to the legal or regulatory processes of a national government that applies due diligence requirements intended to prevent the warehousing of orbital locations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_763_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of expansion during transition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Prevention of expansion during transition During the transition period prior to privatization under this subchapter, INTELSAT and Inmarsat shall be precluded from expanding into additional services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_763_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion to stock corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Conversion to stock corporations Any successor entity or separated entity created out of INTELSAT or Inmarsat shall be a national corporation or similar accepted commercial structure, subject to the laws of the nation in which incorporated, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_763_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Regulatory treatment Any successor entity or separated entity created after March 17, 2000, shall apply through the appropriate national licensing authorities for international frequency assignments and associated orbital registrations for all satellites.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_763_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competition policies in domiciliary country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Competition policies in domiciliary country Any successor entity or separated entity shall be subject to the jurisdiction of a nation or nations that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>