<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/765c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/765c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/765c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_765c"><akn:num>765c</akn:num><akn:heading>ITU functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 765c. ITU functions(a) Technical coordinationThe Commission and United States satellite companies shall utilize the International Telecommunication Union procedures for technical coordination with INTELSAT and its successor entities and separated entities, rather than INTELSAT procedures.


(b) ITU notifying administrationThe President and the Commission shall take the action necessary to ensure that the United States remains the ITU notifying administration for the privatized INTELSAT’s existing and future orbital slot registrations.


(Pub. L. 87–624, title VI, § 644, as added Pub. L. 106–180, § 3, Mar. 17, 2000, 114 Stat. 56.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Technical coordination The Commission and United States satellite companies shall utilize the International Telecommunication Union procedures for technical coordination with INTELSAT and its successor entities and separated entities, rather than INTELSAT procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>ITU notifying administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) ITU notifying administration The President and the Commission shall take the action necessary to ensure that the United States remains the ITU notifying administration for the privatized INTELSAT’s existing and future orbital slot registrations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>