<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_903"><akn:num>903</akn:num><akn:heading>Spectrum management activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 903. Spectrum management activities(a) Revision of regulationsWithin 180 days after October 27, 1992, the Secretary of Commerce and the NTIA shall amend the Department of Commerce spectrum management document entitled “Manual of Regulations and Procedures for Federal Radio Frequency Management” to improve Federal spectrum management activities and shall publish in the Federal Register any changes in the regulations in such document.


(b) Requirements for revisionsThe amendments required by subsection (a) shall—(1) provide for a period at the beginning of each meeting of the Interdepartmental Radio Advisory Committee to be open to the public to make presentations and receive advice, and provide the public with other meaningful opportunities to make presentations and receive advice;

(2) include provisions that will require (A) publication in the Federal Register of major policy proposals that are not classified and that involve spectrum management, and (B) adequate opportunity for public review and comment on those proposals;

(3) include provisions that will require publication in the Federal Register of major policy decisions that are not classified and that involve spectrum management;

(4) include provisions that will require that nonclassified spectrum management information be made available to the public, including access to electronic databases; and

(5) establish procedures that provide for the prompt and impartial consideration of requests for access to Government spectrum by the public, which procedures shall include provisions that will require the disclosure of the status and ultimate disposition of any such request.


(c) Certification to CongressNot later than 180 days after October 27, 1992, the Secretary of Commerce shall certify to Congress that the Secretary has complied with this section.


(d) Radio services(1) Assignments for radio servicesIn assigning frequencies for mobile radio services and other radio services, the Secretary of Commerce s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Revision of regulations Within 180 days after October 27, 1992, the Secretary of Commerce and the NTIA shall amend the Department of Commerce spectrum management document entitled “Manual of Regulations and Procedures for Federal Radio Frequency Management” to improve Federal spectrum management activities and shall publish in the Federal Register any changes in the regulations in such document.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for revisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements for revisions The amendments required by subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certification to Congress Not later than 180 days after October 27, 1992, the Secretary of Commerce shall certify to Congress that the Secretary has complied with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Radio services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Radio services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proof of compliance with FCC licensing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Proof of compliance with FCC licensing requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>