<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_904"><akn:num>904</akn:num><akn:heading>General administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 904. General administrative provisions(a) Interagency functions(1) Agency consultationFederal agencies shall consult with the Assistant Secretary and the NTIA to ensure that the conduct of telecommunications activities by such agencies is consistent with the policies developed under section 902(b)(2)(K) of this title.


(2) Report to PresidentThe Secretary shall timely submit to the President each year the report (including evaluations and recommendations) provided for in section 744(a) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(3) Coordination with Secretary of StateThe Secretary shall coordinate with the Secretary of State the performance of the functions described in section 902(b)(2)(C) of this title. The Corporation and concerned executive agencies shall provide the Secretary with such assistance, documents, and other cooperation as will enable the Secretary to carry out those functions.



(b) Advisory committees and informal consultations with industryTo the extent the Assistant Secretary deems it necessary to continue the Interdepartmental Radio Advisory Committee, such Committee shall serve as an advisory committee to the Assistant Secretary and the NTIA. As permitted by law, the Assistant Secretary may establish one or more telecommunications or information advisory committees (or both) composed of experts in the telecommunications and/or information areas outside the Government. The NTIA may also informally consult with industry as appropriate to carry out the most effective performance of its functions.


(c) General provisions(1) RegulationsThe Secretary and NTIA shall issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the functions assigned under this chapter.


(2) Support and assistance from other agenciesAll executive agencies are authorized and directed to cooperate with the NTIA and to furnish it with such information, support, and assistance, not inconsistent with law, as it may require in the performance of its functions.


(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Interagency functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory committees and informal consultations with industry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advisory committees and informal consultations with industry To the extent the Assistant Secretary deems it necessary to continue the Interdepartmental Radio Advisory Committee, such Committee shall serve as an advisory committee to the Assistant Secretary and the NTIA. As permitted by law, the Assistant Secretary may establish one or more telecommunications or information advisory committees (or both) composed of experts in the telecommunications and/or information areas outside the Government. The NTIA may also informally consult with industry as appropriate to carry out the most effective performance of its functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reorganization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reorganization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on solicitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on solicitations Notwithstanding section 1522 of title 15, neither the Secretary, the Assistant Secretary, nor any officer or employee of the NTIA shall solicit any gift or bequest of property, both real and personal, from any entity for the purpose of furthering the authorized functions of the NTIA if such solicitation would create a conflict of interest or an appearance of a conflict of interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>