<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_906"><akn:num>906</akn:num><akn:heading>Wireless supply chain innovation and multilateral security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 906. Wireless supply chain innovation and multilateral security(a) Communications technology security funds(1) Public Wireless Supply Chain Innovation Fund(A) Establishment(i) In generalThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Public Wireless Supply Chain Innovation Fund” (referred to in this paragraph as the “Innovation Fund”).


(ii) Availability(I) In generalAmounts appropriated to the Innovation Fund shall remain available through the end of the tenth fiscal year beginning after the date on which funds are appropriated to the Fund.


(II) Remainder to TreasuryAny amounts remaining in the Innovation Fund after the end of the tenth fiscal year beginning after the date of appropriation shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury.




(B) Use of Fund(i) In generalAmounts appropriated to the Innovation Fund shall be available to the Secretary, acting through the NTIA Administrator, to make grants on a competitive basis under this paragraph in such amounts as the Secretary, acting through the NTIA Administrator, determines appropriate, subject to clause (ii).


(ii) Limitation on grant amountsThe amount of a grant awarded under this paragraph to a recipient for a specific research focus area may not exceed $50,000,000.



(C) Administration of FundThe Secretary, acting through the NTIA Administrator, in consultation with the Commission, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the Intelligence Advanced Research Projects Activity of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, shall establish criteria for grants awarded under this paragraph, by the NTIA Administrator and administer the Innovation Fund, to support the following:(i) Promoting and deploying technology, including software, hardware, and microprocessing technology, that will enhance competitiveness in the fifth-generation (commonly know</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Communications technology security funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Communications technology security funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting United States leadership in international organizations and communications standards-setting bodies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Promoting United States leadership in international organizations and communications standards-setting bodies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>