<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/923" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/923/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/47/923/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_923"><akn:num>923</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of reallocable frequencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 923. Identification of reallocable frequencies(a) Identification requiredThe Secretary shall, within 18 months after August 10, 1993, and within 6 months after August 5, 1997, prepare and submit to the President and the Congress a report identifying and recommending for reallocation bands of frequencies—(1) that are allocated on a primary basis for Federal Government use;

(2) that are not required for the present or identifiable future needs of the Federal Government;

(3) that can feasibly be made available, as of the date of submission of the report or at any time during the next 15 years, for use under the 1934 Act [47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.] (other than for Federal Government stations under section 305 of the 1934 Act [47 U.S.C. 305]);

(4) the transfer of which (from Federal Government use) will not result in costs to the Federal Government, or losses of services or benefits to the public, that are excessive in relation to the benefits to the public that may be provided by non-Federal licensees; and

(5) that are most likely to have the greatest potential for productive uses and public benefits under the 1934 Act [47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.] if allocated for non-Federal use.


(b) Minimum amount of spectrum recommended(1) Initial reallocation reportIn accordance with the provisions of this section, the Secretary shall recommend for reallocation in the initial report required by subsection (a), for use other than by Federal Government stations under section 305 of the 1934 Act (47 U.S.C. 305), bands of frequencies that in the aggregate span not less than 200 megahertz, that are located below 5 gigahertz, and that meet the criteria specified in paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (a). Such bands of frequencies shall include bands of frequencies, located below 3 gigahertz, that span in the aggregate not less than 100 megahertz.


(2) Mixed uses permitted to be countedBands of frequencies which a report of the Secretary under subsection (a) or (d)(1) recommends be p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Identification required The Secretary shall, within 18 months after August 10, 1993, and within 6 months after August 5, 1997, prepare and submit to the President and the Congress a report identifying and recommending for reallocation bands of frequencies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum amount of spectrum recommended</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Minimum amount of spectrum recommended</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for identification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria for identification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for identification of reallocable bands of frequencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Procedure for identification of reallocable bands of frequencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timetable for reallocation and limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Timetable for reallocation and limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional reallocation report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional reallocation report If the Secretary receives a notice from the Commission pursuant to section 3002(c)(5) of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the President, the Commission, and the Congress a report recommending for reallocation for use other than by Federal Government stations under section 305 of the 1934 Act (47 U.S.C. 305), bands of frequencies that are suitable for the licensees identified in the Commission’s notice. The Commission shall, not later than one year after receipt of such report, prepare, submit to the President and the Congress, and implement, a plan for the immediate allocation and assignment of such frequencies under the 1934 Act [47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.] to incumbent licensees described in the Commission’s notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relocation of and spectrum sharing by Federal Government stations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Relocation of and spectrum sharing by Federal Government stations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development and publication of relocation or sharing transition plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Development and publication of relocation or sharing transition plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute resolution process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Dispute resolution process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relocation prioritized over sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Relocation prioritized over sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>