<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10111"><akn:num>10111</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation of financial management systems of Office of Justice Programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10111. Consolidation of financial management systems of Office of Justice Programs(a) Consolidation of accounting activities and procurement activitiesThe Assistant Attorney General of the Office of Justice Programs, in coordination with the Chief Information Officer and Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Justice, shall ensure that—(1) all accounting activities for all elements of the Office of Justice Programs are carried out under the direct management of the Office of the Comptroller; and

(2) all procurement activities for all elements of the Office are carried out under the direct management of the Office of Administration.


(b) Further consolidation of procurement activitiesThe Assistant Attorney General, in coordination with the Chief Information Officer and Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Justice, shall ensure that, on and after September 30, 2008—(1) all procurement activities for all elements of the Office are carried out through a single management office; and

(2) all contracts and purchase orders used in carrying out those activities are processed through a single procurement system.


(c) Consolidation of financial management systemsThe Assistant Attorney General, in coordination with the Chief Information Officer and Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Justice, shall ensure that, on and after September 30, 2010, all financial management activities (including human resources, payroll, and accounting activities, as well as procurement activities) of all elements of the Office are carried out through a single financial management system.


(d) Achieving compliance(1) ScheduleThe Assistant Attorney General shall undertake a scheduled consolidation of operations to achieve compliance with the requirements of this section.


(2) Specific requirementsWith respect to achieving compliance with the requirements of—(A) subsection (a), the consolidation of operations shall be initiated not later than 90 days after January 5, 200</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation of accounting activities and procurement activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consolidation of accounting activities and procurement activities The Assistant Attorney General of the Office of Justice Programs, in coordination with the Chief Information Officer and Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Justice, shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Further consolidation of procurement activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Further consolidation of procurement activities The Assistant Attorney General, in coordination with the Chief Information Officer and Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Justice, shall ensure that, on and after September 30, 2008—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10111_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation of financial management systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consolidation of financial management systems The Assistant Attorney General, in coordination with the Chief Information Officer and Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Justice, shall ensure that, on and after September 30, 2010, all financial management activities (including human resources, payroll, and accounting activities, as well as procurement activities) of all elements of the Office are carried out through a single financial management system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10111_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Achieving compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Achieving compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>