<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10122" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10122/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10122/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10122"><akn:num>10122</akn:num><akn:heading>National Institute of Justice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10122. National Institute of Justice(a) Establishment; general authority of Attorney General over InstituteThere is established within the Department of Justice, under the general authority of the Attorney General, a National Institute of Justice (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as the “Institute”).


(b) Director of Institute; appointment by President; authority; restrictionsThe Institute shall be headed by a Director appointed by the President. The Director shall have had experience in justice research. The Director shall report to the Attorney General through the Assistant Attorney General. The Director shall have final authority over all grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded by the Institute. The Director shall not engage in any other employment than that of serving as Director; nor shall the Director hold any office in, or act in any capacity for, any organization, agency, or institution with which the Institute makes any contract or other arrangement under this chapter.


(c) Duties and functionsThe Institute is authorized to—(1) make grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with, public agencies, institutions of higher education, private organizations, or individuals to conduct research, demonstrations, or special projects pertaining to the purposes described in this subchapter, and provide technical assistance and training in support of tests, demonstrations, and special projects;

(2) conduct or authorize multiyear and short-term research and development concerning the criminal and civil justice systems in an effort—(A) to identify alternative programs for achieving system goals;

(B) to provide more accurate information on the causes and correlates of crime;

(C) to analyze the correlates of crime and juvenile delinquency and provide more accurate information on the causes and correlates of crime and juvenile delinquency;

(D) to improve the functioning of the criminal justice system;

(E) to develop new met</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10122_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; general authority of Attorney General over Institute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; general authority of Attorney General over Institute There is established within the Department of Justice, under the general authority of the Attorney General, a National Institute of Justice (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as the “Institute”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10122_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of Institute; appointment by President; authority; restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Director of Institute; appointment by President; authority; restrictions The Institute shall be headed by a Director appointed by the President. The Director shall have had experience in justice research. The Director shall report to the Attorney General through the Assistant Attorney General. The Director shall have final authority over all grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded by the Institute. The Director shall not engage in any other employment than that of serving as Director; nor shall the Director hold any office in, or act in any capacity for, any organization, agency, or institution with which the Institute makes any contract or other arrangement under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10122_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties and functions The Institute is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10122_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal and civil justice research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criminal and civil justice research To insure that all criminal and civil justice research is carried out in a coordinated manner, the Director is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>