<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10132" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10132/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10132/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10132"><akn:num>10132</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau of Justice Statistics</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10132. Bureau of Justice Statistics(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Department of Justice, under the general authority of the Attorney General, a Bureau of Justice Statistics (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as “Bureau”).


(b) Appointment of Director; experience; authority; restrictionsThe Bureau shall be headed by a Director appointed by the President. The Director shall have had experience in statistical programs. The Director shall have final authority for all grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded by the Bureau. The Director shall be responsible for the integrity of data and statistics and shall protect against improper or illegal use or disclosure. The Director shall report to the Attorney General through the Assistant Attorney General. The Director shall not engage in any other employment than that of serving as Director; nor shall the Director hold any office in, or act in any capacity for, any organization, agency, or institution with which the Bureau makes any contract or other arrangement under this Act.


(c) Duties and functions of BureauThe Bureau is authorized to—(1) make grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with public agencies, institutions of higher education, private organizations, or private individuals for purposes related to this subchapter; grants shall be made subject to continuing compliance with standards for gathering justice statistics set forth in rules and regulations promulgated by the Director;

(2) collect and analyze information concerning criminal victimization, including crimes against the elderly, and civil disputes;

(3) collect and analyze data that will serve as a continuous and comparable national social indication of the prevalence, incidence, rates, extent, distribution, and attributes of crime, juvenile delinquency, civil disputes, and other statistical factors related to crime, civil disputes, and juvenile delinquency, in support of national, State, triba</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10132_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Department of Justice, under the general authority of the Attorney General, a Bureau of Justice Statistics (hereinafter referred to in this subchapter as “Bureau”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10132_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Director; experience; authority; restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment of Director; experience; authority; restrictions The Bureau shall be headed by a Director appointed by the President. The Director shall have had experience in statistical programs. The Director shall have final authority for all grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded by the Bureau. The Director shall be responsible for the integrity of data and statistics and shall protect against improper or illegal use or disclosure. The Director shall report to the Attorney General through the Assistant Attorney General. The Director shall not engage in any other employment than that of serving as Director; nor shall the Director hold any office in, or act in any capacity for, any organization, agency, or institution with which the Bureau makes any contract or other arrangement under this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10132_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and functions of Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties and functions of Bureau The Bureau is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10132_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Justice statistical collection, analysis, and dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Justice statistical collection, analysis, and dissemination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10132_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing of information, data, or reports by Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Furnishing of information, data, or reports by Federal agencies Federal agencies requested to furnish information, data, or reports pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(C) shall provide such information to the Bureau as is required to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10132_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with representatives of State, tribal, and local government and judiciary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consultation with representatives of State, tribal, and local government and judiciary In recommending standards for gathering justice statistics under this section, the Director shall consult with representatives of State, tribal, and local government, including, where appropriate, representatives of the judiciary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10132_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports Not later than 1 year after July 29, 2010, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress a report describing the data collected and analyzed under this section relating to crimes in Indian country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>