<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10227" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10227/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10227/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10227"><akn:num>10227</akn:num><akn:heading>Title to personal property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10227. Title to personal property
Notwithstanding any other provision of law, title to all expendable and nonexpendable personal property purchased with funds made available under this chapter, including such property purchased with funds made available under this chapter as in effect before October 12, 1984, shall vest in the criminal justice agency or nonprofit organization that purchased the property if it certifies to the State office responsible for the trust fund required by section 10158 of this title, or the State office described in section 1408 11 See References in Text note below.,,22 So in original. as the case may be, that it will use the property for criminal justice purposes. If such certification is not made, title to the property shall vest in the State office, which shall seek to have the property used for criminal justice purposes elsewhere in the State prior to using it or disposing of it in any other manner.
(Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 808, as added Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 609B(g), Oct. 12, 1984, 98 Stat. 2095; amended Pub. L. 99–570, title I, § 1552(b)(4), Oct. 27, 1986, 100 Stat. 3207–46; Pub. L. 101–647, title II, § 241(b)(4), Nov. 29, 1990, 104 Stat. 4813; Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330001(h)(10), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2139; Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1111(c)(2)(E), Jan. 5, 2006, 119 Stat. 3102.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 1408, referred to in text, is section 1408 of Pub. L. 90–351, which was classified to section 3796aa–7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40156(c)(8), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 1924.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 3789 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section. Some section numbers or references in amendment notes below reflect the classification of such sections or references prior to editorial reclassification.

Prior ProvisionsA prior </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>