<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10288" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10288/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10288/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10288"><akn:num>10288</akn:num><akn:heading>Due diligence in paying benefit claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10288. Due diligence in paying benefit claims(a) In generalThe Bureau, with all due diligence, shall expeditiously attempt to obtain the information and documentation necessary to adjudicate a benefit claim filed under this subchapter, including a claim for financial assistance under part B.


(b) Sufficient information unavailableIf a benefit claim filed under this subchapter, including a claim for financial assistance under part B, is unable to be adjudicated by the Bureau because of a lack of information or documentation from a third party, such as a public agency, and such information is not readily available to the claimant, the Bureau—(1) may use available investigative tools, including subpoenas, to—(A) adjudicate or to expedite the processing of the benefit claim, if the Bureau deems such use to be necessary to adjudicate or conducive to expediting the adjudication of such claim; and

(B) obtain information or documentation from third parties, including public agencies, if the Bureau deems such use to be necessary to adjudicate or conducive to expediting the adjudication of a claim; and


(2) may not abandon the benefit claim unless the Bureau has used investigative tools, including subpoenas, to obtain the information or documentation deemed necessary to adjudicate such claim by the Bureau under subparagraph (1)(B).


(Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 1206, as added Pub. L. 115–36, § 4, June 2, 2017, 131 Stat. 852; amended Pub. L. 117–61, § 4, Nov. 18, 2021, 135 Stat. 1478.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 3796c–3 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments2021—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 117–61 substituted “the Bureau—” and pars. (1) and (2) for “the Bureau may not abandon the benefit claim unless the Bureau has utilized the investigative tools available to the Bureau to obtain the necessary information or documentation, including subpoenas.”.

St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10288_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Bureau, with all due diligence, shall expeditiously attempt to obtain the information and documentation necessary to adjudicate a benefit claim filed under this subchapter, including a claim for financial assistance under part B.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10288_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sufficient information unavailable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sufficient information unavailable If a benefit claim filed under this subchapter, including a claim for financial assistance under part B, is unable to be adjudicated by the Bureau because of a lack of information or documentation from a third party, such as a public agency, and such information is not readily available to the claimant, the Bureau—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>