<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10384" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10384/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10384/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10384"><akn:num>10384</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10384. Limitation on use of funds(a) Nonsupplanting requirementFunds made available under this subchapter to States or units of local government shall not be used to supplant State or local funds, or, in the case of Indian tribal governments, funds supplied by the Bureau of Indian Affairs, but shall be used to increase the amount of funds that would, in the absence of Federal funds received under this subchapter, be made available from State or local sources, or in the case of Indian tribal governments, from funds supplied by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.


(b) Non-Federal costs(1) In generalStates and units of local government may use assets received through the Assets Forfeiture equitable sharing program to provide the non-Federal share of the cost of programs, projects, and activities funded under this subchapter.


(2) Indian tribal governmentsFunds appropriated by the Congress for the activities of any agency of an Indian tribal government or the Bureau of Indian Affairs performing law enforcement functions on any Indian lands may be used to provide the non-Federal share of the cost of programs or projects funded under this subchapter.



(c) Hiring costsFunding provided under this subchapter for hiring or rehiring a career law enforcement officer may not exceed $75,000, unless the Attorney General grants a waiver from this limitation.


(d) Guidance for understaffed law enforcement agencies(1) DefinitionsIn this subsection:(A) Covered applicantThe term “covered applicant” means an applicant for a hiring grant under this subchapter seeking funding for a law enforcement agency operating below the budgeted strength of the law enforcement agency.


(B) Budgeted strengthThe term “budgeted strength” means the employment of the maximum number of sworn law enforcement officers the budget of a law enforcement agency allows the agency to employ.



(2) ProceduresNot later than 180 days after May 24, 2024, the Attorney General shall establish consistent procedures for </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10384_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonsupplanting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nonsupplanting requirement Funds made available under this subchapter to States or units of local government shall not be used to supplant State or local funds, or, in the case of Indian tribal governments, funds supplied by the Bureau of Indian Affairs, but shall be used to increase the amount of funds that would, in the absence of Federal funds received under this subchapter, be made available from State or local sources, or in the case of Indian tribal governments, from funds supplied by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10384_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Non-Federal costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10384_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hiring costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hiring costs Funding provided under this subchapter for hiring or rehiring a career law enforcement officer may not exceed $75,000, unless the Attorney General grants a waiver from this limitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10384_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance for understaffed law enforcement agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Guidance for understaffed law enforcement agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>