<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10422" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10422/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10422/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10422"><akn:num>10422</akn:num><akn:heading>State applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10422. State applications(a) In general(1) To request a grant under this subchapter the chief executive of a State shall submit an application to the Attorney General in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.

(2) Such application shall include assurances that Federal funds received under this subchapter shall be used to supplement, not supplant, non-Federal funds that would otherwise be available for activities funded under this subchapter.

(3) Such application shall coordinate the design and implementation of treatment programs between State correctional representatives and the State Alcohol 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. and Drug 1 Abuse 1 agency (and, if appropriate, between representatives of local correctional agencies and representatives of either the State alcohol and drug abuse agency or any appropriate local alcohol and drug abuse agency).


(b) Substance abuse testing requirementTo be eligible to receive funds under this subchapter, a State must agree to implement or continue to require urinalysis or other proven reliable forms of testing, including both periodic and random testing—(1) of an individual before the individual enters a residential substance abuse treatment program and during the period in which the individual participates in the treatment program; and

(2) of an individual released from a residential substance abuse treatment program if the individual remains in the custody of the State.


(c) Requirement for aftercare component(1) To be eligible for funding under this subchapter, a State shall ensure that individuals who participate in the substance abuse treatment program established or implemented with assistance provided under this subchapter will be provided with aftercare services, which may include case management services and a full continuum of support services that ensure providers furnishing services under that program are approved by the appropriate Sta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10422_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10422_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substance abuse testing requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Substance abuse testing requirement To be eligible to receive funds under this subchapter, a State must agree to implement or continue to require urinalysis or other proven reliable forms of testing, including both periodic and random testing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10422_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for aftercare component</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirement for aftercare component</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10422_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination of Federal assistance Each application submitted for a grant under this section shall include a description of how the funds made available under this section will be coordinated with Federal assistance for substance abuse treatment and aftercare services currently provided by the Department of Health and Human Services’ Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10422_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State office The office responsible for the trust fund required by section 10158 of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10422_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant amounts for nonresidential aftercare services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of grant amounts for nonresidential aftercare services A State may use amounts received under this subchapter to provide nonresidential substance abuse treatment aftercare services for inmates or former inmates that meet the requirements of subsection (c), if the chief executive officer of the State certifies to the Attorney General that the State is providing, and will continue to provide, an adequate level of residential treatment services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>