<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10423" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10423/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10423/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10423"><akn:num>10423</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of State applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10423. Review of State applications(a) In generalThe Attorney General shall make a grant under section 10421 of this title to carry out the projects described in the application submitted under section 10422 of this title upon determining that—(1) the application is consistent with the requirements of this subchapter; and

(2) before the approval of the application the Attorney General has made an affirmative finding in writing that the proposed project has been reviewed in accordance with this subchapter.


(b) ApprovalEach application submitted under section 10422 of this title shall be considered approved, in whole or in part, by the Attorney General not later than 90 days after first received unless the Attorney General informs the applicant of specific reasons for disapproval.


(c) RestrictionGrant funds received under this subchapter shall not be used for land acquisition or construction projects.


(d) Disapproval notice and reconsiderationThe Attorney General shall not disapprove any application without first affording the applicant reasonable notice and an opportunity for reconsideration.


(e) Priority for partnerships with community-based drug treatment programsIn considering an application submitted by a State under section 10422 of this title, the Attorney General shall give priority to an application that involves a partnership between the State and a community-based drug treatment program within the State.


(Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 1903, as added Pub. L. 103–322, title III, § 32101(a)(3), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 1899; amended Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1145(c), Jan. 5, 2006, 119 Stat. 3112.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 3796ff–2 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments2006—Subsec. (e). Pub. L. 109–162 added subsec. (e).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2006 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10423_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Attorney General shall make a grant under section 10421 of this title to carry out the projects described in the application submitted under section 10422 of this title upon determining that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10423_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Approval Each application submitted under section 10422 of this title shall be considered approved, in whole or in part, by the Attorney General not later than 90 days after first received unless the Attorney General informs the applicant of specific reasons for disapproval.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10423_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Restriction Grant funds received under this subchapter shall not be used for land acquisition or construction projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10423_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disapproval notice and reconsideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disapproval notice and reconsideration The Attorney General shall not disapprove any application without first affording the applicant reasonable notice and an opportunity for reconsideration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10423_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority for partnerships with community-based drug treatment programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority for partnerships with community-based drug treatment programs In considering an application submitted by a State under section 10422 of this title, the Attorney General shall give priority to an application that involves a partnership between the State and a community-based drug treatment program within the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>