<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10448" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10448/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10448/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10448"><akn:num>10448</akn:num><akn:heading>General terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10448. General terms and conditions(a) Nonmonetary assistanceIn addition to the assistance provided under this subchapter, the Attorney General may request any Federal agency to use its authorities and the resources granted to it under Federal law (including personnel, equipment, supplies, facilities, and managerial, technical, and advisory services) in support of State, tribal, and local assistance efforts.


(b) ReportingNot later than 1 month after the end of each even-numbered fiscal year, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report that includes, for each State and for each grantee Indian tribe—(1) the number of grants made and funds distributed under this subchapter;

(2) a summary of the purposes for which those grants were provided and an evaluation of their progress;

(3) a statistical summary of persons served, detailing the nature of victimization, and providing data on age, sex, relationship of victim to offender, geographic distribution, race, ethnicity, language, and disability, and the membership of persons served in any underserved population; and

(4) an evaluation of the effectiveness of programs funded under this subchapter.


(c) Regulations or guidelinesNot later than 120 days after September 13, 1994, the Attorney General shall publish proposed regulations or guidelines implementing this subchapter. Not later than 180 days after September 13, 1994, the Attorney General shall publish final regulations or guidelines implementing this subchapter.


(Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 2009, formerly § 2004, as added Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40121(a)(3), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 1914; amended Pub. L. 106–386, div. B, title I, § 1103(b)(4), Oct. 28, 2000, 114 Stat. 1497; renumbered § 2009, Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title IV, § 402(2), Nov. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 1789; Pub. L. 108–405, title III, § 310(b), Oct. 30, 2004, 118 Stat. 2276; Pub. L. </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10448_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonmonetary assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nonmonetary assistance In addition to the assistance provided under this subchapter, the Attorney General may request any Federal agency to use its authorities and the resources granted to it under Federal law (including personnel, equipment, supplies, facilities, and managerial, technical, and advisory services) in support of State, tribal, and local assistance efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10448_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reporting Not later than 1 month after the end of each even-numbered fiscal year, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report that includes, for each State and for each grantee Indian tribe—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10448_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations or guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations or guidelines Not later than 120 days after September 13, 1994, the Attorney General shall publish proposed regulations or guidelines implementing this subchapter. Not later than 180 days after September 13, 1994, the Attorney General shall publish final regulations or guidelines implementing this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>