<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10442" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10442/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10442/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10442"><akn:num>10442</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Office on Violence Against Women</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10442. Establishment of Office on Violence Against Women(a) In generalThere is hereby established within the Department of Justice, under the general authority of the Attorney General, an Office on Violence Against Women (in this subchapter referred to as the “Office”).


(b) Separate officeThe Office shall be a separate and distinct office within the Department of Justice, not subsumed by any other office, headed by a Director, who shall report to the Attorney General and serve as Counsel to the Attorney General on the subject of violence against women, and who shall have final authority over all grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded by the Office.


(c) JurisdictionUnder the general authority of the Attorney General, the Office—(1) shall have sole jurisdiction over all duties and functions described in section 10444 of this title; and

(2) shall be solely responsible for coordination with other departments, agencies, or offices of all activities authorized or undertaken under—(A) the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (title IV of Public Law 103–322);

(B) the Violence Against Women Act of 2000 (division B of Public Law 106–386);

(C) the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 (Public Law 109–162; 119 Stat. 2960);

(D) the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2013 (Public Law 113–4; 127 Stat. 54); and

(E) the Violence Against Women Act Reauthorization Act of 2022.



(Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 2002, as added Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title IV, § 402(3), Nov. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 1789; amended Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title IX, § 901(a), Mar. 15, 2022, 136 Stat. 910.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Violence Against Women Act of 1994, referred to in subsec. (c)(2)(A), is title IV of Pub. L. 103–322, Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 1902. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1994 Act note set out under section 10101 of this title and Tables.
The Violence Against Women</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10442_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is hereby established within the Department of Justice, under the general authority of the Attorney General, an Office on Violence Against Women (in this subchapter referred to as the “Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10442_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Separate office The Office shall be a separate and distinct office within the Department of Justice, not subsumed by any other office, headed by a Director, who shall report to the Attorney General and serve as Counsel to the Attorney General on the subject of violence against women, and who shall have final authority over all grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded by the Office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10442_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Jurisdiction Under the general authority of the Attorney General, the Office—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>