<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10453" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10453/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10453/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10453"><akn:num>10453</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal Deputy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10453. Tribal Deputy(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Office on Violence Against Women a Deputy Director for Tribal Affairs.


(b) Duties(1) 11 So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted. In generalThe Deputy Director shall under the guidance and authority of the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women—(A) oversee and manage the administration of grants to and contracts with Indian tribes, tribal courts, tribal organizations, or tribal nonprofit organizations;

(B) ensure that, if a grant under this Act or a contract pursuant to such a grant is made to an organization to perform services that benefit more than 1 Indian tribe, the approval of each Indian tribe to be benefitted shall be a prerequisite to the making of the grant or letting of the contract;

(C) coordinate development of Federal policy, protocols, and guidelines on matters relating to violence against Indian women;

(D) advise the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women concerning policies, legislation, implementation of laws, and other issues relating to violence against Indian women;

(E) represent the Office on Violence Against Women in the annual consultations under section 20126 22 See References in Text note below. of this title;

(F) provide technical assistance, coordination, and support to other offices and bureaus in the Department of Justice to develop policy and to enforce Federal laws relating to violence against Indian women, including through litigation of civil and criminal actions relating to those laws;

(G) maintain a liaison with the judicial branches of Federal, State, and tribal governments on matters relating to violence against Indian women;

(H) support enforcement of tribal protection orders and implementation of full faith and credit educational projects and comity agreements between Indian tribes and States; and

(I) ensure that adequate tribal technical assistance that is developed and provided by entities having expertise in tribal law, cust</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10453_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Office on Violence Against Women a Deputy Director for Tribal Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10453_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10453_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>