<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10455" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10455/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10455/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10455"><akn:num>10455</akn:num><akn:heading>Senior Policy Advisor for Culturally Specific Communities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10455. Senior Policy Advisor for Culturally Specific Communities(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Office on Violence Against Women a Senior Policy Advisor for Culturally Specific Communities.


(b) DutiesThe Senior Policy Advisor for Culturally Specific Communities, under the guidance and authority of the Director, shall—(1) advise on the administration of grants related to culturally specific services and contracts with culturally specific organizations;

(2) coordinate development of Federal policy, protocols, and guidelines on matters relating to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking in culturally specific communities;

(3) advise the Director on policies, legislation, implementation of laws, and other issues relating to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking in culturally specific communities;

(4) provide technical assistance, coordination, and support to other offices and bureaus in the Department of Justice to develop policy and to enforce Federal laws relating to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking in culturally specific communities;

(5) ensure that appropriate technical assistance, developed and provided by entities with expertise in culturally specific communities, is made available to grantees and potential grantees proposing to serve culturally specific communities;

(6) ensure access to grants and technical assistance for culturally specific organizations; and

(7) analyze the distribution of grant funding in order to identify barriers for culturally specific organizations.


(c) QualificationsNot later than 120 days after March 15, 2022, the Director shall hire for the position established under subsection (a) an individual with personal, lived, and work experience from a culturally specific community, and a demonstrated history and expertise addressing domestic violence or sexual assault in a nongovernmental agency.


(Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 2018, as ad</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10455_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Office on Violence Against Women a Senior Policy Advisor for Culturally Specific Communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10455_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Senior Policy Advisor for Culturally Specific Communities, under the guidance and authority of the Director, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10455_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualifications Not later than 120 days after March 15, 2022, the Director shall hire for the position established under subsection (a) an individual with personal, lived, and work experience from a culturally specific community, and a demonstrated history and expertise addressing domestic violence or sexual assault in a nongovernmental agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>