<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10462" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10462/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10462/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10462"><akn:num>10462</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10462. Applications(a) ApplicationAn eligible grantee shall submit an application to the Attorney General that—(1) contains a certification by the chief executive officer of the State, Indian tribal government, court, or local government entity that the conditions of section 10461(c) of this title are met or will be met within the later of—(A) the period ending on the date on which the next session of the State or Indian tribal legislature ends; or

(B) 2 years of September 13, 1994 or, in the case of the condition set forth in subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 10461(c)(4) 22 See References in Text note below. of this title, the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on October 28, 2000;


(2) describes plans to further the purposes stated in section 10461(a) of this title;

(3) identifies the agency or office or groups of agencies or offices responsible for carrying out the program; and

(4) includes documentation from victim service providers and, as appropriate, population specific organizations demonstrating their participation in developing the application, and identifying such programs in which such groups will be consulted for development and implementation.


(b) PriorityIn awarding grants under this subchapter, the Attorney General shall give priority to applicants that—(1) do not currently provide for centralized handling of cases involving domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking by police, prosecutors, and courts;

(2) demonstrate a commitment to strong enforcement of laws, and prosecution of cases, involving domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, including the enforcement of protection orders from other States and jurisdictions (including tribal jurisdictions);

(3) have established cooperative agreements or can demonstrate effective ongoing collaborative arrangements with neighboring jurisdictions to facilitate the enforcement of protection orders from other States and juri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10462_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application An eligible grantee shall submit an application to the Attorney General that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10462_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority In awarding grants under this subchapter, the Attorney General shall give priority to applicants that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10462_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dissemination of information The Attorney General shall annually compile and broadly disseminate (including through electronic publication) information about successful data collection and communication systems that meet the purposes described in this section. Such dissemination shall target States, State and local courts, Indian tribal governments, and units of local government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>