<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10479" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10479/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10479/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10479"><akn:num>10479</akn:num><akn:heading>Mental health responses in the judicial system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10479. Mental health responses in the judicial system(a) Pretrial screening and supervision(1) In generalThe Attorney General may award grants to States, units of local government, territories, Indian Tribes, nonprofit agencies, or any combination thereof, to develop, implement, or expand pretrial services programs to improve the identification and outcomes of individuals with mental illness.


(2) Allowable usesGrants awarded under this subsection may be may be used for—(A) behavioral health needs and risk screening of defendants, including verification of interview information, mental health evaluation, and criminal history screening;

(B) assessment of risk of pretrial misconduct through objective, statistically validated means, and presentation to the court of recommendations based on such assessment, including services that will reduce the risk of pre-trial misconduct;

(C) followup review of defendants unable to meet the conditions of pretrial release;

(D) evaluation of process and results of pre-trial service programs;

(E) supervision of defendants who are on pretrial release, including reminders to defendants of scheduled court dates;

(F) reporting on process and results of pretrial services programs to relevant public and private mental health stakeholders; and

(G) data collection and analysis necessary to make available information required for assessment of risk.



(b) Behavioral health assessments and intervention(1) In generalThe Attorney General may award grants to States, units of local government, territories, Indian Tribes, nonprofit agencies, or any combination thereof, to develop, implement, or expand a behavioral health screening and assessment program framework for State or local criminal justice systems.


(2) Allowable usesGrants awarded under this subsection may be used for—(A) promotion of the use of validated assessment tools to gauge the criminogenic risk, substance abuse needs, and mental health needs of individuals;

(B) initiativ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10479_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pretrial screening and supervision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pretrial screening and supervision</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10479_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Behavioral health assessments and intervention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Behavioral health assessments and intervention</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10479_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of grant funds A State, unit of local government, territory, Indian Tribe, or nonprofit agency that receives a grant under this section shall, in accordance with subsection (b)(2), use grant funds for the expenses of a treatment program, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10479_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement of non-Federal funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Supplement of non-Federal funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10479_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applications To request a grant under this section, a State, unit of local government, territory, Indian Tribe, or nonprofit agency shall submit an application to the Attorney General in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10479_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geographic distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Geographic distribution The Attorney General shall ensure that, to the extent practicable, the distribution of grants under this section is equitable and includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10479_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports and evaluations For each fiscal year, each grantee under this section during that fiscal year shall submit to the Attorney General a report on the effectiveness of activities carried out using such grant. Each report shall include an evaluation in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require. The Attorney General shall specify the dates on which such reports shall be submitted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10479_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Accountability Grants awarded under this section shall be subject to the following accountability provisions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10479_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preventing duplicative grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Preventing duplicative grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>