<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10493" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10493/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10493/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10493"><akn:num>10493</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10493. Uses of funds(a) In generalA State or local law enforcement agency or organization that receives a grant under this subchapter 11 See References in Text note below. shall use amounts provided under the grant to establish or improve training and support programs for law enforcement personnel.


(b) Required activitiesA law enforcement agency or organization that receives funds under this subchapter shall provide at least one of the following services:(1) Counseling for law enforcement officers and family members.

(2) Child care on a 24-hour basis.

(3) Marital and adolescent support groups.

(4) Evidence-based programs to reduce stress, prevent suicide, and promote mental health.

(5) Stress education for law enforcement recruits and families.

(6) Technical assistance and training programs to support any or all of the services described in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), and (5).


(c) Optional activitiesA law enforcement agency or organization that receives funds under this subchapter may provide the following services:(1) Post-shooting debriefing for officers and their spouses.

(2) Group therapy.

(3) Hypertension clinics.

(4) Critical incident response on a 24-hour basis.

(5) Law enforcement family crisis, mental health crisis, and suicide prevention telephone services on a 24-hour basis.

(6) Counseling for law enforcement personnel exposed to infectious disease.

(7) Counseling for peers.

(8) Counseling for families of personnel killed, injured, or permanently disabled in the line of duty.

(9) Seminars regarding alcohol, drug use, gambling, and overeating.

(10) Specialized training for identifying, reporting, and responding to officer mental health crises and suicide.

(11) Technical assistance and training to support any or all of the services described in paragraphs (1) through (10).


(Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 2303, as added Pub. L. 103–322, title XXI, § 210201(a)(3), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2062; amended Pub. L. 116–32, § 2(4), July 25, 2</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10493_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A State or local law enforcement agency or organization that receives a grant under this subchapter 11 See References in Text note below. shall use amounts provided under the grant to establish or improve training and support programs for law enforcement personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10493_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required activities A law enforcement agency or organization that receives funds under this subchapter shall provide at least one of the following services:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10493_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Optional activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Optional activities A law enforcement agency or organization that receives funds under this subchapter may provide the following services:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>