<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10551" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10551/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10551/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10551"><akn:num>10551</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10551. Program authorized(a) In general(1) COPS grantsThe Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services (referred to in this subchapter as the “COPS Director”) is authorized to make grants to States, units of local government, and Indian tribes for the purposes described in paragraphs (5) through (9) of subsection (b).


(2) BJA grantsThe Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance (referred to in this subchapter as the “BJA Director”) is authorized to make grants to States, units of local government, and Indian tribes for the purposes described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (b).



(b) Uses of fundsGrants awarded under this section shall be distributed directly to the State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe, and shall be used to improve security at schools and on school grounds in the jurisdiction of the grantee through evidence-based school safety programs that may include one or more of the following:(1) Training school personnel and students to prevent student violence against others and self.

(2) The development and operation of anonymous reporting systems for threats of school violence, including mobile telephone applications, hotlines, and Internet websites.

(3) The development and operation of—(A) school threat assessment and intervention teams that may include coordination with law enforcement agencies and school personnel; and

(B) specialized training for school officials in responding to mental health crises.


(4) Any other measure that, in the determination of the BJA Director, may provide a significant improvement in training, threat assessments and reporting, and violence prevention.

(5) Coordination with local law enforcement.

(6) Training for local law enforcement officers to prevent student violence against others and self.

(7) Placement and use of metal detectors, locks, lighting, and other deterrent measures.

(8) Acquisition and installation of technology for expedited notification of local law en</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10551_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10551_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uses of funds Grants awarded under this section shall be distributed directly to the State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe, and shall be used to improve security at schools and on school grounds in the jurisdiction of the grantee through evidence-based school safety programs that may include one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10551_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and subawards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contracts and subawards A State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe may, in using a grant under this subchapter for purposes authorized under subsection (b), use the grant to contract with or make 1 or more subawards to 1 or more—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10551_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services and benefits for schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Services and benefits for schools An entity that receives a subaward or contract under subsection (c) may use such funds to provide services or benefits described under subsection (b) to 1 or more schools.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10551_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferential consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preferential consideration In awarding grants under this subchapter, the COPS Director and the BJA Director shall give preferential consideration, if feasible, to an application from a jurisdiction that has a demonstrated need for improved security, has a demonstrated need for financial assistance, has evidenced the ability to make the improvements for which the grant amounts are sought, and will use evidence-based strategies and programs, such as those identified by the Comprehensive School Safety Initiative of the Department of Justice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10551_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Matching funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10551_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Equitable distribution In awarding grants under this subchapter, the COPS Director and the BJA shall each ensure, to the extent practicable, an equitable geographic distribution among the regions of the United States and among urban, suburban, and rural areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10551_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administrative costs The COPS Director and the BJA Director may each reserve not more than 2 percent from amounts appropriated to carry out this subchapter for administrative costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>