<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10564" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10564/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10564/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10564"><akn:num>10564</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10564. Use of grants(a) In generalA State or unit of local government that receives a grant under this subchapter shall use the grant to do any one or more of the following:(1) To carry out all or a substantial part of a program intended to improve the quality and timeliness of forensic science or medical examiner services in the State, including such services provided by the laboratories operated by the State and those operated by units of local government within the State.

(2) To eliminate a backlog in the analysis of forensic science evidence, including firearms examination, latent prints, impression evidence, toxicology, digital evidence, fire evidence, controlled substances, forensic pathology, questionable documents, and trace evidence.

(3) To train, assist, and employ forensic laboratory personnel and medicolegal death investigators, as needed, to eliminate such a backlog.

(4) To address emerging forensic science issues (such as statistics, contextual bias, and uncertainty of measurement) and emerging forensic science technology (such as high throughput automation, statistical software, and new types of instrumentation).

(5) To educate and train forensic pathologists.

(6) To fund medicolegal death investigation systems to facilitate accreditation of medical examiner and coroner offices and certification of medicolegal death investigators.


(b) Permitted categories of fundingSubject to subsections (c) and (d), a grant awarded for the purpose set forth in subsection (a)(1)—(1) may only be used for program expenses relating to facilities, personnel, computerization, equipment, supplies, accreditation and certification, education, and training; and

(2) may not be used for any general law enforcement or nonforensic investigatory function.


(c) Facilities costs(1) States receiving minimum grant amountWith respect to a State that receives a grant under this subchapter (including grants received by units of local government within a State) in an amount that</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10564_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A State or unit of local government that receives a grant under this subchapter shall use the grant to do any one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10564_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permitted categories of funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Permitted categories of funding Subject to subsections (c) and (d), a grant awarded for the purpose set forth in subsection (a)(1)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10564_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Facilities costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10564_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative costs Not more than 10 percent of the total amount of a grant awarded under this subchapter may be used for administrative expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10564_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Backlog defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Backlog defined For purposes of this section, a backlog in the analysis of forensic science evidence exists if such evidence—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>