<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10596" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10596/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10596/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10596"><akn:num>10596</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10596. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Nonviolent parent drug offenderThe term “nonviolent parent drug offender” means an offender who is—(A) pregnant or a parent of an individual under 18 years of age; and

(B) convicted of a drug (or drug-related) felony that is a nonviolent offense.


(2) Nonviolent offenseThe term “nonviolent offense” means an offense that—(A) does not have as an element the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force against the person or property of another; or

(B) is not a felony that by its nature involves a substantial risk that physical force against the person or property of another may be used in the course of committing the offense.


(3) Prison-based family treatment programThe term “prison-based family treatment program” means a program for incarcerated parents or pregnant women in a correctional facility that provides a comprehensive response to offender needs, including substance abuse treatment, child early intervention services, family counseling, legal services, medical care, mental health services, nursery and preschool, parenting skills training, pediatric care, physical therapy, prenatal care, sexual abuse therapy, relapse prevention, transportation, and vocational or GED training.


(Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 2927, as added Pub. L. 110–199, title I, § 113, Apr. 9, 2008, 122 Stat. 676; amended Pub. L. 114–198, title II, § 201(c)(2), July 22, 2016, 130 Stat. 714; Pub. L. 114–255, div. B, title XIV, § 14028(b), Dec. 13, 2016, 130 Stat. 1312.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 3797s–6 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section. Some section numbers or references in amendment notes below reflect the classification of such sections or references prior to editorial reclassification.

Amendments2016—Par. (1)(A). Pub. L. 114–198, § 201(c)(2)(A), inserted “pregnant or” before “a parent”.
Par. (2). Pub. L. 114–2</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10596_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonviolent parent drug offender</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Nonviolent parent drug offender The term “nonviolent parent drug offender” means an offender who is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10596_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonviolent offense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Nonviolent offense The term “nonviolent offense” means an offense that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10596_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prison-based family treatment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Prison-based family treatment program The term “prison-based family treatment program” means a program for incarcerated parents or pregnant women in a correctional facility that provides a comprehensive response to offender needs, including substance abuse treatment, child early intervention services, family counseling, legal services, medical care, mental health services, nursery and preschool, parenting skills training, pediatric care, physical therapy, prenatal care, sexual abuse therapy, relapse prevention, transportation, and vocational or GED training.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>