<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10643" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10643/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10643/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10643"><akn:num>10643</akn:num><akn:heading>Statewide strategic prevention plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10643. Statewide strategic prevention plan(a) In generalA statewide strategic prevention plan shall be used by the rural State to assist local communities, both directly and through existing State programs and services, in building comprehensive, strategic, and innovative approaches to reducing crime, violence, and substance abuse based on local conditions and needs.


(b) GoalsThe plan must contain statewide long-term goals and measurable annual objectives for reducing crime, violence, and substance abuse.


(c) AccountabilityThe rural State shall be required to develop and report in its plan relevant performance targets and measures for the goals and objectives to track changes in crime, violence, and substance abuse.


(d) ConsultationThe rural State shall form a State crime free communities commission that includes representatives of State and local government, and community leaders who will provide advice and recommendations on relevant community goals and objectives, and performance targets and measures.


(Pub. L. 90–351, title I, § 2987, as added Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11027(b), Nov. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 1834.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 3797y–2 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10643_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A statewide strategic prevention plan shall be used by the rural State to assist local communities, both directly and through existing State programs and services, in building comprehensive, strategic, and innovative approaches to reducing crime, violence, and substance abuse based on local conditions and needs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10643_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Goals The plan must contain statewide long-term goals and measurable annual objectives for reducing crime, violence, and substance abuse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10643_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Accountability The rural State shall be required to develop and report in its plan relevant performance targets and measures for the goals and objectives to track changes in crime, violence, and substance abuse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10643_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consultation The rural State shall form a State crime free communities commission that includes representatives of State and local government, and community leaders who will provide advice and recommendations on relevant community goals and objectives, and performance targets and measures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>