<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10651" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10651/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10651/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10651"><akn:num>10651</akn:num><akn:heading>Adult and juvenile collaboration programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10651. Adult and juvenile collaboration programs(a) DefinitionsIn this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) ApplicantThe term “applicant” means States, units of local government, Indian tribes, and tribal organizations that apply for a grant under this section.


(2) Collaboration programThe term “collaboration program” means a program to promote public safety by ensuring access to adequate mental health and other treatment services for mentally ill adults or juveniles that is overseen cooperatively by—(A) a criminal or juvenile justice agency or a mental health court; and

(B) a mental health agency.


(3) Criminal or juvenile justice agencyThe term “criminal or juvenile justice agency” means an agency of a State or local government or its contracted agency that is responsible for detection, arrest, enforcement, prosecution, defense, adjudication, incarceration, probation, or parole relating to the violation of the criminal laws of that State or local government.


(4) Diversion and alternative prosecution and sentencing(A) In generalThe terms “diversion” and “alternative prosecution and sentencing” mean the appropriate use of effective mental health treatment alternatives to juvenile justice or criminal justice system institutional placements for preliminarily qualified offenders.


(B) Appropriate useIn this paragraph, the term “appropriate use” includes the discretion of the judge or supervising authority, the leveraging of graduated sanctions to encourage compliance with treatment, and law enforcement diversion, including crisis intervention teams.


(C) Graduated sanctionsIn this paragraph, the term “graduated sanctions” means an accountability-based graduated series of sanctions (including incentives, treatments, and services) applicable to mentally ill offenders within both the juvenile and adult justice system to hold individuals accountable for their actions and to protect communities by providing appropriate sanctions for inducing law-abid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning and implementation grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Planning and implementation grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority The Attorney General, in awarding funds under this section, shall give priority to applications that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Matching requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Federal use of funds The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, in administering grants under this section, shall use not less than 6 percent of funds appropriated to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency task force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Interagency task force</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration set-aside</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Collaboration set-aside The Attorney General shall use not less than 8 percent of funds appropriated to provide technical assistance to State and local governments receiving grants under this subchapter to foster collaboration between such governments in furtherance of the purposes set forth in section 3 of the Mentally Ill Offender Treatment and Crime Reduction Act of 2004 (34 U.S.C. 10651 note).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law enforcement response to mentally ill offenders improvement grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Law enforcement response to mentally ill offenders improvement grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assisting veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Assisting veterans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10651_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forensic assertive community treatment (FACT) initiative program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Forensic assertive community treatment (FACT) initiative program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>