<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10706" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10706/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/10706/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10706"><akn:num>10706</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10706. Grant accountability(a) Definition of applicable committeesIn this section, the term “applicable committees” means—(1) the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate; and

(2) the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.


(b) AccountabilityAll grants awarded by the Attorney General under this subchapter shall be subject to the following accountability provisions:(1) Audit requirement(A) DefinitionIn this paragraph, the term “unresolved audit finding” means a finding in the final audit report of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice that the audited grantee has utilized grant funds for an unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost that is not closed or resolved within 12 months after the date on which the final audit report is issued.


(B) AuditBeginning in the first fiscal year beginning after July 22, 2016, and in each fiscal year thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct audits of recipients of grants awarded by the Attorney General under this subchapter to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of funds by grantees. The Inspector General shall determine the appropriate number of grantees to be audited each year.


(C) Mandatory exclusionA recipient of grant funds under this subchapter that is found to have an unresolved audit finding shall not be eligible to receive grant funds under this subchapter during the first 2 fiscal years beginning after the end of the 12-month period described in subparagraph (A).


(D) PriorityIn awarding grants under this subchapter, the Attorney General shall give priority to eligible applicants that did not have an unresolved audit finding during the 3 fiscal years before submitting an application for a grant under this subchapter.


(E) ReimbursementIf an entity is awarded grant funds under this subchapter during the 2-fiscal-year period during which the entity is barred from receiving grants under subparagraph (C), the Attorney General shall—(i) depos</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10706_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of applicable committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of applicable committees In this section, the term “applicable committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10706_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Accountability All grants awarded by the Attorney General under this subchapter shall be subject to the following accountability provisions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10706_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preventing duplicative grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preventing duplicative grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>