<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11114" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11114/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11114/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11114"><akn:num>11114</akn:num><akn:heading>Concentration of Federal efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11114. Concentration of Federal efforts(a) Implementation of policy by Administrator; consultation with Council and Advisory Committee(1) The Administrator shall develop objectives, priorities, and a long-term plan to improve the juvenile justice system in the United States, taking into account scientific knowledge regarding adolescent development and behavior and regarding the effects of delinquency prevention programs and juvenile justice interventions on adolescents, and shall implement overall policy and a strategy to carry out such plan, for all Federal juvenile delinquency programs and activities relating to prevention, diversion, training, treatment, rehabilitation, evaluation, and research. In carrying out the functions of the Administrator, the Administrator shall consult with the Council.

(2)(A) The plan described in paragraph (1) shall—(i) contain specific goals and criteria for making grants and contracts, for conducting research, and for carrying out other activities under this subchapter; and

(ii) provide for coordinating the administration programs and activities under this subchapter with the administration of all other Federal juvenile delinquency programs and activities, including proposals for joint funding to be coordinated by the Administrator.


(B) The Administrator shall review the plan described in paragraph (1) annually, revise the plan as the Administrator considers appropriate, and publish the plan in the Federal Register during the 30-day period ending on October 1 of each year.



(b) Duties of AdministratorIn carrying out the purposes of this chapter, the Administrator shall—(1) advise the President through the Attorney General as to all matters relating to federally assisted juvenile delinquency programs and Federal policies regarding juvenile delinquency;

(2) assist operating agencies which have direct responsibilities for the prevention and treatment of juvenile delinquency in the development and promulgation of regulations, gu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11114_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of policy by Administrator; consultation with Council and Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Implementation of policy by Administrator; consultation with Council and Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11114_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties of Administrator In carrying out the purposes of this chapter, the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11114_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information, reports, studies, and surveys from other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information, reports, studies, and surveys from other agencies The Administrator may require, through appropriate authority, Federal departments and agencies engaged in any activity involving any Federal juvenile delinquency program to provide the Administrator with such information as may be appropriate to prevent the duplication of efforts, and to coordinate activities, related to the prevention of juvenile delinquency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11114_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Delegation of functions The Administrator shall have the sole authority to delegate any of the functions of the Administrator under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11114_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of services and facilities of other agencies; reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Utilization of services and facilities of other agencies; reimbursement The Administrator is authorized to utilize the services and facilities of any agency of the Federal Government and of any other public agency or institution in accordance with appropriate agreements, and to pay for such services either in advance or by way of reimbursement as may be agreed upon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11114_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of functions of Administrator and Secretary of Health and Human Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination of functions of Administrator and Secretary of Health and Human Services All functions of the Administrator under this subchapter shall be coordinated as appropriate with the functions of the Secretary of Health and Human Services under subchapter III of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>