<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11112"><akn:num>11112</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11112. Personnel(a) Selection; employment; compensationThe Administrator is authorized to select, employ, and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, including attorneys, as are necessary to perform the functions vested in the Administrator and to prescribe their functions.


(b) Special personnelThe Administrator is authorized to select, appoint, and employ not to exceed three officers and to fix their compensation at rates not to exceed the rate now or hereafter payable under section 5376 of title 5.


(c) Personnel from other agenciesUpon the request of the Administrator, the head of any Federal agency is authorized to detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of its personnel to the Administrator to assist the Administrator in carrying out the functions of the Administrator under this subchapter.


(d) Experts and consultantsThe Administrator may obtain services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, at rates not to exceed the rate now or hereafter payable under section 5376 of title 5.


(Pub. L. 93–415, title II, § 202, Sept. 7, 1974, 88 Stat. 1113; Pub. L. 95–115, § 3(a)(3)(A), Oct. 3, 1977, 91 Stat. 1048; Pub. L. 96–509, § 19(c), Dec. 8, 1980, 94 Stat. 2763; Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 621, Oct. 12, 1984, 98 Stat. 2109; Pub. L. 102–586, § 2(b), Nov. 4, 1992, 106 Stat. 4984; Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title II, § 12221(a)(1), Nov. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 1894.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 5612 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments2002—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 107–273 substituted “payable under section 5376” for “prescribed for GS–18 of the General Schedule by section 5332”.
1992—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 102–586, § 2(b)(1), which directed the substitution of “payable under section 5376” for “prescribes for GS–18 of the General Schedule by section 5332”, could not be executed because the phrase “prescribes for GS–18 of the General Sc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection; employment; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Selection; employment; compensation The Administrator is authorized to select, employ, and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, including attorneys, as are necessary to perform the functions vested in the Administrator and to prescribe their functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special personnel The Administrator is authorized to select, appoint, and employ not to exceed three officers and to fix their compensation at rates not to exceed the rate now or hereafter payable under section 5376 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel from other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Personnel from other agencies Upon the request of the Administrator, the head of any Federal agency is authorized to detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of its personnel to the Administrator to assist the Administrator in carrying out the functions of the Administrator under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11112_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Experts and consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Experts and consultants The Administrator may obtain services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, at rates not to exceed the rate now or hereafter payable under section 5376 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>