<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11133" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11133/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11133/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11133"><akn:num>11133</akn:num><akn:heading>State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11133. State plans(a) RequirementsIn order to receive formula grants under this part, a State shall submit a plan for carrying out its purposes applicable to a 3-year period. Such plan shall be amended annually to include new programs, projects, and activities. The State shall submit annual performance reports to the Administrator which shall describe progress in implementing programs contained in the original plan, and shall describe how the State plan is supported by or takes account of scientific knowledge regarding adolescent development and behavior and regarding the effects of delinquency prevention programs and juvenile justice interventions on adolescents. Not later than 60 days after the date on which a plan or amended plan submitted under this subsection is finalized, a State shall make the plan or amended plan publicly available by posting the plan or amended plan on the State’s publicly available website. In accordance with regulations which the Administrator shall prescribe, such plan shall—(1) designate the State agency as designated by the chief executive officer of the State as the sole agency for supervising the preparation and administration of the plan;

(2) contain satisfactory evidence that the State agency designated in accordance with paragraph (1) has or will have authority, by legislation if necessary, to implement such plan in conformity with this part;

(3) provide for an advisory group that—(A) shall consist of not less than 15 and not more than 33 members appointed by the chief executive officer of the State—(i) which members have training, experience, or special knowledge concerning adolescent development, the prevention and treatment of juvenile delinquency, the administration of juvenile justice, or the reduction of juvenile delinquency;

(ii) which members include—(I) at least 1 locally elected official representing general purpose local government;

(II) representatives of law enforcement and juvenile justice agencies, including j</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11133_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements In order to receive formula grants under this part, a State shall submit a plan for carrying out its purposes applicable to a 3-year period. Such plan shall be amended annually to include new programs, projects, and activities. The State shall submit annual performance reports to the Administrator which shall describe progress in implementing programs contained in the original plan, and shall describe how the State plan is supported by or takes account of scientific knowledge regarding adolescent development and behavior and regarding the effects of delinquency prevention programs and juvenile justice interventions on adolescents. Not later than 60 days after the date on which a plan or amended plan submitted under this subsection is finalized, a State shall make the plan or amended plan publicly available by posting the plan or amended plan on the State’s publicly available website. In accordance with regulations which the Administrator shall prescribe, such plan shal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11133_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval by State agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Approval by State agency The State agency designated under subsection (a)(1), after receiving and considering the advice and recommendations of the advisory group referred to in subsection (a), shall approve the State plan and any modification thereof prior to submission to the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11133_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with statutory requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compliance with statutory requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11133_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonsubmission or nonqualification of plan; expenditure of allotted funds; availability of reallocated funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nonsubmission or nonqualification of plan; expenditure of allotted funds; availability of reallocated funds In the event that any State chooses not to submit a plan, fails to submit a plan, or submits a plan or any modification thereof, which the Administrator, after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing, in accordance with sections 10222 and 10223 of this title and 3785 of title 42 33 See References in Text note below., determines does not meet the requirements of this section, the Administrator shall endeavor to make that State’s allocation under the provisions of section 11132(a) of this title, excluding funds the Administrator shall make available to satisfy the requirement specified in section 11132(d) of this title, available to local public and private nonprofit agencies within such State for use in carrying out activities of the kinds described in the core requirements. The Administrator shall make funds which remain available after disbursements are made by the Adm</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11133_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative and supervisory board membership requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administrative and supervisory board membership requirements Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator shall establish appropriate administrative and supervisory board membership requirements for a State agency designated under subsection (a)(1) and permit the State advisory group appointed under subsection (a)(3) to operate as the supervisory board for such agency, at the discretion of the chief executive officer of the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11133_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Technical assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11133_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compliance determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>