<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11261" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11261/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11261/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11261"><akn:num>11261</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to make grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11261. Authority to make grants(a) In generalThe Secretary may make grants to nonprofit private agencies for the purpose of providing street-based services to runaway and homeless, and street youth, who have been subjected to, or are at risk of being subjected to, sexual abuse, prostitution, sexual exploitation, severe forms of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 7102(9) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 22), or sex trafficking (as defined in section 7102(10) 1 of title 22).


(b) PriorityIn selecting applicants to receive grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to public and nonprofit private agencies that have experience in providing services to runaway and homeless, and street youth.


(Pub. L. 93–415, title III, § 351, as added Pub. L. 106–71, § 3(n)(1)(C), Oct. 12, 1999, 113 Stat. 1040; amended Pub. L. 110–378, § 7, Oct. 8, 2008, 122 Stat. 4071; Pub. L. 114–22, title II, § 201(2), May 29, 2015, 129 Stat. 248.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 7102(9) and (10) of title 22, referred to in subsec. (a), was redesignated section 7102(11) and (12), respectively, of title 22 by Pub. L. 115–427, § 2(1), Jan. 9, 2019, 132 Stat. 5503.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 5714–41 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

AmendmentsSubsec. (a). Pub. L. 114–22 substituted “sexual exploitation, severe forms of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 7102(9) of title 22), or sex trafficking (as defined in section 7102(10) of title 22)” for “or sexual exploitation”.
2008—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 110–378 inserted “public and” after “priority to”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11261_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may make grants to nonprofit private agencies for the purpose of providing street-based services to runaway and homeless, and street youth, who have been subjected to, or are at risk of being subjected to, sexual abuse, prostitution, sexual exploitation, severe forms of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 7102(9) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 22), or sex trafficking (as defined in section 7102(10) 1 of title 22).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11261_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority In selecting applicants to receive grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to public and nonprofit private agencies that have experience in providing services to runaway and homeless, and street youth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>