<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11279" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11279/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11279/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11279"><akn:num>11279</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11279. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Drug abuse education and prevention servicesThe term “drug abuse education and prevention services”—(A) means services to runaway and homeless youth to prevent or reduce the illicit use of drugs by such youth; and

(B) may include—(i) individual, family, group, and peer counseling;

(ii) drop-in services;

(iii) assistance to runaway and homeless youth in rural areas (including the development of community support groups);

(iv) information and training relating to the illicit use of drugs by runaway and homeless youth, to individuals involved in providing services to such youth; and

(v) activities to improve the availability of local drug abuse prevention services to runaway and homeless youth.



(2) Home-based servicesThe term “home-based services”—(A) means services provided to youth and their families for the purpose of—(i) preventing such youth from running away, or otherwise becoming separated, from their families; and

(ii) assisting runaway youth to return to their families; and


(B) includes services that are provided in the residences of families (to the extent practicable), including—(i) intensive individual and family counseling; and

(ii) training relating to life skills and parenting.



(3) Homeless youthThe term “homeless”, used with respect to a youth, means an individual—(A) who is—(i) less than 21 years of age, or, in the case of a youth seeking shelter in a center under part A, less than 18 years of age, or is less than a higher maximum age if the State where the center is located has an applicable State or local law (including a regulation) that permits such higher maximum age in compliance with licensure requirements for child-and youth-serving 11 So in original. facilities; and

(ii) for the purposes of part B, not less than 16 years of age and either—(I) less than 22 years of age; or

(II) not less than 22 years of age, as of the expiration of the maximum period of stay permitted under section 11</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11279_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug abuse education and prevention services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Drug abuse education and prevention services The term “drug abuse education and prevention services”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11279_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Home-based services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Home-based services The term “home-based services”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11279_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Homeless youth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Homeless youth The term “homeless”, used with respect to a youth, means an individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11279_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Runaway youth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Runaway youth The term “runaway”, used with respect to a youth, means an individual who is less than 18 years of age and who absents himself or herself from home or a place of legal residence without the permission of a parent or legal guardian.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11279_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Street-based services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Street-based services The term “street-based services”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11279_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Street youth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Street youth The term “street youth” means an individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11279_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transitional living youth project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Transitional living youth project The term “transitional living youth project” means a project that provides shelter and services designed to promote a transition to self-sufficient living and to prevent long-term dependency on social services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11279_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Youth at risk of separation from the family</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Youth at risk of separation from the family The term “youth at risk of separation from the family” means an individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>