<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11296" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11296/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11296/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11296"><akn:num>11296</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight and accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11296. Oversight and accountability
All grants awarded by the Department of Justice that are authorized under this subchapter shall be subject to the following:(1) Audit requirementFor 2 of the fiscal years in the period of fiscal years 2014 through 2023, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct audits of the recipient of grants under this subchapter to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse by the grantee.


(2) Mandatory exclusionIf the recipient of grant funds under this subchapter is found to have an unresolved audit finding, then that entity shall not be eligible to receive grant funds under this subchapter during the 2 fiscal years beginning after the 12-month period described in paragraph (4).


(3) Repayment of grant fundsIf an entity is awarded grant funds under this subchapter during the 2-fiscal-year period in which the entity is barred from receiving grants under paragraph (2), the Attorney General shall—(A) deposit an amount equal to the grant funds that were improperly awarded to the grantee into the General Fund of the Treasury; and

(B) seek to recoup the costs of the repayment to the fund from the grant recipient that was erroneously awarded grant funds.


(4) Defined termIn this section, the term “unresolved audit finding” means an audit report finding in the final report of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice that the grantee has utilized grant funds for an unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost that is not closed or resolved within a 12-month period beginning on the date when the final audit report is issued.


(5) Nonprofit organization requirements(A) DefinitionFor purposes of this section and the grant programs described in this subchapter, the term “nonprofit”, relating to an entity, means the entity is described in section 501(c)(3) of title 26 and is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such title.


(B) ProhibitionThe Attorney General shall not award a grant under any grant program </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11296_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Audit requirement For 2 of the fiscal years in the period of fiscal years 2014 through 2023, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct audits of the recipient of grants under this subchapter to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse by the grantee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11296_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Mandatory exclusion If the recipient of grant funds under this subchapter is found to have an unresolved audit finding, then that entity shall not be eligible to receive grant funds under this subchapter during the 2 fiscal years beginning after the 12-month period described in paragraph (4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11296_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Repayment of grant funds If an entity is awarded grant funds under this subchapter during the 2-fiscal-year period in which the entity is barred from receiving grants under paragraph (2), the Attorney General shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11296_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defined term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Defined term In this section, the term “unresolved audit finding” means an audit report finding in the final report of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice that the grantee has utilized grant funds for an unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost that is not closed or resolved within a 12-month period beginning on the date when the final audit report is issued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11296_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonprofit organization requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Nonprofit organization requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11296_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conference expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Conference expenditures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11296_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on lobbying activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Prohibition on lobbying activity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>