<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11313"><akn:num>11313</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for local delinquency prevention programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11313. Grants for local delinquency prevention programs(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to enable local communities to address the unmet needs of at-risk or delinquent youth, including through a continuum of delinquency prevention programs for juveniles who have had contact with the juvenile justice system or who are likely to have contact with the juvenile justice system.


(b) Program authorizedThe Administrator shall—(1) for each fiscal year for which less than $25,000,000 is appropriated under section 506,11 See References in Text note below. award grants to not fewer than 3 State entities, but not more than 5 State entities, that apply under subsection (c) and meet the requirements of subsection (d); or

(2) for each fiscal year for which $25,000,000 or more is appropriated under section 506,1 award grants to not fewer than 5 State entities that apply under subsection (c) and meet the requirements of subsection (d).


(c) State applicationTo be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State entity shall submit an application to the Administrator that includes the following:(1) An assurance the State entity will use—(A) not more than 10 percent of such grant, in the aggregate—(i) for the costs incurred by the State entity to carry out this section, except that not more than 3 percent of such grant may be used for such costs; and

(ii) to provide technical assistance to eligible entities receiving a subgrant under subsection (e) in carrying out delinquency prevention programs under the subgrant; and


(B) the remainder of such grant to award subgrants to eligible entities under subsection (e).


(2) An assurance that such grant will supplement, and not supplant, State and local efforts to prevent juvenile delinquency.

(3) An assurance the State entity will evaluate the capacity of eligible entities receiving a subgrant under subsection (e) to fulfill the requirements under such subsection.

(4) An assurance that such application was prepared </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to enable local communities to address the unmet needs of at-risk or delinquent youth, including through a continuum of delinquency prevention programs for juveniles who have had contact with the juvenile justice system or who are likely to have contact with the juvenile justice system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program authorized The Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State application To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State entity shall submit an application to the Administrator that includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of State applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Approval of State applications In awarding grants under this section for a fiscal year, the Administrator may not award a grant to a State entity for a fiscal year unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11313_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subgrant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>