<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/11322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11322"><akn:num>11322</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability and oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11322. Accountability and oversight(a) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that, in order to ensure that at-risk youth, and youth who come into contact with the juvenile justice system or the criminal justice system, are treated fairly and that the outcome of that contact is beneficial to the Nation—(1) the Department of Justice, through its Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention, must restore meaningful enforcement of the core requirements in subchapter II; and

(2) States, which are entrusted with a fiscal stewardship role if they accept funds under subchapter II 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. must exercise vigilant oversight to ensure full compliance with the core requirements for juveniles provided for in subchapter II.


(b) Accountability(1) Agency program review(A) Programmatic and financial assessment(i) In generalNot later than 60 days after December 21, 2018, the Director of the Office of Audit, Assessment, and Management of the Office of Justice Programs at the Department of Justice (referred to in this section as the “Director”) shall—(I) conduct a comprehensive analysis and evaluation of the internal controls of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention (referred to in this section as the “agency”) to determine if States and Indian Tribes receiving grants are following the requirements of the agency grant programs and what remedial action the agency has taken to recover any grant funds that are expended in violation of grant programs, including instances where—(aa) supporting documentation was not provided for cost reports;

(bb) unauthorized expenditures occurred; and

(cc) subrecipients of grant funds were not in compliance with program requirements;


(II) conduct a comprehensive audit and evaluation of a selected statistically significant sample of States and Indian Tribes (as determined by the Director) that have received Federal funds under subchapter II, including a review of i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that, in order to ensure that at-risk youth, and youth who come into contact with the juvenile justice system or the criminal justice system, are treated fairly and that the outcome of that contact is beneficial to the Nation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Accountability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preventing duplicative grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preventing duplicative grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11322_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with auditing standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compliance with auditing standards The Administrator shall comply with the Generally Accepted Government Auditing Standards, published by the General Accountability Office (commonly known as the “Yellow Book”), in the conduct of fiscal, compliance, and programmatic audits of States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>