<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12102"><akn:num>12102</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12102. Authorization of grants(a) In generalThe Attorney General shall provide Violent Offender Incarceration grants under section 12103 of this title and Truth-in-Sentencing Incentive grants under section 12104 of this title to eligible States—(1) to build or expand correctional facilities to increase the bed capacity for the confinement of persons convicted of a part 1 violent crime or adjudicated delinquent for an act which if committed by an adult, would be a part 1 violent crime;

(2) to build or expand temporary or permanent correctional facilities, including facilities on military bases, prison barges, and boot camps, for the confinement of convicted nonviolent offenders and criminal aliens, for the purpose of freeing suitable existing prison space for the confinement of persons convicted of a part 1 violent crime;

(3) to build or expand jails; and

(4) to carry out any activity referred to in section 10631(b) of this title.


(b) Regional compacts(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), States may enter into regional compacts to carry out this part. Such compacts shall be treated as States under this part.


(2) RequirementTo be recognized as a regional compact for eligibility for a grant under section 12103 or 12104 of this title, each member State must be eligible individually.


(3) Limitation on receipt of fundsNo State may receive a grant under this part both individually and as part of a compact.



(c) ApplicabilityNotwithstanding the eligibility requirements of section 12104 of this title, a State that certifies to the Attorney General that, as of April 26, 1996, such State has enacted legislation in reliance on this part, as enacted on September 13, 1994, and would in fact qualify under those provisions, shall be eligible to receive a grant for fiscal year 1996 as though such State qualifies under section 12104 of this title.


(Pub. L. 103–322, title II, § 20102, as added Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101[(a)] [title I, § 114(a)], Apr. 26, 1996, 11</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Attorney General shall provide Violent Offender Incarceration grants under section 12103 of this title and Truth-in-Sentencing Incentive grants under section 12104 of this title to eligible States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional compacts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regional compacts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicability Notwithstanding the eligibility requirements of section 12104 of this title, a State that certifies to the Attorney General that, as of April 26, 1996, such State has enacted legislation in reliance on this part, as enacted on September 13, 1994, and would in fact qualify under those provisions, shall be eligible to receive a grant for fiscal year 1996 as though such State qualifies under section 12104 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>