<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12113"><akn:num>12113</akn:num><akn:heading>Aimee’s Law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12113. Aimee’s Law(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as “Aimee’s Law”.


(b) DefinitionsPursuant to regulations promulgated by the Attorney General hereunder, in this section:(1) Dangerous sexual offenseThe term “dangerous sexual offense” means any offense under State law for conduct that would constitute an offense under chapter 109A of title 18 had the conduct occurred in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States or in a Federal prison.


(2) MurderThe term “murder” has the meaning given the term in part I of the Uniform Crime Reports of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.


(3) RapeThe term “rape” has the meaning given the term in part I of the Uniform Crime Reports of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.



(c) Penalty(1) Single StatePursuant to regulations promulgated by the Attorney General hereunder, in any case in which a criminal-records-reporting State convicts an individual of murder, rape, or a dangerous sexual offense, who has a prior conviction for any one of those offenses in a State described in paragraph (3), it may, under subsection (d), apply to the Attorney General for $10,000, for its related apprehension and prosecution costs, and $22,500 per year (up to a maximum of 5 years), for its related incarceration costs with both amounts for costs adjusted annually for the rate of inflation.


(2) Multiple StatesPursuant to regulations promulgated by the Attorney General hereunder, in any case in which a criminal-records-reporting State convicts an individual of murder, rape, or a dangerous sexual offense, who has a prior conviction for any one or more of those offenses in more than one other State described in paragraph (3), it may, under subsection (d), apply to the Attorney General for $10,000, for its related apprehension and prosecution costs, and $22,500 per year (up to a maximum of 5 years), for its related incarceration costs with both amounts for costs adjusted annually for the rate of inflation.


(3) Sta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as “Aimee’s Law”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions Pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Attorney General hereunder, in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State applications In order to receive an amount under subsection (c), the chief executive of a State shall submit to the Attorney General an application, in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require, which shall include a certification that the State has convicted an individual of murder, rape, or a dangerous sexual offense, who has a prior conviction for one of those offenses in another State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Source of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Construction Nothing in this section may be construed to diminish or otherwise affect any court ordered restitution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exception Pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Attorney General hereunder, this section does not apply if the individual convicted of murder, rape, or a dangerous sexual offense has been released from prison upon the reversal of a conviction for an offense described in subsection (c) and subsequently been convicted for an offense described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report The Attorney General shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of recidivism data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Collection of recidivism data</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Effective date This section shall take effect on January 1, 2002.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>