<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12171" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12171/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12171/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12171"><akn:num>12171</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12171. Grant authority(a) Grants(1) In generalThe Attorney General may make grants to qualified community organizations to assist in meeting the costs of qualified programs which are designed to recruit and retain applicants to police departments.


(2) Consultation with the Ounce of Prevention CouncilThe Attorney General may consult with the Ounce of Prevention Council in making grants under paragraph (1).



(b) Qualified community organizationsAn organization is a qualified community organization which is eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a) if the organization—(1) is a nonprofit organization; and

(2) has training and experience in—(A) working with a police department and with teachers, counselors, and similar personnel,

(B) providing services to the community in which the organization is located,

(C) developing and managing services and techniques to recruit individuals to become members of a police department and to assist such individuals in meeting the membership requirements of police departments,

(D) developing and managing services and techniques to assist in the retention of applicants to police departments, and

(E) developing other programs that contribute to the community.



(c) Qualified programsA program is a qualified program for which a grant may be made under subsection (a) if the program is designed to recruit and train individuals from underrepresented neighborhoods and localities and if—(1) the overall design of the program is to recruit and retain applicants to a police department;

(2) the program provides recruiting services which include tutorial programs to enable individuals to meet police force academic requirements and to pass entrance examinations;

(3) the program provides counseling to applicants to police departments who may encounter problems throughout the application process; and

(4) the program provides retention services to assist in retaining individuals to stay in the application process of a police depart</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12171_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12171_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified community organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified community organizations An organization is a qualified community organization which is eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a) if the organization—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12171_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualified programs A program is a qualified program for which a grant may be made under subsection (a) if the program is designed to recruit and train individuals from underrepresented neighborhoods and localities and if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12171_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applications To qualify for a grant under subsection (a), a qualified organization shall submit an application to the Attorney General in such form as the Attorney General may prescribe. Such application shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12171_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Action by Attorney General Not later than 60 days after the date that an application for a grant under subsection (a) is received, the Attorney General shall consult with the police department which will be involved with the applicant and shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12171_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant disbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grant disbursement The Attorney General shall disburse funds under a grant under subsection (a) in accordance with regulations of the Attorney General which shall ensure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12171_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Grant period A grant under subsection (a) shall be made for a period not longer than 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12171_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grantee reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Grantee reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12171_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Guidelines The Attorney General shall, by regulation, prescribe guidelines on content and results for programs receiving a grant under subsection (a). Such guidelines shall be designed to establish programs which will be effective in training individuals to enter instructional programs for police departments and shall include requirements for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>