<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12291" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12291/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12291/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12291"><akn:num>12291</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and grant provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12291. Definitions and grant provisions(a) DefinitionsIn this subchapter, for the purpose of grants authorized under this subchapter:(1) Abuse in later lifeThe term “abuse in later life”—(A) means—(i) neglect, abandonment, economic abuse, or willful harm of an adult aged 50 or older by an individual in an ongoing relationship of trust with the victim; or

(ii) domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking of an adult aged 50 or older by any individual; and


(B) does not include self-neglect.


(2) Alaska Native villageThe term “Alaska Native village” has the same meaning given such term in the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.).


(3) Child abuse and neglectThe term “child abuse and neglect” means any recent act or failure to act on the part of a parent or caregiver with intent to cause death, serious physical or emotional harm, sexual abuse, or exploitation, or an act or failure to act which presents an imminent risk of serious harm to an unemancipated minor. This definition shall not be construed to mean that failure to leave an abusive relationship, in the absence of other action constituting abuse or neglect, is itself abuse or neglect.


(4) Child maltreatmentThe term “child maltreatment” means the physical or psychological abuse or neglect of a child or youth, including sexual assault and abuse.


(5) Community-based organizationThe term “community-based organization” means a nonprofit, nongovernmental, or tribal organization that serves a specific geographic community that—(A) focuses primarily on domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking;

(B) has established a specialized culturally specific program that addresses domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking;

(C) has a primary focus on underserved populations (and includes representatives of these populations) and domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking; or

(D) obtains expertise, or shows demons</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12291_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this subchapter, for the purpose of grants authorized under this subchapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12291_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>