<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12311"><akn:num>12311</akn:num><akn:heading>Training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12311. Training programs(a) In generalThe Attorney General, after consultation with victim advocates and individuals who have expertise in treating sex offenders, shall establish criteria and develop training programs to assist probation and parole officers and other personnel who work with released sex offenders in the areas of—(1) case management;

(2) supervision; and

(3) relapse prevention.


(b) Training programsThe Attorney General shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that training programs developed under subsection (a) are available in geographically diverse locations throughout the country.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.


(Pub. L. 103–322, title IV, § 40152, Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 1920; Pub. L. 109–162, title I, § 108, title XI, § 1167, Jan. 5, 2006, 119 Stat. 2984, 3121; Pub. L. 109–271, § 2(a), (b), Aug. 12, 2006, 120 Stat. 751, 752; Pub. L. 113–4, title I, § 105, Mar. 7, 2013, 127 Stat. 77; Pub. L. 117–103, div. W, title XIII, § 1304, Mar. 15, 2022, 136 Stat. 927.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 13941 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments2022—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 117–103 amended subsec. (c) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2018.”
2013—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 113–4 substituted “$5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2018.” for “$5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2011.”
2006—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 109–271, § 2(b), which directed amendment of section 1167 of the Violence Against Women Act of 2005, Pub. L. 109–162, by substituting “2007 through 2011” for “2006 through 2010”, was executed to subsec. (c) of this section, which is section 40152 of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Attorney General, after consultation with victim advocates and individuals who have expertise in treating sex offenders, shall establish criteria and develop training programs to assist probation and parole officers and other personnel who work with released sex offenders in the areas of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Training programs The Attorney General shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that training programs developed under subsection (a) are available in geographically diverse locations throughout the country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>