<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12463" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12463/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12463/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12463"><akn:num>12463</akn:num><akn:heading>Saving money and reducing tragedies through prevention (SMART Prevention)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12463. Saving money and reducing tragedies through prevention (SMART Prevention)(a) Grants authorizedThe Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Education, is authorized to award grants for the purpose of preventing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking by focusing on men and youth as leaders and influencers of social norms.


(b) Use of fundsFunds provided under this section may be used to develop, maintain or enhance programs that work with men and youth to prevent domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking by helping men and youth to serve as role models and social influencers of other men and youth at the individual, school, community or statewide levels.


(c) Eligible entitiesTo be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be—(1) a victim service provider, community-based organization, tribe or tribal organization, or other non-profit, nongovernmental organization that has a history of effective work preventing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking and expertise in the specific area for which they are applying for funds; or

(2) a partnership between a victim service provider, community-based organization, tribe or tribal organization, or other non-profit, nongovernmental organization that has a history of effective work preventing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking and at least one of the following that has expertise in serving children exposed to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, youth domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking prevention, or engaging men to prevent domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking:(A) A public, charter, tribal, or nationally accredited private middle or high school, a school administered by the Department of Defense under section 2164 of title 10 or section 921 of title 2</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12463_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Education, is authorized to award grants for the purpose of preventing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking by focusing on men and youth as leaders and influencers of social norms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12463_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds Funds provided under this section may be used to develop, maintain or enhance programs that work with men and youth to prevent domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking by helping men and youth to serve as role models and social influencers of other men and youth at the individual, school, community or statewide levels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12463_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible entities To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12463_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grantee requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grantee requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12463_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and grant conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions and grant conditions In this section, the definitions and grant conditions provided for in section 12291 of this title shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12463_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027. Amounts appropriated under this section may only be used for programs and activities described under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>