<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12475" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12475/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12475/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12475"><akn:num>12475</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to combat violence against women in public and assisted housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12475. Grants to combat violence against women in public and assisted housing(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section to assist eligible grantees in responding appropriately to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking so that the status of being a victim of such a crime is not a reason for the denial or loss of housing. Such assistance shall be accomplished through—(1) education and training of eligible entities;

(2) development and implementation of appropriate housing policies and practices;

(3) enhancement of collaboration with victim service providers and tenant organizations; and

(4) reduction of the number of victims of such crimes who are evicted or denied housing because of crimes and lease violations committed or directly caused by the perpetrators of such crimes.


(b) Grants authorized(1) In generalThe Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women of the Department of Justice (“Director”), and in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (“Secretary”), and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administration for Children, Youth and Families (“ACYF”), shall award grants and contracts for not less than 2 years to eligible grantees to promote the full and equal access to and use of housing by adult and youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.


(2) AmountsNot less than 15 percent of the funds appropriated to carry out this section shall be available for grants to tribally designated housing entities.


(3) Award basisThe Attorney General shall award grants and contracts under this section on a competitive basis.


(4) LimitationAppropriated funds may only be used for the purposes described in subsection (f).



(c) Eligible grantees(1) In generalEligible grantees are—(A) public housing agencies;

(B) principally managed public housing resident management corporations, as determined by the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12475_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this section to assist eligible grantees in responding appropriately to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking so that the status of being a victim of such a crime is not a reason for the denial or loss of housing. Such assistance shall be accomplished through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12475_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12475_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible grantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible grantees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12475_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application Each eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such a time, in such a manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12475_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12475_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of funds Grants and contracts awarded pursuant to subsection (a) shall provide to eligible entities personnel, training, and technical assistance to develop and implement policies, practices, and procedures, making physical improvements or changes, and developing or enhancing collaborations for the purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12475_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12475_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Technical assistance Up to 12 percent of the amount appropriated under subsection (g) for each fiscal year shall be used by the Attorney General for technical assistance costs under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>