<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12474" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12474/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12474/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12474"><akn:num>12474</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaborative grants to increase the long-term stability of victims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12474. Collaborative grants to increase the long-term stability of victims(a) Grants authorized(1) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administration for Children and Families, in partnership with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements for a period of not less than 2 years to eligible entities to develop long-term sustainability and self-sufficiency options for adult and youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who are currently homeless or at risk for becoming homeless.


(2) AmountThe Secretary of Health and Human Services shall award funds in amounts—(A) not less than $25,000 per year; and

(B) not more than $1,000,000 per year.



(b) Eligible entitiesTo be eligible to receive funds under this section, an entity shall demonstrate that it is a coalition or partnership, applying jointly, that—(1) shall include a domestic violence victim service provider;

(2) shall include—(A) a homeless service provider;

(B) a nonprofit, nongovernmental community housing development organization or a Department of Agriculture rural housing service program; or

(C) in the absence of a homeless service provider on tribal lands or nonprofit, nongovernmental community housing development organization on tribal lands, a tribally designated housing entity or tribal housing consortium;


(3) may include a dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking victim service provider;

(4) may include housing developers, housing corporations, State housing finance agencies, other housing agencies, and associations representing landlords;

(5) may include a public housing agency or tribally designated housing entity;

(6) may include tenant organizations in public or tribally designated housing, as well as nonprofit, nongovernmental tenant organizations;

(7) may include other nonprofit, nongovernmental organizations participating in the Department of Ho</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12474_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12474_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entities To be eligible to receive funds under this section, an entity shall demonstrate that it is a coalition or partnership, applying jointly, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12474_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application Each eligible entity seeking funds under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary of Health and Human Services at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary of Health and Human Services may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12474_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds Funds awarded to eligible entities under subsection (a) shall be used to design or replicate and implement new activities, services, and programs to increase the stability and self-sufficiency of, and create partnerships to develop long-term housing options for adult and youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, and their dependents, who are currently homeless or at risk of becoming homeless. Such activities, services, or programs—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12474_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation Funds provided under paragraph 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (a) shall not be used for construction, modernization or renovation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12474_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Underserved populations and priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Underserved populations and priorities In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12474_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12474_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation, monitoring, administration, and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Evaluation, monitoring, administration, and technical assistance For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12474_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated $4,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>