<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12501"><akn:num>12501</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant for national resource center on workplace responses to assist victims of domestic and sexual v</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12501. Grant for national resource center on workplace responses to assist victims of domestic and sexual violence(a) AuthorityThe Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women, may award a grant to an eligible nonprofit nongovernmental entity or tribal organization, in order to provide for the establishment and operation of a national resource center on workplace responses to assist victims of domestic and sexual violence and sexual harassment. The resource center shall provide information and assistance to employers, labor organizations, and victim service providers to aid in their efforts to develop and implement responses to such violence.


(b) ApplicationsTo be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity or organization shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require, including—(1) information that demonstrates that the entity or organization has nationally recognized expertise in the area of domestic or sexual violence;

(2) a plan to maximize, to the extent practicable, outreach to employers (including private companies, public entities such as public institutions of higher education and State and local governments, and employers with fewer than 20 employees) and labor organizations described in subsection (a) concerning developing and implementing workplace responses to assist victims of domestic or sexual violence; and

(3) a plan for developing materials and training for materials for employers that address the needs of employees in cases of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, stalking, and sexual harassment impacting the workplace, including the needs of underserved communities, which materials shall include a website with resources for employers with fewer than 20 employees, including live training materials.


(c) Use of grant amount(1) In generalAn entity or organization that rece</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women, may award a grant to an eligible nonprofit nongovernmental entity or tribal organization, in order to provide for the establishment and operation of a national resource center on workplace responses to assist victims of domestic and sexual violence and sexual harassment. The resource center shall provide information and assistance to employers, labor organizations, and victim service providers to aid in their efforts to develop and implement responses to such violence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity or organization shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12501_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of grant amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12501_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Liability The compliance or noncompliance of any employer or labor organization with any protocol or policy developed by an entity or organization under this section shall not serve as a basis for liability in tort, express or implied contract, or by any other means. No protocol or policy developed by an entity or organization under this section shall be referenced or enforced as a workplace safety standard by any Federal, State, or other governmental agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12501_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pathways to Opportunity Pilot Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Pathways to Opportunity Pilot Project An eligible nonprofit nongovernmental entity or tribal organization that receives a grant under this section may develop a plan to enhance the capacity of survivors to obtain and maintain employment, including through the implementation of a demonstration pilot program to be known as “Pathways to Opportunity”, which shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12501_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12501_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Availability of grant funds Funds appropriated under this section shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>