<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12523" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12523/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12523/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12523"><akn:num>12523</akn:num><akn:heading>Violent crime and drug emergency areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12523. Violent crime and drug emergency areas(a) DefinitionsIn this section—
“major violent crime or drug-related emergency” means an occasion or instance in which violent crime, drug smuggling, drug trafficking, or drug abuse violence reaches such levels, as determined by the President, that Federal assistance is needed to supplement State and local efforts and capabilities to save lives, and to protect property and public health and safety.
“State” means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands.


(b) Declaration of violent crime and drug emergency areasIf a major violent crime or drug-related emergency exists throughout a State or a part of a State, the President may declare the State or part of a State to be a violent crime or drug emergency area and may take appropriate actions authorized by this section.


(c) Procedure(1) In generalA request for a declaration designating an area to be a violent crime or drug emergency area shall be made, in writing, by the chief executive officer of a State or local government, respectively (or in the case of the District of Columbia, the mayor), and shall be forwarded to the Attorney General in such form as the Attorney General may by regulation require. One or more cities, counties, States, or the District of Columbia may submit a joint request for designation as a major violent crime or drug emergency area under this subsection.


(2) FindingA request made under paragraph (1) shall be based on a written finding that the major violent crime or drug-related emergency is of such severity and magnitude that Federal assistance is necessary to ensure an effective response to save lives and to protect property and public health and safety.



(d) Irrelevancy of population densityThe President shall not limit declarations made under this section to highly populated centers of violent crime or drug trafficking, drug</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—
“major violent crime or drug-related emergency” means an occasion or instance in which violent crime, drug smuggling, drug trafficking, or drug abuse violence reaches such levels, as determined by the President, that Federal assistance is needed to supplement State and local efforts and capabilities to save lives, and to protect property and public health and safety.
“State” means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of violent crime and drug emergency areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Declaration of violent crime and drug emergency areas If a major violent crime or drug-related emergency exists throughout a State or a part of a State, the President may declare the State or part of a State to be a violent crime or drug emergency area and may take appropriate actions authorized by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Irrelevancy of population density</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Irrelevancy of population density The President shall not limit declarations made under this section to highly populated centers of violent crime or drug trafficking, drug smuggling, or drug use, but shall also consider applications from governments of less populated areas where the magnitude and severity of such activities is beyond the capability of the State or local government to respond.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirements As part of a request for a declaration under this section, and as a prerequisite to Federal violent crime or drug emergency assistance under this section, the chief executive officer of a State or local government shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Review period The Attorney General shall review a request submitted pursuant to this section, and the President shall decide whether to declare a violent crime or drug emergency area, within 30 days after receiving the request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Federal assistance The President may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Duration of Federal assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations Not later than 120 days after September 13, 1994, the Attorney General shall issue regulations to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12523_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>No effect on existing authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) No effect on existing authority Nothing in this section shall diminish or detract from existing authority possessed by the President or Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>