<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12532" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12532/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12532/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12532"><akn:num>12532</akn:num><akn:heading>Gang investigation coordination and information collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12532. Gang investigation coordination and information collection(a) CoordinationThe Attorney General (or the Attorney General’s designee), in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s designee), shall develop a national strategy to coordinate gang-related investigations by Federal law enforcement agencies.


(b) Data collectionThe Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall acquire and collect information on incidents of gang violence for inclusion in an annual uniform crime report.


(c) ReportThe Attorney General shall prepare a report on national gang violence outlining the strategy developed under subsection (a) to be submitted to the President and Congress by January 1, 1996.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,000,000 for fiscal year 1996.


(Pub. L. 103–322, title XV, § 150008, Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2036.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 14062 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12532_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Coordination The Attorney General (or the Attorney General’s designee), in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s designee), shall develop a national strategy to coordinate gang-related investigations by Federal law enforcement agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12532_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Data collection The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall acquire and collect information on incidents of gang violence for inclusion in an annual uniform crime report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12532_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report The Attorney General shall prepare a report on national gang violence outlining the strategy developed under subsection (a) to be submitted to the President and Congress by January 1, 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12532_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,000,000 for fiscal year 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>