<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12556" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12556/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12556/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12556"><akn:num>12556</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12556. Selection of participants(a) In generalParticipants in State Police Corps programs shall be selected on a competitive basis by each State under regulations prescribed by the Director.


(b) Selection criteria and qualifications(1) In order to participate in a State Police Corps program, a participant shall—(A) be a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States;

(B) meet the requirements for admission as a trainee of the State or local police force to which the participant will be assigned pursuant to section 12559(5) of this title, including achievement of satisfactory scores on any applicable examination, except that failure to meet the age requirement for a trainee of the State or local police shall not disqualify the applicant if the applicant will be of sufficient age upon completing an undergraduate course of study;

(C) possess the necessary mental and physical capabilities and emotional characteristics to discharge effectively the duties of a law enforcement officer;

(D) be of good character and demonstrate sincere motivation and dedication to law enforcement and public service;

(E) in the case of an undergraduate, agree in writing that the participant will complete an educational course of study leading to the award of a baccalaureate degree and will then accept an appointment and complete 4 years of service as an officer in the State police or in a local police department within the State;

(F) in the case of a participant desiring to undertake or continue graduate study, agree in writing that the participant will accept an appointment and complete 4 years of service as an officer in the State police or in a local police department within the State before undertaking or continuing graduate study;

(G) contract, with the consent of the participant’s parent or guardian if the participant is a minor, to serve for 4 years as an officer in the State police or in a local police department, if a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12556_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Participants in State Police Corps programs shall be selected on a competitive basis by each State under regulations prescribed by the Director.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12556_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria and qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection criteria and qualifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12556_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recruitment of minorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recruitment of minorities Each State participating in the Police Corps program shall make special efforts to seek and recruit applicants from among members of all racial, ethnic or gender groups. This subsection does not authorize an exception from the competitive standards for admission established pursuant to subsections (a) and (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12556_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment of applicant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enrollment of applicant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12556_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leave of absence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Leave of absence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12556_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Admission of applicants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Admission of applicants An applicant may be admitted into a State Police Corps program either before commencement of or during the applicant’s course of educational study.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>