<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12573" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12573/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/12573/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12573"><akn:num>12573</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12573. Establishment of program(a) Use of allotment(1) In generalA State that receives an allotment pursuant to section 12572 of this title shall use the allotment to pay the Federal share of the costs of—(A) awarding scholarships to in-service law enforcement personnel to enable such personnel to seek further education; and

(B) providing—(i) full-time employment in summer; or

(ii) part-time (not to exceed 20 hours per week) employment for a period not to exceed 1 year.



(2) EmploymentThe employment described in paragraph (1)(B)—(A) shall be provided by State and local law enforcement agencies for students who are juniors or seniors in high school or are enrolled in an institution of higher education and who demonstrate an interest in undertaking a career in law enforcement;

(B) shall not be in a law enforcement position; and

(C) shall consist of performing meaningful tasks that inform students of the nature of the tasks performed by law enforcement agencies.



(b) Payments; Federal share; non-Federal share(1) PaymentsSubject to the availability of appropriations, the Director shall pay to each State that receives an allotment under section 12572 of this title the Federal share of the cost of the activities described in the application submitted pursuant to section 12576 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(2) Federal shareThe Federal share shall not exceed 60 percent.


(3) Non-Federal shareThe non-Federal share of the cost of scholarships and student employment provided under this part shall be supplied from sources other than the Federal Government.



(c) Responsibilities of DirectorThe Director shall be responsible for the administration of the programs conducted pursuant to this part and shall, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, issue rules to implement this part.


(d) Administrative expensesA State that receives an allotment under section 12572 of this title may reserve not more than 8 percen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12573_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Use of allotment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12573_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments; Federal share; non-Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payments; Federal share; non-Federal share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12573_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities of Director The Director shall be responsible for the administration of the programs conducted pursuant to this part and shall, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Postsecondary Education, issue rules to implement this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12573_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative expenses A State that receives an allotment under section 12572 of this title may reserve not more than 8 percent of the allotment for administrative expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12573_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rule A State that receives an allotment under section 12572 of this title shall ensure that each scholarship recipient under this part be compensated at the same rate of pay and benefits and enjoy the same rights under applicable agreements with labor organizations and under State and local law as other law enforcement personnel of the same rank and tenure in the office of which the scholarship recipient is a member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12573_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplementation of funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Supplementation of funding Funds received under this part shall only be used to supplement, and not to supplant, Federal, State, or local efforts for recruitment and education of law enforcement personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>