<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20102"><akn:num>20102</akn:num><akn:heading>Crime victim compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20102. Crime victim compensation(a) Authority of Director; grants(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Director shall make an annual grant from the Fund to an eligible crime victim compensation program of 75 percent of the amounts awarded during the preceding fiscal year, other than amounts awarded for property damage. Except as provided in paragraph (4), a grant under this section shall be used by such program only for awards of compensation.

(2) If the sums available in the Fund for grants under this section are insufficient to provide grants as provided in paragraph (1), the Director shall make, from the sums available, a grant to each eligible crime victim compensation program so that all such programs receive the same percentage of the amounts awarded by such program during the preceding fiscal year, other than amounts awarded for property damage.

(3) For the purposes of calculating amounts awarded in the previous fiscal year under this subsection, the Director shall not require eligible crime victim compensation programs to deduct recovery costs or collections from restitution or from subrogation for payment under a civil lawsuit.

(4) Not more than 5 percent of a grant made under this section may be used for training purposes and the administration of the State crime victim compensation program receiving the grant.


(b) Eligible crime victim compensation programsA crime victim compensation program is an eligible crime victim compensation program for the purposes of this section if—(1) such program is operated by a State and offers compensation to victims and survivors of victims of criminal violence, including drunk driving and domestic violence for—(A) medical expenses attributable to a physical injury resulting from compensable crime, including expenses for mental health counseling and care;

(B) loss of wages attributable to a physical injury resulting from a compensable crime; and

(C) funeral expenses attributable to a death resulting from a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Director; grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Director; grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible crime victim compensation programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible crime victim compensation programs A crime victim compensation program is an eligible crime victim compensation program for the purposes of this section if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion from income, resources, and assets for purposes of means tests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusion from income, resources, and assets for purposes of means tests Notwithstanding any other law (other than title IV of Public Law 107–42), for the purpose of any maximum allowed income, resource, or asset eligibility requirement in any Federal, State, or local government program using Federal funds that provides medical or other assistance (or payment or reimbursement of the cost of such assistance), any amount of crime victim compensation that the applicant receives through a crime victim compensation program under this section shall not be included in the income, resources, or assets of the applicant, nor shall that amount reduce the amount of the assistance available to the applicant from Federal, State, or local government programs using Federal funds, unless the total amount of assistance that the applicant receives from all such programs is sufficient to fully compensate the applicant for losses suffered as a result of the crime.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20102_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to certain Federal programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Relationship to certain Federal programs Notwithstanding any other law, if the compensation paid by an eligible crime victim compensation program would cover costs that a Federal program, including the program established under title IV of Public Law 107–42, or a federally financed State or local program, would otherwise pay,— 11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>