<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20124" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20124/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20124/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20124"><akn:num>20124</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancing culturally specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual ass</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20124. Enhancing culturally specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking(a) Establishment(1) In generalOf the amounts appropriated under certain grant programs identified in paragraph (2), the Attorney General, through the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women (referred to in this section as the “Director”), shall take 15 percent of such appropriated amounts for the program under paragraph (2)(A) and 5 percent of such appropriated amounts for the programs under subparagraphs (B) through (E) of paragraph (2) and combine them to establish a new grant program to enhance culturally specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Grants made under this new program shall be administered by the Director. The requirements of the grant programs identified in paragraph (2) shall not apply to this new grant program.


(2) Programs coveredThe programs covered by paragraph (1) are the programs carried out under the following provisions:(A) Section 10461 of this title (Grants to Encourage Arrest Policies and Enforcement of Protection Orders).

(B) Section 20121 of this title 11 See References in Text note below. (Legal Assistance for Victims).

(C) Section 12341 of this title (Rural Domestic Violence, Dating Violence, Sexual Assault, Stalking, and Child Abuse Enforcement Assistance).

(D) Section 14041a of title 42 (Enhanced Training and Services to End Violence Against Women Later in Life).1

(E) Section 20122 of this title (Education, Training, and Enhanced Services to End Violence Against and Abuse of Women with Disabilities).


(3) Additional authorization of appropriationsIn addition to the amounts made available under paragraph (1), there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.


(4) Distribution(A) In generalOf the total amount available for grants under this section, not less than 4</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20124_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20124_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of program and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose of program and grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20124_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible entities Eligible entities for grants under this Section 33 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20124_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting The Director shall issue a biennial report on the distribution of funding under this section, the progress made in replicating and supporting increased services to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources, and the types of culturally accessible programs, strategies, technical assistance, and training developed or enhanced through this program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20124_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation The Director shall award a contract or cooperative agreement to evaluate programs under this section to an entity with the demonstrated expertise in and primary goal of providing enhanced cultural access to services and resources for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20124_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-exclusivity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Non-exclusivity Nothing in this Section 3 shall be interpreted to exclude culturally specific community-based programs from applying to other grant programs authorized under this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20124_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and grant conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions and grant conditions In this section the definitions and grant conditions in section 12291 of this title shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>