<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20127" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20127/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20127/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20127"><akn:num>20127</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency and transitional pet shelter and housing assistance grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20127. Emergency and transitional pet shelter and housing assistance grant program(1) Grant program(A) In generalThe Secretary, acting in consultation with the Office of the Violence Against Women 11 So in original. Probably should be “Office on Violence Against Women”. of the Department of Justice, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall award grants under this section to eligible entities to carry out programs to provide the assistance described in paragraph (3) with respect to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking and the pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses of such victims.


(B) Memorandum of understandingThe Secretary may enter into a memorandum of understanding with the head of another Department or agency, as appropriate, to carry out any of the authorities provided to the Secretary under this section.22 See References in Text note below.



(2) Application(A) In generalAn eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including—(i) a description of the activities for which a grant under this section is sought;

(ii) such assurances as the Secretary determines to be necessary to ensure compliance by the entity with the requirements of this section; and

(iii) a certification that the entity, before engaging with any individual domestic violence victim, will disclose to the victim any mandatory duty of the entity to report instances of abuse and neglect (including instances of abuse and neglect of pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses).


(B) Additional requirementsIn addition to the requirements of subparagraph (A), each application submitted by an eligible entity under that subparagraph shall—(i) not include proposals for any activities that may compromise the safe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20127_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Grant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20127_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20127_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Use of funds Grants awarded under this section may only be used for programs that provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20127_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Grant conditions An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall, as a condition of such receipt, agree—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20127_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of assistance provided to victims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Duration of assistance provided to victims</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20127_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Report to the Secretary Not later than 1 year after the date on which an eligible entity receives a grant under this section and each year thereafter in which the grant funds are used, the entity shall submit to the Secretary a report that contains, with respect to assistance provided by the entity to domestic violence victims with pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses using grant funds received under this section, information on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20127_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20127_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20127_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>