<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20121" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20121/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20121/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20121"><akn:num>20121</akn:num><akn:heading>Legal assistance for victims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20121. Legal assistance for victims(a) In generalThe purpose of this section is to enable the Attorney General to award grants to increase the availability of civil and criminal legal assistance necessary to provide effective aid to adult and youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault who are seeking relief in legal matters relating to or arising out of that abuse or violence, at minimal or no cost to the victims. When legal assistance to a dependent is necessary for the safety of a victim, such assistance may be provided. Criminal legal assistance provided for under this section shall be limited to criminal matters relating to or arising out of domestic violence, sexual assault, dating violence, and stalking.


(b) Definitions and grant conditionsIn this section, the definitions and grant conditions provided in section 12291 of this title shall apply.


(c) Legal assistance for victims grantsThe Attorney General may award grants under this subsection to private nonprofit entities, Indian tribal governments and tribal organizations, territorial organizations, and publicly funded organizations not acting in a governmental capacity such as law schools, and which shall be used—(1) to implement, expand, and establish cooperative efforts and projects between domestic violence, dating violence, and sexual assault victim service providers and legal assistance providers to provide legal assistance for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault;

(2) to implement, expand, and establish efforts and projects to provide legal assistance for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault by organizations with a demonstrated history of providing direct legal or advocacy services on behalf of these victims; and

(3) to implement, expand, and establish efforts and projects to provide competent, supervised pro bono legal assistance for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20121_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The purpose of this section is to enable the Attorney General to award grants to increase the availability of civil and criminal legal assistance necessary to provide effective aid to adult and youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault who are seeking relief in legal matters relating to or arising out of that abuse or violence, at minimal or no cost to the victims. When legal assistance to a dependent is necessary for the safety of a victim, such assistance may be provided. Criminal legal assistance provided for under this section shall be limited to criminal matters relating to or arising out of domestic violence, sexual assault, dating violence, and stalking.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20121_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and grant conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions and grant conditions In this section, the definitions and grant conditions provided in section 12291 of this title shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20121_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Legal assistance for victims grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Legal assistance for victims grants The Attorney General may award grants under this subsection to private nonprofit entities, Indian tribal governments and tribal organizations, territorial organizations, and publicly funded organizations not acting in a governmental capacity such as law schools, and which shall be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20121_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility To be eligible for a grant under subsection (c), applicants shall certify in writing that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20121_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation The Attorney General may evaluate the grants funded under this section through contracts or other arrangements with entities expert on domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, and sexual assault, and on evaluation research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20121_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>