<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20123" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20123/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20123/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20123"><akn:num>20123</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for outreach and services to underserved populations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20123. Grants for outreach and services to underserved populations(a) Grants authorized(1) In generalOf the amounts appropriated under the grant programs identified in paragraph (2), the Attorney General shall take 2 percent of such appropriated amounts and combine them to award grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b) of this section to develop and implement outreach strategies targeted at adult or youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking in underserved populations and to provide victim services to meet the needs of adult and youth victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking in underserved populations. The requirements of the grant programs identified in paragraph (2) shall not apply to this grant program.


(2) Programs coveredThe programs covered by paragraph (1) are the programs carried out under the following provisions:(A) Section 10441 of this title (Grants to Combat Violent Crimes Against Women).

(B) Section 10461 of this title (Grants to Encourage Arrest Policies and Enforcement of Protection Orders Program).



(b) Eligible entitiesEligible entities under this section are—(1) population specific organizations that have demonstrated experience and expertise in providing population specific services in the relevant underserved communities, or population specific organizations working in partnership with a victim service provider or domestic violence or sexual assault coalition;

(2) victim service providers offering population specific services for a specific underserved population; or

(3) victim service providers working in partnership with a national, State, tribal, Native Hawaiian, or local organization that has demonstrated experience and expertise in providing population specific services in the relevant underserved population.


(c) Planning grantsThe Attorney General may use up to 25 percent of funds available under this section to make one-time planning grants </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20123_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20123_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entities Eligible entities under this section are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20123_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Planning grants The Attorney General may use up to 25 percent of funds available under this section to make one-time planning grants to eligible entities to support the planning and development of specially designed and targeted programs for adult and youth victims in one or more underserved populations, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20123_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation grants The Attorney General shall make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of providing or enhancing population specific outreach and services to adult and youth victims in one or more underserved populations, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20123_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women at such time, in such form, and in such manner as the Director may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20123_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall submit to the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women a report that describes the activities carried out with grant funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20123_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations In addition to the funds identified in subsection (a)(1), there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20123_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and grant conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions and grant conditions In this section the definitions and grant conditions in section 12291 of this title shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>