<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20129" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20129/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20129/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20129"><akn:num>20129</akn:num><akn:heading>LGBT specific services program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20129. LGBT specific services program(a) EstablishmentThe Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Violence Against Women Office 11 So in original. Probably should be “Office on Violence Against Women”. (referred to in this section as the “Director”), shall make grants to eligible entities to enhance lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (referred to in this section as “LGBT”) specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault and stalking.


(b) Purpose of program and grants(1) General program purposeThe purpose of the program required by this section is to promote the following:(A) The maintenance and replication of existing successful LGBT specific domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking community-based programs providing services and resources for LGBT victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.

(B) The development of innovative LGBT specific strategies and projects to enhance access to services and resources for LGBT victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources.


(2) Purposes for which grants may be usedThe Director shall make grants to community-based programs for the purpose of enhancing LGBT specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking. Grants under the program shall support community-based efforts to address distinctive LGBT specific responses to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including—(A) providing or enhancing services for LGBT victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, including services that address the safety, emotional well-being, economic, housing, legal and workplace needs of LGBT victims;

(B) supporting programs that specifically address underserved LGBT communities, including culturally specific communities, to provide spe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20129_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Violence Against Women Office 11 So in original. Probably should be “Office on Violence Against Women”. (referred to in this section as the “Director”), shall make grants to eligible entities to enhance lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (referred to in this section as “LGBT”) specific services for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault and stalking.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20129_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of program and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose of program and grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20129_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible entities Eligible entities for grants under this section include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20129_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting The Director shall issue a biennial report on the distribution of funding under this section, the progress made in replicating and supporting increased services to LGBT victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking and the types of LGBT specific programs, strategies, technical assistance, and training developed or enhanced through this program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20129_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation The Director shall award a contract or cooperative agreement to evaluate programs under this section to an entity with the demonstrated expertise in and primary goal of providing enhanced access to services and resources for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking who face obstacles to using more traditional services and resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20129_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-exclusivity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Non-exclusivity Nothing in this section shall be construed to exclude LGBT community-based organizations from applying to other grant programs authorized under this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20129_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $8,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>