<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20125" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20125/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20125/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20125"><akn:num>20125</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to combat violent crimes on campuses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20125. Grants to combat violent crimes on campuses(a) Grants authorized(1) In generalThe Attorney General is authorized to make grants to institutions of higher education, for use by such institutions or consortia consisting of campus personnel, student organizations, campus administrators, security personnel, and regional crisis centers affiliated with the institution, to develop and strengthen effective security and investigation strategies to combat domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking on campuses, to develop and strengthen victim services in cases involving such crimes on campuses, which may include partnerships with local criminal justice authorities and community-based victim services agencies, and to develop and strengthen prevention education and awareness programs.


(2) Equitable participationThe Attorney General shall make every effort to ensure—(A) the equitable participation of private and public institutions of higher education in the activities assisted under this section;

(B) the equitable geographic distribution of grants under this section among the various regions of the United States; and

(C) the equitable distribution of grants under this section to tribal colleges and universities and traditionally black colleges and universities.



(b) Use of grant fundsGrant funds awarded under this section may be used for the following purposes:(1) To provide personnel, training, technical assistance, data collection, and other equipment with respect to the increased apprehension, investigation, and adjudication of persons committing domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking on campus.

(2) To develop, strengthen, and implement campus policies, protocols, and services that more effectively identify and respond to the crimes of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking, including the use of technology to commit these crimes, and to train campus administrators, campus security perso</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20125_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20125_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of grant funds Grant funds awarded under this section may be used for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20125_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20125_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>General terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) General terms and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20125_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, of which not less than 10 percent shall be made available for grants to historically Black colleges and universities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20125_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20125_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and grant conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions and grant conditions In this section the definitions and grant conditions in section 12291 of this title shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>