<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20131" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20131/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20131/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20131"><akn:num>20131</akn:num><akn:heading>Media campaign</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20131. Media campaign(1) DefinitionsIn this subsection:(A) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women.


(B) National media campaignThe term “national media campaign” means the national “Choose Respect” media campaign described in paragraph (2).



(2) Media campaignThe Director shall, to the extent feasible and appropriate, conduct a national “Choose Respect” media campaign in accordance with this section for the purposes of—(A) preventing and discouraging violence against women, including domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking by targeting the attitudes, perceptions, and beliefs of individuals who have or are likely to commit such crimes;

(B) encouraging victims of the crimes described in subparagraph (A) to seek help through the means determined to be most effective by the most current evidence available, including seeking legal representation; and

(C) informing the public about the help available to victims of the crimes described in subparagraph (A).


(3) Use of funds(A) In generalAmounts made available to carry out this section for the national media campaign may only be used for the following:(i) The purchase of media time and space, including the strategic planning for, tracking, and accounting of, such purchases.

(ii) Creative and talent costs, consistent with subparagraph (B).

(iii) Advertising production costs, which may include television, radio, internet, social media, and other commercial marketing venues.

(iv) Testing and evaluation of advertising.

(v) Evaluation of the effectiveness of the national media campaign.

(vi) Costs of contracts to carry out activities authorized by this subsection.

(vii) Partnerships with professional and civic groups, community-based organizations, including faith-based organizations and culturally specific organizations, and government organizations related to the national media campaign.

(viii) Entertainment industry outreach, interactive o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20131_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Definitions In this subsection:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20131_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Media campaign</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Media campaign The Director shall, to the extent feasible and appropriate, conduct a national “Choose Respect” media campaign in accordance with this section for the purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20131_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20131_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advertising</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Advertising In carrying out this subsection, the Director shall ensure that sufficient funds are allocated to meet the stated goals of the national media campaign.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20131_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities and functions under the program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Responsibilities and functions under the program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20131_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Prohibitions None of the amounts made available under paragraph (3) may be obligated or expended for any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20131_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial and performance accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Financial and performance accountability The Director shall cause to be performed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20131_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Report to Congress The Director shall submit on an annual basis a report to Congress that describes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20131_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>