<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20141" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20141/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20141/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20141"><akn:num>20141</akn:num><akn:heading>Services to victims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20141. Services to victims(a) Designation of responsible officialsThe head of each department and agency of the United States engaged in the detection, investigation, or prosecution of crime shall designate by names and office titles the persons who will be responsible for identifying the victims of crime and performing the services described in subsection (c) at each stage of a criminal case.


(b) Identification of victimsAt the earliest opportunity after the detection of a crime at which it may be done without interfering with an investigation, a responsible official shall—(1) identify the victim or victims of a crime;

(2) inform the victims of their right to receive, on request, the services described in subsection (c); and

(3) inform each victim of the name, title, and business address and telephone number of the responsible official to whom the victim should address a request for each of the services described in subsection (c).


(c) Description of services(1) A responsible official shall—(A) inform a victim of the place where the victim may receive emergency medical and social services;

(B) inform a victim of any restitution or other relief to which the victim may be entitled under this or any other law and 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “the”. manner in which such relief may be obtained;

(C) inform a victim of public and private programs that are available to provide counseling, treatment, and other support to the victim; and

(D) assist a victim in contacting the persons who are responsible for providing the services and relief described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C).


(2) A responsible official shall arrange for a victim to receive reasonable protection from a suspected offender and persons acting in concert with or at the behest of the suspected offender.

(3) During the investigation and prosecution of a crime, a responsible official shall provide a victim the earliest possible notice of—(A) the status of the investigation</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20141_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of responsible officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation of responsible officials The head of each department and agency of the United States engaged in the detection, investigation, or prosecution of crime shall designate by names and office titles the persons who will be responsible for identifying the victims of crime and performing the services described in subsection (c) at each stage of a criminal case.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20141_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of victims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification of victims At the earliest opportunity after the detection of a crime at which it may be done without interfering with an investigation, a responsible official shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20141_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Description of services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20141_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No cause of action or defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No cause of action or defense This section does not create a cause of action or defense in favor of any person arising out of the failure of a responsible person to provide information as required by subsection (b) or (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20141_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For the purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>