<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20341" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20341/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20341/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20341"><akn:num>20341</akn:num><akn:heading>Child abuse reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20341. Child abuse reporting(a) In general(1) Covered professionalsA person who, while engaged in a professional capacity or activity described in subsection (b) on Federal land or in a federally operated (or contracted) facility, learns of facts that give reason to suspect that a child has suffered an incident of child abuse, shall as soon as possible make a report of the suspected abuse to the agency designated under subsection (d) and to the agency or agencies provided for in subsection (e), if applicable.


(2) Covered individualsA covered individual who learns of facts that give reason to suspect that a child has suffered an incident of child abuse, including sexual abuse, shall as soon as possible make a report of the suspected abuse to the agency designated by the Attorney General under subsection (d).



(b) Covered professionalsPersons engaged in the following professions and activities are subject to the requirements of subsection (a)(1):(1) Physicians, dentists, medical residents or interns, hospital personnel and administrators, nurses, health care practitioners, chiropractors, osteopaths, pharmacists, optometrists, podiatrists, emergency medical technicians, ambulance drivers, undertakers, coroners, medical examiners, alcohol or drug treatment personnel, and persons performing a healing role or practicing the healing arts.

(2) Psychologists, psychiatrists, and mental health professionals.

(3) Social workers, licensed or unlicensed marriage, family, and individual counselors.

(4) Teachers, teacher’s aides or assistants, school counselors and guidance personnel, school officials, and school administrators.

(5) Child care workers and administrators.

(6) Law enforcement personnel, probation officers, criminal prosecutors, and juvenile rehabilitation or detention facility employees.

(7) Foster parents.

(8) Commercial film and photo processors.


(c) DefinitionsFor the purposes of this section—(1) the term “child abuse” means the physical or mental i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20341_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20341_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered professionals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Covered professionals Persons engaged in the following professions and activities are subject to the requirements of subsection (a)(1):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20341_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For the purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20341_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency designated to receive report and action to be taken</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Agency designated to receive report and action to be taken For all Federal lands and all federally operated (or contracted) facilities in which children are cared for or reside and for all covered individuals, the Attorney General shall designate an agency to receive and investigate the reports described in subsection (a). By formal written agreement, the designated agency may be a non-Federal agency. When such reports are received by social services or health care agencies, and involve allegations of sexual abuse, serious physical injury, or life-threatening neglect of a child, there shall be an immediate referral of the report to a law enforcement agency with authority to take emergency action to protect the child. All reports received shall be promptly investigated, and whenever appropriate, investigations shall be conducted jointly by social services and law enforcement personnel, with a view toward avoiding unnecessary multiple interviews with the child.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20341_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporters and recipient of report involving children and homes of members of the Armed Forces</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporters and recipient of report involving children and homes of members of the Armed Forces</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20341_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reporting form In every federally operated (or contracted) facility, on all Federal lands, and for all covered individuals, a standard written reporting form, with instructions, shall be disseminated to all mandated reporter groups. Use of the form shall be encouraged, but its use shall not take the place of the immediate making of oral reports, telephonically or otherwise, when circumstances dictate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20341_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity for good faith reporting and associated actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Immunity for good faith reporting and associated actions All persons who, acting in good faith, make a report by subsection (a), or otherwise provide information or assistance in connection with a report, investigation, or legal intervention pursuant to a report, shall be immune from civil and criminal liability arising out of such actions. There shall be a presumption that any such persons acted in good faith. If a person is sued because of the person’s performance of one of the above functions, and the defendant prevails in the litigation, the court may order that the plaintiff pay the defendant’s legal expenses. Immunity shall not be accorded to persons acting in bad faith.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20341_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training of prospective reporters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Training of prospective reporters All individuals in the occupations listed in subsection (b)(1) who work on Federal lands, or are employed in federally operated (or contracted) facilities, and all covered individuals, shall receive periodic training in the obligation to report, as well as in the identification of abused and neglected children.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20341_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a victim of child abuse to self-report the abuse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>