<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20503"><akn:num>20503</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program for notification and communications systems along highways and major transportation ro</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20503. Grant program for notification and communications systems along highways and major transportation routes for recovery of abducted children(a) Program requiredThe Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall carry out a program to provide grants to States for the development or enhancement of notification or communications systems along highways and at airports, maritime ports, border crossing areas and checkpoints, and ports of exit from the United States for alerts and other information for the recovery of abducted children.


(b) Development grants(1) In generalThe Secretary may make a grant to a State under this subsection for the development of a State program for the use of changeable message signs or other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children. The State program shall provide for the planning, coordination, and design of systems, protocols, and message sets that support the coordination and communication necessary to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children.


(2) Eligible activitiesA grant under this subsection may be used by a State for the following purposes:(A) To develop general policies and procedures to guide the use of changeable message signs or other information systems to notify motorists, aircraft passengers, ship passengers, and travelers about abductions of children.

(B) To develop guidance or policies on the content and format of alert messages to be conveyed on changeable message signs or other traveler information systems.

(C) To coordinate State, regional, and local plans for the use of changeable message signs or other transportation related issues.

(D) To plan secure and reliable communications systems and protocols among public safety and transportation agencies or modify existing communications systems to support the notification of motorists, aircra</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program required The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall carry out a program to provide grants to States for the development or enhancement of notification or communications systems along highways and at airports, maritime ports, border crossing areas and checkpoints, and ports of exit from the United States for alerts and other information for the recovery of abducted children.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Implementation grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20503_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20503_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of grant amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Distribution of grant amounts The Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, distribute grants under this section equally among the States that apply for a grant under this section within the time period prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20503_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administration The Secretary shall prescribe requirements, including application requirements, for the receipt of grants under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20503_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definition In this chapter, the term “State” means any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, American Samoa, Guam, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and any other territory of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20503_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023. Such amounts shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20503_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of State programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Study of State programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>