<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20705a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20705a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20705a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20705a"><akn:num>20705a</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancing the ability of State, local, and Tribal child welfare agencies to identify and respond to </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20705a. Enhancing the ability of State, local, and Tribal child welfare agencies to identify and respond to children who are, or are at risk of being, victims of trafficking(a) Grants to enhance child welfare servicesThe Secretary of Health and Human Services may make grants to eligible States to develop, improve, or expand programs that assist State, local, or Tribal child welfare agencies with identifying and responding to—(1) children considered victims of “child abuse and neglect” and of “sexual abuse” under the application of section 5106g(b)(1) of title 42 because of being identified as being a victim or at risk of being a victim of a severe form of trafficking in persons; and

(2) children over whom such agencies have responsibility for placement, care, or supervision and for whom there is reasonable cause to believe are, or are at risk of being a victim of 1 or more severe forms of trafficking in persons.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ChildThe term “child” means an individual who has not attained 18 years of age or such older age as the State has elected under section 475(8) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 675(8)). At the option of an eligible State, such term may include an individual who has not attained 26 years of age.


(2) Eligible StateThe term “eligible State” means a State that has not received more than 3 grants under this section and meets 1 or more of the following criteria:(A) Elimination of third party control requirementThe State has eliminated or will eliminate any requirement relating to identification of a controlling third party who causes a child to engage in a commercial sex act in order for the child to be considered a victim of trafficking or a victim of 1 or more severe forms of trafficking in persons for purposes of accessing child welfare services and care.


(B) Application of standard for human traffickingThe State considers a child to be a victim of trafficking if the individual is a victim of a severe form of traf</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20705a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to enhance child welfare services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants to enhance child welfare services The Secretary of Health and Human Services may make grants to eligible States to develop, improve, or expand programs that assist State, local, or Tribal child welfare agencies with identifying and responding to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20705a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>