<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20702"><akn:num>20702</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of a grant program to develop, expand, and strengthen assistance programs for certain </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20702. Establishment of a grant program to develop, expand, and strengthen assistance programs for certain persons subject to trafficking(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Assistant SecretaryThe term “Assistant Secretary” means the Assistant Secretary for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services.


(2) Assistant Attorney GeneralThe term “Assistant Attorney General” means the Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice.


(3) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means a State or unit of local government that—(A) has significant criminal activity involving sex trafficking of minors;

(B) has demonstrated cooperation between Federal, State, local, and, where applicable, tribal law enforcement agencies, prosecutors, and social service providers in addressing sex trafficking of minors;

(C) has developed a workable, multi-disciplinary plan to combat sex trafficking of minors, including—(i) building or establishing a residential care facility for minor victims of sex trafficking;

(ii) the provision of rehabilitative care to minor victims of sex trafficking;

(iii) the provision of specialized training for law enforcement officers and social service providers for all forms of sex trafficking, with a focus on sex trafficking of minors;

(iv) prevention, deterrence, and prosecution of offenses involving sex trafficking of minors;

(v) cooperation or referral agreements with organizations providing outreach or other related services to runaway and homeless youth; and

(vi) law enforcement protocols or procedures to screen all individuals arrested for prostitution, whether adult or minor, for victimization by sex trafficking and by other crimes, such as sexual assault and domestic violence; and


(D) provides assurance that a minor victim of sex trafficking shall not be required to collaborate with law enforcement to have access to residential care or services provided with a grant under this se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sex trafficking block grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sex trafficking block grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mandatory exclusion An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section that is found to have utilized grant funds for any unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost shall not be eligible for any grant funds awarded under the grant for 2 fiscal years following the year in which the unauthorized expenditure or unallowable cost is reported.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compliance requirement An eligible entity shall not be eligible to receive a grant under this section if, during the 5 fiscal years before the eligible entity submits an application for the grant, the eligible entity has been found to have violated the terms or conditions of a Government grant program by utilizing grant funds for unauthorized expenditures or otherwise unallowable costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative cap</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administrative cap The cost of administering the grants authorized by this section shall not exceed 3 percent of the total amount appropriated to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Audit requirement For fiscal years 2016 and 2017, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct an audit of all 4 eligible entities that receive block grants under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Match requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Match requirement An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall provide a non-Federal match in an amount equal to not less than—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>No limitation on section 20705 grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No limitation on section 20705 grants An entity that applies for a grant under section 20705 of this title is not prohibited from also applying for a grant under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated $8,000,000 to the Attorney General for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2021 to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20702_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) GAO evaluation Not later than 30 months after March 7, 2013, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to Congress that contains—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>