<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20916" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20916/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20916/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20916"><akn:num>20916</akn:num><akn:heading>Direction to the Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20916. Direction to the Attorney General(a) Requirement that sex offenders provide certain Internet related information to sex offender registriesThe Attorney General, using the authority provided in section 114(a)(7) 11 See References in Text note below. of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act [34 U.S.C. 20914(a)(7)], shall require that each sex offender provide to the sex offender registry those Internet identifiers the sex offender uses or will use of any type that the Attorney General determines to be appropriate under that Act [34 U.S.C. 20901 et seq.]. These records of Internet identifiers shall be subject to the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) to the same extent as the other records in the National Sex Offender Registry.


(b) Timeliness of reporting of informationThe Attorney General, using the authority provided in section 112(b) of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act [34 U.S.C. 20912(b)], shall specify the time and manner for keeping current information required to be provided under this section.


(c) Nondisclosure to general publicThe Attorney General, using the authority provided in section 118(b)(4) of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act [34 U.S.C. 20920(b)(4)], shall exempt from disclosure all information provided by a sex offender under subsection (a).


(d) Notice to sex offenders of new requirementsThe Attorney General shall ensure that procedures are in place to notify each sex offender of changes in requirements that apply to that sex offender as a result of the implementation of this section.


(e) Definitions(1) Of “social networking website”As used in this Act, the term “social networking website”—(A) means an Internet website—(i) that allows users, through the creation of web pages or profiles or by other means, to provide information about themselves that is available to the public or to other users; and

(ii) that offers a mechanism for communication with other users where such users are likely to i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20916_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement that sex offenders provide certain Internet related information to sex offender registries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement that sex offenders provide certain Internet related information to sex offender registries The Attorney General, using the authority provided in section 114(a)(7) 11 See References in Text note below. of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act [34 U.S.C. 20914(a)(7)], shall require that each sex offender provide to the sex offender registry those Internet identifiers the sex offender uses or will use of any type that the Attorney General determines to be appropriate under that Act [34 U.S.C. 20901 et seq.]. These records of Internet identifiers shall be subject to the Privacy Act (5 U.S.C. 552a) to the same extent as the other records in the National Sex Offender Registry.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20916_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timeliness of reporting of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Timeliness of reporting of information The Attorney General, using the authority provided in section 112(b) of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act [34 U.S.C. 20912(b)], shall specify the time and manner for keeping current information required to be provided under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20916_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondisclosure to general public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nondisclosure to general public The Attorney General, using the authority provided in section 118(b)(4) of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act [34 U.S.C. 20920(b)(4)], shall exempt from disclosure all information provided by a sex offender under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20916_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to sex offenders of new requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice to sex offenders of new requirements The Attorney General shall ensure that procedures are in place to notify each sex offender of changes in requirements that apply to that sex offender as a result of the implementation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20916_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>