<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20922" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20922/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20922/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20922"><akn:num>20922</akn:num><akn:heading>Dru Sjodin National Sex Offender Public Website</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20922. Dru Sjodin National Sex Offender Public Website(a) EstablishmentThere is established the Dru Sjodin National Sex Offender Public Website (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Website”), which the Attorney General shall maintain.


(b) Information to be providedThe Website shall include relevant information for each sex offender and other person listed on a jurisdiction’s Internet site. The Website shall allow the public to obtain relevant information for each sex offender by a single query for any given zip code or geographical radius set by the user in a form and with such limitations as may be established by the Attorney General and shall have such other field search capabilities as the Attorney General may provide.


(Pub. L. 109–248, title I, § 120, July 27, 2006, 120 Stat. 597.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Dru Sjodin National Sex Offender Public Website, referred to in text, is located at https://www.nsopw.gov.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 16920 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20922_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established the Dru Sjodin National Sex Offender Public Website (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Website”), which the Attorney General shall maintain.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20922_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information to be provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information to be provided The Website shall include relevant information for each sex offender and other person listed on a jurisdiction’s Internet site. The Website shall allow the public to obtain relevant information for each sex offender by a single query for any given zip code or geographical radius set by the user in a form and with such limitations as may be established by the Attorney General and shall have such other field search capabilities as the Attorney General may provide.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>