<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20942" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20942/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20942/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20942"><akn:num>20942</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Safe Childhood</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20942. Project Safe Childhood(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Child sexual abuse materialThe term “child sexual abuse material” has the meaning given the term “child pornography” in section 2256 of title 18.


(2) Child sexual exploitation offenseThe term “child sexual exploitation offense” means—(A)(i) an offense involving a minor under section 1591 or chapter 117 of title 18;

(ii) an offense under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of section 2251 of title 18;

(iii) an offense under section 2251A or 2252A(g) of title 18; or

(iv) any attempt or conspiracy to commit an offense described in clause (i) or (ii); or


(B) an offense involving a minor under a State or Tribal statute that is similar to a provision described in subparagraph (A).


(3) Circle of trust offenderThe term “circle of trust offender” means an offender who is related to, or in a position of trust, authority, or supervisory control with respect to, a child.


(4) ComputerThe term “computer” has the meaning given the term in section 1030 of title 18.


(5) Contact sexual offenseThe term “contact sexual offense” means—(A) an offense involving a minor under chapter 109A of title 18, or any attempt or conspiracy to commit such an offense; or

(B) an offense involving a minor under a State or Tribal statute that is similar to a provision described in subparagraph (A).


(6) Dual offenderThe term “dual offender” means—(A) a person who commits—(i) a technology-facilitated child sexual exploitation offense or an offense involving child sexual abuse material; and

(ii) a contact sexual offense; and


(B) without regard to whether the offenses described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A)—(i) are committed as part of the same course of conduct; or

(ii) involve the same victim.



(7) FacilitatorThe term “facilitator” means an individual who facilitates the commission by another individual of—(A) a technology-facilitated child sexual exploitation offense or an offense involving child sexual abuse mat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20942_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20942_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of program The Attorney General shall create and maintain a nationwide initiative to align Federal, State, and local entities to combat the growing epidemic of online child sexual exploitation and abuse, to be known as the “Project Safe Childhood program”, in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20942_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Best practices The Attorney General, in coordination with the Child Exploitation and Obscenity Section of the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice and the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention of the Department of Justice, and in consultation with training and technical assistance providers under the ICAC Task Force Program who are funded by the Attorney General and with appropriate nongovernmental organizations, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20942_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation Except as authorized under subsection (e), funds authorized under this section may only be used for the following 4 purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20942_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of Project Safe Childhood</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Expansion of Project Safe Childhood Notwithstanding subsection (d), funds authorized under this section may be also be 11 So in original. used for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20942_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>