<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20990" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20990/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/20990/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20990"><akn:num>20990</akn:num><akn:heading>National registry of substantiated cases of child abuse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20990. National registry of substantiated cases of child abuse(a) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall create a national registry of substantiated cases of child abuse or neglect.


(b) Information(1) CollectionThe information in the registry described in subsection (a) shall be supplied by States and Indian tribes, or, at the option of a State, by political subdivisions of such State, to the Secretary of Health and Human Services.


(2) Type of informationThe registry described in subsection (a) shall collect in a central electronic registry information on persons reported to a State, Indian tribe, or political subdivision of a State as perpetrators of a substantiated case of child abuse or neglect.



(c) Scope of information(1) In general(A) Treatment of reportsThe information to be provided to the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this section shall relate to substantiated reports of child abuse or neglect.


(B) ExceptionIf a State, Indian tribe, or political subdivision of a State has an electronic register of cases of child abuse or neglect equivalent to the registry established under this section that it maintains pursuant to a requirement or authorization under any other provision of law, the information provided to the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this section shall be coextensive with that in such register.



(2) FormInformation provided to the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this section—(A) shall be in a standardized electronic form determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services; and

(B) shall contain case-specific identifying information that is limited to the name of the perpetrator and the nature of the substantiated case of child abuse or neglect, and that complies with clauses (viii) and (ix) of section 5106a(b)(2)(A) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 42.



(d) ConstructionThis section shall not be construed to requi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20990_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall create a national registry of substantiated cases of child abuse or neglect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20990_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20990_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Scope of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20990_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Construction This section shall not be construed to require a State, Indian tribe, or political subdivision of a State to modify—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20990_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accessibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Accessibility Information contained in the national registry shall only be accessible to any Federal, State, Indian tribe, or local government entity, or any agent of such entities, that has a need for such information in order to carry out its responsibilities under law to protect children from child abuse and neglect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20990_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Dissemination The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall establish standards for the dissemination of information in the national registry of substantiated cases of child abuse or neglect. Such standards shall comply with clauses (viii) and (ix) of section 5106a(b)(2)(A) 1 of title 42.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20990_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>