<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21101"><akn:num>21101</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21101. Definitions
In this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Child exploitationThe term “child exploitation” means any conduct, attempted conduct, or conspiracy to engage in conduct involving a minor that violates section 1591, chapter 109A, chapter 110, and chapter 117 of title 18 or any sexual activity involving a minor for which any person can be charged with a criminal offense.


(2) Child obscenityThe term “child obscenity” means any visual depiction proscribed by section 1466A of title 18.


(3) MinorThe term “minor” means any person under the age of 18 years.


(4) Sexually explicit conductThe term “sexually explicit conduct” has the meaning given such term in section 2256 of title 18.


(Pub. L. 110–401, § 2, Oct. 13, 2008, 122 Stat. 4229.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 110–401, Oct. 13, 2008, 122 Stat. 4229, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2008 Act note set out under section 10101 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 17601 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21101_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Child exploitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Child exploitation The term “child exploitation” means any conduct, attempted conduct, or conspiracy to engage in conduct involving a minor that violates section 1591, chapter 109A, chapter 110, and chapter 117 of title 18 or any sexual activity involving a minor for which any person can be charged with a criminal offense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21101_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Child obscenity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Child obscenity The term “child obscenity” means any visual depiction proscribed by section 1466A of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21101_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Minor The term “minor” means any person under the age of 18 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21101_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sexually explicit conduct</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Sexually explicit conduct The term “sexually explicit conduct” has the meaning given such term in section 2256 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>