<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21116" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21116/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21116/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21116"><akn:num>21116</akn:num><akn:heading>ICAC grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21116. ICAC grant program(a) Establishment(1) In generalThe Attorney General is authorized to award grants to State and local ICAC task forces to assist in carrying out the duties and functions described under section 21114 of this title.


(2) Formula grants(A) Development of formulaAt least 75 percent of the total funds appropriated to carry out this section shall be available to award or otherwise distribute grants pursuant to a funding formula established by the Attorney General in accordance with the requirements in subparagraph (B).


(B) Formula requirementsAny formula established by the Attorney General under subparagraph (A) shall—(i) ensure that each State or local ICAC task force shall, at a minimum, receive an amount equal to 0.5 percent of the funds available to award or otherwise distribute grants under subparagraph (A); and

(ii) take into consideration the following factors:(I) The population of each State, as determined by the most recent decennial census performed by the Bureau of the Census.

(II) The number of investigative leads within the applicant’s jurisdiction generated by Operation Fairplay, the ICAC Data Network, the CyberTipline, and other sources.

(III) The number of criminal cases related to Internet crimes against children referred to a task force for Federal, State, or local prosecution.

(IV) The number of successful prosecutions of child exploitation cases by a task force.

(V) The amount of training, technical assistance, and public education or outreach by a task force related to the prevention, investigation, or prosecution of child exploitation offenses.

(VI) Such other criteria as the Attorney General determines demonstrate the level of need for additional resources by a task force.




(3) Distribution of remaining funds based on need(A) In generalAny funds remaining from the total funds appropriated to carry out this section after funds have been made available to award or otherwise distribute formula grants under paragra</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21116_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21116_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21116_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowable uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allowable uses Grants awarded under this section may be used to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21116_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>