<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21115" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21115/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21115/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21115"><akn:num>21115</akn:num><akn:heading>National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21115. National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System(a) In generalThe Attorney General shall establish, consistent with all existing Federal laws relating to the protection of privacy, a National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System. The system shall not be used to search for or obtain any information that does not involve the use of the Internet to facilitate child exploitation.


(b) Intent of CongressIt is the purpose and intent of Congress that the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established in subsection (a) is intended to continue and build upon Operation Fairplay developed by the Wyoming Attorney General’s office, which has established a secure, dynamic undercover infrastructure that has facilitated online law enforcement investigations of child exploitation, information sharing, and the capacity to collect and aggregate data on the extent of the problems of child exploitation.


(c) Purpose of systemThe National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established under subsection (a) shall be dedicated to assisting and supporting credentialed law enforcement agencies authorized to investigate child exploitation in accordance with Federal, State, local, and tribal laws, including by providing assistance and support to—(1) Federal agencies investigating and prosecuting child exploitation;

(2) the ICAC Task Force Program established under section 21112 of this title;

(3) State, local, and tribal agencies investigating and prosecuting child exploitation; and

(4) foreign or international law enforcement agencies, subject to approval by the Attorney General.


(d) Cyber safe deconfliction and information sharingThe National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established under subsection (a)—(1) shall be housed and maintained within the Department of Justice or a credentialed law enforcement agency;

(2) shall be made available for a nominal charge to support credentialed law enforcement agencies in accordan</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21115_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Attorney General shall establish, consistent with all existing Federal laws relating to the protection of privacy, a National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System. The system shall not be used to search for or obtain any information that does not involve the use of the Internet to facilitate child exploitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21115_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intent of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Intent of Congress It is the purpose and intent of Congress that the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established in subsection (a) is intended to continue and build upon Operation Fairplay developed by the Wyoming Attorney General’s office, which has established a secure, dynamic undercover infrastructure that has facilitated online law enforcement investigations of child exploitation, information sharing, and the capacity to collect and aggregate data on the extent of the problems of child exploitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21115_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purpose of system The National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established under subsection (a) shall be dedicated to assisting and supporting credentialed law enforcement agencies authorized to investigate child exploitation in accordance with Federal, State, local, and tribal laws, including by providing assistance and support to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21115_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cyber safe deconfliction and information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cyber safe deconfliction and information sharing The National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21115_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection and reporting of data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Collection and reporting of data</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21115_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory requirements of network</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Mandatory requirements of network The National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System established under subsection (a) shall develop, deploy, and maintain an integrated technology and training program that provides—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21115_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System Steering Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System Steering Committee The Attorney General shall establish a National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System Steering Committee to provide guidance to the Network relating to the program under subsection (f), and to assist in the development of strategic plans for the System. The Steering Committee shall consist of 10 members with expertise in child exploitation prevention and interdiction prosecution, investigation, or prevention, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21115_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2016, $2,000,000 to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>