<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21711"><akn:num>21711</akn:num><akn:heading>Supporting Federal cases involving elder justice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21711. Supporting Federal cases involving elder justice(a) Support and assistance(1) Elder Justice CoordinatorsThe Attorney General shall designate in each Federal judicial district not less than one Assistant United States Attorney to serve as the Elder Justice Coordinator for the district, who, in addition to any other responsibilities, shall be responsible for—(A) serving as the legal counsel for the Federal judicial district on matters relating to elder abuse;

(B) prosecuting, or assisting in the prosecution of, elder abuse cases;

(C) conducting public outreach and awareness activities relating to elder abuse; and

(D) ensuring the collection of data required to be collected under section 21722 of this title.


(2) Investigative supportThe Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, shall, with respect to crimes relating to elder abuse, ensure the implementation of a regular and comprehensive training program to train agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in the investigation and prosecution of such crimes and the enforcement of laws related to elder abuse, which shall include—(A) specialized strategies for communicating with and assisting elder abuse victims; and

(B) relevant forensic training relating to elder abuse.


(3) Resource groupThe Attorney General, through the Executive Office for United States Attorneys, shall ensure the operation of a resource group to facilitate the sharing of knowledge, experience, sample pleadings and other case documents, training materials, and any other resources to assist prosecutors throughout the United States in pursuing cases relating to elder abuse.


(4) Designated elder justice working group or subcommittee to the Attorney General’s Advisory Committee of United States AttorneysNot later than 60 days after October 18, 2017, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Executive Office for United States Attorneys, shall establish a subcommitt</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support and assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Support and assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Justice Elder Justice Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Department of Justice Elder Justice Coordinator</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Trade Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal Trade Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of appropriated funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of appropriated funds No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>