<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21722" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21722/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21722/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21722"><akn:num>21722</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective interagency coordination and Federal data collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21722. Effective interagency coordination and Federal data collection(a) In generalThe Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, on an annual basis—(1) collect from Federal law enforcement agencies, other agencies as appropriate, and Federal prosecutors’ offices statistical data related to elder abuse cases, including cases or investigations where one or more victims were elders, or the case or investigation involved a financial scheme or scam that was either targeted directly toward or largely affected elders; and

(2) publish on the website of the Department of Justice in a publicly accessible manner—(A) a summary of the data collected under paragraph (1); and

(B) recommendations for collecting additional data relating to elder abuse, including recommendations for ways to improve data reporting across Federal, State, and local agencies.



(b) RequirementThe data collected under subsection (a)(1) shall include—(1) the total number of investigations initiated by Federal law enforcement agencies, other agencies as appropriate, and Federal prosecutors’ offices related to elder abuse;

(2) the total number and types of elder abuse cases filed in Federal courts; and

(3) for each case described in paragraph (2)—(A) the name of the district where the case originated;

(B) the style of the case, including the case name and number;

(C) a description of the act or acts giving rise to the elder abuse;

(D) in the case of a scheme or scam, a description of such scheme or scam giving rise to the elder abuse;

(E) information about each alleged perpetrator of the elder abuse; and

(F) the outcome of the case.



(c) HHS requirementThe Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, on an annual basis, provide to the Attorney General statistical data collected by the Secretary relating to elder abuse cases investigated by adult protective services, which shall be included in the summary published under subsection (a)(2).


(d) Pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21722_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, on an annual basis—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21722_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement The data collected under subsection (a)(1) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21722_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>HHS requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) HHS requirement The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, on an annual basis, provide to the Attorney General statistical data collected by the Secretary relating to elder abuse cases investigated by adult protective services, which shall be included in the summary published under subsection (a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21722_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on individual data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition on individual data None of the information reported under this section shall include specific individually identifiable data.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>