<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21901"><akn:num>21901</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21901. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) AMBER Alert communications networkThe term “AMBER Alert communications network” means the AMBER Alert communications network established under subtitle A of title III of the PROTECT Act (34 U.S.C. 20501 et seq.).


(2) Ashanti AlertThe term “Ashanti Alert” means an alert issued through the Ashanti Alert communications network, related to a missing adult.


(3) Ashanti Alert communications networkThe term “Ashanti Alert communications network” means the national communications network established by the Attorney General under section 21902(a) of this title.


(4) Ashanti Alert Coordinator of the Department of Justice; CoordinatorThe term “Ashanti Alert Coordinator of the Department of Justice” or “Coordinator” means the employee designated by the Attorney General to act as the national coordinator of the Ashanti Alert communications network under section 21903(a) of this title.


(5) Ashanti Alert planThe term “Ashanti Alert plan” means a local element of the Ashanti Alert communications network.


(6) Indian TribeThe term “Indian Tribe” means a federally recognized Indian Tribe or a Native village, Regional Corporation, or Village Corporation (as those terms are defined in section 1602 of title 43).


(7) Missing adultThe term “missing adult” means an individual who—(A) is older than the age for which an alert may be issued through the AMBER Alert communications network in the State or territory of an Indian Tribe in which the individual is identified as a missing individual;

(B) is identified by a law enforcement agency as a missing individual; and

(C) meets the requirements to be designated as a missing adult, as determined by the State in which, or the Indian Tribe in the territory of which, the individual is identified as a missing individual.


(8) StateThe term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21901_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>AMBER Alert communications network</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) AMBER Alert communications network The term “AMBER Alert communications network” means the AMBER Alert communications network established under subtitle A of title III of the PROTECT Act (34 U.S.C. 20501 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21901_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ashanti Alert</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Ashanti Alert The term “Ashanti Alert” means an alert issued through the Ashanti Alert communications network, related to a missing adult.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21901_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ashanti Alert communications network</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Ashanti Alert communications network The term “Ashanti Alert communications network” means the national communications network established by the Attorney General under section 21902(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21901_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ashanti Alert Coordinator of the Department of Justice; Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Ashanti Alert Coordinator of the Department of Justice; Coordinator The term “Ashanti Alert Coordinator of the Department of Justice” or “Coordinator” means the employee designated by the Attorney General to act as the national coordinator of the Ashanti Alert communications network under section 21903(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21901_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ashanti Alert plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Ashanti Alert plan The term “Ashanti Alert plan” means a local element of the Ashanti Alert communications network.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21901_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian Tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Indian Tribe The term “Indian Tribe” means a federally recognized Indian Tribe or a Native village, Regional Corporation, or Village Corporation (as those terms are defined in section 1602 of title 43).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21901_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Missing adult</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Missing adult The term “missing adult” means an individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21901_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) State The term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>