<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/21902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21902"><akn:num>21902</akn:num><akn:heading>Ashanti Alert communications network</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21902. Ashanti Alert communications network(a) In generalThe Attorney General shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, establish a national communications network within the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice to provide assistance to regional and local search efforts for missing adults through the initiation, facilitation, and promotion of local elements of the network, in coordination with States, Indian Tribes, units of local government, law enforcement agencies, and other concerned entities with expertise in providing services to adults.


(b) Integration with existing communications networkIn establishing the Ashanti Alert communications network under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall coordinate, when advisable, with missing person alert systems in existence as of December 31, 2018, such as the AMBER Alert communications network and Silver Alert communications networks.


(Pub. L. 106–468, title II, § 202, as added Pub. L. 115–401, § 2(5), Dec. 31, 2018, 132 Stat. 5337.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Attorney General shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, establish a national communications network within the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice to provide assistance to regional and local search efforts for missing adults through the initiation, facilitation, and promotion of local elements of the network, in coordination with States, Indian Tribes, units of local government, law enforcement agencies, and other concerned entities with expertise in providing services to adults.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration with existing communications network</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Integration with existing communications network In establishing the Ashanti Alert communications network under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall coordinate, when advisable, with missing person alert systems in existence as of December 31, 2018, such as the AMBER Alert communications network and Silver Alert communications networks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>