<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30106"><akn:num>30106</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30106. Annual reports(a) Report of the Attorney GeneralNot later than 1 year after October 13, 2008, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to Congress on actions taken to carry out sections 30103 to 30106 of this title. The initial report required under this subsection shall be submitted by May 1, 2009. All subsequent annual reports shall be submitted by May 1st of each fiscal year thereafter. The report required under this subsection may be submitted as part of the annual performance report of the Department of Justice, and shall include the following:(1) With respect to grants issued under section 30103 of this title, the number and identity of State and local law enforcement grant applicants, the number of grants issued, the dollar value of each grant, including a break down of such value showing how the recipient used the funds, the specific purpose of each grant, and the reports from recipients of the grants on the efficacy of the program supported by the grant. The Department of Justice shall use the information provided by the grant recipients to produce a statement for each individual grant. Such statement shall state whether each grantee has accomplished the purposes of the grant as established in section 30103(b) of this title. Those grantees not in compliance with the requirements of sections 30103 to 30106 of this title shall be subject, but not limited to, sanctions as described in the Financial Guide issued by the Office of Justice Programs at the Department of Justice.

(2) With respect to the additional agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation authorized under paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 30104(a) of this title, the number of investigations and actions in which such agents were engaged, the type of each action, the resolution of each action, and any penalties imposed in each action.

(3) With respect to the training program authorized under section 30104(a)(4) of this title, the number of agents of the Federa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report of the Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Report of the Attorney General Not later than 1 year after October 13, 2008, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to Congress on actions taken to carry out sections 30103 to 30106 of this title. The initial report required under this subsection shall be submitted by May 1, 2009. All subsequent annual reports shall be submitted by May 1st of each fiscal year thereafter. The report required under this subsection may be submitted as part of the annual performance report of the Department of Justice, and shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial report of the Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Initial report of the Attorney General The first report required to be submitted by the Attorney General under subsection (a) shall include a summary of the efforts, activities, and resources the Department of Justice has allocated in the 5 years prior to October 13, 2008, as well as the 1-year period following such date, to the enforcement, investigation, and prosecution of intellectual property crimes, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report of the FBI</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report of the FBI Not later than 1 year after October 13, 2008, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall submit a report to Congress on actions taken to carry out sections 30103 to 30106 of this title. The initial report required under this subsection shall be submitted by May 1, 2009. All subsequent annual reports shall be submitted by May 1st of each fiscal year thereafter. The report required under this subsection may be submitted as part of the annual performance report of the Department of Justice, and shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial report of the FBI</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Initial report of the FBI The first report required to be submitted by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation under subsection (c) shall include a summary of the efforts, activities, and resources the Federal Bureau of Investigation has allocated in the 5 years prior to October 13, 2008, as well as the 1-year period following such date to the enforcement, investigation, and prosecution of intellectual property crimes, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>