<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30110" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30110/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30110/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30110"><akn:num>30110</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved investigative and forensic resources for enforcement of laws related to cybercrimes against</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30110. Improved investigative and forensic resources for enforcement of laws related to cybercrimes against individuals
Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this section, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Secretary of Homeland Security, including the Executive Associate Director of Homeland Security Investigations, shall, with respect to cybercrimes against individuals—(1) ensure that there are not fewer than 10 additional operational agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation designated to support the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice in the investigation and coordination of cybercrimes against individuals;

(2) ensure that each office of a United States Attorney designates at least 1 Assistant United States Attorney as responsible for investigating and prosecuting cybercrimes against individuals; and

(3) ensure the implementation of a regular and comprehensive training program—(A) the purpose of which is to train agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in the investigation and prosecution of such crimes and the enforcement of laws related to cybercrimes against individuals; and

(B) that includes relevant forensic training related to investigating and prosecuting cybercrimes against individuals.


(Pub. L. 117–347, title III, § 321, Jan. 5, 2023, 136 Stat. 6206.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Definitions
For definition of “cybercrime against individuals” as used in this section, see section 30107(a) of this title, as made applicable by section 3 of Pub. L. 117–347, which is set out as a note under section 20145 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30110_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) ensure that there are not fewer than 10 additional operational agents of the Federal Bureau of Investigation designated to support the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice in the investigation and coordination of cybercrimes against individuals;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30110_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) ensure that each office of a United States Attorney designates at least 1 Assistant United States Attorney as responsible for investigating and prosecuting cybercrimes against individuals; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30110_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) ensure the implementation of a regular and comprehensive training program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>