<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30309" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30309/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30309/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30309"><akn:num>30309</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30309. Definitions
In this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Carnal knowledgeThe term “carnal knowledge” means contact between the penis and the vulva or the penis and the anus, including penetration of any sort, however slight.


(2) InmateThe term “inmate” means any person incarcerated or detained in any facility who is accused of, convicted of, sentenced for, or adjudicated delinquent for, violations of criminal law or the terms and conditions of parole, probation, pretrial release, or diversionary program.


(3) JailThe term “jail” means a confinement facility of a Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency to hold—(A) persons pending adjudication of criminal charges; or

(B) persons committed to confinement after adjudication of criminal charges for sentences of 1 year or less.


(4) HIVThe term “HIV” means the human immunodeficiency virus.


(5) Oral sodomyThe term “oral sodomy” means contact between the mouth and the penis, the mouth and the vulva, or the mouth and the anus.


(6) Police lockupThe term “police lockup” means a temporary holding facility of a Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency to hold—(A) inmates pending bail or transport to jail;

(B) inebriates until ready for release; or

(C) juveniles pending parental custody or shelter placement.


(7) PrisonThe term “prison” means any confinement facility of a Federal, State, or local government, whether administered by such government or by a private organization on behalf of such government, and includes—(A) any local jail or police lockup; and

(B) any juvenile facility used for the custody or care of juvenile inmates.


(8) Prison rapeThe term “prison rape” includes the rape of an inmate in the actual or constructive control of prison officials.


(9) RapeThe term “rape” means—(A) the carnal knowledge, oral sodomy, sexual assault with an object, or sexual fondling of a person, forcibly or against that person’s will;

(B) the carnal knowledge, oral sodomy, sexual as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carnal knowledge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Carnal knowledge The term “carnal knowledge” means contact between the penis and the vulva or the penis and the anus, including penetration of any sort, however slight.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inmate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Inmate The term “inmate” means any person incarcerated or detained in any facility who is accused of, convicted of, sentenced for, or adjudicated delinquent for, violations of criminal law or the terms and conditions of parole, probation, pretrial release, or diversionary program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jail</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Jail The term “jail” means a confinement facility of a Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency to hold—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>HIV</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) HIV The term “HIV” means the human immunodeficiency virus.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oral sodomy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Oral sodomy The term “oral sodomy” means contact between the mouth and the penis, the mouth and the vulva, or the mouth and the anus.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Police lockup</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Police lockup The term “police lockup” means a temporary holding facility of a Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency to hold—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prison</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Prison The term “prison” means any confinement facility of a Federal, State, or local government, whether administered by such government or by a private organization on behalf of such government, and includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prison rape</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Prison rape The term “prison rape” includes the rape of an inmate in the actual or constructive control of prison officials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rape</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Rape The term “rape” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30309_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sexual assault with an object</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Sexual assault with an object The term “sexual assault with an object” means the use of any hand, finger, object, or other instrument to penetrate, however slightly, the genital or anal opening of the body of another person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>