<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30306"><akn:num>30306</akn:num><akn:heading>National Prison Rape Elimination Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30306. National Prison Rape Elimination Commission(a) EstablishmentThere is established a commission to be known as the National Prison Rape Elimination Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”).


(b) Members(1) In generalThe Commission shall be composed of 9 members, of whom—(A) 3 shall be appointed by the President;

(B) 2 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, unless the Speaker is of the same party as the President, in which case 1 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives and 1 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives;

(C) 1 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives (in addition to any appointment made under subparagraph (B));

(D) 2 shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate, unless the majority leader is of the same party as the President, in which case 1 shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate and 1 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate; and

(E) 1 member appointed by the minority leader of the Senate (in addition to any appointment made under subparagraph (D)).


(2) Persons eligibleEach member of the Commission shall be an individual who has knowledge or expertise in matters to be studied by the Commission.


(3) Consultation requiredThe President, the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives, and the majority leader and minority leader of the Senate shall consult with one another prior to the appointment of the members of the Commission to achieve, to the maximum extent possible, fair and equitable representation of various points of view with respect to the matters to be studied by the Commission.


(4) TermEach member shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.


(5) Time for initial appointmentsThe appointment of the members shall be made not later than 60 days after September 4, 2003.


(6) VacanciesA vacancy in the Commission shall be filled</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established a commission to be known as the National Prison Rape Elimination Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive study of the impacts of prison rape</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Comprehensive study of the impacts of prison rape</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recommendations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with accreditation organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consultation with accreditation organizations In developing recommended national standards for enhancing the detection, prevention, reduction, and punishment of prison rape, the Commission shall consider any standards that have already been developed, or are being developed simultaneously to the deliberations of the Commission. The Commission shall consult with accreditation organizations responsible for the accreditation of Federal, State, local or private prisons, that have developed or are currently developing standards related to prison rape. The Commission will also consult with national associations representing the corrections profession that have developed or are currently developing standards related to prison rape.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Hearings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information from Federal or State agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Information from Federal or State agencies The Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out its duties under this section. The Commission may request the head of any State or local department or agency to furnish such information to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Personnel matters</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30306_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Contracts for research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>