<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30303" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30303/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30303/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30303"><akn:num>30303</akn:num><akn:heading>National prison rape statistics, data, and research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30303. National prison rape statistics, data, and research(a) Annual comprehensive statistical review(1) In generalThe Bureau of Justice Statistics of the Department of Justice (in this section referred to as the “Bureau”) shall carry out, for each calendar year, a comprehensive statistical review and analysis of the incidence and effects of prison rape. The statistical review and analysis shall include, but not be limited to the identification of the common characteristics of—(A) both victims and perpetrators of prison rape; and

(B) prisons and prison systems with a high incidence of prison rape.


(2) ConsiderationsIn carrying out paragraph (1), the Bureau shall consider—(A) how rape should be defined for the purposes of the statistical review and analysis;

(B) how the Bureau should collect information about staff-on-inmate sexual assault;

(C) how the Bureau should collect information beyond inmate self-reports of prison rape;

(D) how the Bureau should adjust the data in order to account for differences among prisons as required by subsection (c)(3);

(E) the categorization of prisons as required by subsection (c)(4); and

(F) whether a preliminary study of prison rape should be conducted to inform the methodology of the comprehensive statistical review.


(3) Solicitation of viewsThe Bureau of Justice Statistics shall solicit views from representatives of the following: State departments of correction; county and municipal jails; juvenile correctional facilities; former inmates; victim advocates; researchers; and other experts in the area of sexual assault.


(4) Sampling techniquesThe review and analysis under paragraph (1) shall be based on a random sample, or other scientifically appropriate sample, of not less than 10 percent of all Federal, State, and county prisons, and a representative sample of municipal prisons. The selection shall include at least one prison from each State. The selection of facilities for sampling shall be made at the latest prac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30303_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual comprehensive statistical review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual comprehensive statistical review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30303_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review Panel on Prison Rape</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review Panel on Prison Rape</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30303_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30303_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contracts and grants In carrying out its duties under this section, the Attorney General may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30303_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2004 through 2010 to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>