<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/30305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30305"><akn:num>30305</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to protect inmates and safeguard communities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30305. Grants to protect inmates and safeguard communities(a) Grants authorizedFrom amounts made available for grants under this section, the Attorney General shall make grants to States to assist those States in ensuring that budgetary circumstances (such as reduced State and local spending on prisons) do not compromise efforts to protect inmates (particularly from prison rape) and to safeguard the communities to which inmates return. The purpose of grants under this section shall be to provide funds for personnel, training, technical assistance, data collection, and equipment to prevent and prosecute prisoner rape.


(b) Use of grant amountsAmounts received by a grantee under this section may be used by the grantee, directly or through subgrants, only for one or more of the following activities:(1) Protecting inmatesProtecting inmates by—(A) undertaking efforts to more effectively prevent prison rape;

(B) investigating incidents of prison rape; or

(C) prosecuting incidents of prison rape.


(2) Safeguarding communitiesSafeguarding communities by—(A) making available, to officials of State and local governments who are considering reductions to prison budgets, training and technical assistance in successful methods for moderating the growth of prison populations without compromising public safety, including successful methods used by other jurisdictions;

(B) developing and utilizing analyses of prison populations and risk assessment instruments that will improve State and local governments’ understanding of risks to the community regarding release of inmates in the prison population;

(C) preparing maps demonstrating the concentration, on a community-by-community basis, of inmates who have been released, to facilitate the efficient and effective—(i) deployment of law enforcement resources (including probation and parole resources); and

(ii) delivery of services (such as job training and substance abuse treatment) to those released inmates;


(D) promoting col</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized From amounts made available for grants under this section, the Attorney General shall make grants to States to assist those States in ensuring that budgetary circumstances (such as reduced State and local spending on prisons) do not compromise efforts to protect inmates (particularly from prison rape) and to safeguard the communities to which inmates return. The purpose of grants under this section shall be to provide funds for personnel, training, technical assistance, data collection, and equipment to prevent and prosecute prisoner rape.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of grant amounts Amounts received by a grantee under this section may be used by the grantee, directly or through subgrants, only for one or more of the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30305_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30305_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by grantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports by grantee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30305_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>State defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) State defined In this section, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30305_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>