<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40701"><akn:num>40701</akn:num><akn:heading>The Debbie Smith DNA Backlog Grant Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40701. The Debbie Smith DNA Backlog Grant Program(a) Authorization of grantsThe Attorney General may make grants to eligible States or units of local government for use by the State or unit of local government for the following purposes:(1) To carry out, for inclusion in the Combined DNA Index System of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, DNA analyses of samples collected under applicable legal authority.

(2) To carry out, for inclusion in such Combined DNA Index System, DNA analyses of samples from crime scenes, prioritizing, to the extent practicable consistent with public safety considerations 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. samples from rape kits, samples from other sexual assault evidence, and samples taken in cases without an identified suspect.

(3) To increase the capacity of laboratories owned by the State or by units of local government to carry out DNA analyses of samples specified in paragraph (1) or (2).

(4) To collect DNA samples specified in paragraph (1).

(5) To ensure that DNA testing and analysis of samples from crimes, including sexual assault and other serious violent crimes, are carried out in a timely manner.

(6) Repealed. Pub. L. 113–4, title X, § 1006, Mar. 7, 2013, 127 Stat. 134.

(7) To conduct an audit consistent with subsection (n) of the samples of sexual assault evidence that are in the possession of the State or unit of local government and are awaiting testing.

(8) To ensure that the collection and processing of DNA evidence by law enforcement agencies from crimes, in particular, sexual assault and other violent crimes against persons, is carried out in an appropriate and timely manner and in accordance with the protocols and practices developed under subsection (o)(1).

(9) To increase the capacity of State and local prosecution offices to address the backlog of violent crime cases in which suspects have been identified through DNA evidence.


(b) EligibilityFor a State or unit of local government t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of grants The Attorney General may make grants to eligible States or units of local government for use by the State or unit of local government for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility For a State or unit of local government to be eligible to receive a grant under this section, the chief executive officer of the State or unit of local government shall submit to the Attorney General an application in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may require. The application shall, as required by the Attorney General—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formula for distribution of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Formula for distribution of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Analysis of samples</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Analysis of samples</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restrictions on use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to the Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports to the Attorney General Each State or unit of local government which receives a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General, for each year in which funds from a grant received under this section is expended, a report at such time and in such manner as the Attorney General may reasonably require, which contains—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports to Congress Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year for which grants are made under this section, the Attorney General shall submit to the Congress a report that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditure records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Expenditure records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definition For purposes of this section, the term “State” means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General for grants under subsection (a) $151,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2029.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>