<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40901"><akn:num>40901</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40901. Establishment(a) Determination of timetablesNot later than 6 months after November 30, 1993, the Attorney General shall—(1) determine the type of computer hardware and software that will be used to operate the national instant criminal background check system and the means by which State criminal records systems and the telephone or electronic device of licensees will communicate with the national system;

(2) investigate the criminal records system of each State and determine for each State a timetable by which the State should be able to provide criminal records on an on-line capacity basis to the national system; and

(3) notify each State of the determinations made pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2).


(b) Establishment of system(1) In generalNot later than 60 months after November 30, 1993, the Attorney General shall establish a national instant criminal background check system that any licensee may contact, by telephone or by other electronic means in addition to the telephone, for information, to be supplied immediately, on whether receipt of a firearm by a prospective transferee would violate section 922 of title 18 or State law.


(2) Voluntary background checks(A) In generalNot later than 90 days after June 25, 2022, the Attorney General shall promulgate regulations allowing licensees to use the national instant criminal background check system established under this section for purposes of voluntarily conducting an employment background check relating to a current or prospective employee. The Attorney General may not collect a fee for an employment background check under this subparagraph.


(B) NoticeBefore conducting an employment background check relating to a current or prospective employee under subparagraph (A), a licensee shall—(i) provide written notice to the current or prospective employee that the licensee intends to conduct the background check; and

(ii) obtain consent to conduct the background check from the current or prospective e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of timetables</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination of timetables Not later than 6 months after November 30, 1993, the Attorney General shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited action by the Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expedited action by the Attorney General The Attorney General shall expedite—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of licensees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification of licensees On establishment of the system under this section, the Attorney General shall notify each licensee and the chief law enforcement officer of each State of the existence and purpose of the system and the means to be used to contact the system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administrative provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written reasons provided on request</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Written reasons provided on request If the national instant criminal background check system determines that an individual is ineligible to receive a firearm and the individual requests the system to provide the reasons for the determination, the system shall provide such reasons to the individual, in writing, within 5 business days after the date of the request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Correction of erroneous system information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Correction of erroneous system information If the system established under this section informs an individual contacting the system that receipt of a firearm by a prospective transferee would violate subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 of title 18 or State law, the prospective transferee may request the Attorney General to provide the prospective transferee with the reasons therefor. Upon receipt of such a request, the Attorney General shall immediately comply with the request. The prospective transferee may submit to the Attorney General information to correct, clarify, or supplement records of the system with respect to the prospective transferee. After receipt of such information, the Attorney General shall immediately consider the information, investigate the matter further, and correct all erroneous Federal records relating to the prospective transferee and give notice of the error to any Federal department or agency or any State that was the source of such erroneous records.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations After 90 days’ notice to the public and an opportunity for hearing by interested parties, the Attorney General shall prescribe regulations to ensure the privacy and security of the information of the system established under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition relating To establishment of registration systems with respect to firearms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Prohibition relating To establishment of registration systems with respect to firearms No department, agency, officer, or employee of the United States may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40901_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>