<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40912" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40912/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40912/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40912"><akn:num>40912</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements to obtain waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40912. Requirements to obtain waiver(a) In generalBeginning 3 years after January 8, 2008, a State shall be eligible to receive a waiver of the 10 percent matching requirement for National Criminal History Improvement Grants under section 40301 of this title if the State is in compliance with an implementation plan established under subsection (b) or provides at least 90 percent of the information described in subsection (c). The length of such a waiver shall not exceed 2 years.


(b) State estimates(1) Initial state estimate(A) In generalTo assist the Attorney General in making a determination under subsection (a) of this section, and under section 40914 of this title, concerning the compliance of the States in providing information to the Attorney General for the purpose of receiving a waiver under subsection (a) of this section, or facing a loss of funds under section 40914 of this title, by a date not later than 180 days after January 8, 2008, each State shall provide the Attorney General with a reasonable estimate, as calculated by a method determined by the Attorney General and in accordance with section 40914(d) of this title, of the number of the records described in subparagraph (C) applicable to such State that concern persons who are prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 of title 18.


(B) Failure to provide initial estimateA State that fails to provide an estimate described in subparagraph (A) by the date required under such subparagraph shall be ineligible to receive any funds under section 40913 of this title, until such date as it provides such estimate to the Attorney General or has established an implementation plan under section 40917 of this title.


(C) Record definedFor purposes of subparagraph (A), a record is the following:(i) A record that identifies a person who has been convicted in any court of a crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year.

(ii) A record that identi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40912_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Beginning 3 years after January 8, 2008, a State shall be eligible to receive a waiver of the 10 percent matching requirement for National Criminal History Improvement Grants under section 40301 of this title if the State is in compliance with an implementation plan established under subsection (b) or provides at least 90 percent of the information described in subsection (c). The length of such a waiver shall not exceed 2 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40912_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State estimates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State estimates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40912_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of State records for submission to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility of State records for submission to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40912_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Privacy protections For any information provided to the Attorney General for use by the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, relating to persons prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm under section 922(g)(4) of title 18, the Attorney General shall work with States and local law enforcement and the mental health community to establish regulations and protocols for protecting the privacy of information provided to the system. The Attorney General shall make every effort to meet with any mental health group seeking to express its views concerning these regulations and protocols and shall seek to develop regulations as expeditiously as practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40912_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney General report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Attorney General report Not later than January 31 of each year, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on the progress of States in automating the databases containing the information described in subsection (b) and in making that information electronically available to the Attorney General pursuant to the requirements of subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>