<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40931" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40931/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/40931/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40931"><akn:num>40931</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40931. Continuing evaluations(a) Evaluation requiredThe Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics (referred to in this section as the “Director”) shall study and evaluate the operations of the National Instant Criminal Background Check System. Such study and evaluation shall include compilations and analyses of the operations and record systems of the agencies and organizations necessary to support such System.


(b) Report on grantsNot later than January 31 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress a report containing the estimates submitted by the States under section 40912(b) of this title.


(c) Report on best practicesNot later than January 31 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress, and to each State participating in the National Criminal History Improvement Program, a report of the practices of the States regarding the collection, maintenance, automation, and transmittal of information relevant to determining whether a person is prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm by Federal or State law, by the State or any other agency, or any other records relevant to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, that the Director considers to be best practices.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013 to complete the studies, evaluations, and reports required under this section.


(Pub. L. 110–180, title II, § 201, Jan. 8, 2008, 121 Stat. 2570.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified in a note under section 922 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40931_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Evaluation required The Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics (referred to in this section as the “Director”) shall study and evaluate the operations of the National Instant Criminal Background Check System. Such study and evaluation shall include compilations and analyses of the operations and record systems of the agencies and organizations necessary to support such System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40931_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report on grants Not later than January 31 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress a report containing the estimates submitted by the States under section 40912(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40931_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report on best practices Not later than January 31 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress, and to each State participating in the National Criminal History Improvement Program, a report of the practices of the States regarding the collection, maintenance, automation, and transmittal of information relevant to determining whether a person is prohibited from possessing or receiving a firearm by Federal or State law, by the State or any other agency, or any other records relevant to the National Instant Criminal Background Check System, that the Director considers to be best practices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40931_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013 to complete the studies, evaluations, and reports required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>