<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/41304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/41304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/41304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41304"><akn:num>41304</akn:num><akn:heading>Family and domestic violence: data collection and reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41304. Family and domestic violence: data collection and reporting(a) Family violence reportingUnder the authority of section 534 of title 28, the Attorney General shall require, and include in uniform crime reports, data that indicate—(1) the age of the victim; and

(2) the relationship of the victim to the offender, for crimes of murder, aggravated assault, simple assault, rape, sexual offenses, and offenses against children.


(b) National Crime SurveyThe Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics, through the annual National Crime Survey, shall collect and publish data that more accurately measures the extent of domestic violence in America, especially the physical and sexual abuse of children and the elderly.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated in fiscal years 1989, 1990, 1991, and 1992, such sums as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.


(Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7609, Nov. 18, 1988, 102 Stat. 4517.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified as a note under section 534 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family violence reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Family violence reporting Under the authority of section 534 of title 28, the Attorney General shall require, and include in uniform crime reports, data that indicate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Crime Survey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National Crime Survey The Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics, through the annual National Crime Survey, shall collect and publish data that more accurately measures the extent of domestic violence in America, especially the physical and sexual abuse of children and the elderly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated in fiscal years 1989, 1990, 1991, and 1992, such sums as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>