<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/41313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/41313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/41313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41313"><akn:num>41313</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO study on incidence of fatal and non-fatal physical and sexual assault of passengers, TNC drivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41313. GAO study on incidence of fatal and non-fatal physical and sexual assault of passengers, TNC drivers, and drivers of other for-hire vehicles(a) GAO reportNot later than 1 year after January 5, 2023, and every 2 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that includes the results of a study regarding—(1) the incidence of fatal and non-fatal physical assault and sexual assault perpetrated in the preceding 2 calendar years (starting with calendar years 2019 and 2020 for the first study)—(A) against TNC drivers and drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs) by passengers and riders of for-hire vehicles; and

(B) against passengers and riders by other passengers and TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs), including the incidences that are committed by individuals who are not TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles but who pose as TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles;


(2) the nature and specifics of any background checks conducted on prospective TNC drivers and drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs), including any State and local laws requiring those background checks; and

(3) the safety steps taken by transportation network companies and other for-hire vehicle services (including taxicab companies) related to rider and driver safety.


(b) Sexual assault definedIn this section, the term “sexual assault” means the occurrence of an act that constitutes any nonconsensual sexual act proscribed by Federal, Tribal, or State law, including when the victim lacks capacity to consent.


(Pub. L. 117–330, § 2, Jan. 5, 2023, 136 Stat. 6114.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) GAO report Not later than 1 year after January 5, 2023, and every 2 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that includes the results of a study regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sexual assault defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sexual assault defined In this section, the term “sexual assault” means the occurrence of an act that constitutes any nonconsensual sexual act proscribed by Federal, Tribal, or State law, including when the victim lacks capacity to consent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>