<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/41507" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/41507/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/41507/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41507"><akn:num>41507</akn:num><akn:heading>National Gang Intelligence Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41507. National Gang Intelligence Center(a) EstablishmentThe Attorney General shall establish a National Gang Intelligence Center and gang information database to be housed at and administered by the Federal Bureau of Investigation to collect, analyze, and disseminate gang activity information from—(1) the Federal Bureau of Investigation;

(2) the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives;

(3) the Drug Enforcement Administration;

(4) the Bureau of Prisons;

(5) the United States Marshals Service;

(6) the Directorate of Border and Transportation Security of the Department of Homeland Security;

(7) the Department of Housing and Urban Development;

(8) the Office of Justice Services of the Bureau of Indian Affairs;

(9) tribal, State, and local law enforcement;

(10) Federal, tribal, State, and local prosecutors;

(11) Federal, tribal, State, and local probation and parole offices;

(12) Federal, tribal, State, and local prisons and jails; and

(13) any other entity as appropriate.


(b) InformationThe Center established under subsection (a) shall make available the information referred to in subsection (a) to—(1) Federal, tribal, State, and local law enforcement agencies;

(2) Federal, tribal, State, and local corrections agencies and penal institutions;

(3) Federal, tribal, State, and local prosecutorial agencies; and

(4) any other entity as appropriate.


(c) Annual reportThe Center established under subsection (a) shall annually submit to Congress a report on gang activity.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2006 and for each fiscal year thereafter.


(Pub. L. 109–162, title XI, § 1107, Jan. 5, 2006, 119 Stat. 3093; Pub. L. 111–211, title II, § 251(a), July 29, 2010, 124 Stat. 2297.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified as a note under section 534 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, prior to editorial reclassificatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41507_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Attorney General shall establish a National Gang Intelligence Center and gang information database to be housed at and administered by the Federal Bureau of Investigation to collect, analyze, and disseminate gang activity information from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41507_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information The Center established under subsection (a) shall make available the information referred to in subsection (a) to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41507_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual report The Center established under subsection (a) shall annually submit to Congress a report on gang activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41507_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2006 and for each fiscal year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>