<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/50301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/50301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/50301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50301"><akn:num>50301</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50301. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Federal agency headThe term “Federal agency head” means the head of any executive, legislative, or judicial branch Government entity that employs Federal law enforcement officers.


(2) Federal BoardThe term “Federal Board” means the Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board established under section 50313(a) of this title.


(3) Federal Board membersThe term “Federal Board members” means the members of the Federal Board appointed under section 50313(c) of this title.


(4) Federal Law Enforcement BadgeThe term “Federal Law Enforcement Badge” means the Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery described in section 50311 of this title.


(5) Federal law enforcement officerThe term “Federal law enforcement officer”—(A) means a Federal employee—(i) who has statutory authority to make arrests or apprehensions;

(ii) who is authorized by the agency of the employee to carry firearms; and

(iii) whose duties are primarily—(I) engagement in or supervision of the prevention, detection, investigation, or prosecution of, or the incarceration of any person for, any violation of law; or

(II) the protection of Federal, State, local, or foreign government officials against threats to personal safety; and



(B) includes a law enforcement officer employed by the Amtrak Police Department or Federal Reserve.


(6) OfficeThe term “Office” means the Congressional Badge of Bravery Office established under section 50331(a) of this title.


(7) State and Local BoardThe term “State and Local Board” means the State and Local Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board established under section 50323(a) of this title.


(8) State and Local Board membersThe term “State and Local Board members” means the members of the State and Local Board appointed under section 50323(c) of this title.


(9) State and Local Law Enforcement BadgeThe term “State and Local Law Enforcement Badge” means the State and Local Law Enfo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agency head</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Federal agency head The term “Federal agency head” means the head of any executive, legislative, or judicial branch Government entity that employs Federal law enforcement officers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Federal Board The term “Federal Board” means the Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board established under section 50313(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Board members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Federal Board members The term “Federal Board members” means the members of the Federal Board appointed under section 50313(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Law Enforcement Badge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Federal Law Enforcement Badge The term “Federal Law Enforcement Badge” means the Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery described in section 50311 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal law enforcement officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Federal law enforcement officer The term “Federal law enforcement officer”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Office The term “Office” means the Congressional Badge of Bravery Office established under section 50331(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and Local Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) State and Local Board The term “State and Local Board” means the State and Local Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board established under section 50323(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and Local Board members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) State and Local Board members The term “State and Local Board members” means the members of the State and Local Board appointed under section 50323(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and Local Law Enforcement Badge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) State and Local Law Enforcement Badge The term “State and Local Law Enforcement Badge” means the State and Local Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery described in section 50321 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50301_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>State or local agency head</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) State or local agency head The term “State or local agency head” means the head of any executive, legislative, or judicial branch entity of a State or local government that employs State or local law enforcement officers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>