<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/50313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/50313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/50313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50313"><akn:num>50313</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50313. Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Department of Justice a Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board.


(b) DutiesThe Federal Board shall do the following:(1) Design the Federal Law Enforcement Badge with appropriate ribbons and appurtenances.

(2) Select an engraver to produce each Federal Law Enforcement Badge.

(3) Recommend recipients of the Federal Law Enforcement Badge from among those nominations timely submitted to the Office.

(4) Annually present to the Attorney General the names of Federal law enforcement officers who the Federal Board recommends as Federal Law Enforcement Badge recipients in accordance with the criteria described in section 50312(a) of this title.

(5) After approval by the Attorney General—(A) procure the Federal Law Enforcement Badges from the engraver selected under paragraph (2);

(B) send a letter announcing the award of each Federal Law Enforcement Badge to the Federal agency head who nominated the recipient of such Federal Law Enforcement Badge;

(C) send a letter to each Member of Congress representing the congressional district where the recipient of each Federal Law Enforcement Badge resides to offer such Member an opportunity to present such Federal Law Enforcement Badge; and

(D) make or facilitate arrangements for presenting each Federal Law Enforcement Badge in accordance with section 50314 of this title.


(6) Set an annual timetable for fulfilling the duties described in this subsection.


(c) Membership(1) Number and appointmentThe Federal Board shall be composed of 7 members appointed as follows:(A) One member jointly appointed by the majority leader and minority leader of the Senate.

(B) One member jointly appointed by the Speaker and minority leader of the House of Representatives.

(C) One member from the Department of Justice appointed by the Attorney General.

(D) Two members of the Federal Law Enforcement Officer</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Department of Justice a Federal Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Federal Board shall do the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50313_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50313_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>