<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/50902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/50902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/50902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50902"><akn:num>50902</akn:num><akn:heading>Best practices and support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50902. Best practices and support(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) First responderThe term “first responder” has the meaning given the term “public safety officer” in section 10284 of this title.


(2) First responder agencyThe term “first responder agency” means a Federal, State, local, or Tribal agency that employs or otherwise engages the services of a first responder.


(3) Peer support counseling programThe term “peer support counseling program” means a program provided by a first responder agency that provides counseling services from a peer support specialist to a first responder of the first responder agency.


(4) Peer support participantThe term “peer support participant” means a first responder who receives counseling services from a peer support specialist.


(5) Peer support specialistThe term “peer support specialist” means a first responder who—(A) has received training in—(i) peer support counseling; and

(ii) providing emotional and moral support to first responders who have been involved in or exposed to an emotionally traumatic experience in the course of the duties of those first responders; and


(B) is designated by a first responder agency to provide the services described in subparagraph (A).



(b) Report on best practicesNot later than 2 years after November 18, 2021, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall develop a report on best practices and professional standards for peer support counseling programs for first responder agencies that includes—(1) advice on—(A) establishing and operating peer support counseling programs; and

(B) training and certifying peer support specialists;


(2) a code of ethics for peer support specialists;

(3) recommendations for continuing education for peer support specialists;

(4) advice on disclosing to first responders any confidentiality rights of peer support participants; and

(5) information on—(A) the different types of peer support counseling pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report on best practices Not later than 2 years after November 18, 2021, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall develop a report on best practices and professional standards for peer support counseling programs for first responder agencies that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Implementation The Attorney General shall support and encourage the implementation of peer support counseling programs in first responder agencies by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>