<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/60105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/60105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/60105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60105"><akn:num>60105</akn:num><akn:heading>State information regarding individuals who die in the custody of law enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60105. State information regarding individuals who die in the custody of law enforcement(a) In generalFor each fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in subsection (c)(1) in which a State receives funds for a program referred to in subsection (c)(2), the State shall report to the Attorney General, on a quarterly basis and pursuant to guidelines established by the Attorney General, information regarding the death of any person who is detained, under arrest, or is in the process of being arrested, is en route to be incarcerated, or is incarcerated at a municipal or county jail, State prison, State-run boot camp prison, boot camp prison that is contracted out by the State, any State or local contract facility, or other local or State correctional facility (including any juvenile facility).


(b) Information requiredThe report required by this section shall contain information that, at a minimum, includes—(1) the name, gender, race, ethnicity, and age of the deceased;

(2) the date, time, and location of death;

(3) the law enforcement agency that detained, arrested, or was in the process of arresting the deceased; and

(4) a brief description of the circumstances surrounding the death.


(c) Compliance and ineligibility(1) Compliance dateEach State shall have not more than 120 days from December 18, 2014, to comply with subsection (a), except that—(A) the Attorney General may grant an additional 120 days to a State that is making good faith efforts to comply with such subsection; and

(B) the Attorney General shall waive the requirements of subsection (a) if compliance with such subsection by a State would be unconstitutional under the constitution of such State.


(2) Ineligibility for fundsFor any fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in paragraph (1), a State that fails to comply with subsection (a), shall, at the discretion of the Attorney General, be subject to not more than a 10-percent reduction of the funds that would othe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For each fiscal year after the expiration of the period specified in subsection (c)(1) in which a State receives funds for a program referred to in subsection (c)(2), the State shall report to the Attorney General, on a quarterly basis and pursuant to guidelines established by the Attorney General, information regarding the death of any person who is detained, under arrest, or is in the process of being arrested, is en route to be incarcerated, or is incarcerated at a municipal or county jail, State prison, State-run boot camp prison, boot camp prison that is contracted out by the State, any State or local contract facility, or other local or State correctional facility (including any juvenile facility).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information required The report required by this section shall contain information that, at a minimum, includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance and ineligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compliance and ineligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60105_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reallocation Amounts not allocated under a program referred to in subsection (c)(2) to a State for failure to fully comply with subsection (a) shall be reallocated under that program to States that have not failed to comply with such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60105_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section the terms “boot camp prison” and “State” have the meaning given those terms, respectively, in section 10251(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60105_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report of information relating to deaths in custody</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Study and report of information relating to deaths in custody</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>