<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/60305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/60305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/60305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60305"><akn:num>60305</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations by Inspector General and administrative remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60305. Evaluations by Inspector General and administrative remedies(a) Evaluation by Inspector General(1) In generalAs soon as practicable after the end of the first fiscal year for which a State receives funds under a grant made under this chapter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice (in this section referred to as the “Inspector General”) shall—(A) submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report evaluating the compliance by the State with the terms and conditions of the grant; and

(B) if the Inspector General concludes that the State is not in compliance with the terms and conditions of the grant, specify any deficiencies and make recommendations to the Attorney General for corrective action.


(2) PriorityIn conducting evaluations under this subsection, the Inspector General shall give priority to States that the Inspector General determines, based on information submitted by the State and other comments provided by any other person, to be at the highest risk of noncompliance.


(3) Determination for statutory procedure StatesFor each State that employs a statutory procedure described in section 60301(e)(1)(C) of this title, the Inspector General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, not later than the end of the first fiscal year for which such State receives funds, a determination as to whether the State is in substantial compliance with the requirements of the applicable State statute.


(4) Comments from publicThe Inspector General shall receive and consider comments from any member of the public regarding any State’s compliance with the terms and conditions of a grant made under this chapter. To facilitate the receipt of such comments, the Inspector General shall maintain on its website a form that any member of the public may submit, either electronically or otherwise,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation by Inspector General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Evaluation by Inspector General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrative review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for noncompliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Penalties for noncompliance If the State fails to take the prescribed corrective action under subsection (b) and is not in compliance with the terms and conditions of the grant, the Attorney General shall discontinue all further funding under sections 60301 and 60302 of this title and require the State to return the funds granted under such sections for that fiscal year. Nothing in this paragraph shall prevent a State which has been subject to penalties for noncompliance from reapplying for a grant under this chapter in another fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60305_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Periodic reports During the grant period, the Inspector General shall periodically review the compliance of each State with the terms and conditions of the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60305_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administrative costs Not less than 2.5 percent of the funds appropriated to carry out this chapter for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2009 shall be made available to the Inspector General for purposes of carrying out this section. Such sums shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60305_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for “statutory procedure” States not in substantial compliance with statutory procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rule for “statutory procedure” States not in substantial compliance with statutory procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>