<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/61101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/61101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/34/61101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_61101"><akn:num>61101</akn:num><akn:heading>Bridging Immigration-related Deficits Experienced Nationwide Reimbursement Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 61101. Bridging Immigration-related Deficits Experienced Nationwide Reimbursement Fund(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Department of Justice a fund, to be known as the “Bridging Immigration-related Deficits Experienced Nationwide (BIDEN) Reimbursement Fund” (referred to in this section as the “Fund”).


(b) Use of fundsThe Attorney General shall use amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for the Fund for grants to eligible States, State agencies, and units of local government, pursuant to their existing statutory authorities, for any of the following purposes:(1) Locating and apprehending aliens who have committed a crime under Federal, State, or local law, in addition to being unlawfully present in the United States.

(2) Collection and analysis of law enforcement investigative information within the United States to counter gang or other criminal activity.

(3) Investigating and prosecuting—(A) crimes committed by aliens within the United States; and

(B) drug and human trafficking crimes committed within the United States.


(4) Court operations related to the prosecution of—(A) crimes committed by aliens; and

(B) drug and human trafficking crimes.


(5) Temporary criminal detention of aliens.

(6) Transporting aliens described in paragraph (1) within the United States to locations related to the apprehension, detention, and prosecution of such aliens.

(7) Vehicle maintenance, logistics, transportation, and other support provided to law enforcement agencies by a State agency to enhance the ability to locate and apprehend aliens who have committed crimes under Federal, State, or local law, in addition to being unlawfully present in the United States.


(c) AppropriationIn addition to amounts otherwise available for the purposes described in subsection (b), there is appropriated to the Attorney General for fiscal year 2025, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, not to exceed $3,500,000,000, to remain available un</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_61101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Department of Justice a fund, to be known as the “Bridging Immigration-related Deficits Experienced Nationwide (BIDEN) Reimbursement Fund” (referred to in this section as the “Fund”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_61101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds The Attorney General shall use amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for the Fund for grants to eligible States, State agencies, and units of local government, pursuant to their existing statutory authorities, for any of the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_61101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appropriation In addition to amounts otherwise available for the purposes described in subsection (b), there is appropriated to the Attorney General for fiscal year 2025, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, not to exceed $3,500,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028, for the Fund for qualified and documented expenses that achieve any such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_61101_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant eligibility of completed, ongoing, or new activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant eligibility of completed, ongoing, or new activities The Attorney General may provide grants under this section to State agencies and units of local government for expenditures made by State agencies or units of local government for completed, ongoing, or new activities determined to be eligible for such grant funding that occurred on or after January 20, 2021. Amounts made available under this section shall be distributed to more than 1 State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>