<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1305"><akn:num>1305</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal jurisdiction in Alaska</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1305. Tribal jurisdiction in Alaska(a) In generalSubject to title II of Public Law 90–284 (25 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.) (commonly known as the “Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968”), Congress recognizes and affirms the inherent authority of any Indian tribe occupying a Village in the State to exercise criminal and civil jurisdiction over all Indians present in the Village.


(b) Tribal civil jurisdiction to enforce protection orders(1) In generalA court of any Indian tribe in the State shall have full civil jurisdiction to issue and enforce protection orders involving any person in matters—(A) arising within the Village of the Indian tribe; or

(B) otherwise within the authority of the Indian tribe.


(2) InclusionsThe full civil jurisdiction to issue and enforce protection orders under paragraph (1) includes the authority to enforce protection orders through—(A) civil contempt proceedings;

(B) exclusion of violators from the Village of the Indian tribe; and

(C) other appropriate mechanisms.



(c) Special Tribal criminal jurisdiction(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, in addition to all powers of self-government recognized and affirmed under subsection (a), the powers of self-government of a participating Tribe include the inherent power of the participating Tribe, which is hereby recognized and affirmed, to exercise special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over a defendant for a covered crime that occurs in the Village of the participating Tribe.


(2) Concurrent jurisdictionThe exercise of special Tribal criminal jurisdiction by a participating Tribe shall be concurrent with the jurisdiction of the United States, the State, or both.


(3) Exception if victim and defendant are both non-Indians(A) In generalA participating Tribe may not exercise special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over an alleged offense of a covered crime, other than obstruction of justice or assault of Tribal justice personnel, if neither the defendant nor the alleged victim is an I</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to title II of Public Law 90–284 (25 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.) (commonly known as the “Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968”), Congress recognizes and affirms the inherent authority of any Indian tribe occupying a Village in the State to exercise criminal and civil jurisdiction over all Indians present in the Village.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal civil jurisdiction to enforce protection orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tribal civil jurisdiction to enforce protection orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Tribal criminal jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special Tribal criminal jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot program for special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over persons who are not Indians</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Pilot program for special Tribal criminal jurisdiction over persons who are not Indians</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sentences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sentences In a criminal proceeding in which an Indian court of a participating Tribe, in exercising special Tribal criminal jurisdiction with respect to a covered crime, imposes a sentence of imprisonment of more than 1 year on a defendant pursuant to section 202(b) of Public Law 90–284 (25 U.S.C. 1302(b)) (commonly known as the “Indian Civil Rights Act of 1968”), the Indian court may require the defendant—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Memoranda of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Memoranda of agreement The Attorney General and the Secretary of the Interior may enter into such memoranda of agreement with participating Tribes and the State as are necessary and appropriate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alaska Tribal Public Safety Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Alaska Tribal Public Safety Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report to Congress Not later than 5 years after March 15, 2022, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and affected Indian tribes, shall submit to Congress a report describing the results of the pilot program, including an explanation of any modifications to law necessary to facilitate improved law enforcement in Villages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Applicability Nothing in this subtitle—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>