<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/13a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/13a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/13a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13a"><akn:num>13a</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryover funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13a. Carryover funding
Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any funds appropriated pursuant to section 13 of this title, for any fiscal year which are not obligated or expended prior to the beginning of the fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year for which such funds were appropriated shall remain available for obligation or expenditures during such succeeding fiscal year. In the case of amounts made available to a tribal organization under a self-determination contract, if the funds are to be expended in the succeeding fiscal year for the purpose for which they were originally appropriated, contracted or granted, or for which they are authorized to be used pursuant to the provisions of section 5325(a)(3) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, no additional justification or documentation of such purposes need be provided by the tribal organization to the Secretary as a condition of receiving or expending such funds.
(Pub. L. 93–638, § 8, Jan. 4, 1975, 88 Stat. 2206; Pub. L. 100–472, title I, § 105, Oct. 5, 1988, 102 Stat. 2287.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 5325(a)(3) of this title, referred to in text, was repealed and a new subsec. (a)(3) of section 5325 was added by Pub. L. 103–413, title I, § 102(14)(C), Oct. 25, 1994, 108 Stat. 4257. See section 5325(a)(4) of this title.

Amendments1988—Pub. L. 100–472 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “The provisions of any other laws to the contrary notwithstanding, any funds appropriated pursuant to section 13 of this title, for any fiscal year which are not obligated and expended prior to the beginning of the fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year for which such funds were appropriated shall remain available for obligation and expenditure during such succeeding fiscal year.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>