<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/155b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/155b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/155b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_155b"><akn:num>155b</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeds of labor accounts; deposits limited to funds held in trust for Indian tribes or individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 155b. Proceeds of labor accounts; deposits limited to funds held in trust for Indian tribes or individuals
Except in the case of funds held in trust for Indian tribes or individuals, the funds available for expenditure under the “Indian moneys, proceeds of labor” accounts authorized by section 155 of this title may be expended until September 30, 1982 for any purpose for which funds are appropriated under the subheading “Operation of Indian Programs”.
No funds shall be deposited in such “Indian money, proceeds of labor” (IMPL) accounts after September 30, 1982. The unobligated balance in IMPL accounts as of the close of business on September 30, 1982, including the income resulting from the investment of funds from such accounts prior to such date, shall be transferred to and held in escrow accounts at the locations of the IMPL accounts from which they are transferred. Funds in such escrow accounts may be invested as provided in section 162a of this title and the investment income added to such accounts. The Secretary shall determine no later than September 30, 1985 (after consultation with appropriate tribes and individual Indians) the extent to which the funds held in such escrow accounts represent income from the investment of special deposits relating to specific tribes or individual Indians. Upon such a determination by the Secretary and express acceptance of the determination by the beneficiary, the Secretary shall transfer such funds to trust accounts for such tribes or individual Indians. Not more than ten percent of the funds transferred to trust accounts for any tribe or individual Indian under this provision may be utilized to pay for legal or other representation relating to claims for such funds. Not to exceed two percent of the funds transferred from the IMPL accounts shall be available to reimburse the Bureau of Indian Affairs for administrative expenses incurred in determining ownership of the funds. Acceptance of a determination by the Secretary a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>