<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1614" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1614/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1614/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1614"><akn:num>1614</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian health service extern programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1614. Indian health service extern programs(a) Employment of scholarship grantees during non­academic periodsAny individual who receives a scholarship grant pursuant to section 1613a of this title shall be entitled to employment in the Service during any nonacademic period of the year. Periods of employment pursuant to this subsection shall not be counted in determining the fulfillment of the service obligation incurred as a condition of the scholarship grant.


(b) Employment of medical and other students during nonacademic periodsAny individual enrolled in a course of study in the health professions may be employed by the Service during any nonacademic period of the year. Any such employment shall not exceed one hundred and twenty days during any calendar year.


(c) Employment without regard to competitive personnel system or agency personnel limitation; compensationAny employment pursuant to this section shall be made without regard to any competitive personnel system or agency personnel limitation and to a position which will enable the individual so employed to receive practical experience in the health profession in which he or she is engaged in study. Any individual so employed shall receive payment for his or her services comparable to the salary he or she would receive if he or she were employed in the competitive system. Any individual so employed shall not be counted against any employment ceiling affecting the Service or the Department of Health and Human Services.


(Pub. L. 94–437, title I, § 105, Sept. 30, 1976, 90 Stat. 1404; Pub. L. 95–83, title III, § 307(n)(2), Aug. 1, 1977, 91 Stat. 393; Pub. L. 96–537, § 3(c), Dec. 17, 1980, 94 Stat. 3174; Pub. L. 100–713, title I, § 103, Nov. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 4786; Pub. L. 102–573, title I, §§ 102(e), 117(b)(2), title IX, § 902(2)(B), Oct. 29, 1992, 106 Stat. 4532, 4544, 4591.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1992—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 102–573, § 102(e)(1), substituted “section 1613a of this title” for “section</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1614_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of scholarship grantees during non­academic periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employment of scholarship grantees during non­academic periods Any individual who receives a scholarship grant pursuant to section 1613a of this title shall be entitled to employment in the Service during any nonacademic period of the year. Periods of employment pursuant to this subsection shall not be counted in determining the fulfillment of the service obligation incurred as a condition of the scholarship grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1614_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of medical and other students during nonacademic periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Employment of medical and other students during nonacademic periods Any individual enrolled in a course of study in the health professions may be employed by the Service during any nonacademic period of the year. Any such employment shall not exceed one hundred and twenty days during any calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1614_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment without regard to competitive personnel system or agency personnel limitation; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Employment without regard to competitive personnel system or agency personnel limitation; compensation Any employment pursuant to this section shall be made without regard to any competitive personnel system or agency personnel limitation and to a position which will enable the individual so employed to receive practical experience in the health profession in which he or she is engaged in study. Any individual so employed shall receive payment for his or her services comparable to the salary he or she would receive if he or she were employed in the competitive system. Any individual so employed shall not be counted against any employment ceiling affecting the Service or the Department of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>