<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1616h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1616h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1616h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1616h"><akn:num>1616h</akn:num><akn:heading>Health training programs of community colleges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1616h. Health training programs of community colleges(a) Grants(1) The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall award grants to community colleges for the purpose of assisting the community college in the establishment of programs which provide education in a health profession leading to a degree or diploma in a health profession for individuals who desire to practice such profession on an Indian reservation or in a tribal clinic.

(2) The amount of any grant awarded to a community college under paragraph (1) for the first year in which such a grant is provided to the community college shall not exceed $100,000.


(b) Eligibility(1) The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall award grants to community colleges that have established a program described in subsection (a)(1) for the purpose of maintaining the program and recruiting students for the program.

(2) Grants may only be made under this section to a community college which—(A) is accredited,

(B) has access to a hospital facility, Service facility, or hospital that could provide training of nurses or health professionals,

(C) has entered into an agreement with an accredited college or university medical school, the terms of which—(i) provide a program that enhances the transition and recruitment of students into advanced baccalaureate or graduate programs which train health professionals, and

(ii) stipulate certifications necessary to approve internship and field placement opportunities at service unit facilities of the Service or at tribal health facilities,


(D) has a qualified staff which has the appropriate certifications, and

(E) is capable of obtaining State or regional accreditation of the program described in subsection (a)(1).



(c) Agreements and technical assistanceThe Secretary shall encourage community colleges described in subsection (b)(2) to establish and maintain programs described in subsection (a)(1) by—(1) entering into agreements with such colleges for the provision of qua</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreements and technical assistance The Secretary shall encourage community colleges described in subsection (b)(2) to establish and maintain programs described in subsection (a)(1) by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Advanced training Any program receiving assistance under this section that is conducted with respect to a health profession shall also offer courses of study which provide advanced training for any health professional who— Such courses of study may be offered in conjunction with the college or university with which the community college has entered into the agreement required under subsection (b)(2)(C).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>