<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1616m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1616m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1616m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1616m"><akn:num>1616m</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching grants to tribes for scholarship programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1616m. Matching grants to tribes for scholarship programs(a) In general(1) The Secretary shall make grants to Indian tribes and tribal organizations for the purpose of assisting such tribes and tribal organizations in educating Indians to serve as health professionals in Indian communities.

(2) Amounts available for grants under paragraph (1) for any fiscal year shall not exceed 5 percent of amounts available for such fiscal year for Indian Health Scholarships under section 1613a of this title.

(3) An application for a grant under paragraph (1) shall be in such form and contain such agreements, assurances, and information as the Secretary determines are necessary to carry out this section.


(b) Compliance with requirements(1) An Indian tribe or tribal organization receiving a grant under subsection (a) shall agree to provide scholarships to Indians pursuing education in the health professions in accordance with the requirements of this section.

(2) With respect to the costs of providing any scholarship pursuant to paragraph (1)—(A) 80 percent of the costs of the scholarship shall be paid from the grant made under subsection (a) to the Indian tribe or tribal organization; and

(B) 20 percent of such costs shall be paid from non-Federal contributions by the Indian tribe or tribal organization through which the scholarship is provided.


(3) In determining the amount of non-Federal contributions that have been provided for purposes of subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2), any amounts provided by the Federal Government to the Indian tribe or tribal organization involved or to any other entity shall not be included.

(4) Non-Federal contributions required by subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2) may be provided directly by the Indian tribe or tribal organization involved or through donations from public and private entities.


(c) Course of study in health professionsAn Indian tribe or tribal organization shall provide scholarships under subsection (b) only to Indians enr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compliance with requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Course of study in health professions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Course of study in health professions An Indian tribe or tribal organization shall provide scholarships under subsection (b) only to Indians enrolled or accepted for enrollment in a course of study (approved by the Secretary) in one of the health professions described in section 1613a(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contract requirements In providing scholarships under subsection (b), the Secretary and the Indian tribe or tribal organization shall enter into a written contract with each recipient of such scholarship. Such contract shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616m_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Breach of contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Breach of contract</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616m_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscriminatory practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nondiscriminatory practice The recipient of a scholarship under subsection (b) shall agree, in providing health care pursuant to the requirements of subsection (d)(1)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616m_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments for subsequent fiscal years</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payments for subsequent fiscal years The Secretary may not make any payments under subsection (a) to an Indian tribe or tribal organization for any fiscal year subsequent to the first fiscal year of such payments unless the Secretary determines that, for the immediately preceding fiscal year, the Indian tribe or tribal organization has complied with requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>