<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1616a–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1616a–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1616a–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1616a_1"><akn:num>1616a–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarship and Loan Repayment Recovery Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1616a–1. Scholarship and Loan Repayment Recovery Fund(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the Indian Health Scholarship and Loan Repayment Recovery Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Fund”). The Fund shall consist of such amounts as may be appropriated to the Fund under subsection (b). Amounts appropriated for the Fund shall remain available until expended.


(b) Authorization of appropriationsFor each fiscal year, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund an amount equal to the sum of—(1) the amount collected during the preceding fiscal year by the Federal Government pursuant to—(A) the liability of individuals under subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 1613a(b)(5) of this title for the breach of contracts entered into under section 1613a of this title; and

(B) the liability of individuals under section 1616a(l) of this title for the breach of contracts entered into under section 1616a of this title; and


(2) the aggregate amount of interest accruing during the preceding fiscal year on obligations held in the Fund pursuant to subsection (d) and the amount of proceeds from the sale or redemption of such obligations during such fiscal year.


(c) Use of funds(1) Amounts in the Fund and available pursuant to appropriation Acts may be expended by the Secretary, acting through the Service, to make payments to an Indian tribe or tribal organization administering a health care program pursuant to a contract entered into under the Indian Self-Determination Act [25 U.S.C. 5321 et seq.]—(A) to which a scholarship recipient under section 1613a of this title or a loan repayment program participant under section 1616a of this title has been assigned to meet the obligated service requirements pursuant to 11 So in original. Probably should be “to such”. sections; and

(B) that has a need for a health professional to provide health care services as a result of such recipient or participant havi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616a_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the Indian Health Scholarship and Loan Repayment Recovery Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Fund”). The Fund shall consist of such amounts as may be appropriated to the Fund under subsection (b). Amounts appropriated for the Fund shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616a_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations For each fiscal year, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund an amount equal to the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616a_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1616a_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of excess funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Investment of excess funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>