<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1621a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1621a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1621a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1621a"><akn:num>1621a</akn:num><akn:heading>Catastrophic Health Emergency Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1621a. Catastrophic Health Emergency Fund(a) EstablishmentThere is established an Indian Catastrophic Health Emergency Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “CHEF”) consisting of—(1) the amounts deposited under subsection (f); and

(2) the amounts appropriated to CHEF under this section.


(b) AdministrationCHEF shall be administered by the Secretary, acting through the headquarters of the Service, solely for the purpose of meeting the extraordinary medical costs associated with the treatment of victims of disasters or catastrophic illnesses who are within the responsibility of the Service.


(c) Conditions on use of FundNo part of CHEF or its administration shall be subject to contract or grant under any law, including the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. nor shall CHEF funds be allocated, apportioned, or delegated on an Area Office, Service Unit, or other similar basis.


(d) RegulationsThe Secretary shall promulgate regulations consistent with the provisions of this section to—(1) establish a definition of disasters and catastrophic illnesses for which the cost of the treatment provided under contract would qualify for payment from CHEF;

(2) provide that a Service Unit shall not be eligible for reimbursement for the cost of treatment from CHEF until its cost of treating any victim of such catastrophic illness or disaster has reached a certain threshold cost which the Secretary shall establish at—(A) the 2000 level of $19,000; and

(B) for any subsequent year, not less than the threshold cost of the previous year increased by the percentage increase in the medical care expenditure category of the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for the 12-month period ending with December of the previous year;


(3) establish a procedure for the reimbursement of the portion of the costs that exceeds such threshold cost incurred by—(A) Servic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established an Indian Catastrophic Health Emergency Fund (hereafter in this section referred to as the “CHEF”) consisting of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration CHEF shall be administered by the Secretary, acting through the headquarters of the Service, solely for the purpose of meeting the extraordinary medical costs associated with the treatment of victims of disasters or catastrophic illnesses who are within the responsibility of the Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions on use of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Conditions on use of Fund No part of CHEF or its administration shall be subject to contract or grant under any law, including the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. nor shall CHEF funds be allocated, apportioned, or delegated on an Area Office, Service Unit, or other similar basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations The Secretary shall promulgate regulations consistent with the provisions of this section to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No offset or limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No offset or limitation Amounts appropriated to CHEF under this section shall not be used to offset or limit appropriations made to the Service under the authority of section 13 of this title, or any other law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of reimbursement funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Deposit of reimbursement funds There shall be deposited into CHEF all reimbursements to which the Service is entitled from any Federal, State, local, or private source (including third party insurance) by reason of treatment rendered to any victim of a disaster or catastrophic illness the cost of which was paid from CHEF.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>