<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1621e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1621e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1621e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1621e"><akn:num>1621e</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement from certain third parties of costs of health services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1621e. Reimbursement from certain third parties of costs of health services(a) Right of recoveryExcept as provided in subsection (f), the United States, an Indian tribe, or tribal organization shall have the right to recover from an insurance company, health maintenance organization, employee benefit plan, third-party tortfeasor, or any other responsible or liable third party (including a political subdivision or local governmental entity of a State) the reasonable charges billed by the Secretary, an Indian tribe, or tribal organization in providing health services through the Service, an Indian tribe, or tribal organization, or, if higher, the highest amount the third party would pay for care and services furnished by providers other than governmental entities, to any individual to the same extent that such individual, or any nongovernmental provider of such services, would be eligible to receive damages, reimbursement, or indemnification for such charges or expenses if—(1) such services had been provided by a nongovernmental provider; and

(2) such individual had been required to pay such charges or expenses and did pay such charges or expenses.


(b) Limitations on recoveries from StatesSubsection (a) shall provide a right of recovery against any State, only if the injury, illness, or disability for which health services were provided is covered under—(1) workers’ compensation laws; or

(2) a no-fault automobile accident insurance plan or program.


(c) Nonapplicability of other lawsNo law of any State, or of any political subdivision of a State and no provision of any contract, insurance or health maintenance organization policy, employee benefit plan, self-insurance plan, managed care plan, or other health care plan or program entered into or renewed after November 23, 1988, shall prevent or hinder the right of recovery of the United States, an Indian tribe, or tribal organization under subsection (a).


(d) No effect on private rights of actionNo action take</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of recovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Right of recovery Except as provided in subsection (f), the United States, an Indian tribe, or tribal organization shall have the right to recover from an insurance company, health maintenance organization, employee benefit plan, third-party tortfeasor, or any other responsible or liable third party (including a political subdivision or local governmental entity of a State) the reasonable charges billed by the Secretary, an Indian tribe, or tribal organization in providing health services through the Service, an Indian tribe, or tribal organization, or, if higher, the highest amount the third party would pay for care and services furnished by providers other than governmental entities, to any individual to the same extent that such individual, or any nongovernmental provider of such services, would be eligible to receive damages, reimbursement, or indemnification for such charges or expenses if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on recoveries from States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations on recoveries from States Subsection (a) shall provide a right of recovery against any State, only if the injury, illness, or disability for which health services were provided is covered under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nonapplicability of other laws No law of any State, or of any political subdivision of a State and no provision of any contract, insurance or health maintenance organization policy, employee benefit plan, self-insurance plan, managed care plan, or other health care plan or program entered into or renewed after November 23, 1988, shall prevent or hinder the right of recovery of the United States, an Indian tribe, or tribal organization under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No effect on private rights of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No effect on private rights of action No action taken by the United States, an Indian tribe, or tribal organization to enforce the right of recovery provided under this section shall operate to deny to the injured person the recovery for that portion of the person’s damage not covered hereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation Absent specific written authorization by the governing body of an Indian tribe for the period of such authorization (which may not be for a period of more than 1 year and which may be revoked at any time upon written notice by the governing body to the Service), the United States shall not have a right of recovery under this section if the injury, illness, or disability for which health services were provided is covered under a self-insurance plan funded by an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization. Where such authorization is provided, the Service may receive and expend such amounts for the provision of additional health services consistent with such authorization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs and attorney’s fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Costs and attorney’s fees In any action brought to enforce the provisions of this section, a prevailing plaintiff shall be awarded its reasonable attorney’s fees and costs of litigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of claims filing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Nonapplicability of claims filing requirements An insurance company, health maintenance organization, self-insurance plan, managed care plan, or other health care plan or program (under the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.] or otherwise) may not deny a claim for benefits submitted by the Service or by an Indian tribe or tribal organization based on the format in which the claim is submitted if such format complies with the format required for submission of claims under title XVIII of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.] or recognized under section 1175 of such Act [42 U.S.C. 1320d–4].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to urban Indian organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Application to urban Indian organizations The previous provisions of this section shall apply to urban Indian organizations with respect to populations served by such Organizations 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. in the same manner they apply to Indian tribes and tribal organizations with respect to populations served by such Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621e_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statute of limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Statute of limitations The provisions of section 2415 of title 28 shall apply to all actions commenced under this section, and the references therein to the United States are deemed to include Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>