<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1621q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1621q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1621q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1621q"><akn:num>1621q</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention, control, and elimination of communicable and infectious diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1621q. Prevention, control, and elimination of communicable and infectious diseases(a) Grants authorizedThe Secretary, acting through the Service, and after consultation with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants available to Indian tribes and tribal organizations for the following:(1) Projects for the prevention, control, and elimination of communicable and infectious diseases, including tuberculosis, hepatitis, HIV, respiratory syncytial virus, hanta virus, sexually transmitted diseases, and H. pylori.

(2) Public information and education programs for the prevention, control, and elimination of communicable and infectious diseases.

(3) Education, training, and clinical skills improvement activities in the prevention, control, and elimination of communicable and infectious diseases for health professionals, including allied health professionals.

(4) Demonstration projects for the screening, treatment, and prevention of hepatitis C virus (HCV).


(b) Application requiredThe Secretary may provide funding under subsection (a) only if an application or proposal for funding is submitted to the Secretary.


(c) Coordination with health agenciesIndian tribes and tribal organizations receiving funding under this section are encouraged to coordinate their activities with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and State and local health agencies.


(d) Technical assistance; reportIn carrying out this section, the Secretary—(1) may, at the request of an Indian tribe or tribal organization, provide technical assistance; and

(2) shall prepare and submit a report to Congress biennially on the use of funds under this section and on the progress made toward the prevention, control, and elimination of communicable and infectious diseases among Indians and urban Indians.


(Pub. L. 94–437, title II, § 218, as added Pub. L. 102–573, title II, § 214, Oct. 29, 1992, 106 Stat. 4556; amended Pub. L. 103–437, § 10(e)(1), (2)(B), Nov. 2, 1994, 108 St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized The Secretary, acting through the Service, and after consultation with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants available to Indian tribes and tribal organizations for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application required The Secretary may provide funding under subsection (a) only if an application or proposal for funding is submitted to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with health agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination with health agencies Indian tribes and tribal organizations receiving funding under this section are encouraged to coordinate their activities with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and State and local health agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1621q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance; report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance; report In carrying out this section, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>