<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1632" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1632/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1632/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1632"><akn:num>1632</akn:num><akn:heading>Safe water and sanitary waste disposal facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1632. Safe water and sanitary waste disposal facilities(a) Congressional findingsThe Congress hereby finds and declares that—(1) the provision of safe water supply systems and sanitary sewage and solid waste disposal systems is primarily a health consideration and function;

(2) Indian people suffer an inordinately high incidence of disease, injury, and illness directly attributable to the absence or inadequacy of such systems;

(3) the long-term cost to the United States of treating and curing such disease, injury, and illness is substantially greater than the short-term cost of providing such systems and other preventive health measures;

(4) many Indian homes and communities still lack safe water supply systems and sanitary sewage and solid waste disposal systems; and

(5) it is in the interest of the United States, and it is the policy of the United States, that all Indian communities and Indian homes, new and existing, be provided with safe and adequate water supply systems and sanitary sewage waste disposal systems as soon as possible.


(b) Authority; assistance; transfer of funds(1) In furtherance of the findings and declarations made in subsection (a), Congress reaffirms the primary responsibility and authority of the Service to provide the necessary sanitation facilities and services as provided in section 2004a of title 42.

(2) The Secretary, acting through the Service, is authorized to provide under section 2004a of title 42—(A) financial and technical assistance to Indian tribes and communities in the establishment, training, and equipping of utility organizations to operate and maintain Indian sanitation facilities;

(B) ongoing technical assistance and training in the management of utility organizations which operate and maintain sanitation facilities; and

(C) operation and maintenance assistance for, and emergency repairs to, tribal sanitation facilities when necessary to avoid a health hazard or to protect the Federal investment in sanitation fa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings The Congress hereby finds and declares that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority; assistance; transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority; assistance; transfer of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>10-year plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) 10-year plan Beginning in fiscal year 1990, the Secretary, acting through the Service, shall develop and begin implementation of a 10-year plan to provide safe water supply and sanitation sewage and solid waste disposal facilities to existing Indian homes and communities and to new and renovated Indian homes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal capability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tribal capability The financial and technical capability of an Indian tribe or community to safely operate and maintain a sanitation facility shall not be a prerequisite to the provision or construction of sanitation facilities by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amount of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of programs administered by Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligibility of programs administered by Indian tribes Programs administered by Indian tribes or tribal organizations under the authority of the Indian Self-Determination Act [25 U.S.C. 5321 et seq.] shall be eligible for— on an equal basis with programs that are administered directly by the Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1632_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report; sanitation deficiency levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Annual report; sanitation deficiency levels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>