<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1638a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1638a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1638a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1638a"><akn:num>1638a</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal management of federally owned quarters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1638a. Tribal management of federally owned quarters(a) Rental rates(1) EstablishmentNotwithstanding any other provision of law, a tribal health program that operates a hospital or other health facility and the federally owned quarters associated with such a facility pursuant to a contract or compact under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.) 11 See References in Text note below. may establish the rental rates charged to the occupants of those quarters, on providing notice to the Secretary.


(2) ObjectivesIn establishing rental rates under this subsection, a tribal health program shall attempt—(A) to base the rental rates on the reasonable value of the quarters to the occupants of the quarters; and

(B) to generate sufficient funds to prudently provide for the operation and maintenance of the quarters, and at the discretion of the tribal health program, to supply reserve funds for capital repairs and replacement of the quarters.


(3) Equitable fundingA federally owned quarters the rental rates for which are established by a tribal health program under this subsection shall remain eligible to receive improvement and repair funds to the same extent that all federally owned quarters used to house personnel in programs of the Service are eligible to receive those funds.


(4) Notice of rate changeA tribal health program that establishes a rental rate under this subsection shall provide occupants of the federally owned quarters a notice of any change in the rental rate by not later than the date that is 60 days notice before the effective date of the change.


(5) Rates in AlaskaA rental rate established by a tribal health program under this section for a federally owned quarters in the State of Alaska may be based on the cost of comparable private rental housing in the nearest established community with a year-round population of 1,500 or more individuals.



(b) Direct collection of rent(1) In generalNotwithstanding any</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rental rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rental rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct collection of rent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Direct collection of rent</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>