<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1638g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1638g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1638g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1638g"><akn:num>1638g</akn:num><akn:heading>Mobile health stations demonstration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1638g. Mobile health stations demonstration program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible tribal consortiumThe term “eligible tribal consortium” means a consortium composed of 2 or more Service units between which a mobile health station can be transported by road in up to 8 hours. A Service unit operated by the Service or by an Indian tribe or tribal organization shall be equally eligible for participation in such consortium.


(2) Mobile health stationThe term “mobile health station” means a health care unit that—(A) is constructed, maintained, and capable of being transported within a semi-trailer truck or similar vehicle;

(B) is equipped for the provision of 1 or more specialty health care services; and

(C) can be equipped to be docked to a stationary health care facility when appropriate.


(3) Specialty health care service(A) In generalThe term “specialty health care service” means a health care service which requires the services of a health care professional with specialized knowledge or experience.


(B) InclusionsThe term “specialty health care service” includes any service relating to—(i) dialysis;

(ii) surgery;

(iii) mammography;

(iv) dentistry; or

(v) any other specialty health care service.




(b) EstablishmentThe Secretary, acting through the Service, shall establish a demonstration program under which the Secretary shall provide at least 3 mobile health station projects.


(c) PetitionTo be eligible to receive a mobile health station under the demonstration program, an eligible tribal consortium shall submit to the Secretary, 11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. a petition at such time, in such manner, and containing—(1) a description of the Indian population to be served;

(2) a description of the specialty service or services for which the mobile health station is requested and the extent to which such service or services are currently available to the Indian population to be served; and

(3) such other information</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall establish a demonstration program under which the Secretary shall provide at least 3 mobile health station projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Petition To be eligible to receive a mobile health station under the demonstration program, an eligible tribal consortium shall submit to the Secretary, 11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. a petition at such time, in such manner, and containing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds The Secretary shall use amounts made available to carry out the demonstration program under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports Not later than 1 year after the date on which the demonstration program is established under subsection (b) and annually thereafter, the Secretary, acting through the Service, shall submit to Congress a report describing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 per year to carry out the demonstration program under this section for the first 5 fiscal years, and such sums as may be needed to carry out the program in subsequent fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>