<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1638e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1638e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1638e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1638e"><akn:num>1638e</akn:num><akn:heading>Other funding, equipment, and supplies for facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1638e. Other funding, equipment, and supplies for facilities(a) Authorization(1) Authority to transfer fundsThe head of any Federal agency to which funds, equipment, or other supplies are made available for the planning, design, construction, or operation of a health care or sanitation facility may transfer the funds, equipment, or supplies to the Secretary for the planning, design, construction, or operation of a health care or sanitation facility to achieve—(A) the purposes of this chapter; and

(B) the purposes for which the funds, equipment, or supplies were made available to the Federal agency.


(2) Authority to accept fundsThe Secretary may—(A) accept from any source, including Federal and State agencies, funds, equipment, or supplies that are available for the construction or operation of health care or sanitation facilities; and

(B) use those funds, equipment, and supplies to plan, design,,11 So in original. construct, and operate health care or sanitation facilities for Indians, including pursuant to a contract or compact under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.).22 See References in Text note below.


(3) Effect of receiptReceipt of funds by the Secretary under this subsection shall not affect any priority established under section 1631 of this title.



(b) Interagency agreementsThe Secretary may enter into interagency agreements with Federal or State agencies and other entities, and accept funds, equipment, or other supplies from those entities, to provide for the planning, design, construction, and operation of health care or sanitation facilities to be administered by Indian health programs to achieve—(1) the purposes of this chapter; and

(2) the purposes for which the funds were appropriated or otherwise provided.


(c) Establishment of standards(1) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Service, shall establish, by regulation, standards for the planning, design, construction, and operation of h</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interagency agreements The Secretary may enter into interagency agreements with Federal or State agencies and other entities, and accept funds, equipment, or other supplies from those entities, to provide for the planning, design, construction, and operation of health care or sanitation facilities to be administered by Indian health programs to achieve—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of sanitation facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definition of sanitation facility In this section, the term “sanitation facility” means a safe and adequate water supply system, sanitary sewage disposal system, or sanitary solid waste system (including all related equipment and support infrastructure).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>