<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1642" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1642/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1642/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1642"><akn:num>1642</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchasing health care coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1642. Purchasing health care coverage(a) In generalInsofar as amounts are made available under law (including a provision of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.], the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. or other law, other than under section 1644 of this title) to Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations for health benefits for Service beneficiaries, Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations may use such amounts to purchase health benefits coverage (including coverage for a service, or service within a contract health service delivery area, or any portion of a contract health service delivery area that would otherwise be provided as a contract health service) for such beneficiaries in any manner, including through—(1) a tribally owned and operated health care plan;

(2) a State or locally authorized or licensed health care plan;

(3) a health insurance provider or managed care organization;

(4) a self-insured plan; or

(5) a high deductible or health savings account plan.


(b) Financial needThe purchase of coverage under subsection (a) by an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization may be based on the financial needs of such beneficiaries (as determined by the 1 or more Indian tribes being served based on a schedule of income levels developed or implemented by such 1 ore 22 So in original. Probably should be “or”. more Indian tribes).


(c) Expenses for self-insured planIn the case of a self-insured plan under subsection (a)(4), the amounts may be used for expenses of operating the plan, including administration and insurance to limit the financial risks to the entity offering the plan.


(d) ConstructionNothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the use of any amounts not referred to in subsection (a).


(Pub. L. 94–437, title IV, § 402, Sept. 30, 1976, 90 Stat. 1409; Pub. L. 100–713</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1642_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Insofar as amounts are made available under law (including a provision of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.], the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. or other law, other than under section 1644 of this title) to Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations for health benefits for Service beneficiaries, Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and urban Indian organizations may use such amounts to purchase health benefits coverage (including coverage for a service, or service within a contract health service delivery area, or any portion of a contract health service delivery area that would otherwise be provided as a contract health service) for such beneficiaries in any manner, including through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1642_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial need</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Financial need The purchase of coverage under subsection (a) by an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization may be based on the financial needs of such beneficiaries (as determined by the 1 or more Indian tribes being served based on a schedule of income levels developed or implemented by such 1 ore 22 So in original. Probably should be “or”. more Indian tribes).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1642_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses for self-insured plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expenses for self-insured plan In the case of a self-insured plan under subsection (a)(4), the amounts may be used for expenses of operating the plan, including administration and insurance to limit the financial risks to the entity offering the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1642_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Construction Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the use of any amounts not referred to in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>