<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1647a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1647a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1647a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1647a"><akn:num>1647a</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination under Federal health care programs in qualifications for reimbursement for service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1647a. Nondiscrimination under Federal health care programs in qualifications for reimbursement for services(a) Requirement to satisfy generally applicable participation requirements(1) In generalA Federal health care program must accept an entity that is operated by the Service, an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization as a provider eligible to receive payment under the program for health care services furnished to an Indian on the same basis as any other provider qualified to participate as a provider of health care services under the program if the entity meets generally applicable State or other requirements for participation as a provider of health care services under the program.


(2) Satisfaction of State or local licensure or recognition requirementsAny requirement for participation as a provider of health care services under a Federal health care program that an entity be licensed or recognized under the State or local law where the entity is located to furnish health care services shall be deemed to have been met in the case of an entity operated by the Service, an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization if the entity meets all the applicable standards for such licensure or recognition, regardless of whether the entity obtains a license or other documentation under such State or local law. In accordance with section 1621t of this title, the absence of the licensure of a health professional employed by such an entity under the State or local law where the entity is located shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining whether the entity meets such standards, if the professional is licensed in another State.



(b) Application of exclusion from participation in Federal health care programs(1) Excluded entitiesNo entity operated by the Service, an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization that has been excluded from participation in any Federal health care program or for </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1647a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to satisfy generally applicable participation requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement to satisfy generally applicable participation requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1647a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of exclusion from participation in Federal health care programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of exclusion from participation in Federal health care programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1647a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Related provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Related provisions For provisions related to nondiscrimination against providers operated by the Service, an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or urban Indian organization, see section 1320b–9(c) 22 See References in Text note below. of title 42.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>