<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1665j"><akn:num>1665j</akn:num><akn:heading>Behavioral health program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1665j. Behavioral health program(a) Innovative programsThe Secretary, acting through the Service, consistent with section 1665a of this title, may plan, develop, implement, and carry out programs to deliver innovative community-based behavioral health services to Indians.


(b) Awards; criteriaThe Secretary may award a grant for a project under subsection (a) to an Indian tribe or tribal organization and may consider the following criteria:(1) The project will address significant unmet behavioral health needs among Indians.

(2) The project will serve a significant number of Indians.

(3) The project has the potential to deliver services in an efficient and effective manner.

(4) The Indian tribe or tribal organization has the administrative and financial capability to administer the project.

(5) The project may deliver services in a manner consistent with traditional health care practices.

(6) The project is coordinated with, and avoids duplication of, existing services.


(c) Equitable treatmentFor purposes of this subsection,11 So in original. Probably should be “section,”. the Secretary shall, in evaluating project applications or proposals, use the same criteria that the Secretary uses in evaluating any other application or proposal for such funding.


(Pub. L. 94–437, title VII, § 711, as added Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10221(a), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 935.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section 711 of Pub. L. 94–437 is based on section 181 of title I of S. 1790, One Hundred Eleventh Congress, as reported by the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate in Dec. 2009, which was enacted into law by section 10221(a) of Pub. L. 111–148.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1665j, Pub. L. 94–437, title VII, § 711, as added Pub. L. 102–573, title VII, § 702(a), Oct. 29, 1992, 106 Stat. 4580; amended Pub. L. 104–313, § 2(f), Oct. 19, 1996, 110 Stat. 3822; Pub. L. 105–244, title IX, § 901(d), Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1828; Pub. L. 105–256, § 13(a), Oct. 14, 1998, 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Innovative programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Innovative programs The Secretary, acting through the Service, consistent with section 1665a of this title, may plan, develop, implement, and carry out programs to deliver innovative community-based behavioral health services to Indians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards; criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Awards; criteria The Secretary may award a grant for a project under subsection (a) to an Indian tribe or tribal organization and may consider the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Equitable treatment For purposes of this subsection,11 So in original. Probably should be “section,”. the Secretary shall, in evaluating project applications or proposals, use the same criteria that the Secretary uses in evaluating any other application or proposal for such funding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>