<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1665"><akn:num>1665</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1665. Definitions
In this part:(1) Alcohol-related neurodevelopmental disorders; ARNDThe term “alcohol-related neurodevelopmental disorders” or “ARND” means, with a history of maternal alcohol consumption during pregnancy, central nervous system abnormalities, which may range from minor intellectual deficits and developmental delays to mental retardation. ARND children may have behavioral problems, learning disabilities, problems with executive functioning, and attention disorders. The neurological defects of ARND may be as severe as FAS, but facial anomalies and other physical characteristics are not present in ARND, thus making diagnosis difficult.


(2) AssessmentThe term “assessment” means the systematic collection, analysis, and dissemination of information on health status, health needs, and health problems.


(3) Behavioral health aftercareThe term “behavioral health aftercare” includes those activities and resources used to support recovery following inpatient, residential, intensive substance abuse, or mental health outpatient or outpatient treatment. The purpose is to help prevent or deal with relapse by ensuring that by the time a client or patient is discharged from a level of care, such as outpatient treatment, an aftercare plan has been developed with the client. An aftercare plan may use such resources as a community-based therapeutic group, transitional living facilities, a 12-step sponsor, a local 12-step or other related support group, and other community-based providers.


(4) Dual diagnosisThe term “dual diagnosis” means coexisting substance abuse and mental illness conditions or diagnosis. Such clients are sometimes referred to as mentally ill chemical abusers (MICAs).


(5) Fetal alcohol spectrum disorders(A) In generalThe term “fetal alcohol spectrum disorders” includes a range of effects that can occur in an individual whose mother drank alcohol during pregnancy, including physical, mental, behavioral, and/or learning disabilities with poss</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alcohol-related neurodevelopmental disorders; ARND</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Alcohol-related neurodevelopmental disorders; ARND The term “alcohol-related neurodevelopmental disorders” or “ARND” means, with a history of maternal alcohol consumption during pregnancy, central nervous system abnormalities, which may range from minor intellectual deficits and developmental delays to mental retardation. ARND children may have behavioral problems, learning disabilities, problems with executive functioning, and attention disorders. The neurological defects of ARND may be as severe as FAS, but facial anomalies and other physical characteristics are not present in ARND, thus making diagnosis difficult.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Assessment The term “assessment” means the systematic collection, analysis, and dissemination of information on health status, health needs, and health problems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Behavioral health aftercare</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Behavioral health aftercare The term “behavioral health aftercare” includes those activities and resources used to support recovery following inpatient, residential, intensive substance abuse, or mental health outpatient or outpatient treatment. The purpose is to help prevent or deal with relapse by ensuring that by the time a client or patient is discharged from a level of care, such as outpatient treatment, an aftercare plan has been developed with the client. An aftercare plan may use such resources as a community-based therapeutic group, transitional living facilities, a 12-step sponsor, a local 12-step or other related support group, and other community-based providers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dual diagnosis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Dual diagnosis The term “dual diagnosis” means coexisting substance abuse and mental illness conditions or diagnosis. Such clients are sometimes referred to as mentally ill chemical abusers (MICAs).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fetal alcohol spectrum disorders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Fetal alcohol spectrum disorders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>FAS or fetal alcohol syndrome</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) FAS or fetal alcohol syndrome The term “FAS” or “fetal alcohol syndrome” means a syndrome in which, with a history of maternal alcohol consumption during pregnancy, the following criteria are met:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Rehabilitation The term “rehabilitation” means medical and health care services that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substance abuse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Substance abuse The term “substance abuse” includes inhalant abuse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>