<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1665m"><akn:num>1665m</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic and sexual violence prevention and treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1665m. Domestic and sexual violence prevention and treatment(a) In generalThe Secretary, in accordance with section 1665a of this title, is authorized to establish in each Service area programs involving the prevention and treatment of—(1) Indian victims of domestic violence or sexual abuse; and

(2) other members of the household or family of the victims described in paragraph (1).


(b) Use of fundsFunds made available to carry out this section shall be used—(1) to develop and implement prevention programs and community education programs relating to domestic violence and sexual abuse;

(2) to provide behavioral health services, including victim support services, and medical treatment (including examinations performed by sexual assault nurse examiners) to Indian victims of domestic violence or sexual abuse;

(3) to purchase rape kits; and

(4) to develop prevention and intervention models, which may incorporate traditional health care practices.


(c) Training and certification(1) In generalNot later than 1 year after March 23, 2010, the Secretary shall establish appropriate protocols, policies, procedures, standards of practice, and, if not available elsewhere, training curricula and training and certification requirements for services for victims of domestic violence and sexual abuse.


(2) ReportNot later than 18 months after March 23, 2010, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report that describes the means and extent to which the Secretary has carried out paragraph (1).



(d) Coordination(1) In generalThe Secretary, in coordination with the Attorney General, Federal and tribal law enforcement agencies, Indian health programs, and domestic violence or sexual assault victim organizations, shall develop appropriate victim services and victim advocate training programs—(A) to improve domestic violence or sexual abuse responses;

(B) to improve foren</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, in accordance with section 1665a of this title, is authorized to establish in each Service area programs involving the prevention and treatment of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds Funds made available to carry out this section shall be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Training and certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>