<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1665l"><akn:num>1665l</akn:num><akn:heading>Child sexual abuse prevention and treatment programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1665l. Child sexual abuse prevention and treatment programs(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary, acting through the Service, shall establish, consistent with section 1665a of this title, in every Service area, programs involving treatment for—(1) victims of sexual abuse who are Indian children or children in an Indian household; and

(2) other members of the household or family of the victims described in paragraph (1).


(b) Use of fundsFunding provided pursuant to this section shall be used for the following:(1) To develop and provide community education and prevention programs related to sexual abuse of Indian children or children in an Indian household.

(2) To identify and provide behavioral health treatment to victims of sexual abuse who are Indian children or children in an Indian household, and to their family members who are affected by sexual abuse.

(3) To develop prevention and intervention models which incorporate traditional health care practices, cultural values, and community involvement.

(4) To develop and implement culturally sensitive assessment and diagnostic tools for use in Indian communities and urban centers.


(c) CoordinationThe programs established under subsection (a) shall be carried out in coordination with programs and services authorized under the Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention Act (25 U.S.C. 3201 et seq.).


(Pub. L. 94–437, title VII, § 713, as added Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10221(a), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 935.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is title IV of Pub. L. 101–630, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4544, which is classified principally to chapter 34 (§ 3201 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 3201 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section 713 of Pub. L. 94–437 is based on section 181 of title I of S. 1790, One Hundred Elev</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall establish, consistent with section 1665a of this title, in every Service area, programs involving treatment for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds Funding provided pursuant to this section shall be used for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination The programs established under subsection (a) shall be carried out in coordination with programs and services authorized under the Indian Child Protection and Family Violence Prevention Act (25 U.S.C. 3201 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>