<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1665a"><akn:num>1665a</akn:num><akn:heading>Behavioral health prevention and treatment services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1665a. Behavioral health prevention and treatment services(a) PurposesThe purposes of this section are as follows:(1) To authorize and direct the Secretary, acting through the Service, Indian tribes, and tribal organizations, to develop a comprehensive behavioral health prevention and treatment program which emphasizes collaboration among alcohol and substance abuse, social services, and mental health programs.

(2) To provide information, direction, and guidance relating to mental illness and dysfunction and self-destructive behavior, including child abuse and family violence, to those Federal, tribal, State, and local agencies responsible for programs in Indian communities in areas of health care, education, social services, child and family welfare, alcohol and substance abuse, law enforcement, and judicial services.

(3) To assist Indian tribes to identify services and resources available to address mental illness and dysfunctional and self-destructive behavior.

(4) To provide authority and opportunities for Indian tribes and tribal organizations to develop, implement, and coordinate with community-based programs which include identification, prevention, education, referral, and treatment services, including through multidisciplinary resource teams.

(5) To ensure that Indians, as citizens of the United States and of the States in which they reside, have the same access to behavioral health services to which all citizens have access.

(6) To modify or supplement existing programs and authorities in the areas identified in paragraph (2).


(b) Plans(1) DevelopmentThe Secretary, acting through the Service, Indian tribes, and tribal organizations, shall encourage Indian tribes and tribal organizations to develop tribal plans, and urban Indian organizations to develop local plans, and for all such groups to participate in developing areawide plans for Indian Behavioral Health Services. The plans shall include, to the extent feasible, the following components:(A) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purposes The purposes of this section are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Programs The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall provide, to the extent feasible and if funding is available, programs including the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community behavioral health plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Community behavioral health plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination for availability of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination for availability of services The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall coordinate behavioral health planning, to the extent feasible, with other Federal agencies and with State agencies, to encourage comprehensive behavioral health services for Indians regardless of their place of residence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mental health care need assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Mental health care need assessment Not later than 1 year after March 23, 2010, the Secretary, acting through the Service, shall make an assessment of the need for inpatient mental health care among Indians and the availability and cost of inpatient mental health facilities which can meet such need. In making such assessment, the Secretary shall consider the possible conversion of existing, underused Service hospital beds into psychiatric units to meet such need.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>