<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1665g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1665g"><akn:num>1665g</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian youth program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1665g. Indian youth program(a) Detoxification and rehabilitationThe Secretary, acting through the Service, consistent with section 1665a of this title, shall develop and implement a program for acute detoxification and treatment for Indian youths, including behavioral health services. The program shall include regional treatment centers designed to include detoxification and rehabilitation for both sexes on a referral basis and programs developed and implemented by Indian tribes or tribal organizations at the local level under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.).11 See References in Text note below. Regional centers shall be integrated with the intake and rehabilitation programs based in the referring Indian community.


(b) Alcohol and substance abuse treatment centers or facilities(1) Establishment(A) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Service, shall construct, renovate, or, as necessary, purchase, and appropriately staff and operate, at least 1 youth regional treatment center or treatment network in each area under the jurisdiction of an area office.


(B) Area office in CaliforniaFor the purposes of this subsection, the area office in California shall be considered to be 2 area offices, 1 office whose jurisdiction shall be considered to encompass the northern area of the State of California, and 1 office whose jurisdiction shall be considered to encompass the remainder of the State of California for the purpose of implementing California treatment networks.



(2) FundingFor the purpose of staffing and operating such centers or facilities, funding shall be pursuant to section 13 of this title.


(3) LocationA youth treatment center constructed or purchased under this subsection shall be constructed or purchased at a location within the area described in paragraph (1) agreed upon (by appropriate tribal resolution) by a majority of the Indian tribes to be served by such center.


(4) Specific provision of f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detoxification and rehabilitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Detoxification and rehabilitation The Secretary, acting through the Service, consistent with section 1665a of this title, shall develop and implement a program for acute detoxification and treatment for Indian youths, including behavioral health services. The program shall include regional treatment centers designed to include detoxification and rehabilitation for both sexes on a referral basis and programs developed and implemented by Indian tribes or tribal organizations at the local level under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.).11 See References in Text note below. Regional centers shall be integrated with the intake and rehabilitation programs based in the referring Indian community.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alcohol and substance abuse treatment centers or facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alcohol and substance abuse treatment centers or facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intermediate adolescent behavioral health services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Intermediate adolescent behavioral health services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federally owned structures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federally owned structures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation and aftercare services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rehabilitation and aftercare services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of family in youth treatment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Inclusion of family in youth treatment program In providing the treatment and other services to Indian youths authorized by this section, the Secretary, acting through the Service, shall provide for the inclusion of family members of such youths in the treatment programs or other services as may be appropriate. Not less than 10 percent of the funds appropriated for the purposes of carrying out subsection (e) shall be used for outpatient care of adult family members related to the treatment of an Indian youth under that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multidrug abuse program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Multidrug abuse program The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall provide, consistent with section 1665a of this title, programs and services to prevent and treat the abuse of multiple forms of substances, including alcohol, drugs, inhalants, and tobacco, among Indian youths residing in Indian communities, on or near reservations, and in urban areas and provide appropriate mental health services to address the incidence of mental illness among such youths.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1665g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian youth mental health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Indian youth mental health The Secretary, acting through the Service, shall collect data for the report under section 1671 of this title with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>