<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1667c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1667c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1667c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1667c"><akn:num>1667c</akn:num><akn:heading>Substance abuse and mental health services Administration grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1667c. Substance abuse and mental health services Administration grants(a) Grant applications(1) Efficiency of grant application processThe Secretary, acting through the Administration, shall carry out such measures as the Secretary determines to be necessary to maximize the time and workload efficiency of the process by which Indian tribes and tribal organizations apply for grants under any program administered by the Administration, including by providing methods other than electronic methods of submitting applications for those grants, if necessary.


(2) Priority for certain grants(A) In generalTo fulfill the trust responsibility of the United States to Indian tribes, in awarding relevant grants pursuant to a program described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall take into consideration the needs of Indian tribes or tribal organizations, as applicable, that serve populations with documented high suicide rates, regardless of whether those Indian tribes or tribal organizations possess adequate personnel or infrastructure to fulfill all applicable requirements of the relevant program.


(B) Description of grant programsA grant program referred to in subparagraph (A) is a grant program—(i) administered by the Administration to fund activities relating to mental health, suicide prevention, or suicide-related risk factors; and

(ii) under which an Indian tribe or tribal organization is an eligible recipient.



(3) Clarification regarding Indian tribes and tribal organizationsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, in applying for a grant under any program administered by the Administration, no Indian tribe or tribal organization shall be required to apply through a State or State agency.


(4) Requirements for affected States(A) DefinitionsIn this paragraph:(i) Affected StateThe term “affected State” means a State—(I) the boundaries of which include 1 or more Indian tribes; and

(II) the application for a grant under any program administered by the Administ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1667c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1667c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>No non-Federal share requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No non-Federal share requirement Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Indian tribe or tribal organization shall be required to provide a non-Federal share of the cost of any project or activity carried out using a grant provided under any program administered by the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1667c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach for rural and isolated Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Outreach for rural and isolated Indian tribes Due to the rural, isolated nature of most Indian reservations and communities (especially those reservations and communities in the Great Plains region), the Secretary shall conduct outreach activities, with a particular emphasis on the provision of telemental health services, to achieve the purposes of this part with respect to Indian tribes located in rural, isolated areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1667c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of other assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provision of other assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1667c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Early intervention and assessment services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Early intervention and assessment services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>