<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1672" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1672/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1672/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1672"><akn:num>1672</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1672. Regulations
Prior to any revision of or amendment to rules or regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter, the Secretary shall consult with Indian tribes and appropriate national or regional Indian organizations and shall publish any proposed revision or amendment in the Federal Register not less than sixty days prior to the effective date of such revision or amendment in order to provide adequate notice to, and receive comments from, other interested parties.
(Pub. L. 94–437, title VIII, § 802, formerly title VII, § 702, Sept. 30, 1976, 90 Stat. 1413; renumbered title VIII, § 802, and amended Pub. L. 102–573, title VII, § 701(a), (b), title VIII, § 802, Oct. 29, 1992, 106 Stat. 4572, 4585.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 94–437, Sept. 30, 1976, 90 Stat. 1400, known as the Indian Health Care Improvement Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1601 of this title and Tables.

Amendments1992—Pub. L. 102–573, § 802, amended section generally, substituting present provisions for former provisions relating in subsec. (a) to consideration, formulation, proposal, and promulgation of regulations and in subsec. (b) to revision and amendment of regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>