<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1678a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1678a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1678a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1678a"><akn:num>1678a</akn:num><akn:heading>North Dakota and South Dakota as contract health service delivery area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1678a. North Dakota and South Dakota as contract health service delivery area(a) In generalThe States of North Dakota and South Dakota shall be designated as a contract health service delivery area by the Service for the purpose of providing contract health care services to members of Indian tribes in the States of North Dakota and South Dakota.


(b) Maintenance of servicesThe Service shall not curtail any health care services provided to Indians residing on any reservation, or in any county that has a common boundary with any reservation, in the State of North Dakota or South Dakota if the curtailment is due to the provision of contract services in those States pursuant to the designation of the States as a contract health service delivery area by subsection (a).


(Pub. L. 94–437, title VIII, § 808A, as added Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10221(a), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 935.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section 808A of Pub. L. 94–437 is based on section 192(2) of title I of S. 1790, One Hundred Eleventh Congress, as reported by the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate in Dec. 2009, which was enacted into law by section 10221(a) of Pub. L. 111–148.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1678a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The States of North Dakota and South Dakota shall be designated as a contract health service delivery area by the Service for the purpose of providing contract health care services to members of Indian tribes in the States of North Dakota and South Dakota.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1678a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Maintenance of services The Service shall not curtail any health care services provided to Indians residing on any reservation, or in any county that has a common boundary with any reservation, in the State of North Dakota or South Dakota if the curtailment is due to the provision of contract services in those States pursuant to the designation of the States as a contract health service delivery area by subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>