<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1806" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1806/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1806/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1806"><akn:num>1806</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1806. Eligibility studies(a) Development of plans, procedures, and criteriaThe Secretary is authorized to enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Education to assist the Bureau of Indian Affairs in developing plans, procedures, and criteria for conducting the eligibility studies required by this section. Such agreement shall provide for continuing technical assistance in the conduct of such studies.


(b) Initiation by Secretary; grant applications and budgetsThe Secretary, within thirty days after a request by any Indian tribe, shall initiate a 11 So in original. Probably should be “an”. eligibility study to determine whether there is justification to encourage and maintain a tribally controlled college or university, and, upon a positive determination, shall aid in the preparation of grant applications and related budgets which will insure successful operation of such an institution. Such a positive determination shall be effective for the fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year in which such determination is made.


(c) Source of appropriationsFunds to carry out the purposes of this section for any fiscal year may be drawn from either—(1) general administrative appropriations to the Secretary made after October 17, 1978 for such fiscal year; or

(2) not more than 5 per centum of the funds appropriated to carry out section 1807 of this title for such fiscal year.


(Pub. L. 95–471, title I, § 106, formerly § 105, Oct. 17, 1978, 92 Stat. 1326; renumbered § 106 and amended Pub. L. 98–192, §§ 4(a)(1), (b)(1), 6(a), Dec. 1, 1983, 97 Stat. 1336, 1337; Pub. L. 105–244, title IX, § 901(b)(5), Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1828.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 105–244 substituted “college or university” for “community college”.
1983—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 98–192, § 6(a)(2), (3), substituted “eligibility” for “feasibility” and “Secretary of Education” for “Assistant Secretary of Education of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare”.
Subsec. (b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of plans, procedures, and criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development of plans, procedures, and criteria The Secretary is authorized to enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Education to assist the Bureau of Indian Affairs in developing plans, procedures, and criteria for conducting the eligibility studies required by this section. Such agreement shall provide for continuing technical assistance in the conduct of such studies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiation by Secretary; grant applications and budgets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Initiation by Secretary; grant applications and budgets The Secretary, within thirty days after a request by any Indian tribe, shall initiate a 11 So in original. Probably should be “an”. eligibility study to determine whether there is justification to encourage and maintain a tribally controlled college or university, and, upon a positive determination, shall aid in the preparation of grant applications and related budgets which will insure successful operation of such an institution. Such a positive determination shall be effective for the fiscal year succeeding the fiscal year in which such determination is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Source of appropriations Funds to carry out the purposes of this section for any fiscal year may be drawn from either—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>