<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1807" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1807/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1807/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1807"><akn:num>1807</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to tribally controlled colleges or universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1807. Grants to tribally controlled colleges or universities(a) Submission of applications; necessity of eligibility studyGrants shall be made under this subchapter only in response to applications by tribally controlled colleges or universities. Such applications shall be submitted at such time, in such manner, and will contain or be accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require pursuant to regulations. Such application shall include a description of recordkeeping procedures for the expenditure of funds received under this chapter which will allow the Secretary to audit and monitor programs conducted with such funds. The Secretary shall not consider any grant application unless a 11 So in original. Probably should be “an”. eligibility study has been conducted under section 1806 of this title and it has been found that the applying college or university will service a reasonable student population.


(b) Determination of support; factors consideredThe Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Education to determine the reasonable number of students required to support a tribally controlled college or university. Consideration shall be given to such factors as tribal and cultural differences, isolation, the presence of alternate education sources, and proposed curriculum.


(c) Priority and number of grantsPriority in grants shall be given to institutions which are operating on October 17, 1978, and which have a history of service to the Indian people. In the first year for which funds are appropriated to carry out this section, the number of grants shall be limited to not less than eight nor more than fifteen.


(d) Consultation with national Indian organizations and tribal governmentsIn making grants pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, consult with national Indian organizations and with tribal governments chartering the institutions being considered.


(Pub. L. 95–471, title I, § 107, formerly § </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1807_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of applications; necessity of eligibility study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission of applications; necessity of eligibility study Grants shall be made under this subchapter only in response to applications by tribally controlled colleges or universities. Such applications shall be submitted at such time, in such manner, and will contain or be accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require pursuant to regulations. Such application shall include a description of recordkeeping procedures for the expenditure of funds received under this chapter which will allow the Secretary to audit and monitor programs conducted with such funds. The Secretary shall not consider any grant application unless a 11 So in original. Probably should be “an”. eligibility study has been conducted under section 1806 of this title and it has been found that the applying college or university will service a reasonable student population.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1807_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of support; factors considered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of support; factors considered The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Education to determine the reasonable number of students required to support a tribally controlled college or university. Consideration shall be given to such factors as tribal and cultural differences, isolation, the presence of alternate education sources, and proposed curriculum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1807_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority and number of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority and number of grants Priority in grants shall be given to institutions which are operating on October 17, 1978, and which have a history of service to the Indian people. In the first year for which funds are appropriated to carry out this section, the number of grants shall be limited to not less than eight nor more than fifteen.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1807_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with national Indian organizations and tribal governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consultation with national Indian organizations and tribal governments In making grants pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, consult with national Indian organizations and with tribal governments chartering the institutions being considered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>