<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1862" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1862/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1862/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1862"><akn:num>1862</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institutions program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1862. Tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institutions program(a) In generalSubject to the availability of appropriations, for fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall—(1) subject to subsection (b), select two tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institutions to receive assistance under this subchapter; and

(2) provide funding to the selected tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institutions to pay the costs (including institutional support costs) of operating postsecondary career and technical education programs for Indian students at the tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institutions.


(b) Selection of certain institutions(1) RequirementFor each fiscal year during which the Secretary determines that a tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institution described in paragraph (2) meets the definition referred to in section 1861 of this title, the Secretary shall select that tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institution under subsection (a)(1) to receive funding under this section.


(2) InstitutionsThe two tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institutions referred to in paragraph (1) are—(A) the United Tribes Technical College; and

(B) the Navajo Technical College.



(c) Method of paymentFor each applicable fiscal year, the Secretary shall provide funding under this section to each tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institution selected for the fiscal year under subsection (a)(1) in a lump sum payment for the fiscal year.


(d) Distribution(1) In generalFor fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, of amounts made available pursuant to section 1864 of this title, the Secretary shall distribute to each tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institution selected for the fiscal year under subsection (a)(1) an amount equal to the greater of—(A) the total amount ap</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to the availability of appropriations, for fiscal year 2009 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of certain institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection of certain institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Method of payment For each applicable fiscal year, the Secretary shall provide funding under this section to each tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institution selected for the fiscal year under subsection (a)(1) in a lump sum payment for the fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Distribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>