<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1913" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1913/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1913/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1913"><akn:num>1913</akn:num><akn:heading>Parental rights; voluntary termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1913. Parental rights; voluntary termination(a) Consent; record; certification matters; invalid consentsWhere any parent or Indian custodian voluntarily consents to a foster care placement or to termination of parental rights, such consent shall not be valid unless executed in writing and recorded before a judge of a court of competent jurisdiction and accompanied by the presiding judge’s certificate that the terms and consequences of the consent were fully explained in detail and were fully understood by the parent or Indian custodian. The court shall also certify that either the parent or Indian custodian fully understood the explanation in English or that it was interpreted into a language that the parent or Indian custodian understood. Any consent given prior to, or within ten days after, birth of the Indian child shall not be valid.


(b) Foster care placement; withdrawal of consentAny parent or Indian custodian may withdraw consent to a foster care placement under State law at any time and, upon such withdrawal, the child shall be returned to the parent or Indian custodian.


(c) Voluntary termination of parental rights or adoptive placement; withdrawal of consent; return of custodyIn any voluntary proceeding for termination of parental rights to, or adoptive placement of, an Indian child, the consent of the parent may be withdrawn for any reason at any time prior to the entry of a final decree of termination or adoption, as the case may be, and the child shall be returned to the parent.


(d) Collateral attack; vacation of decree and return of custody; limitationsAfter the entry of a final decree of adoption of an Indian child in any State court, the parent may withdraw consent thereto upon the grounds that consent was obtained through fraud or duress and may petition the court to vacate such decree. Upon a finding that such consent was obtained through fraud or duress, the court shall vacate such decree and return the child to the parent. No adoption which</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1913_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consent; record; certification matters; invalid consents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consent; record; certification matters; invalid consents Where any parent or Indian custodian voluntarily consents to a foster care placement or to termination of parental rights, such consent shall not be valid unless executed in writing and recorded before a judge of a court of competent jurisdiction and accompanied by the presiding judge’s certificate that the terms and consequences of the consent were fully explained in detail and were fully understood by the parent or Indian custodian. The court shall also certify that either the parent or Indian custodian fully understood the explanation in English or that it was interpreted into a language that the parent or Indian custodian understood. Any consent given prior to, or within ten days after, birth of the Indian child shall not be valid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1913_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foster care placement; withdrawal of consent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Foster care placement; withdrawal of consent Any parent or Indian custodian may withdraw consent to a foster care placement under State law at any time and, upon such withdrawal, the child shall be returned to the parent or Indian custodian.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1913_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary termination of parental rights or adoptive placement; withdrawal of consent; return of custody</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Voluntary termination of parental rights or adoptive placement; withdrawal of consent; return of custody In any voluntary proceeding for termination of parental rights to, or adoptive placement of, an Indian child, the consent of the parent may be withdrawn for any reason at any time prior to the entry of a final decree of termination or adoption, as the case may be, and the child shall be returned to the parent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1913_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collateral attack; vacation of decree and return of custody; limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Collateral attack; vacation of decree and return of custody; limitations After the entry of a final decree of adoption of an Indian child in any State court, the parent may withdraw consent thereto upon the grounds that consent was obtained through fraud or duress and may petition the court to vacate such decree. Upon a finding that such consent was obtained through fraud or duress, the court shall vacate such decree and return the child to the parent. No adoption which has been effective for at least two years may be invalidated under the provisions of this subsection unless otherwise permitted under State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>