<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1918" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1918/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/1918/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1918"><akn:num>1918</akn:num><akn:heading>Reassumption of jurisdiction over child cus­tody proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1918. Reassumption of jurisdiction over child cus­tody proceedings(a) Petition; suitable plan; approval by SecretaryAny Indian tribe which became subject to State jurisdiction pursuant to the provisions of the Act of August 15, 1953 (67 Stat. 588), as amended by title IV of the Act of April 11, 1968 (82 Stat. 73, 78), or pursuant to any other Federal law, may reassume jurisdiction over child custody proceedings. Before any Indian tribe may reassume jurisdiction over Indian child custody proceedings, such tribe shall present to the Secretary for approval a petition to reassume such jurisdiction which includes a suitable plan to exercise such jurisdiction.


(b) Criteria applicable to consideration by Secretary; partial retrocession(1) In considering the petition and feasibility of the plan of a tribe under subsection (a), the Secretary may consider, among other things:(i) whether or not the tribe maintains a membership roll or alternative provision for clearly identifying the persons who will be affected by the reassumption of jurisdiction by the tribe;

(ii) the size of the reservation or former reservation area which will be affected by retrocession and reassumption of jurisdiction by the tribe;

(iii) the population base of the tribe, or distribution of the population in homogeneous communities or geographic areas; and

(iv) the feasibility of the plan in cases of multitribal occupation of a single reservation or geographic area.


(2) In those cases where the Secretary determines that the jurisdictional provisions of section 1911(a) of this title are not feasible, he is authorized to accept partial retrocession which will enable tribes to exercise referral jurisdiction as provided in section 1911(b) of this title, or, where appropriate, will allow them to exercise exclusive jurisdiction as provided in section 1911(a) of this title over limited community or geographic areas without regard for the reservation status of the area affected.


(c) Approval of petitio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1918_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition; suitable plan; approval by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Petition; suitable plan; approval by Secretary Any Indian tribe which became subject to State jurisdiction pursuant to the provisions of the Act of August 15, 1953 (67 Stat. 588), as amended by title IV of the Act of April 11, 1968 (82 Stat. 73, 78), or pursuant to any other Federal law, may reassume jurisdiction over child custody proceedings. Before any Indian tribe may reassume jurisdiction over Indian child custody proceedings, such tribe shall present to the Secretary for approval a petition to reassume such jurisdiction which includes a suitable plan to exercise such jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1918_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria applicable to consideration by Secretary; partial retrocession</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria applicable to consideration by Secretary; partial retrocession</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1918_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of petition; publication in Federal Register; notice; reassumption period; correction of causes for disapproval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Approval of petition; publication in Federal Register; notice; reassumption period; correction of causes for disapproval If the Secretary approves any petition under subsection (a), the Secretary shall publish notice of such approval in the Federal Register and shall notify the affected State or States of such approval. The Indian tribe concerned shall reassume jurisdiction sixty days after publication in the Federal Register of notice of approval. If the Secretary disapproves any petition under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide such technical assistance as may be necessary to enable the tribe to correct any deficiency which the Secretary identified as a cause for disapproval.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1918_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pending actions or proceedings unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Pending actions or proceedings unaffected Assumption of jurisdiction under this section shall not affect any action or proceeding over which a court has already assumed jurisdiction, except as may be provided pursuant to any agreement under section 1919 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>