<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2005" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2005/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2005/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2005"><akn:num>2005</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2005. Facilities construction(a) National survey of facilities conditions(1) In generalNot later than 12 months after January 8, 2002, the Government Accountability Office shall compile, collect, and secure the data that are needed to prepare a national survey of the physical conditions of all Bureau-funded school facilities.


(2) Data and methodologiesIn preparing the national survey required under paragraph (1), the Government Accountability Office shall use the following data and methodologies:(A) The existing Department of Defense formula for determining the condition and adequacy of Department of Defense facilities.

(B) Data related to conditions of Bureau-funded schools that has previously been compiled, collected, or secured from whatever source derived so long as the data are accurate, relevant, timely, and necessary to the survey.

(C) The methodologies of the American Institute of Architects, or other accredited and reputable architecture or engineering associations.


(3) Consultations(A) In generalIn carrying out the survey required under paragraph (1), the Government Accountability Office shall, to the maximum extent practicable, consult (and if necessary contract) with national, regional, and tribal Indian education organizations to ensure that a complete and accurate national survey is achieved.


(B) Requests for informationAll Bureau-funded schools shall comply with reasonable requests for information by the Government Accountability Office and shall respond to such requests in a timely fashion.



(4) SubmissionNot later than 2 years after January 8, 2002, the Government Accountability Office shall submit the results of the national survey conducted under paragraph (1) to the Committee on Indian Affairs, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Resources, the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Represe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National survey of facilities conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National survey of facilities conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with health and safety standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compliance with health and safety standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compliance plan At the time that the annual budget request for Bureau educational services is presented, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a detailed plan to bring all facilities covered under subsection (a) into compliance with the standards referred to in that subsection that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Construction priorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous condition at Bureau-funded school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Hazardous condition at Bureau-funded school</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No reduction in Federal funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No reduction in Federal funding Nothing in this section shall diminish any Federal funding due to the receipt by the school of funding for facilities improvement or construction from a State or any other source.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>