<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2006" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2006/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2006/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2006"><akn:num>2006</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau of Indian Affairs education functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2006. Bureau of Indian Affairs education functions(a) Formulation and establishment of policy and procedure; supervision of programs and expendituresThe Secretary shall vest in the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs all functions with respect to formulation and establishment of policy and procedure and supervision of programs and expenditures of Federal funds for the purpose of Indian education administered by the Bureau. The Assistant Secretary shall carry out such functions through the Director of the Office of Indian Education Programs.


(b) Direction and supervision of personnel operations(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after January 8, 2002, the Director of the Office shall direct and supervise the operations of all personnel directly and substantially involved in the provision of education program services by the Bureau, including school or institution custodial or maintenance personnel, and personnel responsible for contracting, procurement, and finance functions connected with school operation programs.


(2) TransfersThe Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs shall, not later than 180 days after January 8, 2002, coordinate the transfer of functions relating to procurements for, contracts of, operation of, and maintenance of schools and other support functions to the Director.



(c) Inherent Federal functionFor purposes of this Act, all functions relating to education that are located at the Area or Agency level and performed by an education line officer shall be subject to contract under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.], unless determined by the Secretary to be inherently Federal functions as defined in section 2021(12) of this title.


(d) Evaluation of programs; services and support functions; technical and coordinating assistanceEducation personnel who are under the direction and supervision of the Director of the Office of Indian Education Programs in accordance with subsection (b)(1) shal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formulation and establishment of policy and procedure; supervision of programs and expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Formulation and establishment of policy and procedure; supervision of programs and expenditures The Secretary shall vest in the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs all functions with respect to formulation and establishment of policy and procedure and supervision of programs and expenditures of Federal funds for the purpose of Indian education administered by the Bureau. The Assistant Secretary shall carry out such functions through the Director of the Office of Indian Education Programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direction and supervision of personnel operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Direction and supervision of personnel operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inherent Federal function</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inherent Federal function For purposes of this Act, all functions relating to education that are located at the Area or Agency level and performed by an education line officer shall be subject to contract under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.], unless determined by the Secretary to be inherently Federal functions as defined in section 2021(12) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of programs; services and support functions; technical and coordinating assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluation of programs; services and support functions; technical and coordinating assistance Education personnel who are under the direction and supervision of the Director of the Office of Indian Education Programs in accordance with subsection (b)(1) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction, improvement, operation, and maintenance of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Construction, improvement, operation, and maintenance of facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of gifts and bequests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Acceptance of gifts and bequests</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definition of functions For the purpose of this section, the term “functions” includes powers and duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>