<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2007" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2007/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2007/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2007"><akn:num>2007</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment formula</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2007. Allotment formula(a) Factors considered; revision to reflect standards(1) FormulaThe Secretary shall establish, by regulation adopted in accordance with section 2017 of this title, a formula for determining the minimum annual amount of funds necessary to sustain each Bureau-funded school. In establishing such formula, the Secretary shall consider—(A) the number of eligible Indian students served and total student population of the school;

(B) special cost factors, such as—(i) the isolation of the school;

(ii) the need for special staffing, transportation, or educational programs;

(iii) food and housing costs;

(iv) maintenance and repair costs associated with the physical condition of the educational facilities;

(v) special transportation and other costs of isolated and small schools;

(vi) the costs of home-living (dormitory) arrangements, where determined necessary by a tribal governing body or designated school board;

(vii) costs associated with greater lengths of service by education personnel;

(viii) the costs of therapeutic programs for students requiring such programs; and

(ix) special costs for gifted and talented students;


(C) the cost of providing academic services which are at least equivalent to those provided by public schools in the State in which the school is located;

(D) whether the available funding will enable the school involved to comply with the accreditation standards applicable to the school under section 2001 of this title; and

(E) such other relevant factors as the Secretary determines are appropriate.


(2) Revision of formula(A) In generalUpon the establishment of the standards required in section 2002 of this title, the Secretary shall revise the formula established under this subsection to reflect the cost of funding such standards.


(B) Review of formulaNot later than January 1, 2003, the Secretary shall review the formula established under this section and shall take such steps as are necessary to increase the avai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors considered; revision to reflect standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Factors considered; revision to reflect standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pro rata allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pro rata allotment Notwithstanding any other provision of law, Federal funds appropriated for the general local operation of Bureau-funded schools shall be allotted pro rata in accordance with the formula established under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual adjustment; reservation of amount for school board activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual adjustment; reservation of amount for school board activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation of amount for emergencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reservation of amount for emergencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Supplemental appropriations Supplemental appropriations enacted to meet increased pay costs attributable to school level personnel shall be distributed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Indian student defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligible Indian student defined In this section, the term “eligible Indian student” means a student who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tuition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Tuition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds available without fiscal year limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funds available without fiscal year limitation Notwithstanding any other provision of law, at the election of the school board of a Bureau school made at any time during the fiscal year, a portion equal to not more than 15 percent of the funds allocated with respect to a school under this section for any fiscal year shall remain available to the school for expenditure without fiscal year limitation. The Assistant Secretary shall take such steps as are necessary to implement this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Students at Richfield dormitory, Richfield, Utah</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Students at Richfield dormitory, Richfield, Utah</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>