<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2008" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2008/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2008/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2008"><akn:num>2008</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative cost grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2008. Administrative cost grants(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Administrative cost(A) In generalThe term “administrative cost” means the cost of necessary administrative functions which—(i) the tribe or tribal organization incurs as a result of operating a tribal elementary or secondary educational program;

(ii) are not customarily paid by comparable Bureau-operated programs out of direct program funds; and

(iii) are either—(I) normally provided for comparable Bureau programs by Federal officials using resources other than Bureau direct program funds; or

(II) are otherwise required of tribal self-determination program operators by law or prudent management practice.



(B) InclusionsThe term “administrative cost” may include—(i) contract or grant (or other agreement) administration;

(ii) executive, policy, and corporate leadership and decisionmaking;

(iii) program planning, development, and management;

(iv) fiscal, personnel, property, and procurement management;

(v) related office services and record keeping; and

(vi) costs of necessary insurance, auditing, legal, safety and security services.



(2) Bureau elementary and secondary functionsThe term “Bureau elementary and secondary functions” means—(A) all functions funded at Bureau schools by the Office;

(B) all programs—(i) funds for which are appropriated to other agencies of the Federal Government; and

(ii) which are administered for the benefit of Indians through Bureau schools; and


(C) all operation, maintenance, and repair funds for facilities and Government quarters used in the operation or support of elementary and secondary education functions for the benefit of Indians, from whatever source derived.


(3) Direct cost base(A) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in subparagraph (B), the direct cost base of a tribe or tribal organization for the fiscal year is the aggregate direct cost program funding for all tribal elementary or secondary educational programs operated by the tribe or t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants; effect upon appropriated amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants; effect upon appropriated amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of grant amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination of grant amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative cost percentage rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative cost percentage rate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Combining funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Combining funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Availability of funds Funds received as grants under this section with respect to tribal elementary or secondary education programs shall remain available to the contract or grant school without fiscal year limitation and without diminishing the amount of any grants otherwise payable to the school under this section for any fiscal year beginning after the fiscal year for which the grant is provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Treatment of funds Funds received as grants under this section for Bureau-funded programs operated by a tribe or tribal organization under a contract or agreement shall not be taken into consideration for purposes of indirect cost underrecovery and overrecovery determinations by any Federal agency for any other funds, from whatever source derived.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of entity operating other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Treatment of entity operating other programs In applying this section and section 106 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5325] with respect to an Indian tribe or tribal organization that— the Secretary shall ensure that the Indian tribe or tribal organization is provided with the full amount of the administrative costs that are associated with operating the contract or grant school, and of the indirect costs, that are associated with all of such other programs, except that funds appropriated for implementation of this section shall be used only to supply the amount of the grant required to be provided by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies for determination of factors affecting costs; base rates limits; standard direct cost base; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Studies for determination of factors affecting costs; base rates limits; standard direct cost base; report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>