<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2019" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2019/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2019/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2019"><akn:num>2019</akn:num><akn:heading>Early childhood development program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2019. Early childhood development program(a) In generalThe Secretary shall provide grants to tribes, tribal organizations, and consortia of tribes and tribal organizations to fund early childhood development programs that are operated by such tribes, organizations, or consortia.


(b) Amount of grants(1) In generalThe total amount of the grants provided under subsection (a) with respect to each tribe, tribal organization, or consortium of tribes or tribal organizations for each fiscal year shall be equal to the amount which bears the same relationship to the total amount appropriated under the authority of subsection (g) for such fiscal year (less amounts provided under subsection (f)) as—(A) the total number of children under 6 years of age who are members of—(i) such tribe;

(ii) the tribe that authorized such tribal organization; or

(iii) any tribe that—(I) is a member of such consortium; or

(II) authorizes any tribal organization that is a member of such consortium; bears to



(B) the total number of all children under 6 years of age who are members of any tribe that—(i) is eligible to receive funds under subsection (a);

(ii) is a member of a consortium that is eligible to receive such funds; or

(iii) authorizes a tribal organization that is eligible to receive such funds.



(2) LimitationNo grant may be provided under subsection (a)—(A) to any tribe that has less than 500 members;

(B) to any tribal organization which is authorized—(i) by only one tribe that has less than 500 members; or

(ii) by one or more tribes that have a combined total membership of less than 500 members; or


(C) to any consortium composed of tribes, or tribal organizations authorized by tribes, that have a combined total tribal membership of less than 500 members.



(c) Application(1) In generalA grant may be provided under subsection (a) to a tribe, tribal organization, or consortium of tribes and tribal organizations only if the tribe, organization, or consortium submits to t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2019_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall provide grants to tribes, tribal organizations, and consortia of tribes and tribal organizations to fund early childhood development programs that are operated by such tribes, organizations, or consortia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2019_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2019_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2019_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of programs funded</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirement of programs funded The early childhood development programs that are funded by grants provided under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2019_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of family literacy programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination of family literacy programs Family literacy programs operated under this section and other family literacy programs operated by the Bureau of Indian Affairs shall be coordinated with family literacy programs for Indian children under subpart 2 of part B of title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 6641 et seq.] in order to avoid duplication and to encourage the dissemination of information on quality family literacy programs serving Indians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2019_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative costs The Secretary shall, out of funds appropriated under subsection (g), include in the grants provided under subsection (a) amounts for administrative costs incurred by the tribe, tribal organization, or consortium of tribes in establishing and maintaining the early childhood development program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2019_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>