<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2020" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2020/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2020/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2020"><akn:num>2020</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal departments or divisions of education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2020. Tribal departments or divisions of education(a) In generalSubject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall make grants and provide technical assistance to tribes for the development and operation of tribal departments or divisions of education for the purpose of planning and coordinating all educational programs of the tribe.


(b) ApplicationsFor a tribe to be eligible to receive a grant under this section, the governing body of the tribe shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(c) DiversityThe Secretary shall award grants under this section in a manner that fosters geographic and population diversity.


(d) UseTribes that receive grants under this section shall use the funds made available through the grants—(1) to facilitate tribal control in all matters relating to the education of Indian children on reservations (and on former Indian reservations in Oklahoma);

(2) to provide for the development of coordinated educational programs (including all preschool, elementary, secondary, and higher or vocational educational programs funded by tribal, Federal, or other sources) on reservations (and on former Indian reservations in Oklahoma) by encouraging tribal administrative support of all Bureau-funded educational programs as well as encouraging tribal cooperation and coordination with entities carrying out all educational programs receiving financial support from other Federal agencies, State agencies, or private entities; and

(3) to provide for the development and enforcement of tribal educational codes, including tribal educational policies and tribal standards applicable to curriculum, personnel, students, facilities, and support programs.


(e) PrioritiesIn making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to any application that—(1) includes—(A) assurances that the applicant serves three or more separate Bureau-funded sc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2020_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall make grants and provide technical assistance to tribes for the development and operation of tribal departments or divisions of education for the purpose of planning and coordinating all educational programs of the tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2020_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications For a tribe to be eligible to receive a grant under this section, the governing body of the tribe shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2020_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diversity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Diversity The Secretary shall award grants under this section in a manner that fosters geographic and population diversity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2020_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use Tribes that receive grants under this section shall use the funds made available through the grants—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2020_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priorities In making grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to any application that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2020_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time period of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Time period of grant Subject to the availability of appropriated funds, a grant provided under this section shall be provided for a period of 3 years. If the performance of the grant recipient is satisfactory to the Secretary, the grant may be renewed for additional 3-year terms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2020_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms, conditions, or requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Terms, conditions, or requirements A tribe that receives a grant under this section shall comply with regulations relating to grants made under section 5322(a) of this title that are in effect on the date that the tribal governing body submits the application for the grant under subsection (b). The Secretary shall not impose any terms, conditions, or requirements on the provision of grants under this section that are not specified in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2020_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>