<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2021"><akn:num>2021</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2021. Definitions
For the purposes of this chapter, unless otherwise specified:(1) Agency school boardThe term “agency school board” means a body—(A) the members of which are appointed by all of the school boards of the schools located within an agency, including schools operated under contract or grant; and

(B) the number of such members is determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the affected tribes;


except that, in agencies serving a single school, the school board of such school shall fulfill these duties, and in agencies having schools or a school operated under contract or grant, one such member at least shall be from such a school.

(2) BureauThe term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior.


(3) Bureau-funded schoolThe term “Bureau-funded school” means—(A) a Bureau school;

(B) a contract or grant school; or

(C) a school for which assistance is provided under the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 [25 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.].


(4) Bureau schoolThe term “Bureau school” means a Bureau-operated elementary or secondary day or boarding school or a Bureau-operated dormitory for students attending a school other than a Bureau school.


(5) Complementary educational facilitiesThe term “complementary educational facilities” means educational program functional spaces such as libraries, gymnasiums, and cafeterias.


(6) Contract or grant schoolThe term “contract or grant school” means an elementary school, secondary school, or dormitory that receives financial assistance for its operation under a contract, grant, or agreement with the Bureau under section 5321, 5322(a), or 5352 of this title, or under the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 [25 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.].


(7) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Indian Education Programs.


(8) Education line officerThe term “education line officer” means a member of the education personnel under the supervision of the Director of the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency school board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agency school board The term “agency school board” means a body— except that, in agencies serving a single school, the school board of such school shall fulfill these duties, and in agencies having schools or a school operated under contract or grant, one such member at least shall be from such a school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Bureau The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau-funded school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Bureau-funded school The term “Bureau-funded school” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Bureau school The term “Bureau school” means a Bureau-operated elementary or secondary day or boarding school or a Bureau-operated dormitory for students attending a school other than a Bureau school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Complementary educational facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Complementary educational facilities The term “complementary educational facilities” means educational program functional spaces such as libraries, gymnasiums, and cafeterias.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract or grant school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Contract or grant school The term “contract or grant school” means an elementary school, secondary school, or dormitory that receives financial assistance for its operation under a contract, grant, or agreement with the Bureau under section 5321, 5322(a), or 5352 of this title, or under the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 [25 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Director The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Indian Education Programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education line officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Education line officer The term “education line officer” means a member of the education personnel under the supervision of the Director of the Office, whether located in a central, area, or agency office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family literacy services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Family literacy services The term “family literacy services” has the meaning given that term in section 7801 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Financial plan The term “financial plan” means a plan of services provided by each Bureau school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>