<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2205" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2205/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2205/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2205"><akn:num>2205</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal probate codes; acquisitions of fractional interests by tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2205. Tribal probate codes; acquisitions of fractional interests by tribes(a) Tribal probate codes(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, any Indian tribe may adopt a tribal probate code to govern descent and distribution of trust or restricted lands that are—(A) located within that Indian tribe’s reservation; or

(B) otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of that Indian tribe.


(2) Possible inclusionsA tribal probate code referred to in paragraph (1) may include—(A) rules of intestate succession; and

(B) other tribal probate code provisions that are consistent with Federal law and that promote the policies set forth in section 102 of the Indian Land Consolidation Act Amendments of 2000.


(3) Tribal probate codesExcept as provided in any applicable Federal law, the Secretary shall not approve a tribal probate code, or an amendment to such a code, that prohibits the devise of an interest in trust or restricted land to—(A) an Indian lineal descendant of the original allottee; or

(B) an Indian who is not a member of the Indian tribe with jurisdiction over such an interest;


unless the code provides for—
(i) the renouncing of interests to eligible devisees in accordance with the code;

(ii) the opportunity for a devisee who is the spouse or lineal descendant of a testator to reserve a life estate without regard to waste; and

(iii) payment of fair market value in the manner prescribed under subsection (c)(2).



(b) Secretarial approval(1) In generalAny tribal probate code enacted under subsection (a), and any amendment to such a tribal probate code, shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary.


(2) Review and approval(A) In generalEach Indian tribe that adopts a tribal probate code under subsection (a) shall submit that code to the Secretary for review. Not later than 180 days after a tribal probate code is submitted to the Secretary under this paragraph, the Secretary shall review and approve or disapprove that tribal probate code.


(B)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2205_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal probate codes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Tribal probate codes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2205_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Secretarial approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2205_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority available to Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority available to Indian tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2205_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of proposed findings by tribal justice systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of proposed findings by tribal justice systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>