<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2216" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2216/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2216/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2216"><akn:num>2216</akn:num><akn:heading>Trust and restricted land transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2216. Trust and restricted land transactions(a) PolicyIt is the policy of the United States to encourage and assist the consolidation of land ownership through transactions—(1) involving individual Indians;

(2) between Indians and the tribal government that exercises jurisdiction over the land; or

(3) between individuals who own an interest in trust and restricted land who wish to convey that interest to an Indian or the tribal government that exercises jurisdiction over the parcel of land involved;


in a manner consistent with the policy of maintaining the trust status of allotted lands. Nothing in this section shall be construed to apply to or to authorize the sale of trust or restricted lands to a person who is not an Indian.

(b) Sales, exchanges and gift deeds between Indians and between Indians and Indian tribes(1) In general(A) Estimate of valueNotwithstanding any other provision of law and only after the Indian selling, exchanging, or conveying by gift deed for no or nominal consideration an interest in land, has been provided with an estimate of the value of the interest of the Indian pursuant to this section—(i) the sale or exchange or conveyance of an interest in trust or restricted land may be made for an amount that is less than the fair market value of that interest; and

(ii) the approval of a transaction that is in compliance with this section shall not constitute a breach of trust by the Secretary.


(B) Waiver of requirementThe requirement for an estimate of value under subparagraph (A) may be waived in writing by an owner of a trust or restricted interest in land either selling, exchanging, or conveying by gift deed for no or nominal consideration such interest—(i) to an Indian person who is the owner’s spouse, brother, sister, lineal ancestor, lineal descendant, or collateral heir; or

(ii) to an Indian co-owner or to the tribe with jurisdiction over the subject parcel of land, where the grantor owns a fractional interest that represents 5 p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2216_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Policy It is the policy of the United States to encourage and assist the consolidation of land ownership through transactions— in a manner consistent with the policy of maintaining the trust status of allotted lands. Nothing in this section shall be construed to apply to or to authorize the sale of trust or restricted lands to a person who is not an Indian.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2216_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales, exchanges and gift deeds between Indians and between Indians and Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sales, exchanges and gift deeds between Indians and between Indians and Indian tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2216_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of interest by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Acquisition of interest by Secretary An Indian, or the recognized tribal government of a reservation, in possession of an interest in trust or restricted lands, at least a portion of which is in trust or restricted status on November 7, 2000, and located within a reservation, may request that the interest be taken into trust by the Secretary. Upon such a request, the Secretary shall forthwith take such interest into trust.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2216_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Status of lands The sale, exchange, or conveyance by gift deed for no or nominal consideration of an interest in trust or restricted land under this section shall not affect the status of that land as trust or restricted land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2216_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land ownership information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Land ownership information Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the names and mailing addresses of the owners of any interest in trust or restricted lands, and information on the location of the parcel and the percentage of undivided interest owned by each individual shall, upon written request, be made available to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2216_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of land by Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Purchase of land by Indian tribe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>