<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2218" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2218/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2218/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2218"><akn:num>2218</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of leases, rights-of-way, and sales of natural resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2218. Approval of leases, rights-of-way, and sales of natural resources(a) Approval by the Secretary(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may approve any lease or agreement that affects individually owned allotted land or any other land held in trust or restricted status by the Secretary on behalf of an Indian, if—(A) the owners of not less than the applicable percentage (determined under subsection (b)) of the undivided interest in the allotted land that is covered by the lease or agreement consent in writing to the lease or agreement; and

(B) the Secretary determines that approving the lease or agreement is in the best interest of the owners of the undivided interest in the allotted land.


(2) Rule of constructionNothing in this section shall be construed to apply to leases involving coal or uranium.


(3) DefinitionIn this section, the term “allotted land” includes any land held in trust or restricted status by the Secretary on behalf of one or more Indians.



(b) Applicable percentage(1) Percentage interestThe applicable percentage referred to in subsection (a)(1) shall be determined as follows:(A) If there are 5 or fewer owners of the undivided interest in the allotted land, the applicable percentage shall be 90 percent.

(B) If there are more than 5 such owners, but fewer than 11 such owners, the applicable percentage shall be 80 percent.

(C) If there are more than 10 such owners, but fewer than 20 such owners, the applicable percentage shall be 60 percent.

(D) If there are 20 or more such owners, the applicable percentage shall be a majority of the interests in the allotted land.


(2) Determination of owners(A) In generalFor purposes of this subsection, in determining the number of owners of, and their interests in, the undivided interest in the allotted land with respect to a lease or agreement, the Secretary shall make such determination based on the records of the Department of the Interior that identify the owners</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval by the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Approval by the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable percentage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicable percentage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary to sign lease or agreement on behalf of certain owners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority of Secretary to sign lease or agreement on behalf of certain owners The Secretary may give written consent to a lease or agreement under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect of approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of proceeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Distribution of proceeds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to amend or modify the provisions of Public Law 105–188 (25 U.S.C. 396 note), the American Indian Agricultural Resources Management Act (25 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.), title II of the Indian Land Consolidation Act Amendments of 2000, or any other Act that provides specific standards for the percentage of ownership interest that must approve a lease or agreement on a specified reservation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Other laws Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to supersede, repeal, or modify any general or specific statute authorizing the grant or approval of any type of land use transaction involving fractional interests in trust or restricted land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>