<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2219" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2219/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2219/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2219"><akn:num>2219</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to Alaska</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2219. Application to Alaska(a) FindingsCongress finds that—(1) numerous academic and governmental organizations have studied the nature and extent of fractionated ownership of Indian land outside of Alaska and have proposed solutions to this problem; and

(2) despite these studies, there has not been a comparable effort to analyze the problem, if any, of fractionated ownership in Alaska.


(b) Application of chapter to AlaskaExcept as provided in this section, this chapter shall not apply to land located within Alaska.


(c) Rule of constructionNothing in this section shall be construed to constitute a ratification of any determination by any agency, instrumentality, or court of the United States that may support the assertion of tribal jurisdiction over allotment lands or interests in such land in Alaska.


(Pub. L. 97–459, title II, § 220, as added Pub. L. 106–462, title I, § 103(6), Nov. 7, 2000, 114 Stat. 2006.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, which was translated as reading “this title”, meaning title II of Pub. L. 97–459, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2219_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2219_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of chapter to Alaska</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of chapter to Alaska Except as provided in this section, this chapter shall not apply to land located within Alaska.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2219_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to constitute a ratification of any determination by any agency, instrumentality, or court of the United States that may support the assertion of tribal jurisdiction over allotment lands or interests in such land in Alaska.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>