<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2415" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2415/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2415/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2415"><akn:num>2415</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal facilities, property, and equipment; leasing of tribal property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2415. Federal facilities, property, and equipment; leasing of tribal property(a) Facility availabilityIn the furtherance of the purposes and goals of this chapter, the Secretary of the Interior, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall make available for community use, to the extent permitted by law and as may be provided in a Tribal Action Plan, local Federal facilities, property, and equipment, including school facilities. Such facility availability shall include school facilities under the Secretary of the Interior’s jurisdiction: Provided, That the use of any school facilities shall be conditioned upon approval of the local school board with jurisdiction over such school.


(b) CostsAny additional cost associated with the use of Federal facilities, property, or equipment under subsection (a) may be borne by the Secretary of the Interior, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services out of available Federal, tribal, State, local, or private funds, if not otherwise prohibited by law. This subsection does not require the Secretary of the Interior, nor the Attorney General, nor the Secretary of Health and Human Services to expend additional funds to meet the additional costs which may be associated with the provision of such facilities, property, or equipment for community use. Where the use of Federal facilities, property, or equipment under subsection (a) furthers the purposes and goals of this chapter, the use of funds other than those funds appropriated to the Department of the Interior, the Department of Justice, or the Department of Health and Human Services to meet the additional costs associated with such use shall not constitute an augmentation of Federal appropriations.


(c) Leases(1) The Secretary of the Interior, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services are authorized to enter into long-term leases of tribally owned or leased facilities to house programs established </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2415_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facility availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Facility availability In the furtherance of the purposes and goals of this chapter, the Secretary of the Interior, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall make available for community use, to the extent permitted by law and as may be provided in a Tribal Action Plan, local Federal facilities, property, and equipment, including school facilities. Such facility availability shall include school facilities under the Secretary of the Interior’s jurisdiction: Provided, That the use of any school facilities shall be conditioned upon approval of the local school board with jurisdiction over such school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2415_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Costs Any additional cost associated with the use of Federal facilities, property, or equipment under subsection (a) may be borne by the Secretary of the Interior, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services out of available Federal, tribal, State, local, or private funds, if not otherwise prohibited by law. This subsection does not require the Secretary of the Interior, nor the Attorney General, nor the Secretary of Health and Human Services to expend additional funds to meet the additional costs which may be associated with the provision of such facilities, property, or equipment for community use. Where the use of Federal facilities, property, or equipment under subsection (a) furthers the purposes and goals of this chapter, the use of funds other than those funds appropriated to the Department of the Interior, the Department of Justice, or the Department of Health and Human Services to meet the additional costs associated with such use shall not constit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2415_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Leases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>