<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2503"><akn:num>2503</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2503. Composition of grants(a) In generalThe grant provided under this chapter to an Indian tribe or tribal organization for any fiscal year shall consist of—(1) the total amount of funds allocated for such fiscal year under sections 1127 and 1128 of the Education Amendments of 1978 [25 U.S.C. 2007, 2008] with respect to the tribally controlled schools eligible for assistance under this chapter which are operated by such Indian tribe or tribal organization, including, but not limited to, funds provided under such sections, or under any other provision of law, for transportation costs;

(2) to the extent requested by such Indian tribe or tribal organization, the total amount of funds provided from operations and maintenance accounts and, notwithstanding section 5324 of this title, or any other provision of law, other facilities accounts for such schools for such fiscal year (including but not limited to those referenced under section 1126(d) of the Education Amendments of 1978 [25 U.S.C. 2006(d)] or any other law); and

(3) the total amount of funds that are allocated to such schools for such fiscal year under—(A) title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.];

(B) the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act [20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.]; and

(C) any other Federal education law, that are allocated to such schools for such fiscal year.11 So in original. The words “, that are allocated to such schools for such fiscal year” probably should not appear.



(b) Special rules(1) In general(A) Applicability of certain lawsFunds allocated to a tribally controlled school by reason of paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall be subject to the provisions of this chapter and shall not be subject to any additional restriction, priority, or limitation that is imposed by the Bureau with respect to funds provided under—(i) title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.];

(ii) the Individuals with D</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The grant provided under this chapter to an Indian tribe or tribal organization for any fiscal year shall consist of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>