<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2504"><akn:num>2504</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2504. Eligibility for grants(a) Rules(1) In generalA tribally controlled school is eligible for assistance under this chapter if the school—(A) on April 28, 1988, was a contract school under title XI of the Education Amendments of 1978 [25 U.S.C. 2000 et seq.] and the tribe or tribal organization operating the school submits to the Secretary a written notice of election to receive a grant under this chapter;

(B) was a Bureau-operated school under title XI of the Education Amendments of 1978 [25 U.S.C. 2000 et seq.] and has met the requirements of subsection (b);

(C) is a school for which the Bureau has not provided funds, but which has met the requirements of subsection (c); or

(D) is a school with respect to which an election has been made under paragraph (2) and which has met the requirements of subsection (b).


(2) New schoolsAny application which has been submitted under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.] by an Indian tribe for a school which is not in operation on January 8, 2002, shall be reviewed under the guidelines and regulations for applications submitted under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act that were in effect at the time the application was submitted, unless the Indian tribe or tribal organization elects to have the application reviewed under the provisions of subsection (b).



(b) Additional requirements for Bureau-funded schools and certain electing schools(1) Bureau-funded schoolsA school that was a Bureau-funded school under title XI of the Education Amendments of 1978 [25 U.S.C. 2000 et seq.] on January 8, 2002, and any school with respect to which an election is made under subsection (a)(2), meets the requirements of this subsection if—(A) the Indian tribe or tribal organization that operates, or desires to operate, the school submits to the Secretary an application requesting that the Secretary—(i) transfer operation of the school to the Indian tribe or tribal org</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements for Bureau-funded schools and certain electing schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional requirements for Bureau-funded schools and certain electing schools</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements for a school which is not a Bureau-funded school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional requirements for a school which is not a Bureau-funded school</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of applications and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Filing of applications and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date for approved applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date for approved applications Except as provided by subsection (c)(2)(E), a grant provided under this chapter, and any transfer of the operation of a Bureau school made under subsection (b), shall become effective beginning the academic year succeeding the fiscal year in which the application for the grant or transfer is made, or at an earlier date determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Denial of applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report The Bureau shall submit an annual report to the Congress on all applications received, and actions taken (including the costs associated with such actions), under this section at the same time that the President is required to submit to Congress the budget under section 1105 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>