<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2505" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2505/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2505/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2505"><akn:num>2505</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of eligibility determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2505. Duration of eligibility determination(a) In generalIf the Secretary determines that a tribally controlled school is eligible for assistance under this chapter, the eligibility determination shall remain in effect until the determination is revoked by the Secretary, and the requirements of subsection (b) or (c) of section 2504 of this title, if applicable, shall be considered to have been met with respect to such school until the eligibility determination is revoked by the Secretary.


(b) Annual reports(1) In generalEach recipient of a grant provided under this chapter shall complete an annual report which shall be limited to—(A) an annual financial statement reporting revenue and expenditures as defined by the cost accounting established by the grantee;

(B) an annual financial audit conducted pursuant to the standards of the Single Audit Act of 1984 [31 U.S.C. 7501 et seq.];

(C) a biennial compliance audit of the procurement of personal property during the period for which the report is being prepared that shall be in compliance with written procurement standards that are developed by the local school board;

(D) an annual submission to the Secretary of the number of students served and a brief description of programs offered under the grant; and

(E) a program evaluation conducted by an impartial evaluation review team, to be based on the standards established for purposes of subsection (c)(1)(A)(ii).11 So in original. Probably should be subsection “(c)(1)(B)(ii).”


(2) Evaluation review teamsWhere appropriate, other tribally controlled schools and representatives of tribally controlled community colleges shall make up members of the evaluation review teams.


(3) EvaluationsIn the case of a school which is accredited, evaluations will be conducted at intervals under the terms of accreditation.


(4) Submission of report(A) To tribal governing bodyUpon completion of the report required under paragraph (1), the recipient of the grant shall send (via firs</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2505_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If the Secretary determines that a tribally controlled school is eligible for assistance under this chapter, the eligibility determination shall remain in effect until the determination is revoked by the Secretary, and the requirements of subsection (b) or (c) of section 2504 of this title, if applicable, shall be considered to have been met with respect to such school until the eligibility determination is revoked by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2505_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2505_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation of eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Revocation of eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2505_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of section pursuant to election under section 2507(b)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of section pursuant to election under section 2507(b) With respect to a tribally controlled school that receives assistance under this chapter pursuant to an election made under section 2507(b) of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>