<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2511" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2511/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2511/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2511"><akn:num>2511</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2511. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) BureauThe term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior.


(2) Eligible Indian studentThe term “eligible Indian student” has the meaning given such term in section 2007(f) of this title.


(3) IndianThe term “Indian” means a member of an Indian tribe, and includes individuals who are eligible for membership in a tribe, and the child or grandchild of such an individual.


(4) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including an Alaska Native Village Corporation or Regional Corporation (as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.]), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.


(5) Local educational agencyThe term “local educational agency” means a public board of education or other public authority legally constituted within a State for either administrative control or direction of, or to perform a service function for, public elementary schools or secondary schools in a city, county, township, school district, or other political subdivision of a State or such combination of school districts or counties as are recognized in a State as an administrative agency for the State’s public elementary schools or secondary schools. Such term includes any other public institution or agency having administrative control and direction of a public elementary school or secondary school.


(6) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.


(7) Tribal governing bodyThe term “tribal governing body” means, with respect to any school that receives assistance under this Act,11 See References in Text note below. the recognized governing body of the Indian tribe involved.


(8) Tribal organization(A) In generalThe term “tribal organization” means—(i) the recog</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2511_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Bureau The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2511_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Indian student</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Eligible Indian student The term “eligible Indian student” has the meaning given such term in section 2007(f) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2511_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Indian The term “Indian” means a member of an Indian tribe, and includes individuals who are eligible for membership in a tribe, and the child or grandchild of such an individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2511_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including an Alaska Native Village Corporation or Regional Corporation (as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.]), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2511_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local educational agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Local educational agency The term “local educational agency” means a public board of education or other public authority legally constituted within a State for either administrative control or direction of, or to perform a service function for, public elementary schools or secondary schools in a city, county, township, school district, or other political subdivision of a State or such combination of school districts or counties as are recognized in a State as an administrative agency for the State’s public elementary schools or secondary schools. Such term includes any other public institution or agency having administrative control and direction of a public elementary school or secondary school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2511_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2511_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal governing body</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Tribal governing body The term “tribal governing body” means, with respect to any school that receives assistance under this Act,11 See References in Text note below. the recognized governing body of the Indian tribe involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2511_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Tribal organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2511_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribally controlled school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Tribally controlled school The term “tribally controlled school” means a school that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>