<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2711"><akn:num>2711</akn:num><akn:heading>Management contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2711. Management contracts(a) Class II gaming activity; information on operators(1) Subject to the approval of the Chairman, an Indian tribe may enter into a management contract for the operation and management of a class II gaming activity that the Indian tribe may engage in under section 2710(b)(1) of this title, but, before approving such contract, the Chairman shall require and obtain the following information:(A) the name, address, and other additional pertinent background information on each person or entity (including individuals comprising such entity) having a direct financial interest in, or management responsibility for, such contract, and, in the case of a corporation, those individuals who serve on the board of directors of such corporation and each of its stockholders who hold (directly or indirectly) 10 percent or more of its issued and outstanding stock;

(B) a description of any previous experience that each person listed pursuant to subparagraph (A) has had with other gaming contracts with Indian tribes or with the gaming industry generally, including specifically the name and address of any licensing or regulatory agency with which such person has had a contract relating to gaming; and

(C) a complete financial statement of each person listed pursuant to subparagraph (A).


(2) Any person listed pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) shall be required to respond to such written or oral questions that the Chairman may propound in accordance with his responsibilities under this section.

(3) For purposes of this chapter, any reference to the management contract described in paragraph (1) shall be considered to include all collateral agreements to such contract that relate to the gaming activity.


(b) ApprovalThe Chairman may approve any management contract entered into pursuant to this section only if he determines that it provides at least—(1) for adequate accounting procedures that are maintained, and for verifiable financial reports that are prepared, b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Class II gaming activity; information on operators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Class II gaming activity; information on operators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Approval The Chairman may approve any management contract entered into pursuant to this section only if he determines that it provides at least—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee based on percentage of net revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fee based on percentage of net revenues</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period for approval; extension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Period for approval; extension By no later than the date that is 180 days after the date on which a management contract is submitted to the Chairman for approval, the Chairman shall approve or disapprove such contract on its merits. The Chairman may extend the 180-day period by not more than 90 days if the Chairman notifies the Indian tribe in writing of the reason for the extension. The Indian tribe may bring an action in a United States district court to compel action by the Chairman if a contract has not been approved or disapproved within the period required by this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2711_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disapproval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disapproval The Chairman shall not approve any contract if the Chairman determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2711_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification or voiding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Modification or voiding The Chairman, after notice and hearing, shall have the authority to require appropriate contract modifications or may void any contract if he subsequently determines that any of the provisions of this section have been violated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2711_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest in land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Interest in land No management contract for the operation and management of a gaming activity regulated by this chapter shall transfer or, in any other manner, convey any interest in land or other real property, unless specific statutory authority exists and unless clearly specified in writing in said contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2711_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authority The authority of the Secretary under section 81 of this title, relating to management contracts regulated pursuant to this chapter, is hereby transferred to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2711_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Investigation fee The Commission shall require a potential contractor to pay a fee to cover the cost of the investigation necessary to reach a determination required in subsection (e) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>