<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2716" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2716/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2716/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2716"><akn:num>2716</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigative powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2716. Investigative powers(a) Confidential informationExcept as provided in subsection (b), the Commission shall preserve any and all information received pursuant to this chapter as confidential pursuant to the provisions of paragraphs (4) and (7) of section 552(b) of title 5.


(b) Provision to law enforcement officialsThe Commission shall, when such information indicates a violation of Federal, State, or tribal statutes, ordinances, or resolutions, provide such information to the appropriate law enforcement officials.


(c) Attorney GeneralThe Attorney General shall investigate activities associated with gaming authorized by this chapter which may be a violation of Federal law.


(Pub. L. 100–497, § 17, Oct. 17, 1988, 102 Stat. 2484.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 100–497, Oct. 17, 1988, 102 Stat. 2467, known as the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2701 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2716_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidential information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Confidential information Except as provided in subsection (b), the Commission shall preserve any and all information received pursuant to this chapter as confidential pursuant to the provisions of paragraphs (4) and (7) of section 552(b) of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2716_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision to law enforcement officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Provision to law enforcement officials The Commission shall, when such information indicates a violation of Federal, State, or tribal statutes, ordinances, or resolutions, provide such information to the appropriate law enforcement officials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2716_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Attorney General The Attorney General shall investigate activities associated with gaming authorized by this chapter which may be a violation of Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>