<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2812" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2812/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/2812/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2812"><akn:num>2812</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian Law and Order Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2812. Indian Law and Order Commission(a) EstablishmentThere is established a commission to be known as the Indian Law and Order Commission (referred to in this section as the “Commission”).


(b) Membership(1) In generalThe Commission shall be composed of 9 members, of whom—(A) 3 shall be appointed by the President, in consultation with—(i) the Attorney General; and

(ii) the Secretary;


(B) 2 shall be appointed by the Majority Leader of the Senate, in consultation with the Chairpersons of the Committees on Indian Affairs and the Judiciary of the Senate;

(C) 1 shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate, in consultation with the Vice Chairperson and Ranking Member of the Committees on Indian Affairs and the Judiciary of the Senate;

(D) 2 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Chairpersons of the Committees on the Judiciary and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and

(E) 1 shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Ranking Members of the Committees on the Judiciary and Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.


(2) Requirements for eligibilityEach member of the Commission shall have significant experience and expertise in—(A) the Indian country criminal justice system; and

(B) matters to be studied by the Commission.


(3) Consultation requiredThe President, the Speaker and Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, and the Majority Leader and Minority Leader of the Senate shall consult before the appointment of members of the Commission under paragraph (1) to achieve, to the maximum extent practicable, fair and equitable representation of various points of view with respect to the matters to be studied by the Commission.


(4) TermEach member shall be appointed for the life of the Commission.


(5) Time for initial appointmentsThe appointment of the members of the Commission shall be made not later than 60 da</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established a commission to be known as the Indian Law and Order Commission (referred to in this section as the “Commission”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive study of criminal justice system relating to Indian country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Comprehensive study of criminal justice system relating to Indian country The Commission shall conduct a comprehensive study of law enforcement and criminal justice in tribal communities, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recommendations Taking into consideration the results of the study under paragraph (1),11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (d),”. the Commission shall develop recommendations on necessary modifications and improvements to justice systems at the tribal, Federal, and State levels, including consideration of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the President and Congress a report that contains—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission personnel matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Commission personnel matters</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Contracts for research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2812_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Tribal Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>