<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3001" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3001/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3001/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3001"><akn:num>3001</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3001. Definitions
For purposes of this chapter, the term—(1) “burial site” means any natural or prepared physical location, whether originally below, on, or above the surface of the earth, into which as a part of the death rite or ceremony of a culture, individual human remains are deposited.

(2) “cultural affiliation” means that there is a relationship of shared group identity which can be reasonably traced historically or prehistorically between a present day Indian tribe or Native Hawaiian organization and an identifiable earlier group.

(3) “cultural items” means human remains and—(A) “associated funerary objects” which shall mean objects that, as a part of the death rite or ceremony of a culture, are reasonably believed to have been placed with individual human remains either at the time of death or later, and both the human remains and associated funerary objects are presently in the possession or control of a Federal agency or museum, except that other items exclusively made for burial purposes or to contain human remains shall be considered as associated funerary objects.11 So in original. The period probably should be a comma.

(B) “unassociated funerary objects” which shall mean objects that, as a part of the death rite or ceremony of a culture, are reasonably believed to have been placed with individual human remains either at the time of death or later, where the remains are not in the possession or control of the Federal agency or museum and the objects can be identified by a preponderance of the evidence as related to specific individuals or families or to known human remains or, by a preponderance of the evidence, as having been removed from a specific burial site of an individual culturally affiliated with a particular Indian tribe,

(C) “sacred objects” which shall mean specific ceremonial objects which are needed by traditional Native American religious leaders for the practice of traditional Native American religions by their present day adhere</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) “burial site” means any natural or prepared physical location, whether originally below, on, or above the surface of the earth, into which as a part of the death rite or ceremony of a culture, individual human remains are deposited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) “cultural affiliation” means that there is a relationship of shared group identity which can be reasonably traced historically or prehistorically between a present day Indian tribe or Native Hawaiian organization and an identifiable earlier group.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) “cultural items” means human remains and—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) “Federal agency” means any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States. Such term does not include the Smithsonian Institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) “Federal lands” means any land other than tribal lands which are controlled or owned by the United States, including lands selected by but not yet conveyed to Alaska Native Corporations and groups organized pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act of 1971 [43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) “Hui Malama I Na Kupuna O Hawai’i Nei” means the nonprofit, Native Hawaiian organization incorporated under the laws of the State of Hawaii by that name on April 17, 1989, for the purpose of providing guidance and expertise in decisions dealing with Native Hawaiian cultural issues, particularly burial issues.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) “Indian tribe” means any tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community of Indians, including any Alaska Native village (as defined in, or established pursuant to, the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act [43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.]), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) “museum” means any institution or State or local government agency (including any institution of higher learning) that receives Federal funds and has possession of, or control over, Native American cultural items. Such term does not include the Smithsonian Institution or any other Federal agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) “Native American” means of, or relating to, a tribe, people, or culture that is indigenous to the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) “Native Hawaiian” means any individual who is a descendant of the aboriginal people who, prior to 1778, occupied and exercised sovereignty in the area that now constitutes the State of Hawaii.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>