<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3006" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3006/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3006/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3006"><akn:num>3006</akn:num><akn:heading>Review committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3006. Review committee(a) EstablishmentWithin 120 days after November 16, 1990, the Secretary shall establish a committee to monitor and review the implementation of the inventory and identification process and repatriation activities required under sections 3003, 3004 and 3005 of this title.


(b) Membership(1) The Committee 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. established under subsection (a) shall be composed of 7 members,(A) 3 of whom shall be appointed by the Secretary from nominations submitted by Indian tribes, Native Hawaiian organizations, and traditional Native American religious leaders with at least 2 of such persons being traditional Indian religious leaders;

(B) 3 of whom shall be appointed by the Secretary from nominations submitted by national museum organizations and scientific organizations; and

(C) 1 who shall be appointed by the Secretary from a list of persons developed and consented to by all of the members appointed pursuant to subparagraphs (A) and (B).


(2) The Secretary may not appoint Federal officers or employees to the committee.

(3) In the event vacancies shall occur, such vacancies shall be filled by the Secretary in the same manner as the original appointment within 90 days of the occurrence of such vacancy.

(4) Members of the committee established under subsection (a) shall serve without pay, but shall be reimbursed at a rate equal to the daily rate for GS–18 of the General Schedule for each day (including travel time) for which the member is actually engaged in committee business. Each member shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with sections 5702 and 5703 of title 5.


(c) ResponsibilitiesThe committee established under subsection (a) shall be responsible for—(1) designating one of the members of the committee as chairman;

(2) monitoring the inventory and identification process conducted under sections 3003 and 3004 of this title to ensure a fair, objectiv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3006_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Within 120 days after November 16, 1990, the Secretary shall establish a committee to monitor and review the implementation of the inventory and identification process and repatriation activities required under sections 3003, 3004 and 3005 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3006_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3006_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities The committee established under subsection (a) shall be responsible for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3006_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Admissibility of records and findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Admissibility of records and findings Any records and findings made by the review committee pursuant to this chapter relating to the identity or cultural affiliation of any cultural items and the return of such items may be admissible in any action brought under section 3013 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3006_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recommendations and report The committee shall make the recommendations under paragraph 22 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (c)(5) in consultation with Indian tribes and Native Hawaiian organizations and appropriate scientific and museum groups.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3006_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Access The Secretary shall ensure that the committee established under subsection (a) and the members of the committee have reasonable access to Native American cultural items under review and to associated scientific and historical documents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3006_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Duties of Secretary The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3006_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Annual report The committee established under subsection (a) shall submit an annual report to the Congress on the progress made, and any barriers encountered, in implementing this section during the previous year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3006_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination The committee established under subsection (a) shall terminate at the end of the 120-day period beginning on the day the Secretary certifies, in a report submitted to Congress, that the work of the committee has been completed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>