<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3054" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3054/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3054/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3054"><akn:num>3054</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary closure for traditional and cultural purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3054. Temporary closure for traditional and cultural purposes(a) Recognition of historic useTo the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure access to National Forest System land by Indians for traditional and cultural purposes, in accordance with subsection (b), in recognition of the historic use by Indians of National Forest System land.


(b) Closing land from public access(1) Authority to closeUpon the approval by the Secretary of a request from an Indian tribe, the Secretary may temporarily close from public access specifically identified National Forest System land to protect the privacy of tribal activities for traditional and cultural purposes.


(2) LimitationA closure of National Forest System land under paragraph (1) shall affect the smallest practicable area for the minimum period necessary for activities of the applicable Indian tribe.


(3) ConsistencyAccess by Indian tribes to National Forest System land under this subsection shall be consistent with the purposes of Public Law 95–341 (commonly known as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act; 42 U.S.C. 1996).



(Pub. L. 110–234, title VIII, § 8104, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1288; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VIII, § 8104, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2049.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe American Indian Religious Freedom Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(3), is Pub. L. 95–341, Aug. 11, 1978, 92 Stat. 469, which is classified to sections 1996 and 1996a of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1996 of Title 42 and Tables.

Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 enacted identical sections. Pub. L. 110–234 was repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection and repeal of Pub. L. 110–234 by Pub. L. 110–246 effective May 22, 2008, the date of enactment of Pub. L. 110–234, see section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246, set out </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition of historic use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recognition of historic use To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure access to National Forest System land by Indians for traditional and cultural purposes, in accordance with subsection (b), in recognition of the historic use by Indians of National Forest System land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3054_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Closing land from public access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Closing land from public access</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>