<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/305e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/305e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/305e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_305e"><akn:num>305e</akn:num><akn:heading>Cause of action for misrepresentation of Indian produced goods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 305e. Cause of action for misrepresentation of Indian produced goods(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) IndianThe term “Indian” means an individual that—(A) is a member of an Indian tribe; or

(B) is certified as an Indian artisan by an Indian tribe.


(2) Indian productThe term “Indian product” has the meaning given the term in any regulation promulgated by the Secretary.


(3) Indian tribe(A) In generalThe term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of this title.


(B) InclusionThe term “Indian tribe” includes, for purposes of this section only, an Indian group that has been formally recognized as an Indian tribe by—(i) a State legislature;

(ii) a State commission; or

(iii) another similar organization vested with State legislative tribal recognition authority.



(4) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.



(b) Injunctive or equitable relief; damagesA person specified in subsection (d) may, in a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction, bring an action against a person who, directly or indirectly, offers or displays for sale or sells a good, with or without a Government trademark, in a manner that falsely suggests it is Indian produced, an Indian product, or the product of a particular Indian or Indian tribe or Indian arts and crafts organization, resident within the United States, to—(1) obtain injunctive or other equitable relief; and

(2) recover the greater of—(A) treble damages; or

(B) in the case of each aggrieved individual Indian, Indian tribe, or Indian arts and crafts organization, not less than $1,000 for each day on which the offer or display for sale or sale continues.



For purposes of paragraph (2)(A), damages shall include any and all gross profits accrued by the defendant as a result of the activities found to violate this subsection.

(c) Punitive damages; attorney’s feeIn addition to the relief specified in subsection (b), the court may award punitive damages and the costs of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctive or equitable relief; damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Injunctive or equitable relief; damages A person specified in subsection (d) may, in a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction, bring an action against a person who, directly or indirectly, offers or displays for sale or sells a good, with or without a Government trademark, in a manner that falsely suggests it is Indian produced, an Indian product, or the product of a particular Indian or Indian tribe or Indian arts and crafts organization, resident within the United States, to— For purposes of paragraph (2)(A), damages shall include any and all gross profits accrued by the defendant as a result of the activities found to violate this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Punitive damages; attorney’s fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Punitive damages; attorney’s fee In addition to the relief specified in subsection (b), the court may award punitive damages and the costs of the civil action and a reasonable attorney’s fee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons that may initiate civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Persons that may initiate civil actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Savings provision If any provision of this section is held invalid, it is the intent of Congress that the remaining provisions of this section shall continue in full force and effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations Not later than 180 days after November 9, 2000, the Board shall promulgate regulations to include in the definition of the term “Indian product” specific examples of such product to provide guidance to Indian artisans as well as to purveyors and consumers of Indian arts and crafts, as defined under this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>