<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3208" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3208/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3208/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3208"><akn:num>3208</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian Child Abuse Treatment Grant Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3208. Indian Child Abuse Treatment Grant Program(a) EstablishmentThe Service, in cooperation with the Bureau, shall establish an Indian Child Abuse Treatment Grant Program that provides grants to any Indian tribe or inter­tribal consortium for the establishment on Indian reservations of treatment programs for Indians who have been victims of child abuse or neglect.


(b) Grant applications(1) Any Indian tribe or intertribal consortium, on its own or in partnership with an urban Indian organization, may submit to the Service an application for a grant under subsection (a).

(2) Any application submitted under paragraph (1)—(A) shall be in such form as the Service may prescribe;

(B) shall be submitted to the Service on or before the date designated by the Service; and

(C) shall specify—(i) the nature of the program proposed by the applicant,

(ii) the data and information on which the program is based,

(iii) the extent to which the program plans to use or incorporate existing services available on the reservation, and

(iv) the specific treatment concepts to be used under the program.




(c) Culturally appropriate treatmentIn awarding grants under this section, the Service shall encourage the use of culturally appropriate treatment services and programs that respond to the unique cultural values, customs, and traditions of applicant Indian Tribes.


(d) Grant administration and final reportEach recipient of a grant awarded under subsection (a) shall—(1) furnish the Service with such information as the Service may require to—(A) evaluate the program for which the grant is made, and

(B) ensure that the grant funds are expended for the purposes for which the grant was made, and


(2) submit to the Service at the close of the term of the grant a final report which shall include such information as the Service may require.


(e) ReportNot later than 2 years after December 23, 2024, the Service shall submit a report to Congress on the award of grants under this secti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Service, in cooperation with the Bureau, shall establish an Indian Child Abuse Treatment Grant Program that provides grants to any Indian tribe or inter­tribal consortium for the establishment on Indian reservations of treatment programs for Indians who have been victims of child abuse or neglect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Culturally appropriate treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Culturally appropriate treatment In awarding grants under this section, the Service shall encourage the use of culturally appropriate treatment services and programs that respond to the unique cultural values, customs, and traditions of applicant Indian Tribes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant administration and final report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant administration and final report Each recipient of a grant awarded under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report Not later than 2 years after December 23, 2024, the Service shall submit a report to Congress on the award of grants under this section. The report shall contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations there 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. is hereby authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1992, 1993, 1994, 1995, 1996, and 1997.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>