<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3305"><akn:num>3305</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3305. Allocation of grant funds(a) Allocation of funds(1) In generalThe Secretary shall continue to determine the amount of program funds to be received by each grantee under this subchapter by the same method used for determining such distribution in fiscal year 1991 for tribally-administered and Bureau-administered programs of grants to individual Indians to defray postsecondary expenses.


(2) Administrative costsIn addition to the amount determined under paragraph (1), a grantee which has exercised the option given in section 3304(a) of this title to administer the program under a grant shall receive an amount for administrative costs determined pursuant to the method used by the grantee during the preceding contract period. All other grantees shall receive an amount for administrative costs determined pursuant to the regulations governing such determinations under the Indian Self Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.], as in effect at the time of application to grants being made.


(3) Single grant; separate accountsEach grantee shall receive only one grant during any fiscal year, which shall include both of the amounts under paragraphs (1) and (2). Each grantee shall maintain this grant in a separate account.



(b) Use of fundsFunds provided by grants under this subchapter shall be used—(1) to make grants to individual Indian students to meet, on the basis of need, any educational expense of attendance in a postsecondary education program (as determined under the contracts applying to the postsecondary education program administered by tribes under the Indian Self Determination and Education Assistance Act (Public Law 93–638) [25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.]), to the extent that such expense is not met from other sources or cannot be defrayed through the action of any State, Federal, or municipal Act, except that nothing in this subsection shall be interpreted as requiring any priority in consideration of resources; and

(2) costs of ad</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allocation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds Funds provided by grants under this subchapter shall be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>