<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3401"><akn:num>3401</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3401. Statement of purpose
The purpose of this chapter is to facilitate the ability of Indian tribes and tribal organizations to integrate the employment, training and related services they provide from diverse Federal sources in order to improve the effectiveness of those services, reduce joblessness in Indian communities, and serve tribally determined goals consistent with the policy of self-determination, while reducing administrative, reporting, and accounting costs.
(Pub. L. 102–477, § 2, Oct. 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 2302; Pub. L. 115–93, § 3, Dec. 18, 2017, 131 Stat. 2026.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2017—Pub. L. 115–93 substituted “The purpose of this chapter is to facilitate the ability of Indian tribes and tribal organizations to” for “The purposes of this chapter are to demonstrate how Indian tribal governments can” and “, and serve tribally determined” for “and serve tribally-determined” and inserted “from diverse Federal sources” after “they provide” and “, while reducing administrative, reporting, and accounting costs” after “self-determination”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 2017 AmendmentPub. L. 115–93, § 1, Dec. 18, 2017, 131 Stat. 2026, provided that: “This Act [amending this section and sections 3402 to 3407, 3409 to 3413, 3416, and 3417 of this title, repealing sections 3414 and 3415 of this title, and enacting and amending provisions set out as notes under this section] may be cited as the ‘Indian Employment, Training and Related Services Consolidation Act of 2017’.”


Short Title of 2000 AmendmentPub. L. 106–568, title XI, § 1101, Dec. 27, 2000, 114 Stat. 2930, provided that: “This title [amending sections 3402, 3404, and 3406 to 3408 of this title and enacting provisions set out as notes under this section] may be cited as the ‘Indian Employment, Training, and Related Services Demonstration Act Amendments of 2000’.”


Short TitlePub. L. 102–477, § 1, Oct. 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 2302, as amended by Pub. L. 115–93, § 2(a), D</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>