<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3413" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3413/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3413/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3413"><akn:num>3413</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3413. Administration of funds(a) Requirements(1) In general(A) Consolidation and reallocation of fundsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, all amounts transferred to a tribe pursuant to an approved plan may be consolidated, reallocated, and rebudgeted as specified in the approved plan to best meet the employment, training, and related needs of the local community served by the Indian tribe.


(B) Authorized use of fundsThe amounts used to carry out a plan approved under this chapter shall be administered in such manner as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to ensure the amounts are spent on activities authorized under the approved plan.


(C) EffectNothing in this section interferes with the ability of the Secretary or the lead agency to use accounting procedures that conform to generally accepted accounting principles, auditing procedures, and safeguarding of funds that conform to chapter 75 of title 31 (commonly known as the “Single Audit Act of 1984”).



(2) Separate records and audits not requiredNotwithstanding any other provision of law (including regulations and circulars of any agency (including Office of Management and Budget Circular A–133)), an Indian tribe that has in place an approved plan under this chapter shall not be required—(A) to maintain separate records that trace any service or activity conducted under the approved plan to the program for which the funds were initially authorized or transferred;

(B) to allocate expenditures among such a program; or

(C) to audit expenditures by the original source of the program.



(b) Carryover(1) In generalAny funds transferred to an Indian tribe under this chapter that are not obligated or expended prior to the beginning of the fiscal year after the fiscal year for which the funds were appropriated shall remain available for obligation or expenditure without fiscal year limitation, subject to the condition that the funds shall be obligated or expended in accordance with the approved plan</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryover</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Carryover</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indirect costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Indirect costs Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an Indian tribe shall be entitled to recover 100 percent of any indirect costs incurred by the Indian tribe as a result of the transfer of funds to the Indian tribe under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Overage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Matching funds Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any funds transferred to an Indian tribe under this chapter shall be treated as non-Federal funds for purposes of meeting matching requirements under any other Federal law, except those administered by the Department of Labor or the Department of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Claims The following provisions of law shall apply to plans approved under this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest or other income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Interest or other income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>