<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3416" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3416/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3416/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3416"><akn:num>3416</akn:num><akn:heading>Labor market information on Indian work force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3416. Labor market information on Indian work force(a) ReportThe Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary, Indian tribes, and the Director of the Bureau of the Census, shall develop, maintain and publish, not less than biennially, a report on the population eligible for the services which the Secretary provides to Indian people. The report shall include, but is not limited to, information at the national level by State, Bureau of Indian Affairs Service area, and tribal level for the—(1) total service population;

(2) the service population under age 16 and over 64;

(3) the population available for work, including those not considered to be actively seeking work;

(4) the employed population, including those employed with annual earnings below the poverty line; and

(5) the numbers employed in private sector positions and in public sector positions.


(b) Indian demographic informationThe Secretary, in consultation with the Bureau of the Census of the Department of Commerce, and the National Center for Native American Studies and Policy Development authorized by Public Law 101–301, shall prepare a report on the need for comprehensive, accurate and periodically updated information on the size and characteristics of the Indian and Alaska Native population throughout the entire United States. This report shall include the need for information, together with the cost of acquiring such information, on the characteristics and need for education, health, housing, job training, and other basic needs of such population, and shall take into consideration the need for this information by Indian tribes and organizations serving Indians in nonreservation areas. The report shall be submitted to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives not later than 12 months after October 23, 1992.


(Pub. L. 102–477, § 15, formerly § 17, Oct. 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 2</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3416_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Report The Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary, Indian tribes, and the Director of the Bureau of the Census, shall develop, maintain and publish, not less than biennially, a report on the population eligible for the services which the Secretary provides to Indian people. The report shall include, but is not limited to, information at the national level by State, Bureau of Indian Affairs Service area, and tribal level for the—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3416_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian demographic information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Indian demographic information The Secretary, in consultation with the Bureau of the Census of the Department of Commerce, and the National Center for Native American Studies and Policy Development authorized by Public Law 101–301, shall prepare a report on the need for comprehensive, accurate and periodically updated information on the size and characteristics of the Indian and Alaska Native population throughout the entire United States. This report shall include the need for information, together with the cost of acquiring such information, on the characteristics and need for education, health, housing, job training, and other basic needs of such population, and shall take into consideration the need for this information by Indian tribes and organizations serving Indians in nonreservation areas. The report shall be submitted to the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources and the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>