<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3501"><akn:num>3501</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3501. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Indian Energy Policy and Programs, Department of Energy.

(2) The term “Indian land” means—(A) any land located within the boundaries of an Indian reservation, pueblo, or rancheria;

(B) any land not located within the boundaries of an Indian reservation, pueblo, or rancheria, the title to which is held—(i) in trust by the United States for the benefit of an Indian tribe or an individual Indian;

(ii) by an Indian tribe or an individual Indian, subject to restriction against alienation under laws of the United States; or

(iii) by a dependent Indian community;


(C) land that is owned by an Indian tribe and was conveyed by the United States to a Native Corporation pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.), or that was conveyed by the United States to a Native Corporation in exchange for such land;

(D) any land located in a census tract in which the majority of residents are Natives (as defined in section 3(b) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1602(b))); and

(E) any land located in a census tract in which the majority of residents are persons who are enrolled members of a federally recognized Tribe or village.


(3) The term “Indian reservation” includes—(A) an Indian reservation in existence in any State or States as of August 8, 2005;

(B) a public domain Indian allotment; and

(C) a dependent Indian community located within the borders of the United States, regardless of whether the community is located—(i) on original or acquired territory of the community; or

(ii) within or outside the boundaries of any State or States.



(4)(A) The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450b).11 See References in Text note below.

(B) For the purpose of paragraph (12) and sections 3503(b)(1)(C) and 3504 of this title, the term “I</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Indian Energy Policy and Programs, Department of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “Indian land” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “Indian reservation” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “integration of energy resources” means any project or activity that promotes the location and operation of a facility (including any pipeline, gathering system, transportation system or facility, or electric transmission or distribution facility) on or near Indian land to process, refine, generate electricity from, or otherwise develop energy resources on, Indian land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “Native Corporation” has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1602).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “organization” means a partnership, joint venture, limited liability company, or other unincorporated association or entity that is established to develop Indian energy resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “Program” means the Indian energy resource development program established under section 3502(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “qualified Indian tribe” means an Indian tribe that has—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>