<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3611"><akn:num>3611</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Tribal Justice Support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3611. Office of Tribal Justice Support(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established within the Bureau the Office of Tribal Justice Support. The purpose of the Office shall be to further the development, operation, and enhancement of tribal justice systems and Courts of Indian Offenses.


(b) Transfer of existing functions and personnelAll functions performed before December 3, 1993, by the Branch of Judicial Services of the Bureau and all personnel assigned to such Branch as of December 3, 1993, are hereby transferred to the Office of Tribal Justice Support. Any reference in any law, regulation, executive order, reorganization plan, or delegation of authority to the Branch of Judicial Services is deemed to be a reference to the Office of Tribal Justice Support.


(c) FunctionsIn addition to the functions transferred to the Office pursuant to subsection (b), the Office shall perform the following functions:(1) Provide funds to Indian tribes and tribal organizations for the development, enhancement, and continuing operation of tribal justice systems.

(2) Provide technical assistance and training, including programs of continuing education and training for personnel of Courts of Indian Offenses.

(3) Study and conduct research concerning the operation of tribal justice systems.

(4) Promote cooperation and coordination among tribal justice systems and the Federal and State judiciary systems.

(5) Oversee the continuing operations of the Courts of Indian Offenses.

(6) Provide funds to Indian tribes and tribal organizations for the continuation and enhancement of traditional tribal judicial practices.


(d) No imposition of standardsNothing in this chapter shall be deemed or construed to authorize the Office to impose justice standards on Indian tribes.


(e) Assistance to tribes(1) The Office shall provide technical assistance and training to any Indian tribe or tribal organization upon request. Technical assistance and training shall include (but not be limited to) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3611_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established within the Bureau the Office of Tribal Justice Support. The purpose of the Office shall be to further the development, operation, and enhancement of tribal justice systems and Courts of Indian Offenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3611_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of existing functions and personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of existing functions and personnel All functions performed before December 3, 1993, by the Branch of Judicial Services of the Bureau and all personnel assigned to such Branch as of December 3, 1993, are hereby transferred to the Office of Tribal Justice Support. Any reference in any law, regulation, executive order, reorganization plan, or delegation of authority to the Branch of Judicial Services is deemed to be a reference to the Office of Tribal Justice Support.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3611_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions In addition to the functions transferred to the Office pursuant to subsection (b), the Office shall perform the following functions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3611_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No imposition of standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No imposition of standards Nothing in this chapter shall be deemed or construed to authorize the Office to impose justice standards on Indian tribes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3611_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assistance to tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3611_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information clearinghouse on tribal justice systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Information clearinghouse on tribal justice systems The Office shall maintain an information clearinghouse (which shall include an electronic data base) on tribal justice systems and Courts of Indian Offenses, including (but not limited to) information on staffing, funding, model tribal codes, tribal justice activities, and tribal judicial decisions. The Office shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure the confidentiality of records and other matters involving privacy rights.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>