<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3712" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3712/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3712/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3712"><akn:num>3712</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian participation in land management activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3712. Indian participation in land management activities(a) Tribal recognitionThe Secretary shall conduct all land management activities on Indian agricultural land in accordance with goals and objectives set forth in the approved agricultural resource management plan, in an integrated resource management plan, and in accordance with all tribal laws and ordinances, except in specific instances where such compliance would be contrary to the trust responsibility of the United States.


(b) Tribal lawsUnless otherwise prohibited by Federal law, the Secretary shall comply with tribal laws and ordinances pertaining to Indian agricultural lands, including laws regulating the environment and historic or cultural preservation, and laws or ordinances adopted by the tribal government to regulate land use or other activities under tribal jurisdiction. The Secretary shall—(1) provide assistance in the enforcement of such tribal laws;

(2) provide notice of such laws to persons or entities undertaking activities on Indian agricultural lands; and

(3) upon the request of an Indian tribe, require appropriate Federal officials to appear in tribal forums.


(c) Waiver of regulationsIn any case in which a regulation or administrative policy of the Department of the Interior conflicts with the objectives of the agricultural resource management plan provided for in section 3711 of this title, or with a tribal law, the Secretary may waive the application of such regulation or administrative policy unless such waiver would constitute a violation of a Federal statute or judicial decision or would conflict with his general trust responsibility under Federal law.


(d) Sovereign immunityThis section does not constitute a waiver of the sovereign immunity of the United States, nor does it authorize tribal justice systems to review actions of the Secretary.


(Pub. L. 103–177, title I, § 102, Dec. 3, 1993, 107 Stat. 2015.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3712_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal recognition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Tribal recognition The Secretary shall conduct all land management activities on Indian agricultural land in accordance with goals and objectives set forth in the approved agricultural resource management plan, in an integrated resource management plan, and in accordance with all tribal laws and ordinances, except in specific instances where such compliance would be contrary to the trust responsibility of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3712_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tribal laws Unless otherwise prohibited by Federal law, the Secretary shall comply with tribal laws and ordinances pertaining to Indian agricultural lands, including laws regulating the environment and historic or cultural preservation, and laws or ordinances adopted by the tribal government to regulate land use or other activities under tribal jurisdiction. The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3712_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver of regulations In any case in which a regulation or administrative policy of the Department of the Interior conflicts with the objectives of the agricultural resource management plan provided for in section 3711 of this title, or with a tribal law, the Secretary may waive the application of such regulation or administrative policy unless such waiver would constitute a violation of a Federal statute or judicial decision or would conflict with his general trust responsibility under Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3712_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sovereign immunity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Sovereign immunity This section does not constitute a waiver of the sovereign immunity of the United States, nor does it authorize tribal justice systems to review actions of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>