<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3803"><akn:num>3803</akn:num><akn:heading>Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3803. Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a dam safety maintenance and repair program within the Bureau to ensure maintenance and monitoring of the condition of each dam identified pursuant to subsection (e) necessary to maintain the dam in a satisfactory condition on a long-term basis.


(b) Transfer of existing functions and personnelAll functions performed before August 23, 1994, pursuant to the Dam Safety Program established by the Secretary of the Interior by order dated February 28, 1980, and all Bureau of Indian Affairs personnel assigned to such program as of August 23, 1994, are hereby transferred to the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program. Any reference in any law, regulation, executive order, reorganization plan, or delegation of authority to the Dam Safety Program is deemed to be a reference to the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program.


(c) RehabilitationUnder the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program, the Secretary shall perform such rehabilitation work as is necessary to bring the dams identified pursuant to subsection (e) to a satisfactory condition. In addition, each dam located on Indian lands shall be regularly maintained pursuant to the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program established pursuant to subsection (a).


(d) Maintenance action planThe Secretary shall develop a maintenance action plan, which shall include a prioritization of actions to be taken, for those dams with a risk hazard rating of high or significant as identified pursuant to subsection (e).


(e) Identification of dams(1) Development of listThe Secretary shall develop a comprehensive list of dams located on Indian lands that describes the dam safety condition classification of each dam, as specified in paragraph (2), the risk hazard classification of each dam, as specified in paragraph (3), and the conditions resulting from maintenance deficiencies.


(2) Dam safety condition classificationsThe dam safety </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a dam safety maintenance and repair program within the Bureau to ensure maintenance and monitoring of the condition of each dam identified pursuant to subsection (e) necessary to maintain the dam in a satisfactory condition on a long-term basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of existing functions and personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of existing functions and personnel All functions performed before August 23, 1994, pursuant to the Dam Safety Program established by the Secretary of the Interior by order dated February 28, 1980, and all Bureau of Indian Affairs personnel assigned to such program as of August 23, 1994, are hereby transferred to the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program. Any reference in any law, regulation, executive order, reorganization plan, or delegation of authority to the Dam Safety Program is deemed to be a reference to the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rehabilitation Under the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program, the Secretary shall perform such rehabilitation work as is necessary to bring the dams identified pursuant to subsection (e) to a satisfactory condition. In addition, each dam located on Indian lands shall be regularly maintained pursuant to the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program established pursuant to subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance action plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Maintenance action plan The Secretary shall develop a maintenance action plan, which shall include a prioritization of actions to be taken, for those dams with a risk hazard rating of high or significant as identified pursuant to subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of dams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Identification of dams</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on program authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on program authorization Work authorized by this chapter shall be for the purpose of dam safety maintenance and structural repair. The Secretary may authorize, upon request of an Indian tribe, up to 20 percent of the cost of repairs to be used to provide additional conservation storage capacity or developing benefits beyond those provided by the original dams and reservoirs. This chapter is not intended to preclude development of increased storage or benefits under any other authority or to preclude measures to protect fish and wildlife.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Technical assistance To carry out the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary may obtain technical assistance on a nonreimbursable basis from other departments and agencies. Notwithstanding any such technical assistance, the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program established under subsection (a) shall be under the direction and control of the Bureau.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Contract authority In addition to any other authority established by law, the Secretary is authorized to contract with Indian tribes under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.) 11 See References in Text note below. to carry out the Dam Safety Maintenance and Repair Program established under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3803_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Annual report The Secretary shall submit an annual report on the implementation of this chapter. The report shall include— The report shall be submitted at the time the budget is required to be submitted under section 1105 of title 31 to the Subcommittee on Native American Affairs of the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>