<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/3906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3906"><akn:num>3906</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal demonstration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3906. Tribal demonstration project(a) In generalThe Director may establish and carry out a program providing for demonstration projects involving open dumps on Indian land or Alaska Native land. It shall be the purpose of such projects to determine if there are unique cost factors involved in the cleanup and maintenance of open dumps on such land, and the extent to which advanced closure planning is necessary. Under the program, the Director is authorized to select no less than three Indian tribal governments or Alaska Native entities to participate in such demonstration projects.


(b) CriteriaCriteria established by the Director for the selection and participation of an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity in the demonstration project shall provide that in order to be eligible to participate, an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity must—(1) have one or more existing open dumps on Indian lands or Alaska Native lands which are under its authority;

(2) have developed a comprehensive solid waste management plan for such lands; and

(3) have developed a closure and postclosure maintenance plan for each dump located on such lands.


(c) Duration of funding for projectNo demonstration project shall be funded for more than three fiscal years.


(Pub. L. 103–399, § 7, Oct. 22, 1994, 108 Stat. 4167.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director may establish and carry out a program providing for demonstration projects involving open dumps on Indian land or Alaska Native land. It shall be the purpose of such projects to determine if there are unique cost factors involved in the cleanup and maintenance of open dumps on such land, and the extent to which advanced closure planning is necessary. Under the program, the Director is authorized to select no less than three Indian tribal governments or Alaska Native entities to participate in such demonstration projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria Criteria established by the Director for the selection and participation of an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity in the demonstration project shall provide that in order to be eligible to participate, an Indian tribal government or Alaska Native entity must—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3906_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of funding for project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duration of funding for project No demonstration project shall be funded for more than three fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>