<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4023" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4023/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4023/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4023"><akn:num>4023</akn:num><akn:heading>Judgment funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4023. Judgment funds(a) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to approve plans under section 4022 of this title for the withdrawal of judgment funds held by the Secretary.


(b) LimitationOnly such funds held by the Secretary under the terms of the Indian Judgment Funds Use or Distribution Act [25 U.S.C. 1401 et seq.] or an Act of Congress which provides for the secretarial management of such judgment funds shall be included in such plans.


(c) Secretarial dutiesIn approving such plans, the Secretary shall ensure—(1) that the purpose and use of the judgment funds identified in the previously approved judgment fund plan will continue to be followed by the Indian tribe in the management of the judgment funds; and

(2) that only funds held for Indian tribes may be withdrawn and that any funds held for individual tribal members are not to be included in the plan.


(Pub. L. 103–412, title II, § 203, Oct. 25, 1994, 108 Stat. 4242.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Indian Judgment Funds Use or Distribution Act, referred to in subsec. (b), probably means the Indian Tribal Judgment Funds Use or Distribution Act, Pub. L. 93–134, Oct. 19, 1973, 87 Stat. 466, which is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 1401 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4023_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary is authorized to approve plans under section 4022 of this title for the withdrawal of judgment funds held by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4023_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation Only such funds held by the Secretary under the terms of the Indian Judgment Funds Use or Distribution Act [25 U.S.C. 1401 et seq.] or an Act of Congress which provides for the secretarial management of such judgment funds shall be included in such plans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4023_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Secretarial duties In approving such plans, the Secretary shall ensure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>