<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4046" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4046/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4046/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4046"><akn:num>4046</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4046. Advisory board(a) Establishment and membershipNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Special Trustee shall establish an advisory board to provide advice on all matters within the jurisdiction of the Special Trustee. The advisory board shall consist of nine members, appointed by the Special Trustee after consultation with Indian tribes and appropriate Indian organizations, of which—(1) five members shall represent trust fund account holders, including both tribal and Individual Indian Money accounts;

(2) two members shall have practical experience in trust fund and financial management;

(3) one member shall have practical experience in fiduciary investment management; and

(4) one member, from academia, shall have knowledge of general management of large organizations.


(b) TermEach member shall serve a term of two years.


(c) Chapter 10 of title 5The advisory board shall not be subject to chapter 10 of title 5.


(d) TerminationThe advisory board shall terminate upon termination of the Office of Special Trustee.


(Pub. L. 103–412, title III, § 306, Oct. 25, 1994, 108 Stat. 4249; Pub. L. 104–109, § 6(b), Feb. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 764; Pub. L. 117–286, § 4(a)(184), Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4326.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2022—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 117–286 substituted “Chapter 10 of title 5” for “FACA” in heading and “chapter 10 of title 5.” for “the Federal Advisory Committee Act.” in text.
1996—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 104–109 substituted “advisory board” for “Advisory Board”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Appointment of New MembersPub. L. 108–7, div. F, title I, § 133, Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 243, provided that: “Within 90 days of enactment of this Act [Feb. 20, 2003] the Special Trustee for American Indians, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior and the Tribes, shall appoint new members to the Special Trustee Advisory Board.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and membership Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Special Trustee shall establish an advisory board to provide advice on all matters within the jurisdiction of the Special Trustee. The advisory board shall consist of nine members, appointed by the Special Trustee after consultation with Indian tribes and appropriate Indian organizations, of which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Term Each member shall serve a term of two years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chapter 10 of title 5 The advisory board shall not be subject to chapter 10 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination The advisory board shall terminate upon termination of the Office of Special Trustee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>