<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4103"><akn:num>4103</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4103. Definitions
For purposes of this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Adjusted incomeThe term “adjusted income” means the annual income that remains after excluding the following amounts:(A) Youths, students, and persons with disabilities$480 for each member of the family residing in the household (other than the head of the household or the spouse of the head of the household)—(i) who is under 18 years of age; or

(ii) who is—(I) 18 years of age or older; and

(II) a person with disabilities or a full-time student.



(B) Elderly and disabled families$400 for an elderly or disabled family.


(C) Medical and attendant expensesThe amount by which 3 percent of the annual income of the family is exceeded by the aggregate of—(i) medical expenses, in the case of an elderly or disabled family; and

(ii) reasonable attendant care and auxiliary apparatus expenses for each family member who is a person with disabilities, to the extent necessary to enable any member of the family (including a member who is a person with disabilities) to be employed.


(D) Child care expensesChild care expenses, to the extent necessary to enable another member of the family to be employed or to further his or her education.


(E) Earned income of minorsThe amount of any earned income of any member of the family who is less than 18 years of age.


(F) Travel expensesExcessive travel expenses, not to exceed $25 per family per week, for employment- or education-related travel.


(G) Other amountsSuch other amounts as may be provided in the Indian housing plan for an Indian tribe.



(2) Affordable housingThe term “affordable housing” means housing that complies with the requirements for affordable housing under subchapter II. The term includes permanent housing for homeless persons who are persons with disabilities, transitional housing, and single room occupancy housing.


(3) Drug-related criminal activityThe term “drug-related criminal activity” means the illegal manufact</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjusted income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Adjusted income The term “adjusted income” means the annual income that remains after excluding the following amounts:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affordable housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Affordable housing The term “affordable housing” means housing that complies with the requirements for affordable housing under subchapter II. The term includes permanent housing for homeless persons who are persons with disabilities, transitional housing, and single room occupancy housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug-related criminal activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Drug-related criminal activity The term “drug-related criminal activity” means the illegal manufacture, sale, distribution, use, or possession with intent to manufacture, sell, distribute, or use, of a controlled substance (as such term is defined in section 802 of title 21).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elderly families and near-elderly families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Elderly families and near-elderly families The terms “elderly family” and “near-elderly family” mean a family whose head (or his or her spouse), or whose sole member, is an elderly person or a near-elderly person, respectively. Such terms include 2 or more elderly persons or near-elderly persons living together, and 1 or more such persons living with 1 or more persons determined under the Indian housing plan for the agency to be essential to their care or well-being.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elderly person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Elderly person The term “elderly person” means a person who is at least 62 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Family The term “family” includes a family with or without children, an elderly family, a near-­elderly family, a disabled family, and a single person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant beneficiary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Grant beneficiary The term “grant beneficiary” means the Indian tribe or tribes on behalf of which a grant is made under this chapter to a recipient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing related community development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Housing related community development</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Income The term “income” means income from all sources of each member of the household, as determined in accordance with criteria prescribed by the Secretary, except that the following amounts may not be considered as income under this paragraph:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Indian The term “Indian” means any person who is a member of an Indian tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>