<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4114" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4114/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4114/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4114"><akn:num>4114</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of program income and labor standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4114. Treatment of program income and labor standards(a) Program income(1) Authority to retainNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a recipient may retain any program income that is realized from any grant amounts under this chapter if—(A) such income was realized after the initial disbursement of the grant amounts received by the recipient; and

(B) the recipient has agreed that it will utilize such income for housing related activities in accordance with this chapter.


(2) Prohibition of restricted access or reduction of grantThe Secretary may not restrict access to or reduce the grant amount for any Indian tribe based solely on—(A) whether the recipient for the tribe retains program income under paragraph (1);

(B) the amount of any such program income retained;

(C) whether the recipient retains reserve amounts described in section 4140 of this title; or

(D) whether the recipient has expended retained program income for housing-related activities.


(3) Exclusion of amountsThe Secretary may, by regulation, exclude from consideration as program income any amounts determined to be so small that compliance with the requirements of this subsection would create an unreasonable administrative burden on the recipient.


(4) Exclusion from program income of regular developer’s fees for low-income housing tax credit projectsNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, any income derived from a regular and customary developer’s fee for any project that receives a low-income housing tax credit under section 42 of title 26, and that is initially funded using a grant provided under this chapter, shall not be considered to be program income if the developer’s fee is approved by the State housing credit agency.



(b) Labor standards(1) In generalAny contract or agreement for assistance, sale, or lease pursuant to this chapter shall contain a provision requiring that not less than the wages prevailing in the locality, as determined or adopted (subseq</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4114_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4114_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labor standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Labor standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>