<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4132" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4132/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4132/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4132"><akn:num>4132</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible affordable housing activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4132. Eligible affordable housing activities
Affordable housing activities under this subchapter are activities, in accordance with the requirements of this subchapter, to develop, operate, maintain, or support affordable housing for rental or homeownership, or to provide housing services with respect to affordable housing, through the following activities:(1) Indian housing assistanceThe provision of modernization or operating assistance for housing previously developed or operated pursuant to a contract between the Secretary and an Indian housing authority.


(2) DevelopmentThe acquisition, new construction, reconstruction, or moderate or substantial rehabilitation of affordable housing, which may include real property acquisition, site improvement, development and rehabilitation of utilities, necessary infrastructure, and utility services, conversion, demolition, financing, administration and planning, improvement to achieve greater energy efficiency, mold remediation, and other related activities.


(3) Housing servicesThe provision of housing-related services for affordable housing, such as housing counseling in connection with rental or homeownership assistance, establishment and support of resident organizations and resident management corporations, energy auditing, activities related to the provision of self-sufficiency and other services, and other services related to assisting owners, tenants, contractors, and other entities, participating or seeking to participate in other housing activities assisted pursuant to this section.


(4) Housing management servicesThe provision of management services for affordable housing, including preparation of work specifications, loan processing, inspections, tenant selection, management of tenant-based rental assistance, the costs of operation and maintenance of units developed with funds provided under this chapter, and management of affordable housing projects.


(5) Crime prevention and safety activitiesThe provisio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4132_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian housing assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Indian housing assistance The provision of modernization or operating assistance for housing previously developed or operated pursuant to a contract between the Secretary and an Indian housing authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4132_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Development The acquisition, new construction, reconstruction, or moderate or substantial rehabilitation of affordable housing, which may include real property acquisition, site improvement, development and rehabilitation of utilities, necessary infrastructure, and utility services, conversion, demolition, financing, administration and planning, improvement to achieve greater energy efficiency, mold remediation, and other related activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4132_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Housing services The provision of housing-related services for affordable housing, such as housing counseling in connection with rental or homeownership assistance, establishment and support of resident organizations and resident management corporations, energy auditing, activities related to the provision of self-sufficiency and other services, and other services related to assisting owners, tenants, contractors, and other entities, participating or seeking to participate in other housing activities assisted pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4132_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing management services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Housing management services The provision of management services for affordable housing, including preparation of work specifications, loan processing, inspections, tenant selection, management of tenant-based rental assistance, the costs of operation and maintenance of units developed with funds provided under this chapter, and management of affordable housing projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4132_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crime prevention and safety activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Crime prevention and safety activities The provision of safety, security, and law enforcement measures and activities appropriate to protect residents of affordable housing from crime.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4132_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Model activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Model activities Housing activities under model programs that are designed to carry out the purposes of this chapter and are specifically approved by the Secretary as appropriate for such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4132_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community development demonstration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Community development demonstration project</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4132_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-Determination Act demonstration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Self-Determination Act demonstration project</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4132_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Reserve accounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>