<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4145d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4145d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4145d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4145d"><akn:num>4145d</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4145d. Review and report(a) ReviewDuring calendar year 2011, the Secretary shall conduct a review of the results achieved by the program under this part to determine—(1) the housing constructed, acquired, or rehabilitated under the program;

(2) the effects of the housing described in paragraph (1) on costs to low-income families of affordable housing;

(3) the effectiveness of each recipient in achieving the results intended to be achieved, as described in the Indian housing plan for the Indian tribe; and

(4) the need for, and effectiveness of, extending the duration of the program and increasing the amount of grants under section 4111 of this title that may be used under the program.


(b) ReportNot later than December 31, 2011, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the information obtained pursuant to the review under subsection (a) (including any conclusions and recommendations of the Secretary with respect to the program under this part), including—(1) recommendations regarding extension of the program for subsequent fiscal years and increasing the amounts under section 4145a(c) of this title that may be used under the program; and

(2) recommendations for—(A)(i) specific Indian tribes or recipients that should be prohibited from participating in the program for failure to achieve results; and

(ii) the period for which such a prohibition should remain in effect; or


(B) standards and procedures by which Indian tribes or recipients may be prohibited from participating in the program for failure to achieve results.



(c) Provision of information to SecretaryNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, recipients participating in the program under this part shall provide such information to the Secretary as the Secretary may request, in sufficient detail and in a timely manner sufficient to ensure that the review and report required by this section is accomplished in a timely manner.


(Pub. L. 104–330, title II, § 235, as added </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4145d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Review During calendar year 2011, the Secretary shall conduct a review of the results achieved by the program under this part to determine—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4145d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report Not later than December 31, 2011, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the information obtained pursuant to the review under subsection (a) (including any conclusions and recommendations of the Secretary with respect to the program under this part), including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4145d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of information to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provision of information to Secretary Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, recipients participating in the program under this part shall provide such information to the Secretary as the Secretary may request, in sufficient detail and in a timely manner sufficient to ensure that the review and report required by this section is accomplished in a timely manner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>