<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4183" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4183/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4183/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4183"><akn:num>4183</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4183. Savings provision(a) Existing rights and dutiesExcept as provided in sections 4181 and 4182 of this title, this chapter may not be construed to affect the validity of any right, duty, or obligation of the United States or other person arising under or pursuant to any commitment or agreement lawfully entered into before October 1, 1997, under the United States Housing Act of 1937 [42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.], subtitle D of title IV of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act [42 U.S.C. 12899 et seq.],11 See References in Text note below. title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act [42 U.S.C. 12721 et seq.], title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act [42 U.S.C. 11360 et seq.], or section 2 of the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993.


(b) Obligations under repealed provisionsNotwithstanding the amendments made by this subchapter, any obligation of the Secretary made under or pursuant to title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act [42 U.S.C. 12721 et seq.], title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act [42 U.S.C. 11360 et seq.], or section 2 of the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993 shall continue to be governed by the provisions of such Acts (as in effect before the date of the effectiveness of the amendments made by this subchapter).


(Pub. L. 104–330, title V, § 507, Oct. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 4045; Pub. L. 106–400, § 2, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1675; Pub. L. 109–281, § 2(d)(2), Sept. 22, 2006, 120 Stat. 1181.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 104–330, Oct. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 4016, known as the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 4101 of this title and Tables.
The United States Housing Act of 1937, referred to in subsec. (a), is act Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 896, as revised generally</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4183_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing rights and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Existing rights and duties Except as provided in sections 4181 and 4182 of this title, this chapter may not be construed to affect the validity of any right, duty, or obligation of the United States or other person arising under or pursuant to any commitment or agreement lawfully entered into before October 1, 1997, under the United States Housing Act of 1937 [42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.], subtitle D of title IV of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act [42 U.S.C. 12899 et seq.],11 See References in Text note below. title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act [42 U.S.C. 12721 et seq.], title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act [42 U.S.C. 11360 et seq.], or section 2 of the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4183_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations under repealed provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Obligations under repealed provisions Notwithstanding the amendments made by this subchapter, any obligation of the Secretary made under or pursuant to title II of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act [42 U.S.C. 12721 et seq.], title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act [42 U.S.C. 11360 et seq.], or section 2 of the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993 shall continue to be governed by the provisions of such Acts (as in effect before the date of the effectiveness of the amendments made by this subchapter).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>