<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4196" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4196/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4196/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4196"><akn:num>4196</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration program for guaranteed loans to finance tribal community and economic development acti</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4196. Demonstration program for guaranteed loans to finance tribal community and economic development activities(a) Authority(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), to the extent and in such amounts as are provided in appropriation Acts, subject to the requirements of this section, and in accordance with such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may guarantee and make commitments to guarantee the notes and obligations issued by Indian tribes or tribally designated housing entities with tribal approval, for the purposes of financing activities carried out on Indian reservations and in other Indian areas that, under the first sentence of section 5308(a) of title 42, are eligible for financing with notes and other obligations guaranteed pursuant to that section.


(2) LimitationThe Secretary may guarantee, or make commitments to guarantee, under paragraph (1) the notes or obligations of not more than 4 Indian tribes or tribally designated housing entities located in each Department of Housing and Urban Development Office of Native American Programs region.



(b) Low-income benefit requirementNot less than 70 percent of the aggregate amount received by an Indian tribe or tribally designated housing entity as a result of a guarantee under this section shall be used for the support of activities that benefit low-income families on Indian reservations and other Indian areas.


(c) Financial soundness(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish underwriting criteria for guarantees under this section, including fees for the guarantees, as the Secretary determines to be necessary to ensure that the program under this section is financially sound.


(2) Amounts of feesFees for guarantees established under paragraph (1) shall be established in amounts that are sufficient, but do not exceed the minimum amounts necessary, to maintain a negative credit subsidy for the program under this section, as determined based on the risk to the Federal Governm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-income benefit requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Low-income benefit requirement Not less than 70 percent of the aggregate amount received by an Indian tribe or tribally designated housing entity as a result of a guarantee under this section shall be used for the support of activities that benefit low-income families on Indian reservations and other Indian areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial soundness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Financial soundness</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms of obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on percentage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on percentage A guarantee made under this section shall guarantee repayment of 95 percent of the unpaid principal and interest due on the note or other obligation guaranteed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security and repayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Security and repayment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Training and information The Secretary, in cooperation with Indian tribes and tribally designated housing entities, may carry out training and information activities with respect to the guarantee program under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on amount of guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations on amount of guarantees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report Not later than 4 years after October 14, 2008, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the use of the authority under this section by Indian tribes and tribally designated housing entities, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4196_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Termination The authority of the Secretary under this section to make new guarantees for notes and obligations shall terminate on October 1, 2013.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>