<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4223" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4223/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4223/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4223"><akn:num>4223</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4223. Housing plan(a) Plan submissionThe Secretary shall—(1) require the Director to submit a housing plan under this section for each fiscal year; and

(2) provide for the review of each plan submitted under paragraph (1).


(b) Five-year planEach housing plan under this section shall—(1) be in a form prescribed by the Secretary; and

(2) contain, with respect to the 5-year period beginning with the fiscal year for which the plan is submitted, the following information:(A) Mission statement.—A general statement of the mission of the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands to serve the needs of the low-income families to be served by the Department.

(B) Goals and objectives.—A statement of the goals and objectives of the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands to enable the Department to serve the needs identified in subparagraph (A) during the period.

(C) Activities plans.—An overview of the activities planned during the period including an analysis of the manner in which the activities will enable the Department to meet its mission, goals, and objectives.



(c) One-year planA housing plan under this section shall—(1) be in a form prescribed by the Secretary; and

(2) contain the following information relating to the fiscal year for which the assistance under this subchapter is to be made available:(A) Goals and objectives.—A statement of the goals and objectives to be accomplished during the period covered by the plan.

(B) Statement of needs.—A statement of the housing needs of the low-income families served by the Department and the means by which those needs will be addressed during the period covered by the plan, including—(i) a description of the estimated housing needs and the need for assistance for the low-income families to be served by the Department, including a description of the manner in which the geographical distribution of assistance is consistent with—(I) the geographical needs of those families; and

(II) needs for various categories of housing assista</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4223_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan submission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Plan submission The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4223_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Five-year plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Five-year plan Each housing plan under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4223_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>One-year plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) One-year plan A housing plan under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4223_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of civil rights statutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of civil rights statutes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4223_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of nonprofit organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of nonprofit organizations As a condition of receiving grant amounts under this subchapter, the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands shall, to the extent practicable, provide for private nonprofit organizations experienced in the planning and development of affordable housing for Native Hawaiians to carry out affordable housing activities with those grant amounts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>