<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4228" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4228/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/4228/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4228"><akn:num>4228</akn:num><akn:heading>Affordable housing activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4228. Affordable housing activities(a) 11 So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted. National objectives and eligible families(1) Primary objectiveThe national objectives of this subchapter are—(A) to assist and promote affordable housing activities to develop, maintain, and operate affordable housing in safe and healthy environments for occupancy by low-income Native Hawaiian families;

(B) to ensure better access to private mortgage markets and to promote self-sufficiency of low-income Native Hawaiian families;

(C) to coordinate activities to provide housing for low-income Native Hawaiian families with Federal, State, and local activities to further economic and community development;

(D) to plan for and integrate infrastructure resources on the Hawaiian Home Lands with housing development; and

(E) to—(i) promote the development of private capital markets; and

(ii) allow the markets referred to in clause (i) to operate and grow, thereby benefiting Native Hawaiian communities.



(2) Eligible families(A) In generalExcept as provided under subparagraph (B), assistance for eligible housing activities under this subchapter shall be limited to low-income Native Hawaiian families.


(B) Exception to low-income requirement(i) In generalThe Director may provide assistance for homeownership activities under—(I) section 4229(b) of this title;

(II) model activities under section 4229(f) of this title; or

(III) loan guarantee activities under section 1715z–13b of title 12 to Native Hawaiian families who are not low-income families, to the extent that the Secretary approves the activities under that section to address a need for housing for those families that cannot be reasonably met without that assistance.


(ii) LimitationsThe Secretary shall establish limitations on the amount of assistance that may be provided under this subchapter for activities for families that are not low-income families.



(C) Other familiesNotwithstanding paragraph (1), the Director </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4228_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted. National objectives and eligible families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>