<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5103"><akn:num>5103</akn:num><akn:heading>Restoration of lands to tribal ownership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5103. Restoration of lands to tribal ownership(a) Protection of existing rightsThe Secretary of the Interior, if he shall find it to be in the public interest, is authorized to restore to tribal ownership the remaining surplus lands of any Indian reservation heretofore opened, or authorized to be opened, to sale, or any other form of disposal by Presidential proclamation, or by any of the public-land laws of the United States: Provided, however, That valid rights or claims of any persons to any lands so withdrawn existing on the date of the withdrawal shall not be affected by this Act: Provided further, That this section shall not apply to lands within any reclamation project heretofore authorized in any Indian reservation.


(b) Papago Indians; permits for easements, etc.(1), (2) Repealed. May 27, 1955, ch. 106, § 1, 69 Stat. 67.

(3) Water reservoirs, charcos, water holes, springs, wells, or any other form of water development by the United States or the Papago Indians shall not be used for mining purposes under the terms of this Act, except under permit from the Secretary of the Interior approved by the Papago Indian Council: Provided, That nothing herein shall be construed as interfering with or affecting the validity of the water rights of the Indians of this reservation: Provided further, That the appropriation of living water heretofore or hereafter affected, by the Papago Indians is recognized and validated subject to all the laws applicable thereto.

(4) Nothing herein contained shall restrict the granting or use of permits for easements or rights-of-way; or ingress or egress over the lands for all proper and lawful purposes.


(June 18, 1934, ch. 576, § 3, 48 Stat. 984; Aug. 28, 1937, ch. 866, 50 Stat. 862; May 27, 1955, ch. 106, § 1, 69 Stat. 67.)

Editorial Notes

References in Text“Heretofore”, referred to in subsec. (a), means before June 18, 1934.
This Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b)(3), is act June 18, 1934, ch. 576, 48 Stat. 984, popularl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of existing rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Protection of existing rights The Secretary of the Interior, if he shall find it to be in the public interest, is authorized to restore to tribal ownership the remaining surplus lands of any Indian reservation heretofore opened, or authorized to be opened, to sale, or any other form of disposal by Presidential proclamation, or by any of the public-land laws of the United States: Provided, however, That valid rights or claims of any persons to any lands so withdrawn existing on the date of the withdrawal shall not be affected by this Act: Provided further, That this section shall not apply to lands within any reclamation project heretofore authorized in any Indian reservation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Papago Indians; permits for easements, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Papago Indians; permits for easements, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>