<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5117" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5117/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5117/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5117"><akn:num>5117</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian preference laws applicable to Bureau of Indian Affairs and Indian Health Service positions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5117. Indian preference laws applicable to Bureau of Indian Affairs and Indian Health Service positions(a) Establishment of retention categories for purposes of reduction-in-force proceduresFor purposes of applying reduction-in-force procedures under subsection (a) of section 3502 of title 5 with respect to positions within the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Indian Health Service, the competitive and excepted service retention registers shall be combined, and any employee entitled to Indian preference who is within a retention category established under regulations prescribed under such subsection to provide due effect to military preference shall be entitled to be retained in preference to other employees not entitled to Indian preference who are within such retention category.


(b) Reassignment of employees other than to positions in higher grades; authority to make determinations respecting(1) The Indian preference laws shall not apply in the case of any reassignment within the Bureau of Indian Affairs or within the Indian Health Service (other than to a position in a higher grade) of an employee not entitled to Indian preference if it is determined that under the circumstances such reassignment is necessary—(A) to assure the health or safety of the employee or of any member of the employee’s household;

(B) in the course of a reduction in force; or

(C) because the employee’s working relationship with a tribe has so deteriorated that the employee cannot provide effective service for such tribe or the Federal Government.


(2) The authority to make any determination under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1) is vested in the Secretary of the Interior with respect to the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to the Indian Health Service, and, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary involved may not delegate such authority to any individual other than a Deputy Secretary or Assistant Sec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5117_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of retention categories for purposes of reduction-in-force procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of retention categories for purposes of reduction-in-force procedures For purposes of applying reduction-in-force procedures under subsection (a) of section 3502 of title 5 with respect to positions within the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Indian Health Service, the competitive and excepted service retention registers shall be combined, and any employee entitled to Indian preference who is within a retention category established under regulations prescribed under such subsection to provide due effect to military preference shall be entitled to be retained in preference to other employees not entitled to Indian preference who are within such retention category.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5117_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reassignment of employees other than to positions in higher grades; authority to make determinations respecting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reassignment of employees other than to positions in higher grades; authority to make determinations respecting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5117_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of applicability in personnel actions; scope, procedures, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver of applicability in personnel actions; scope, procedures, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5117_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Placement of non-Indian employees in other Federal positions; assistance of Office of Personnel Management; cooperation of other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Placement of non-Indian employees in other Federal positions; assistance of Office of Personnel Management; cooperation of other Federal agencies The Office of Personnel Management shall provide all appropriate assistance to the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Indian Health Service in placing non-Indian employees of such agencies in other Federal positions. All other Federal agencies shall cooperate to the fullest extent possible in such placement efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5117_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>