<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5136" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5136/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5136/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5136"><akn:num>5136</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans to purchasers of highly fractioned land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5136. Loans to purchasers of highly fractioned land(a) In generalThe Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to make direct loans in a manner consistent with direct loans pursuant to subtitle D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (7 U.S.C. 1981 et seq.), to any Indian tribe recognized by the Secretary of the Interior or tribal corporation established pursuant to the Indian Reorganization Act (25 U.S.C. 477),11 See References in Text note below. which does not have adequate uncommitted funds, to acquire lands or interests therein within the tribe’s reservation as determined by the Secretary of the Interior, or within a community in Alaska incorporated by the Secretary pursuant to the Indian Reorganization Act [25 U.S.C. 5101 et seq.], for use of the tribe or the corporation or the members of either. Such loans shall be limited to such Indian tribes or tribal corporations as have reasonable prospects of success in their proposed operations and as are unable to obtain sufficient credit elsewhere at reasonable rates and terms to finance the purposes authorized in sections 5136 to 5143 of this title.


(b) Highly fractionated land(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the Secretary of Agriculture may make and insure loans in accordance with section 1929 of title 7 to eligible purchasers of highly fractionated land or to intermediaries in order to establish revolving loan funds for the purchase of highly fractionated land under that section.


(2) ExclusionSection 5140 of this title shall not apply to trust land, restricted tribal land, or tribal corporation land that is mortgaged in accordance with paragraph (1).



(Pub. L. 91–229, § 1, Apr. 11, 1970, 84 Stat. 120; Pub. L. 110–234, title V, § 5501, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1161; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title V, § 5501, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1922; Pub. L. 113–79, title V, § 5402, Feb. 7, 2014, 128 Stat. 840.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5136_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to make direct loans in a manner consistent with direct loans pursuant to subtitle D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (7 U.S.C. 1981 et seq.), to any Indian tribe recognized by the Secretary of the Interior or tribal corporation established pursuant to the Indian Reorganization Act (25 U.S.C. 477),11 See References in Text note below. which does not have adequate uncommitted funds, to acquire lands or interests therein within the tribe’s reservation as determined by the Secretary of the Interior, or within a community in Alaska incorporated by the Secretary pursuant to the Indian Reorganization Act [25 U.S.C. 5101 et seq.], for use of the tribe or the corporation or the members of either. Such loans shall be limited to such Indian tribes or tribal corporations as have reasonable prospects of success in their proposed operations and as are unable to obtain sufficient credit elsewhere at reasonable rates and term</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5136_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Highly fractionated land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Highly fractionated land</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>