<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5142" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5142/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5142/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5142"><akn:num>5142</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of unpaid principal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5142. Reduction of unpaid principal(a) In generalThe Secretary of Agriculture may, on the application of the borrower of a loan or loans made under sections 5136 to 5143 of this title, reduce the unpaid principal balance of such loan or loans to the current fair market value of the land purchased with the proceeds of the loan or loans if—(1) the fair market value of the land has declined by at least 25 percent since such land was purchased by the borrower;

(2) the land has been held by the borrower for a period of at least 5 years; and

(3) the Secretary of the Interior finds that the borrower has insufficient income to both repay the loan or loans and provide normal tribal governmental services.


(b) Fair market value(1) AppraisalCurrent fair market value under subsection (a) of this section shall be determined through an appraisal by an independent qualified fee appraiser, selected by mutual agreement between the borrower and the Secretary of Agriculture.


(2) CostsThe cost of appraisals undertaken under paragraph (1) shall be paid by the borrower.



(c) AppealsDecisions of the Secretary of Agriculture under this section shall be appealable in accordance with the provisions of section 333B 11 See References in Text note below. of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (7 U.S.C. 1983b).


(d) Future applicationsA borrower that had a loan or loans reduced under this section shall not submit an application for another reduction on such loan or loans for a period of 5 years after the initial reduction.


(Pub. L. 91–229, § 6, as added Pub. L. 101–82, title III, § 303, Aug. 14, 1989, 103 Stat. 583.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 333B of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (7 U.S.C. 1983b), referred to in subsec. (c), probably means section 333B of Pub. L. 87–128, as added by Pub. L. 99–198, title XIII, § 1313(a), Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1525, and amended, which related to appeals from adverse decisions under the Act, prior to re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5142_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Agriculture may, on the application of the borrower of a loan or loans made under sections 5136 to 5143 of this title, reduce the unpaid principal balance of such loan or loans to the current fair market value of the land purchased with the proceeds of the loan or loans if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5142_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fair market value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fair market value</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5142_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appeals Decisions of the Secretary of Agriculture under this section shall be appealable in accordance with the provisions of section 333B 11 See References in Text note below. of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (7 U.S.C. 1983b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5142_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Future applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Future applications A borrower that had a loan or loans reduced under this section shall not submit an application for another reduction on such loan or loans for a period of 5 years after the initial reduction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>