<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/53" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/53/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/53/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_53"><akn:num>53</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbursing officers; acting clerks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 53. Disbursing officers; acting clerks
Any disbursing agent of the Indian Service, with the approval of the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, may authorize a clerk employed in his office to act in his place and discharge all the duties devolved upon him by law or regulations during such time as he may be unable to perform the duties of his position because of absence, physical disability, or other disqualifying circumstances: Provided, That such clerk, while acting for his principal, shall be subject to all the liabilities and penalties prescribed by law for official misconduct of disbursing agents.
(Feb. 14, 1920, ch. 75, § 1, 41 Stat. 414; Pub. L. 92–310, title II, § 229(f), June 6, 1972, 86 Stat. 209.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1972—Pub. L. 92–310 struck out provisions which related to official bond of disbursing agent.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions of other officers, employees, and agencies of Department of the Interior, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of the Interior, with power to delegate, see Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1950, §§ 1, 2, eff. May 24, 1950, 15 F.R. 3174, 64 Stat. 1262, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.
Disbursement functions of all Government agencies, except Departments of the Army, Navy, and Air Force and the Panama Canal, transferred to Division of Disbursements, Department of the Treasury, by Ex. Ord. No. 6166, § 4, June 10, 1933, and Ex. Ord. No. 6728, May 29, 1934. Division subsequently consolidated with other agencies into Fiscal Service in Department of the Treasury by Reorg. Plan No. III of 1940, § 1(a)(1), eff. June 30, 1940, 5 F.R. 2107, 54 Stat. 1231. See section 306 of Title 31, Money and Finance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>