<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5321"><akn:num>5321</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-determination contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5321. Self-determination contracts(a) Request by tribe; authorized programs(1) The Secretary is directed, upon the request of any Indian tribe by tribal resolution, to enter into a self-determination contract or contracts with a tribal organization to plan, conduct, and administer programs or portions thereof, including construction programs—(A) provided for in the Act of April 16, 1934 (48 Stat. 596), as amended [25 U.S.C. 5342 et seq.];

(B) which the Secretary is authorized to administer for the benefit of Indians under the Act of November 2, 1921 (42 Stat. 208) [25 U.S.C. 13], and any Act subsequent thereto;

(C) provided by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under the Act of August 5, 1954 (68 Stat. 674), as amended [42 U.S.C. 2001 et seq.];

(D) administered by the Secretary for the benefit of Indians for which appropriations are made to agencies other than the Department of Health and Human Services or the Department of the Interior; and

(E) for the benefit of Indians because of their status as Indians without regard to the agency or office of the Department of Health and Human Services or the Department of the Interior within which it is performed.


The programs, functions, services, or activities that are contracted under this paragraph shall include administrative functions of the Department of the Interior and the Department of Health and Human Services (whichever is applicable) that support the delivery of services to Indians, including those administrative activities supportive of, but not included as part of, the service delivery programs described in this paragraph that are otherwise contractable. The administrative functions referred to in the preceding sentence shall be contractable without regard to the organizational level within the Department that carries out such functions.

(2) If so authorized by an Indian tribe under paragraph (1) of this subsection, a tribal organization may submit a proposal for a self-determination contract, o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request by tribe; authorized programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Request by tribe; authorized programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure upon refusal of request to contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedure upon refusal of request to contract Whenever the Secretary declines to enter into a self-determination contract or contracts pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5321_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability insurance; waiver of defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Liability insurance; waiver of defense</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5321_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal organizations and Indian contractors deemed part of Public Health Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tribal organizations and Indian contractors deemed part of Public Health Service For purposes of section 233 of title 42, with respect to claims by any person, initially filed on or after December 22, 1987, whether or not such person is an Indian or Alaska Native or is served on a fee basis or under other circumstances as permitted by Federal law or regulations for personal injury, including death, resulting from the performance prior to, including, or after December 22, 1987, of medical, surgical, dental, or related functions, including the conduct of clinical studies or investigations, or for purposes of section 2679, title 28, with respect to claims by any such person, on or after November 29, 1990, for personal injury, including death, resulting from the operation of an emergency motor vehicle, an Indian tribe, a tribal organization or Indian contractor carrying out a contract, grant agreement, or cooperative agreement under sections 22 So in original. Probably should be “secti</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5321_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Burden of proof at hearing or appeal declining contract; final agency action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Burden of proof at hearing or appeal declining contract; final agency action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5321_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Good faith requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Good faith requirement In the negotiation of contracts and funding agreements, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5321_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rule of construction Subject to section 101(a) of the PROGRESS for Indian Tribes Act, each provision of this chapter and each provision of a contract or funding agreement shall be liberally construed for the benefit of the Indian Tribe participating in self-determination, and any ambiguity shall be resolved in favor of the Indian Tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>