<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5323"><akn:num>5323</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of Federal employee coverage, rights and benefits by employees of tribal organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5323. Retention of Federal employee coverage, rights and benefits by employees of tribal organizations(a) to (d) Omitted

(e) Eligible employees; Federal employee programs subject to retentionNotwithstanding the provisions of sections 8347(o), 8713, and 8914 of title 5, executive order, or administrative regulation, an employee serving under an appointment not limited to one year or less who leaves Federal employment to be employed by a tribal organization, the city of St. Paul, Alaska, the city of St. George, Alaska, upon incorporation, or the Village Corporations of St. Paul and St. George Islands established pursuant to section 1607 of title 43, in connection with governmental or other activities which are or have been performed by employees in or for Indian communities is entitled, if the employee and the tribal organization so elect, to the following:(1) To retain coverage, rights, and benefits under subchapter I of chapter 81 (“Compensation for Work Injuries”) of title 5, and for this purpose his employment with the tribal organization shall be deemed employment by the United States. However, if an injured employee, or his dependents in case of his death, receives from the tribal organization any payment (including an allowance, gratuity, payment under an insurance policy for which the premium is wholly paid by the tribal organization, or other benefit of any kind) on account of the same injury or death, the amount of that payment shall be credited against any benefit payable under subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5, as follows:(A) payments on account of injury or disability shall be credited against disability compensation payable to the injured employee; and

(B) payments on account of death shall be credited against death compensation payable to dependents of the deceased employee.


(2) To retain coverage, rights, and benefits under chapter 83 (“Retirement”) or chapter 84 (“Federal Employees Retirement System”) of title 5, if necessary employee deduct</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>to (d) Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) to (d) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible employees; Federal employee programs subject to retention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligible employees; Federal employee programs subject to retention Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 8347(o), 8713, and 8914 of title 5, executive order, or administrative regulation, an employee serving under an appointment not limited to one year or less who leaves Federal employment to be employed by a tribal organization, the city of St. Paul, Alaska, the city of St. George, Alaska, upon incorporation, or the Village Corporations of St. Paul and St. George Islands established pursuant to section 1607 of title 43, in connection with governmental or other activities which are or have been performed by employees in or for Indian communities is entitled, if the employee and the tribal organization so elect, to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit by tribal organization of employee deductions and agency contributions in appropriate funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Deposit by tribal organization of employee deductions and agency contributions in appropriate funds During the period an employee is entitled to the coverage, rights, and benefits pursuant to the preceding subsection, the tribal organization employing such employee shall deposit currently in the appropriate funds the employee deductions and agency contributions required by paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of such preceding subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election for retention by employee and tribal organization before date of employment by tribal organization; transfer of employee to another tribal organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Election for retention by employee and tribal organization before date of employment by tribal organization; transfer of employee to another tribal organization An employee who is employed by a tribal organization under subsection (e) of this section and such tribal organization shall make the election to retain the coverages, rights, and benefits in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of such subsection (e) before the date of his employment by a tribal organization. An employee who is employed by a tribal organization under subsection (e) of this section shall continue to be entitled to the benefits of such subsection if he is employed by another tribal organization to perform service in activities of the type described in such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Employee” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Employee” defined For the purposes of subsections (e), (f), and (g) of this section, the term “employee” means an employee as defined in section 2105 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of implementation regulations by President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Promulgation of implementation regulations by President The President may prescribe regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of subsections (e), (f), (g), and (h) of this section and to protect and assure the compensation, retirement, insurance, leave, reemployment rights, and such other similar civil service employment rights as he finds appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional employee employment rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Additional employee employment rights Anything in sections 205 and 207 of title 18 to the contrary notwithstanding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (l) Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) , (l) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_m"><akn:num>(m)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion to career appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(m) Conversion to career appointment The status of an Indian (as defined in section 5129 of this title) appointed (except temporary appointments) to the Federal service under an excepted appointment under the authority of section 5116 of this title, or any other provision of law granting a preference to Indians in personnel actions, shall be converted to a career appointment in the competitive service after three years of continuous service and satisfactory performance. The conversion shall not alter the Indian’s eligibility for preference in personnel actions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>