<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5324" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5324/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5324/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5324"><akn:num>5324</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract or grant provisions and administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5324. Contract or grant provisions and administration(a) Applicability of Federal contracting laws and regulations; waiver of requirements(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, subject to paragraph (3), the contracts and cooperative agreements entered into with tribal organizations pursuant to section 5321 of this title shall not be subject to Federal contracting or cooperative agreement laws (including any regulations), except to the extent that such laws expressly apply to Indian tribes.

(2) Program standards applicable to a nonconstruction self-determination contract shall be set forth in the contract proposal and the final contract of the tribe or tribal organization.

(3)(A) With respect to a construction contract (or a subcontract of such a construction contract), the provisions of division B (except sections 1123, 2303, 2304, and 2313) of subtitle I of title 41 and the regulations relating to acquisitions promulgated under division B (except sections 1123, 2303, 2304, and 2313) of subtitle I of title 41 shall apply only to the extent that the application of such provision 11 So in original. Probably should be “provisions”. to the construction contract (or subcontract) is—(i) necessary to ensure that the contract may be carried out in a satisfactory manner;

(ii) directly related to the construction activity; and

(iii) not inconsistent with this chapter.


(B) A list of the Federal requirements that meet the requirements of clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (A) shall be included in an attachment to the contract pursuant to negotiations between the Secretary and the tribal organization.

(C)(i) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), no Federal law listed in clause (ii) or any other provision of Federal law (including an Executive order) relating to acquisition by the Federal Government shall apply to a construction contract that a tribe or tribal organization enters into under this chapter, unless expressly provided in such law.

(ii) The </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Federal contracting laws and regulations; waiver of requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability of Federal contracting laws and regulations; waiver of requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments; transfer of funds by Treasury for disbursement by tribal organization; accountability for interest accrued prior to disbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payments; transfer of funds by Treasury for disbursement by tribal organization; accountability for interest accrued prior to disbursement Payments of any grants or under any contracts pursuant to sections 5321 and 5322 of this title may be made in advance or by way of reimbursement and in such installments and on such conditions as the appropriate Secretary deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter. The transfer of funds shall be scheduled consistent with program requirements and applicable Treasury regulations, so as to minimize the time elapsing between the transfer of such funds from the United States Treasury and the disbursement thereof by the tribal organization, whether such disbursement occurs prior to or subsequent to such transfer of funds. Tribal organizations shall not be held accountable for interest earned on such funds, pending their disbursement by such organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of self-determination contracts; annual renegotiation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Term of self-determination contracts; annual renegotiation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calendar year basis for contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Calendar year basis for contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date for retrocession of contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date for retrocession of contract If an Indian tribe, or a tribal organization authorized by a tribe, requests retrocession of the appropriate Secretary for any contract or portion of a contract entered into pursuant to this chapter, unless the tribe or tribal organization rescinds the request for retrocession, such retrocession shall become effective on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of existing school buildings, hospitals, and other facilities and equipment therein; acquisition and donation of excess or surplus Government personal property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of existing school buildings, hospitals, and other facilities and equipment therein; acquisition and donation of excess or surplus Government personal property In connection with any self-determination contract or grant made pursuant to section 5321 or 5322 of this title, the appropriate Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance of personal services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Performance of personal services The contracts authorized under section 5321 of this title and grants pursuant to section 5322 of this title may include provisions for the performance of personal services which would otherwise be performed by Federal employees including, but in no way limited to, functions such as determination of eligibility of applicants for assistance, benefits, or services, and the extent or amount of such assistance, benefits, or services to be provided and the provisions of such assistance, benefits, or services, all in accordance with the terms of the contract or grant and applicable rules and regulations of the appropriate Secretary: Provided, That the Secretary shall not make any contract which would impair his ability to discharge his trust responsibilities to any Indian tribe or individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fair and uniform provision by tribal organization of services and assistance to covered Indians</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Fair and uniform provision by tribal organization of services and assistance to covered Indians Contracts and grants with tribal organizations pursuant to sections 5321 and 5322 of this title shall include provisions to assure the fair and uniform provision by such tribal organizations of the services and assistance they provide to Indians under such contracts and grants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Division of administration of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Division of administration of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposal to redesign program, activity, function, or service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Proposal to redesign program, activity, function, or service Upon providing notice to the Secretary, a tribal organization that carries out a nonconstruction self-determination contract may propose a redesign of a program, activity, function, or service carried out by the tribal organization under the contract, including any nonstatutory program standard, in such manner as to best meet the local geographic, demographic, economic, cultural, health, and institutional needs of the Indian people and tribes served under the contract. The Secretary shall evaluate any proposal to redesign any program, activity, function, or service provided under the contract. With respect to declining to approve a redesigned program, activity, function, or service under this subsection, the Secretary shall apply the criteria and procedures set forth in section 5321 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>