<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5325" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5325/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5325/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5325"><akn:num>5325</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract funding and indirect costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5325. Contract funding and indirect costs(a) Amount of funds provided(1) The amount of funds provided under the terms of self-determination contracts entered into pursuant to this chapter shall not be less than the appropriate Secretary would have otherwise provided for the operation of the programs or portions thereof for the period covered by the contract, without regard to any organizational level within the Department of the Interior or the Department of Health and Human Services, as appropriate, at which the program, function, service, or activity or portion thereof, including supportive administrative functions that are otherwise contractable, is operated.

(2) There shall be added to the amount required by paragraph (1) contract support costs which shall consist of an amount for the reasonable costs for activities which must be carried on by a tribal organization as a contractor to ensure compliance with the terms of the contract and prudent management, but which—(A) normally are not carried on by the respective Secretary in his direct operation of the program; or

(B) are provided by the Secretary in support of the contracted program from resources other than those under contract.


(3)(A) The contract support costs that are eligible costs for the purposes of receiving funding under this chapter shall include the costs of reimbursing each tribal contractor for reasonable and allowable costs of—(i) direct program expenses for the operation of the Federal program that is the subject of the contract; and

(ii) any additional administrative or other expense incurred by the governing body of the Indian Tribe or Tribal organization and any overhead expense incurred by the tribal contractor in connection with the operation of the Federal program, function, service, or activity pursuant to the contract,


except that such funding shall not duplicate any funding provided under subsection (a)(1) of this section.

(B) In calculating the reimbursement rate for expense</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of funds provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amount of funds provided</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reductions and increases in amount of funds provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reductions and increases in amount of funds provided The amount of funds required by subsection (a) of this section— Notwithstanding any other provision in this chapter, the provision of funds under this chapter is subject to the availability of appropriations and the Secretary is not required to reduce funding for programs, projects, or activities serving a tribe to make funds available to another tribe or tribal organization under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual reports Not later than May 15 of each year, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress an annual report on the implementation of this chapter. Such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of shortfalls in indirect cost recoveries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of shortfalls in indirect cost recoveries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for indebtedness incurred before fiscal year 1992</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Liability for indebtedness incurred before fiscal year 1992 Indian tribes and tribal organizations shall not be held liable for amounts of indebtedness attributable to theoretical or actual under-recoveries or theoretical over-recoveries of indirect costs, as defined in Office of Management and Budget Circular A–87, incurred for fiscal years prior to fiscal year 1992.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on remedies relating to cost disallowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on remedies relating to cost disallowances Any right of action or other remedy (other than those relating to a criminal offense) relating to any disallowance of costs shall be barred unless the Secretary has given notice of any such disallowance within three hundred and sixty-five days of receiving any required annual single agency audit report or, for any period covered by law or regulation in force prior to October 19, 1984, any other required final audit report. Such notice shall set forth the right of appeal and hearing to the board of contract appeals pursuant to section 5331 of this title. For the purpose of determining the 365-day period specified in this paragraph, an audit report shall be deemed to have been received on the date of actual receipt by the Secretary, if, within 60 days after receiving the report, the Secretary does not give notice of a determination by the Secretary to reject the single-agency report as insufficient due to noncompliance with chapte</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Addition to contract of full amount contractor entitled; adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Addition to contract of full amount contractor entitled; adjustment Upon the approval of a self-determination contract, the Secretary shall add to the contract the full amount of funds to which the contractor is entitled under subsection (a) of this section, subject to adjustments for each subsequent year that such tribe or tribal organization administers a Federal program, function, service, or activity under such contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indirect costs for contracts for construction programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Indirect costs for contracts for construction programs In calculating the indirect costs associated with a self-determination contract for a construction program, the Secretary shall take into consideration only those costs associated with the administration of the contract and shall not take into consideration those moneys actually passed on by the tribal organization to construction contractors and subcontractors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian Health Service and Bureau of Indian Affairs budget consultations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Indian Health Service and Bureau of Indian Affairs budget consultations On an annual basis, the Secretary shall consult with, and solicit the participation of, Indian tribes and tribal organizations in the development of the budget for the Indian Health Service and the Bureau of Indian Affairs (including participation of Indian tribes and tribal organizations in formulating annual budget requests that the Secretary submits to the President for submission to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds for matching or cost participation requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Use of funds for matching or cost participation requirements Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a tribal organization may use funds provided under a self-determination contract to meet matching or cost participation requirements under other Federal and non-Federal programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>