<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5346" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5346/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5346/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5346"><akn:num>5346</akn:num><akn:heading>Local committee of Indian parents in school districts having school boards composed of non-Indian ma</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5346. Local committee of Indian parents in school districts having school boards composed of non-Indian majority(a) Election; functionsWhenever a school district affected by a contract or contracts for the education of Indians pursuant to sections 5342 to 5348 of this title has a local school board not composed of a majority of Indians, the parents of the Indian children enrolled in the school or schools affected by such contract or contracts shall elect a local committee from among their number. Such committee shall fully participate in the development of, and shall have the authority to approve or disapprove programs to be conducted under such contract or contracts, and shall carry out such other duties, and be so structured, as the Secretary of the Interior shall by regulation provide: Provided, however, That, whenever a local Indian committee or committees established pursuant to section 7424(c)(4) of title 20 or an Indian advisory school board or boards established pursuant to sections 5342 to 5348 of this title prior to January 4, 1975, exists in such school district, such committee or board may, in the discretion of the affected tribal governing body or bodies, be utilized for the purposes of this section.


(b) Revocation of contractsThe Secretary of the Interior may, in his discretion, revoke any contract if the contractor fails to permit a local committee to perform its duties pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.


(Apr. 16, 1934, ch. 147, § 5, as added Pub. L. 93–638, title II, § 202, Jan. 4, 1975, 88 Stat. 2213; amended Pub. L. 103–382, title III, § 393(d), Oct. 20, 1994, 108 Stat. 4027; Pub. L. 107–110, title VII, § 702(e), Jan. 8, 2002, 115 Stat. 1947; Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(a), Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 2166.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 456 of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 5 of act Apr. 16, 1934, ch. 147, 4</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5346_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election; functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Election; functions Whenever a school district affected by a contract or contracts for the education of Indians pursuant to sections 5342 to 5348 of this title has a local school board not composed of a majority of Indians, the parents of the Indian children enrolled in the school or schools affected by such contract or contracts shall elect a local committee from among their number. Such committee shall fully participate in the development of, and shall have the authority to approve or disapprove programs to be conducted under such contract or contracts, and shall carry out such other duties, and be so structured, as the Secretary of the Interior shall by regulation provide: Provided, however, That, whenever a local Indian committee or committees established pursuant to section 7424(c)(4) of title 20 or an Indian advisory school board or boards established pursuant to sections 5342 to 5348 of this title prior to January 4, 1975, exists in such school district, such committee or bo</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5346_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation of contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Revocation of contracts The Secretary of the Interior may, in his discretion, revoke any contract if the contractor fails to permit a local committee to perform its duties pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>