<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5348" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5348/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5348/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5348"><akn:num>5348</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of student count</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5348. Computation of student count(a) DefinitionsFor the purposes of sections 5342 to 5348 of this title, the following definitions apply:(1) Contracting partyThe term “contracting party” means an entity that has a contract through a program authorized under sections 5342 to 5348 of this title.


(2) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means an entity that is eligible to apply for a contract for a supplemental or operational support program under sections 5342 to 5348 of this title, as outlined in section 5342 of this title.


(3) Existing contracting partyThe term “existing contracting party” means a contracting party that has a contract under sections 5342 to 5348 of this title that is in effect on December 31, 2018.


(4) JOM Modernization ActThe term “JOM Modernization Act” means the Johnson-O’Malley Supplemental Indian Education Program Modernization Act.


(5) New contracting partyThe term “new contracting party” means an entity that enters into a contract under sections 5342 to 5348 of this title after December 31, 2018.


(6) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.



(b) Determination of the number of eligible Indian students(1) Initial determinations(A) In generalThe Secretary shall make an initial determination of the number of eligible Indian students served or potentially served by each eligible entity in accordance with subparagraph (B).


(B) Process for making the initial determination(i) Preliminary reportNot later than 180 days after December 31, 2018, the Secretary shall publish a preliminary report describing the number of eligible Indian students served or potentially served by each eligible entity, using the most applicable and accurate data (as determined by the Secretary in consultation with eligible entities) from the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the initial determination is to be made from—(I) the Bureau of the Census;

(II) the National Center for Education Statistics; or

(III) the Off</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For the purposes of sections 5342 to 5348 of this title, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of the number of eligible Indian students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of the number of eligible Indian students</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting party student count reporting compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contracting party student count reporting compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hold harmless</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Hold harmless</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding allocation and reform</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding allocation and reform</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased geographical and tribal participation in the Johnson-O’Malley supplementary education program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Increased geographical and tribal participation in the Johnson-O’Malley supplementary education program To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall consult with Indian tribes and contact State educational agencies, local educational agencies, and Alaska Native organizations that have not previously entered into a contract under sections 5342 to 5348 of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rulemaking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student privacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Student privacy The Secretary shall ensure that data is collected and each report is prepared under this section in a manner that protects the rights of eligible Indian students in accordance with section 1232g of title 20 (commonly referred to as the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5348_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) GAO Report Not later than 18 months after the final report described in subsection (b)(1)(B)(iv) is published, the Comptroller General shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>