<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5351"><akn:num>5351</akn:num><akn:heading>School construction, acquisition, or renovation contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5351. School construction, acquisition, or renovation contracts(a) Authorization; prerequisitesThe Secretary is authorized to enter into a contract or contracts with any State education agency or school district for the purpose of assisting such agency or district in the acquisition of sites for, or the construction, acquisition, or renovation of facilities (including all necessary equipment) in school districts on or adjacent to or in close proximity to any Indian reservation or other lands held in trust by the United States for Indians, if such facilities are necessary for the education of Indians residing on any such reservation or lands.


(b) Eligibility requirements for assistance in federally-affected areas; applicability to projects in determining maximum amount, allocation, of funds, etc.The Secretary may expend not less than 75 per centum of such funds as are authorized and appropriated pursuant to this section on those projects which meet the eligibility requirements under subsections (a) and (b) of section 644 11 See References in Text note below. of title 20. Such funds shall be allocated on the basis of existing funding priorities, if any, established by the Secretary of Education under subsections (a) and (b) of section 644 1 of title 20. The Secretary of Education is directed to submit to the Secretary, at the beginning of each fiscal year, commencing with the first full fiscal year after January 4, 1975, a list of those projects eligible for funding under subsections (a) and (b) of section 644 1 of title 20.


(c) Eligibility of private schools to receive funds; maximum amountThe Secretary may expend not more than 25 per centum of such funds as may be authorized and appropriated pursuant to this section on any school eligible to receive funds under section 5355 of this title.


(d) Duties of State education agencies pursuant to contractsAny contract entered into by the Secretary pursuant to this section shall contain provisions requiring the relev</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5351_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization; prerequisites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization; prerequisites The Secretary is authorized to enter into a contract or contracts with any State education agency or school district for the purpose of assisting such agency or district in the acquisition of sites for, or the construction, acquisition, or renovation of facilities (including all necessary equipment) in school districts on or adjacent to or in close proximity to any Indian reservation or other lands held in trust by the United States for Indians, if such facilities are necessary for the education of Indians residing on any such reservation or lands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5351_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility requirements for assistance in federally-affected areas; applicability to projects in determining maximum amount, allocation, of funds, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility requirements for assistance in federally-affected areas; applicability to projects in determining maximum amount, allocation, of funds, etc. The Secretary may expend not less than 75 per centum of such funds as are authorized and appropriated pursuant to this section on those projects which meet the eligibility requirements under subsections (a) and (b) of section 644 11 See References in Text note below. of title 20. Such funds shall be allocated on the basis of existing funding priorities, if any, established by the Secretary of Education under subsections (a) and (b) of section 644 1 of title 20. The Secretary of Education is directed to submit to the Secretary, at the beginning of each fiscal year, commencing with the first full fiscal year after January 4, 1975, a list of those projects eligible for funding under subsections (a) and (b) of section 644 1 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5351_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of private schools to receive funds; maximum amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility of private schools to receive funds; maximum amount The Secretary may expend not more than 25 per centum of such funds as may be authorized and appropriated pursuant to this section on any school eligible to receive funds under section 5355 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5351_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of State education agencies pursuant to contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties of State education agencies pursuant to contracts Any contract entered into by the Secretary pursuant to this section shall contain provisions requiring the relevant State educational agency to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5351_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory consultations by Secretary with affected entities and governing bodies prior to contracts; applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Advisory consultations by Secretary with affected entities and governing bodies prior to contracts; applicability The Secretary shall consult with the entity designated pursuant to section 5346 of this title, and with the governing body of any Indian tribe or tribes the educational opportunity for the members of which will be significantly affected by any contract entered into pursuant to this section. Such consultation shall be advisory only, but shall occur prior to the entering into of any such contract. The foregoing provisions of this subsection shall not be applicable where the application for a contract pursuant to this section is submitted by an elected school board of which a majority of its members are Indians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5351_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and report to Congress of effectiveness of construction, etc., programs; scope and content of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Evaluation and report to Congress of effectiveness of construction, etc., programs; scope and content of report Within ninety days following the expiration of the three year period following January 4, 1975, the Secretary shall evaluate the effectiveness of the program pursuant to this section and transmit a report of such evaluation to the Congress. Such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5351_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this section, there is authorized to be appropriated the sum of $35,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1974; $35,000,000 for each of the four succeeding fiscal years; and thereafter, such sums as may be necessary, all of such sums to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>