<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5354" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5354/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5354/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5354"><akn:num>5354</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5354. Rules and regulations(a) Prerequisites for promulgation(1) Within six months from January 4, 1975, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, consult with national and regional Indian organizations with experiences in Indian education to consider and formulate appropriate rules and regulations to implement the provisions of this subchapter.

(2) Within seven months from January 4, 1975, the Secretary shall present the proposed rules and regulations to the Committees on Interior and Insular Affairs of the United States Senate and House of Representatives.

(3) Within eight months from January 4, 1975, the Secretary shall publish proposed rules and regulations in the Federal Register for the purpose of receiving comments from interested parties.

(4) Within ten months from January 4, 1975, the Secretary shall promulgate rules and regulations to implement the provisions of this subchapter.


(b) Revision and amendmentThe Secretary is authorized to revise and amend any rules or regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (a) of this section: Provided, That prior to any revision or amendment to such rules or regulations the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, consult with appropriate national and regional Indian organizations, and shall publish any proposed revisions in the Federal Register not less than sixty days prior to the effective date of such rules and regulations in order to provide adequate notice to, and receive comments from, other interested parties.


(Pub. L. 93–638, title II, § 207, Jan. 4, 1975, 88 Stat. 2216.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 458c of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs of the Senate abolished and replaced by Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, effective Feb. 11, 1977. See Rule XXV of Standing Rules of the Senate</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5354_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisites for promulgation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prerequisites for promulgation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5354_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision and amendment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Revision and amendment The Secretary is authorized to revise and amend any rules or regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (a) of this section: Provided, That prior to any revision or amendment to such rules or regulations the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, consult with appropriate national and regional Indian organizations, and shall publish any proposed revisions in the Federal Register not less than sixty days prior to the effective date of such rules and regulations in order to provide adequate notice to, and receive comments from, other interested parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>