<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5368" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5368/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5368/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5368"><akn:num>5368</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5368. Payment(a) In generalAt the request of the governing body of an Indian Tribe and under the terms of an applicable funding agreement, the Secretary shall provide funding to the Indian Tribe to carry out the funding agreement.


(b) Advance annual paymentAt the option of the Indian Tribe, a funding agreement shall provide for an advance annual payment to an Indian Tribe.


(c) Amount(1) In generalSubject to subsection (e) and sections 5363 and 5365 of this title, the Secretary shall provide funds to the Indian Tribe under a funding agreement for programs in an amount that is equal to the amount that the Indian Tribe would have been entitled to receive under contracts and grants under this chapter (including amounts for direct program and contract support costs and, in addition, any funds that are specifically or functionally related to the provision by the Secretary of services and benefits to the Indian Tribe or its members) without regard to the organization level within the Department at which the programs are carried out.


(2) Savings clauseNothing in this section reduces programs, services, or funds of, or provided to, another Indian Tribe.



(d) Timing(1) In generalPursuant to the terms of any compact or funding agreement entered into under this subchapter, the Secretary shall transfer to the Indian Tribe all funds provided for in the funding agreement, pursuant to subsection (c), and provide funding for periods covered by joint resolution adopted by Congress making continuing appropriations, to the extent permitted by such resolution.


(2) TransfersNot later than 1 year after October 21, 2020, in any instance in which a funding agreement requires an annual transfer of funding to be made at the beginning of a fiscal year or requires semiannual or other periodic transfers of funding to be made commencing at the beginning of a fiscal year, the first such transfer shall be made not later than 10 days after the apportionment of such funds by the Office of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general At the request of the governing body of an Indian Tribe and under the terms of an applicable funding agreement, the Secretary shall provide funding to the Indian Tribe to carry out the funding agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance annual payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advance annual payment At the option of the Indian Tribe, a funding agreement shall provide for an advance annual payment to an Indian Tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Timing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability Funds for trust services to individual Indians shall be available under a funding agreement only to the extent that the same services that would have been provided by the Secretary are provided to individual Indians by the Indian Tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiyear funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Multiyear funding A funding agreement may provide for multiyear funding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on authority of the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitations on authority of the Secretary The Secretary shall not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Federal resources If an Indian Tribe elects to carry out a compact or funding agreement with the use of Federal personnel, Federal supplies (including supplies available from Federal warehouse facilities), Federal supply sources (including lodging, airline transportation, and other means of transportation, including the use of interagency motor pool vehicles), or other Federal resources (including supplies, services, and resources available to the Secretary under any procurement contracts in which the Department is eligible to participate), the Secretary shall, as soon as practicable, acquire and transfer such personnel, supplies, or resources to the Indian Tribe under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt Payment Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Prompt Payment Act Chapter 39 of title 31 shall apply to the transfer of funds due under a compact or funding agreement authorized under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest or other income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Interest or other income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>