<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5372" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5372/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5372/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5372"><akn:num>5372</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5372. Reports(a) In general(1) RequirementOn January 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report regarding the administration of this subchapter.


(2) AnalysisAny Indian Tribe may submit to the Office of Self-Governance and to the appropriate committees of Congress a detailed annual analysis of unmet Tribal needs for funding agreements under this subchapter.



(b) ContentsThe report under subsection (a)(1) shall—(1) be compiled from information contained in funding agreements, annual audit reports, and data of the Secretary regarding the disposition of Federal funds;

(2) identify—(A) the relative costs and benefits of self-governance;

(B) with particularity, all funds that are specifically or functionally related to the provision by the Secretary of services and benefits to self-governance Indian Tribes and members of Indian Tribes;

(C) the funds transferred to each Indian Tribe and the corresponding reduction in the Federal employees and workload; and

(D) the funding formula for individual Tribal shares of all Central Office funds, together with the comments of affected Indian Tribes, developed under subsection (d);


(3) before being submitted to Congress, be distributed to the Indian Tribes for comment (with a comment period of not less than 30 days);

(4) include the separate views and comments of each Indian Tribe or Tribal organization; and

(5) include a list of—(A) all such programs that the Secretary determines, in consultation with Indian Tribes participating in self-governance, are eligible for negotiation to be included in a funding agreement at the request of a participating Indian Tribe; and

(B) all such programs which Indian Tribes have formally requested to include in a funding agreement under section 5363(c) of this title due to the special geographic, historical, or cultural significance of the program to the Indian Tribe, indicating whether each request was granted or denied, and stating the grounds for any denial.



</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5372_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5372_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents The report under subsection (a)(1) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5372_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on non-BIA programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report on non-BIA programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5372_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on Central Office funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report on Central Office funds Not later than January 1, 2020, the Secretary shall, in consultation with Indian Tribes, develop a funding formula to determine the individual Tribal share of funds controlled by the Central Office of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Office of the Special Trustee for inclusion in the compacts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>