<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5373" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5373/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5373/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5373"><akn:num>5373</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5373. Regulations(a) In general(1) PromulgationNot later than 90 days after October 21, 2020, the Secretary shall initiate procedures under subchapter III of chapter 5 of title 5 to negotiate and promulgate such regulations as are necessary to carry out this subchapter.


(2) Publication of proposed regulationsProposed regulations to implement this subchapter shall be published in the Federal Register not later than 38 months after October 21, 2020.


(3) Expiration of authorityThe authority to promulgate regulations under paragraph (1) shall expire on the date that is 50 months after October 21, 2020.



(b) Committee(1) MembershipA negotiated rulemaking committee established pursuant to section 565 of title 5 to carry out this section shall have as its members only representatives of the Federal Government and Tribal government.


(2) Lead agencyAmong the Federal representatives described in paragraph (1), the Office of Self-Governance shall be the lead agency for the Department.



(c) Adaptation of proceduresThe Secretary shall adapt the negotiated rulemaking procedures to the unique context of self-governance and the government-to-government relationship between the United States and Indian Tribes.


(d) Effect(1) RepealThe Secretary may repeal any regulation that is inconsistent with this chapter.


(2) Conflicting provisionsSubject to section 101(a) of the PROGRESS for Indian Tribes Act and except with respect to programs described under section 5363(c) of this title, this subchapter shall supersede any conflicting provision of law (including any conflicting regulations).


(3) Effectiveness without regard to regulationsThe lack of promulgated regulations on an issue shall not limit the effect or implementation of this subchapter.



(Pub. L. 93–638, title IV, § 413, as added Pub. L. 116–180, title I, § 101(e), Oct. 21, 2020, 134 Stat. 877; amended Pub. L. 118–15, div. B, title I, § 2102, Sept. 30, 2023, 137 Stat. 82.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextTh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5373_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5373_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5373_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adaptation of procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adaptation of procedures The Secretary shall adapt the negotiated rulemaking procedures to the unique context of self-governance and the government-to-government relationship between the United States and Indian Tribes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5373_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>