<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5381" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5381/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5381/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5381"><akn:num>5381</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5381. Definitions(a) In generalIn this subchapter:(1) Construction projectThe term “construction project”—(A) means an organized noncontinuous undertaking to complete a specific set of predetermined objectives for the planning, environmental determination, design, construction, repair, improvement, or expansion of buildings or facilities, as described in a construction project agreement; and

(B) does not include construction program administration and activities described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of section 5304(m) of this title, that may otherwise be included in a funding agreement under this subchapter.


(2) Construction project agreementThe term “construction project agreement” means a negotiated agreement between the Secretary and an Indian tribe, that at a minimum—(A) establishes project phase start and completion dates;

(B) defines a specific scope of work and standards by which it will be accomplished;

(C) identifies the responsibilities of the Indian tribe and the Secretary;

(D) addresses environmental considerations;

(E) identifies the owner and operations and maintenance entity of the proposed work;

(F) provides a budget;

(G) provides a payment process; and

(H) establishes the duration of the agreement based on the time necessary to complete the specified scope of work, which may be 1 or more years.


(3) Gross mismanagementThe term “gross mismanagement” means a significant, clear, and convincing violation of a compact, funding agreement, or regulatory, or statutory requirements applicable to Federal funds transferred to an Indian tribe by a compact or funding agreement that results in a significant reduction of funds available for the programs, services, functions, or activities (or portions thereof) assumed by an Indian tribe.


(4) Inherent Federal functionsThe term “inherent Federal functions” means those Federal functions which cannot legally be delegated to Indian tribes.


(5) Inter-tribal consortiumThe term “inter-tribal consortium”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5381_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In this subchapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5381_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Indian tribe In any case in which an Indian tribe has authorized another Indian tribe, an inter-tribal consortium, or a tribal organization to plan for or carry out programs, services, functions, or activities (or portions thereof) on its behalf under this subchapter, the authorized Indian tribe, inter-tribal consortium, or tribal organization shall have the rights and responsibilities of the authorizing Indian tribe (except as otherwise provided in the authorizing resolution or in this subchapter). In such event, the term “Indian tribe” as used in this subchapter shall include such other authorized Indian tribe, inter-tribal consortium, or tribal organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>