<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5387" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5387/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5387/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5387"><akn:num>5387</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5387. Provisions relating to the Secretary(a) Mandatory provisions(1) Health status reportsCompacts or funding agreements negotiated between the Secretary and an Indian tribe shall include a provision that requires the Indian tribe to report on health status and service delivery—(A) to the extent such data is not otherwise available to the Secretary and specific funds for this purpose are provided by the Secretary under the funding agreement; and

(B) if such reporting shall impose minimal burdens on the participating Indian tribe and such requirements are promulgated under section 5397 of this title.


(2) Reassumption(A) In generalCompacts or funding agreements negotiated between the Secretary and an Indian tribe shall include a provision authorizing the Secretary to reassume operation of a program, service, function, or activity (or portions thereof) and associated funding if there is a specific finding relative to that program, service, function, or activity (or portion thereof) of—(i) imminent endangerment of the public health caused by an act or omission of the Indian tribe, and the imminent endangerment arises out of a failure to carry out the compact or funding agreement; or

(ii) gross mismanagement with respect to funds transferred to a tribe by a compact or funding agreement, as determined by the Secretary in consultation with the Inspector General, as appropriate.


(B) ProhibitionThe Secretary shall not reassume operation of a program, service, function, or activity (or portions thereof) unless—(i) the Secretary has first provided written notice and a hearing on the record to the Indian tribe; and

(ii) the Indian tribe has not taken corrective action to remedy the imminent endangerment to public health or gross mismanagement.


(C) Exception(i) In generalNotwithstanding subparagraph (B), the Secretary may, upon written notification to the Indian tribe, immediately reassume operation of a program, service, function, or activity (or portion thereof) if</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Mandatory provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final offer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Final offer In the event the Secretary and a participating Indian tribe are unable to agree, in whole or in part, on the terms of a compact or funding agreement (including funding levels), the Indian tribe may submit a final offer to the Secretary. Not more than 45 days after such submission, or within a longer time agreed upon by the Indian tribe, the Secretary shall review and make a determination with respect to such offer. In the absence of a timely rejection of the offer, in whole or in part, made in compliance with subsection (c) of this section, the offer shall be deemed agreed to by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rejection of final offers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rejection of final offers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Burden of proof</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Burden of proof With respect to any hearing or appeal or civil action conducted pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall have the burden of demonstrating by clear and convincing evidence the validity of the grounds for rejecting the offer (or a provision thereof) made under subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Good faith</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Good faith In the negotiation of compacts and funding agreements the Secretary shall at all times negotiate in good faith to maximize implementation of the self-governance policy. The Secretary shall carry out this subchapter in a manner that maximizes the policy of tribal self-governance, in a manner consistent with the purposes specified in section 3 of the Tribal Self-Governance Amendments of 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Savings To the extent that programs, functions, services, or activities (or portions thereof) carried out by Indian tribes under this subchapter reduce the administrative or other responsibilities of the Secretary with respect to the operation of Indian programs and result in savings that have not otherwise been included in the amount of tribal shares and other funds determined under section 5388(c) of this title, the Secretary shall make such savings available to the Indian tribes, inter-tribal consortia, or tribal organizations for the provision of additional services to program beneficiaries in a manner equitable to directly served, contracted, and compacted programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trust responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Trust responsibility The Secretary is prohibited from waiving, modifying, or diminishing in any way the trust responsibility of the United States with respect to Indian tribes and individual Indians that exists under treaties, Executive orders, other laws, or court decisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisionmaker</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Decisionmaker A decision that constitutes final agency action and relates to an appeal within the Department of Health and Human Services conducted under subsection (c) of this section shall be made either—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>