<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5612" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5612/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5612/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5612"><akn:num>5612</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of demonstration project; selection of participating Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5612. Establishment of demonstration project; selection of participating Indian tribes(a) In generalThe Secretary shall establish and carry out an Indian trust asset management demonstration project, in accordance with this subchapter.


(b) Selection of participating Indian tribes(1) In generalAn Indian tribe shall be eligible to participate in the project if—(A) the Indian tribe submits to the Secretary an application under subsection (c); and

(B) the Secretary approves the application of the Indian tribe.


(2) Notice(A) In generalThe Secretary shall provide a written notice to each Indian tribe approved to participate in the project.


(B) ContentsA notice under subparagraph (A) shall include—(i) a statement that the application of the Indian tribe has been approved by the Secretary; and

(ii) a requirement that the Indian tribe shall submit to the Secretary a proposed Indian trust asset management plan in accordance with section 5613 of this title.




(c) Application(1) In generalTo be eligible to participate in the project, an Indian tribe shall submit to the Secretary a written application in accordance with paragraph (2).


(2) RequirementsThe Secretary shall consider an application under this subsection only if the application—(A) includes a copy of a resolution or other appropriate action by the governing body of the Indian tribe, as determined by the Secretary, in support of or authorizing the application;

(B) is received by the Secretary after June 22, 2016; and

(C) states that the Indian tribe is requesting to participate in the project.



(d) DurationThe project—(1) shall remain in effect for a period of 10 years after June 22, 2016; but

(2) may be extended at the discretion of the Secretary.


(Pub. L. 114–178, title II, § 203, June 22, 2016, 130 Stat. 433.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5612_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall establish and carry out an Indian trust asset management demonstration project, in accordance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5612_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of participating Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection of participating Indian tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5612_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5612_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duration The project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>