<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5613" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5613/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5613/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5613"><akn:num>5613</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian trust asset management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5613. Indian trust asset management plan(a) Proposed plan(1) SubmissionAfter the date on which an Indian tribe receives a notice from the Secretary under section 5612(b)(2) of this title, the Indian tribe shall submit to the Secretary a proposed Indian trust asset management plan in accordance with paragraph (2).


(2) ContentsA proposed Indian trust asset management plan shall include provisions that—(A) identify the trust assets that will be subject to the plan;

(B) establish trust asset management objectives and priorities for Indian trust assets that are located within the reservation, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction, of the Indian tribe;

(C) allocate trust asset management funding that is available for the Indian trust assets subject to the plan in order to meet the trust asset management objectives and priorities;

(D) if the Indian tribe has contracted or compacted functions or activities under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450 et seq.) 11 See References in Text note below. relating to the management of trust assets—(i) identify the functions or activities that are being or will be performed by the Indian tribe under the contracts, compacts, or other agreements under that Act, which may include any of the surface leasing or forest land management activities authorized by the proposed plan pursuant to section 5614(b) of this title; and

(ii) describe the practices and procedures that the Indian tribe will follow;


(E) establish procedures for nonbinding mediation or resolution of any dispute between the Indian tribe and the United States relating to the trust asset management plan;

(F) include a process for the Indian tribe and the Federal agencies affected by the trust asset management plan to conduct evaluations to ensure that trust assets are being managed in accordance with the plan; and

(G) identify any Federal regulations that will be superseded by the plan.


(3) Technical assistance and informatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5613_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposed plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proposed plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5613_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval and disapproval of proposed plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Approval and disapproval of proposed plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5613_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicable laws Subject to section 5614 of this title, an Indian trust asset management plan, and any activity carried out under the plan, shall not be approved unless the proposed plan is consistent with any treaties, statutes, and Executive orders that are applicable to the trust assets, or the management of the trust assets, identified in the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5613_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination of plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>