<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5636" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5636/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5636/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5636"><akn:num>5636</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5636. Cost savings(a) In generalFor any program, function, service, or activity (or any portion of a program, function, service, or activity) of the Office of the Special Trustee that will not be operated or carried out as a result of a transfer of functions and personnel following enactment of this chapter, the Secretary shall—(1) identify the amounts that the Secretary would otherwise have expended to operate or carry out each program, function, service, and activity (or portion of a program, function, service, or activity); and

(2) provide to the tribal representatives of the Tribal-Interior Budget Council or the representative of any other appropriate entity that advises the Secretary on Indian program budget or funding issues a list that describes—(A) the programs, functions, services, and activities (or any portion of a program, function, service, or activity) identified under paragraph (1); and

(B) the amounts associated with each program, function, service, and activity (or portion of a program, function, service, or activity).



(b) Tribal recommendationsNot later than 90 days after the date of receipt of a list under subsection (a)(2), the tribal representatives of the Tribal-Interior Budget Council and the representatives of any other appropriate entities that advise the Secretary on Indian program budget or funding issues may provide recommendations regarding how any amounts or cost savings should be reallocated, incorporated into future budget requests, or appropriated to—(1) the Secretary;

(2) the Office of Management and Budget;

(3) the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;

(4) the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives;

(5) the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and

(6) the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate.


(Pub. L. 114–178, title III, § 306, June 22, 2016, 130 Stat. 442.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5636_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For any program, function, service, or activity (or any portion of a program, function, service, or activity) of the Office of the Special Trustee that will not be operated or carried out as a result of a transfer of functions and personnel following enactment of this chapter, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5636_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tribal recommendations Not later than 90 days after the date of receipt of a list under subsection (a)(2), the tribal representatives of the Tribal-Interior Budget Council and the representatives of any other appropriate entities that advise the Secretary on Indian program budget or funding issues may provide recommendations regarding how any amounts or cost savings should be reallocated, incorporated into future budget requests, or appropriated to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>