<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/5802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5802"><akn:num>5802</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5802. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Business incubatorThe term “business incubator” means an organization that—(A) provides physical workspace and facilities resources to startups and established businesses; and

(B) is designed to accelerate the growth and success of businesses through a variety of business support resources and services, including—(i) access to capital, business education, and counseling;

(ii) networking opportunities;

(iii) mentorship opportunities; and

(iv) other services intended to aid in developing a business.



(2) Eligible applicantThe term “eligible applicant” means an applicant eligible to apply for a grant under section 5803(b) of this title.


(3) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of this title.


(4) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 1001 of title 20.


(5) Native American; NativeThe terms “Native American” and “Native” have the meaning given the term “Indian” in section 5304 of this title.


(6) Native businessThe term “Native business” means a business concern that is at least 51-percent owned and controlled by 1 or more Native Americans.


(7) Native entrepreneurThe term “Native entrepreneur” means an entrepreneur who is a Native American.


(8) ProgramThe term “program” means the program established under section 5803(a) of this title.


(9) ReservationThe term “reservation” has the meaning given the term in section 1452 of this title.


(10) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.


(11) Tribal college or universityThe term “tribal college or university” has the meaning given the term “Tribal College or University” in section 1059c(b) of title 20.


(Pub. L. 116–174, § 3, Oct. 20, 2020, 134 Stat. 839.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Business incubator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Business incubator The term “business incubator” means an organization that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible applicant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Eligible applicant The term “eligible applicant” means an applicant eligible to apply for a grant under section 5803(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Institution of higher education The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 1001 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native American; Native</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Native American; Native The terms “Native American” and “Native” have the meaning given the term “Indian” in section 5304 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Native business The term “Native business” means a business concern that is at least 51-percent owned and controlled by 1 or more Native Americans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native entrepreneur</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Native entrepreneur The term “Native entrepreneur” means an entrepreneur who is a Native American.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Program The term “program” means the program established under section 5803(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Reservation The term “reservation” has the meaning given the term in section 1452 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>