<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/71" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/71/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/25/71/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_71"><akn:num>71</akn:num><akn:heading>Future treaties with Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 71. Future treaties with Indian tribes
No Indian nation or tribe within the territory of the United States shall be acknowledged or recognized as an independent nation, tribe, or power with whom the United States may contract by treaty; but no obligation of any treaty lawfully made and ratified with any such Indian nation or tribe prior to March 3, 1871, shall be hereby invalidated or impaired. Such treaties, and any Executive orders and Acts of Congress under which the rights of any Indian tribe to fish are secured, shall be construed to prohibit (in addition to any other prohibition) the imposition under any law of a State or political subdivision thereof of any tax on any income derived from the exercise of rights to fish secured by such treaty, Executive order, or Act of Congress if section 7873 of title 26 does not permit a like Federal tax to be imposed on such income.
(R.S. § 2079; Pub. L. 100–647, title III, § 3042, Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3641.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
R.S. § 2079 derived from act Mar. 3, 1871, ch. 120, § 1, 16 Stat. 566.

Amendments1988—Pub. L. 100–647 inserted sentence at end relating to State tax treatment of income derived by Indians from exercise of fishing rights secured by treaties, Executive orders, or Acts of Congress.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1988 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 100–647 applicable to all periods beginning before, on, or after Nov. 10, 1988, with no inference created as to existence or nonexistence or scope of any income tax exemption derived from fishing rights secured as of Mar. 17, 1988, by any treaty, law, or Executive order, see section 3044 of Pub. L. 100–647, set out as an Effective Date note under section 7873 of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code.

Short Title of 2022 AmendmentPub. L. 117–317, § 1, Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4419, provided that: “This Act [repealing sections 72, 127 to 130, 137, 138, 273, 283, 285, and 302 of this title] may be cited as the ‘Repealing E</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>