<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/27/101...108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/27/101...108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/27/101...108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_101___108"><akn:num>101...108</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 740, title I, § 1, 49 Stat. 872</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 101 to 108. Repealed. Aug. 27, 1935, ch. 740, title I, § 1, 49 Stat. 872

Section 101, act May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 1, 46 Stat. 427, provided that this chapter may be cited as the “Prohibition Reorganization Act of 1930”.


Section 102, act May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 2, 46 Stat. 427, established a Bureau of Prohibition in Department of Justice and authorized appointment of a Director and Assistant Director of Prohibition and designation of officers and employees.


Section 103, act May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 3, 46 Stat. 428, related to creation of an enforcement division in Bureau of Prohibition in Treasury Department.


Section 104, act May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 4, 46 Stat. 428, related to imposition of duties on Attorney General with respect to enforcement of prohibition laws.


Section 105, acts May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 5, 46 Stat. 429; Mar. 31, 1933, ch. 18, § 4, 48 Stat. 24, authorized Attorney General and Secretary of the Treasury to jointly prescribe regulations relating to permits and prescriptions for liquor for medicinal purposes.


Section 106, act May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 6, 46 Stat. 429, related to filing of reports by Attorney General with Secretary of the Treasury with respect to civil liabilities for taxes and penalties and filing of reports by Secretary of the Treasury with Attorney General with respect to revocation of permits.


Section 107, act May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 7, 46 Stat. 429, related to grant, renewal, and amendment of permits.


Section 108, act May 27, 1930, ch. 342, § 8, 46 Stat. 430, provided that Bureau of Prohibition shall hereafter be known as Bureau of Industrial Alcohol, and Commissioner of Prohibition shall hereafter have title of Commissioner of Industrial Alcohol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>