<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/27/122a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/27/122a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/27/122a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_122a"><akn:num>122a</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctive relief in Federal district court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 122a. Injunctive relief in Federal district court(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “attorney general” means the attorney general or other chief law enforcement officer of a State or the designee thereof;

(2) the term “intoxicating liquor” means any spirituous, vinous, malted, fermented, or other intoxicating liquor of any kind;

(3) the term “person” means any individual and any partnership, corporation, company, firm, society, association, joint stock company, trust, or other entity capable of holding a legal or beneficial interest in property, but does not include a State or agency thereof; and

(4) the term “State” means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States.


(b) Action by State attorney generalIf the attorney general has reasonable cause to believe that a person is engaged in, or has engaged in, any act that would constitute a violation of a State law regulating the importation or transportation of any intoxicating liquor, the attorney general may bring a civil action in accordance with this section for injunctive relief (including a preliminary or permanent injunction) against the person, as the attorney general determines to be necessary to—(1) restrain the person from engaging, or continuing to engage, in the violation; and

(2) enforce compliance with the State law.


(c) Federal jurisdiction(1) In generalThe district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction over any action brought under this section by an attorney general against any person, except one licensed or otherwise authorized to produce, sell, or store intoxicating liquor in such State.


(2) VenueAn action under this section may be brought only in accordance with section 1391 of title 28 or in the district in which the recipient of the intoxicating liquor resides or is found.


(3) Form of reliefAn action under this section is limited to actions seeking injunctive reli</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action by State attorney general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Action by State attorney general If the attorney general has reasonable cause to believe that a person is engaged in, or has engaged in, any act that would constitute a violation of a State law regulating the importation or transportation of any intoxicating liquor, the attorney general may bring a civil action in accordance with this section for injunctive relief (including a preliminary or permanent injunction) against the person, as the attorney general determines to be necessary to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for injunctions and orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirements for injunctions and orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rules of construction This section shall be construed only to extend the jurisdiction of Federal courts in connection with State law that is a valid exercise of power vested in the States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional remedies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>