<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_102"><akn:num>102</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of the President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 102. Compensation of the President
The President shall receive in full for his services during the term for which he shall have been elected compensation in the aggregate amount of $400,000 a year, to be paid monthly, and in addition an expense allowance of $50,000 to assist in defraying expenses relating to or resulting from the discharge of his official duties. Any unused amount of such expense allowance shall revert to the Treasury pursuant to section 1552 of title 31, United States Code. No amount of such expense allowance shall be included in the gross income of the President. He shall be entitled also to the use of the furniture and other effects belonging to the United States and kept in the Executive Residence at the White House.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 644, 62 Stat. 678; Jan. 19, 1949, ch. 2, § 1(a), 63 Stat. 4; Oct. 20, 1951, ch. 521, title VI, § 619(a), 65 Stat. 569; Pub. L. 91–1, § 1, Jan. 17, 1969, 83 Stat. 3; Pub. L. 95–570, § 5(a), Nov. 2, 1978, 92 Stat. 2450; Pub. L. 106–58, title VI, § 644(a), Sept. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 478; Pub. L. 108–199, div. F, title III, § 301, Jan. 23, 2004, 118 Stat. 326.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2004—Pub. L. 108–199 substituted “. Any unused amount of such expense allowance shall revert to the Treasury pursuant to section 1552 of title 31, United States Code. No amount of such expense allowance shall be included in the gross income of the President.” for “, for which expense allowance no accounting, other than for income tax purposes, shall be made by him.”
1999—Pub. L. 106–58 substituted “$400,000” for “$200,000”.
1978—Pub. L. 95–570 substituted “Executive Residence at the White House” for “Executive Mansion”.
1969—Pub. L. 91–1 substituted “$200,000” for “$100,000”.
1951—Act Oct. 20, 1951, made President’s expense allowance taxable.
1949—Act Jan. 19, 1949, increased salary from $75,000 to $100,000 per year, and gave President a yearly expense account of $50,000 for which he was to make no accounting and which was tax free.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>