<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_112"><akn:num>112</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail of employees of executive departments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 112. Detail of employees of executive departments
The head of any department, agency, or independent establishment of the executive branch of the Government may detail, from time to time, employees of such department, agency, or establishment to the White House Office, the Executive Residence at the White House, the Office of the Vice President, the Domestic Policy Staff, and the Office of Administration. Any such office to which an employee has been detailed for service to such office shall reimburse the detailing department, agency, or establishment for the pay of each employee thereof—(1) who is so detailed, and

(2) who is performing services which have been or would otherwise be performed by an employee of such office,


for any period occurring during any fiscal year after 180 calendar days after the employee is detailed in such year.
(Added Pub. L. 95–570, § 3(a), Nov. 2, 1978, 92 Stat. 2449.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable to any fiscal year beginning on or after Oct. 1, 1978, see section 6(a) of Pub. L. 95–570, set out as an Effective Date of 1978 Amendment note under section 102 of this title.

Authority With Respect to Detailed EmployeesPub. L. 107–67, title VI, § 637, Nov. 12, 2001, 115 Stat. 553, provided that: “During fiscal year 2002 and thereafter, the head of an entity named in 3 U.S.C. 112 may, with respect to civilian personnel of any branch of the Federal Government performing duties in such entity, exercise authority comparable to the authority that may by law (including chapter 57 and sections 8344 and 8468 of title 5, United States Code) be exercised with respect to the employees of an Executive agency (as defined in 5 U.S.C. 105) by the head of such Executive agency, and the authority granted by this section shall be in addition to any other authority available in law.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_112_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) who is so detailed, and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_112_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) who is performing services which have been or would otherwise be performed by an employee of such office,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>