<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/412" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/412/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/412/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_412"><akn:num>412</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights and protections under the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 412. Rights and protections under the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993(a) Family and Medical Leave Rights and Protections Provided.—(1) In general.—The rights and protections established by sections 101 through 105 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 shall apply to covered employees.

(2) Definitions.—For purposes of the application described in paragraph (1)—(A) the term “employer” as used in the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 means any employing office; and

(B) the term “eligible employee” as used in the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 means a covered employee who has been employed in any employing office for 12 months and for at least 1,250 hours of employment during the previous 12 months.


(3) Exception.—Notwithstanding section 401(b)(2), the requirements of paragraph (2)(B) shall not apply with respect to leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)).


(b) Remedy.—The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy, including liquidated damages, as would be appropriate if awarded under paragraph (1) of section 107(a) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993.

(c) Special Rules for Substitution of Paid Leave.—(1) Substitution of paid leave.—A covered employee may elect to substitute for any leave without pay under subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)) any paid leave which is available to such employee for that purpose.

(2) Available leave.—The paid leave that is available to a covered employee for purposes of paragraph (1) is leave of the type and in the amount available to an employee under section 6382(d)(2)(B) of title 5, United States Code, for substitution for leave without pay under subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 6382(a)(1) of such title.

(3) Consistency with title 5.—Paid leave shall be substituted under this subsection in a manner that is consistent with</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family and Medical Leave Rights and Protections Provided.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy, including liquidated damages, as would be appropriate if awarded under paragraph (1) of section 107(a) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Rules for Substitution of Paid Leave.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations To Implement Section.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Date.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subsections (a) and (b) shall take effect on the earlier of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>