<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/452" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/452/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/3/452/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_452"><akn:num>452</akn:num><akn:heading>Counseling and mediation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 452. Counseling and mediation(a) In General.—The President, or the designee of the President, shall by regulation establish procedures substantially similar to those under sections 402 and 403 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 for the counseling and mediation of alleged violations of a law made applicable under part A of subchapter II.

(b) Exhaustion Requirement.—A covered employee who has not exhausted counseling and mediation under subsection (a) shall be ineligible to make any election under section 453 or otherwise pursue any further form of relief under this subchapter.

(Added Pub. L. 104–331, § 2(a), Oct. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 4067.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSections 402 and 403 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995, referred to in subsec. (a), are classified to sections 1402 and 1403, respectively, of Title 2, The Congress.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1997, except that subsec. (a) of this section effective Oct. 26, 1996, see section 471 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_452_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The President, or the designee of the President, shall by regulation establish procedures substantially similar to those under sections 402 and 403 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 for the counseling and mediation of alleged violations of a law made applicable under part A of subchapter II.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_452_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exhaustion Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A covered employee who has not exhausted counseling and mediation under subsection (a) shall be ineligible to make any election under section 453 or otherwise pursue any further form of relief under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>