<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_101"><akn:num>101</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain death benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 101. Certain death benefits(a) Proceeds of life insurance contracts payable by reason of death(1) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), subsection (d), subsection (f), and subsection (j), gross income does not include amounts received (whether in a single sum or otherwise) under a life insurance contract, if such amounts are paid by reason of the death of the insured.


(2) Transfer for valuable considerationIn the case of a transfer for a valuable consideration, by assignment or otherwise, of a life insurance contract or any interest therein, the amount excluded from gross income by paragraph (1) shall not exceed an amount equal to the sum of the actual value of such consideration and the premiums and other amounts subsequently paid by the transferee. The preceding sentence shall not apply in the case of such a transfer—(A) if such contract or interest therein has a basis for determining gain or loss in the hands of a transferee determined in whole or in part by reference to such basis of such contract or interest therein in the hands of the transferor, or

(B) if such transfer is to the insured, to a partner of the insured, to a partnership in which the insured is a partner, or to a corporation in which the insured is a shareholder or officer.


The term “other amounts” in the first sentence of this paragraph includes interest paid or accrued by the transferee on indebtedness with respect to such contract or any interest therein if such interest paid or accrued is not allowable as a deduction by reason of section 264(a)(4).

(3) Exception to valuable consideration rules for commercial transfers(A) In generalThe second sentence of paragraph (2) shall not apply in the case of a transfer of a life insurance contract, or any interest therein, which is a reportable policy sale.


(B) Reportable policy saleFor purposes of this paragraph, the term “reportable policy sale” means the acquisition of an interest in a life insurance contract, d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeds of life insurance contracts payable by reason of death</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proceeds of life insurance contracts payable by reason of death</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1402(a), Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1789]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interest If any amount excluded from gross income by subsection (a) is held under an agreement to pay interest thereon, the interest payments shall be included in gross income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of life insurance proceeds at a date later than death</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment of life insurance proceeds at a date later than death</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 421(b)(2), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 794]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeds of flexible premium contracts issued before January 1, 1985 payable by reason of death</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Proceeds of flexible premium contracts issued before</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain accelerated death benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Treatment of certain accelerated death benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Survivor benefits attributable to service by a public safety officer who is killed in the line of duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Survivor benefits attributable to service by a public safety officer who is killed in the line of duty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain employee death benefits payable by reason of death of certain terrorist victims or astronauts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Certain employee death benefits payable by reason of death of certain terrorist victims or astronauts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain employer-owned life insurance contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Treatment of certain employer-owned life insurance contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>