<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1031" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1031/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1031/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1031"><akn:num>1031</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange of real property held for productive use or investment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1031. Exchange of real property held for productive use or investment(a) Nonrecognition of gain or loss from exchanges solely in kind(1) In generalNo gain or loss shall be recognized on the exchange of real property held for productive use in a trade or business or for investment if such real property is exchanged solely for real property of like kind which is to be held either for productive use in a trade or business or for investment.


(2) Exception for real property held for saleThis subsection shall not apply to any exchange of real property held primarily for sale.


(3) Requirement that property be identified and that exchange be completed not more than 180 days after transfer of exchanged propertyFor purposes of this subsection, any property received by the taxpayer shall be treated as property which is not like-kind property if—(A) such property is not identified as property to be received in the exchange on or before the day which is 45 days after the date on which the taxpayer transfers the property relinquished in the exchange, or

(B) such property is received after the earlier of—(i) the day which is 180 days after the date on which the taxpayer transfers the property relinquished in the exchange, or

(ii) the due date (determined with regard to extension) for the transferor’s return of the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year in which the transfer of the relinquished property occurs.




(b) Gain from exchanges not solely in kindIf an exchange would be within the provisions of subsection (a), of section 1035(a), of section 1036(a), or of section 1037(a), if it were not for the fact that the property received in exchange consists not only of property permitted by such provisions to be received without the recognition of gain, but also of other property or money, then the gain, if any, to the recipient shall be recognized, but in an amount not in excess of the sum of such money and the fair market value of such other property.


(c) Loss </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1031_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonrecognition of gain or loss from exchanges solely in kind</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nonrecognition of gain or loss from exchanges solely in kind</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1031_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gain from exchanges not solely in kind</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Gain from exchanges not solely in kind If an exchange would be within the provisions of subsection (a), of section 1035(a), of section 1036(a), or of section 1037(a), if it were not for the fact that the property received in exchange consists not only of property permitted by such provisions to be received without the recognition of gain, but also of other property or money, then the gain, if any, to the recipient shall be recognized, but in an amount not in excess of the sum of such money and the fair market value of such other property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1031_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loss from exchanges not solely in kind</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Loss from exchanges not solely in kind If an exchange would be within the provisions of subsection (a), of section 1035(a), of section 1036(a), or of section 1037(a), if it were not for the fact that the property received in exchange consists not only of property permitted by such provisions to be received without the recognition of gain or loss, but also of other property or money, then no loss from the exchange shall be recognized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1031_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Basis If property was acquired on an exchange described in this section, section 1035(a), section 1036(a), or section 1037(a), then the basis shall be the same as that of the property exchanged, decreased in the amount of any money received by the taxpayer and increased in the amount of gain or decreased in the amount of loss to the taxpayer that was recognized on such exchange. If the property so acquired consisted in part of the type of property permitted by this section, section 1035(a), section 1036(a), or section 1037(a), to be received without the recognition of gain or loss, and in part of other property, the basis provided in this subsection shall be allocated between the properties (other than money) received, and for the purpose of the allocation there shall be assigned to such other property an amount equivalent to its fair market value at the date of the exchange. For purposes of this section, section 1035(a), and section 1036(a), where as part of the consideration to t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1031_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to certain partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application to certain partnerships For purposes of this section, an interest in a partnership which has in effect a valid election under section 761(a) to be excluded from the application of all of subchapter K shall be treated as an interest in each of the assets of such partnership and not as an interest in a partnership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1031_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for exchanges between related persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rules for exchanges between related persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1031_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule where substantial diminution of risk</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rule where substantial diminution of risk</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1031_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for foreign real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rules for foreign real property Real property located in the United States and real property located outside the United States are not property of a like kind.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>