<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1032" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1032/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1032/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1032"><akn:num>1032</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange of stock for property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1032. Exchange of stock for property(a) Nonrecognition of gain or lossNo gain or loss shall be recognized to a corporation on the receipt of money or other property in exchange for stock (including treasury stock) of such corporation. No gain or loss shall be recognized by a corporation with respect to any lapse or acquisition of an option, or with respect to a securities futures contract (as defined in section 1234B), to buy or sell its stock (including treasury stock).


(b) BasisFor basis of property acquired by a corporation in certain exchanges for its stock, see section 362.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 303; Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 57(a), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 574; Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title IV, § 401(c)], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, 2763A–649.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2000—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 106–554 inserted “, or with respect to a securities futures contract (as defined in section 1234B),” after “an option” in second sentence.
1984—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 98–369 inserted provision that no gain or loss shall be recognized by a corporation with respect to any lapse or acquisition of an option to buy or sell its stock (including treasury stock).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2000 AmendmentPub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(7) [title IV, § 401(j)], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, 2763A–651, provided that: “The amendments made by this section [enacting section 1234B of this title and amending this section and sections 1091, 1092, 1223, 1233, 1234A, 1256 and 7701 of this title] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [Dec. 21, 2000].”


Effective Date of 1984 AmendmentPub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 57(b), July 18, 1984, 1984, 98 Stat. 574, provided that: “The amendment made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall apply to options acquired or lapsed after the date of the enactment of this Act [July 18, 1984] in taxable years ending after such date.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1032_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonrecognition of gain or loss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nonrecognition of gain or loss No gain or loss shall be recognized to a corporation on the receipt of money or other property in exchange for stock (including treasury stock) of such corporation. No gain or loss shall be recognized by a corporation with respect to any lapse or acquisition of an option, or with respect to a securities futures contract (as defined in section 1234B), to buy or sell its stock (including treasury stock).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1032_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Basis For basis of property acquired by a corporation in certain exchanges for its stock, see section 362.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>