<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1037" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1037/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1037/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1037"><akn:num>1037</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain exchanges of United States obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1037. Certain exchanges of United States obligations(a) General ruleWhen so provided by regulations promulgated by the Secretary in connection with the issue of obligations of the United States, no gain or loss shall be recognized on the surrender to the United States of obligations of the United States issued under chapter 31 of title 31 in exchange solely for other obligations issued under such chapter.


(b) Application of original issue discount rules(1) Exchanges involving obligations issued at a discountIn any case in which gain has been realized but not recognized because of the provisions of subsection (a) (or so much of section 1031(b) as relates to subsection (a) of this section), to the extent such gain is later recognized by reason of a disposition or redemption of an obligation received in an exchange subject to such provisions, the first sentence of section 1271(c)(2) 11 See References in Text note below. shall apply to such gain as though the obligation disposed of or redeemed were the obligation surrendered to the Government in the exchange rather than the obligation actually disposed of or redeemed. For purposes of this paragraph and subpart A of part V of subchapter P, if the obligation surrendered in the exchange is a nontransferable obligation described in subsection (a) or (c) of section 454—(A) the aggregate amount considered, with respect to the obligation surrendered, as ordinary income shall not exceed the difference between the issue price and the stated redemption price which applies at the time of the exchange, and

(B) the issue price of the obligation received in the exchange shall be considered to be the stated redemption price of the obligation surrendered in the exchange, increased by the amount of other consideration (if any) paid to the United States as a part of the exchange.


(2) Exchanges of transferable obligations issued at not less than parIn any case in which subsection (a) (or so much of section 1031(b) or (c) as relates</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1037_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule When so provided by regulations promulgated by the Secretary in connection with the issue of obligations of the United States, no gain or loss shall be recognized on the surrender to the United States of obligations of the United States issued under chapter 31 of title 31 in exchange solely for other obligations issued under such chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1037_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of original issue discount rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of original issue discount rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1037_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>