<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_105"><akn:num>105</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts received under accident and health plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 105. Amounts received under accident and health plans(a) Amounts attributable to employer contributionsExcept as otherwise provided in this section, amounts received by an employee through accident or health insurance for personal injuries or sickness shall be included in gross income to the extent such amounts (1) are attributable to contributions by the employer which were not includible in the gross income of the employee, or (2) are paid by the employer.


(b) Amounts expended for medical careExcept in the case of amounts attributable to (and not in excess of) deductions allowed under section 213 (relating to medical, etc., expenses) for any prior taxable year, gross income does not include amounts referred to in subsection (a) if such amounts are paid, directly or indirectly, to the taxpayer to reimburse the taxpayer for expenses incurred by him for the medical care (as defined in section 213(d)) of the taxpayer, his spouse, his dependents (as defined in section 152, determined without regard to subsections (b)(1), (b)(2), and (d)(1)(B) thereof), and any child (as defined in section 152(f)(1)) of the taxpayer who as of the end of the taxable year has not attained age 27. Any child to whom section 152(e) applies shall be treated as a dependent of both parents for purposes of this subsection.


(c) Payments unrelated to absence from workGross income does not include amounts referred to in subsection (a) to the extent such amounts—(1) constitute payment for the permanent loss or loss of use of a member or function of the body, or the permanent disfigurement, of the taxpayer, his spouse, or a dependent (as defined in section 152, determined without regard to subsections (b)(1), (b)(2), and (d)(1)(B) thereof), and

(2) are computed with reference to the nature of the injury without regard to the period the employee is absent from work.


[(d) Repealed. Pub. L. 98–21, title I, § 122(b), Apr. 20, 1983, 97 Stat. 87]

(e) Accident and health plansFor purposes of this </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts attributable to employer contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amounts attributable to employer contributions Except as otherwise provided in this section, amounts received by an employee through accident or health insurance for personal injuries or sickness shall be included in gross income to the extent such amounts (1) are attributable to contributions by the employer which were not includible in the gross income of the employee, or (2) are paid by the employer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts expended for medical care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amounts expended for medical care Except in the case of amounts attributable to (and not in excess of) deductions allowed under section 213 (relating to medical, etc., expenses) for any prior taxable year, gross income does not include amounts referred to in subsection (a) if such amounts are paid, directly or indirectly, to the taxpayer to reimburse the taxpayer for expenses incurred by him for the medical care (as defined in section 213(d)) of the taxpayer, his spouse, his dependents (as defined in section 152, determined without regard to subsections (b)(1), (b)(2), and (d)(1)(B) thereof), and any child (as defined in section 152(f)(1)) of the taxpayer who as of the end of the taxable year has not attained age 27. Any child to whom section 152(e) applies shall be treated as a dependent of both parents for purposes of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments unrelated to absence from work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments unrelated to absence from work Gross income does not include amounts referred to in subsection (a) to the extent such amounts—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 98–21, title I, § 122(b), Apr. 20, 1983, 97 Stat. 87]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accident and health plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Accident and health plans For purposes of this section and section 104— shall be treated as amounts received through accident or health insurance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules for application of section 213</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rules for application of section 213 For purposes of section 213(a) (relating to medical, dental, etc., expenses) amounts excluded from gross income under subsection (c) shall not be considered as compensation (by insurance or otherwise) for expenses paid for medical care.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-employed individual not considered an employee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Self-employed individual not considered an employee For purposes of this section, the term “employee” does not include an individual who is an employee within the meaning of section 401(c)(1) (relating to self-employed individuals).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount paid to highly compensated individuals under a discriminatory self-insured medical expense reimbursement plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Amount paid to highly compensated individuals under a discriminatory self-insured medical expense reimbursement plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sick pay under Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Sick pay under Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act Notwithstanding any other provision of law, gross income includes benefits paid under section 2(a) of the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act for days of sickness; except to the extent such sickness (as determined in accordance with standards prescribed by the Railroad Retirement Board) is the result of on-the-job injury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_105_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for certain governmental plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Special rule for certain governmental plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>