<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1060" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1060/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1060/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1060"><akn:num>1060</akn:num><akn:heading>Special allocation rules for certain asset acquisitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1060. Special allocation rules for certain asset acquisitions(a) General ruleIn the case of any applicable asset acquisition, for purposes of determining both—(1) the transferee’s basis in such assets, and

(2) the gain or loss of the transferor with respect to such acquisition,


the consideration received for such assets shall be allocated among such assets acquired in such acquisition in the same manner as amounts are allocated to assets under section 338(b)(5). If in connection with an applicable asset acquisition, the transferee and transferor agree in writing as to the allocation of any consideration, or as to the fair market value of any of the assets, such agreement shall be binding on both the transferee and transferor unless the Secretary determines that such allocation (or fair market value) is not appropriate.

(b) Information required to be furnished to SecretaryUnder regulations, the transferor and transferee in an applicable asset acquisition shall, at such times and in such manner as may be provided in such regulations, furnish to the Secretary the following information:(1) The amount of the consideration received for the assets which is allocated to section 197 intangibles.

(2) Any modification of the amount described in paragraph (1).

(3) Any other information with respect to other assets transferred in such acquisition as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.


(c) Applicable asset acquisitionFor purposes of this section, the term “applicable asset acquisition” means any transfer (whether directly or indirectly)—(1) of assets which constitute a trade or business, and

(2) with respect to which the transferee’s basis in such assets is determined wholly by reference to the consideration paid for such assets.


A transfer shall not be treated as failing to be an applicable asset acquisition merely because section 1031 applies to a portion of the assets transferred.

(d) Treatment of certain partnership transac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of any applicable asset acquisition, for purposes of determining both— the consideration received for such assets shall be allocated among such assets acquired in such acquisition in the same manner as amounts are allocated to assets under section 338(b)(5). If in connection with an applicable asset acquisition, the transferee and transferor agree in writing as to the allocation of any consideration, or as to the fair market value of any of the assets, such agreement shall be binding on both the transferee and transferor unless the Secretary determines that such allocation (or fair market value) is not appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required to be furnished to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information required to be furnished to Secretary Under regulations, the transferor and transferee in an applicable asset acquisition shall, at such times and in such manner as may be provided in such regulations, furnish to the Secretary the following information:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable asset acquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicable asset acquisition For purposes of this section, the term “applicable asset acquisition” means any transfer (whether directly or indirectly)— A transfer shall not be treated as failing to be an applicable asset acquisition merely because section 1031 applies to a portion of the assets transferred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain partnership transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of certain partnership transactions In the case of a distribution of partnership property or a transfer of an interest in a partnership—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required in case of certain transfers of interests in entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Information required in case of certain transfers of interests in entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cross reference For provisions relating to penalties for failure to file a return required by this section, see section 6721.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>