<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1062" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1062/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1062/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1062"><akn:num>1062</akn:num><akn:heading>Gain from the sale or exchange of qualified farmland property to qualified farmers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1062. Gain from the sale or exchange of qualified farmland property to qualified farmers(a) Election to pay tax in installmentsIn the case of gain from the sale or exchange of qualified farmland property to a qualified farmer, at the election of the taxpayer, the portion of the net income tax of such taxpayer for the taxable year of the sale or exchange which is equal to the applicable net tax liability shall be paid in 4 equal installments.


(b) Rules relating to installment payments(1) Date for payment of installmentsIf an election is made under subsection (a), the first installment shall be paid on the due date (determined without regard to any extension of time for filing the return) for the return of tax for the taxable year in which the sale or exchange occurs and each succeeding installment shall be paid on the due date (as so determined) for the return of tax for the taxable year following the taxable year with respect to which the preceding installment was made.


(2) Acceleration of payment(A) In generalIf there is an addition to tax for failure to timely pay any installment required under this section, then the unpaid portion of all remaining installments shall be due on the date of such failure.


(B) IndividualsIn the case of an individual, if the individual dies, then the unpaid portion of all remaining installment shall be paid on the due date for the return of tax for the taxable year in which the taxpayer dies.


(C) C corporationsIn the case of a taxpayer which is a C corporation, trust, or estate, if there is a liquidation or sale of substantially all the assets of the taxpayer (including in a title 11 or similar case), a cessation of business by the taxpayer (in the case of a C corporation), or any similar circumstance, then the unpaid portion of all remaining installments shall be due on the date of such event (or in the case of a title 11 or similar case, the day before the petition is filed). The preceding sentence shall not apply to the sa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1062_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to pay tax in installments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Election to pay tax in installments In the case of gain from the sale or exchange of qualified farmland property to a qualified farmer, at the election of the taxpayer, the portion of the net income tax of such taxpayer for the taxable year of the sale or exchange which is equal to the applicable net tax liability shall be paid in 4 equal installments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1062_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules relating to installment payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rules relating to installment payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1062_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Election</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1062_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1062_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Return requirement A taxpayer making an election under subsection (a) shall include with the return for the taxable year of the sale or exchange described in subsection (a) a copy of the covenant or other legally enforceable restriction described in subsection (d)(2)(A)(ii).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>