<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_112"><akn:num>112</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain combat zone compensation of members of the Armed Forces</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 112. Certain combat zone compensation of members of the Armed Forces(a) Enlisted personnelGross income does not include compensation received for active service as a member below the grade of commissioned officer in the Armed Forces of the United States for any month during any part of which such member—(1) served in a combat zone, or

(2) was hospitalized as a result of wounds, disease, or injury incurred while serving in a combat zone; but this paragraph shall not apply for any month beginning more than 2 years after the date of the termination of combatant activities in such zone.


With respect to service in the combat zone designated for purposes of the Vietnam conflict, paragraph (2) shall not apply to any month after January 1978.

(b) Commissioned officersGross income does not include so much of the compensation as does not exceed the maximum enlisted amount received for active service as a commissioned officer in the Armed Forces of the United States for any month during any part of which such officer—(1) served in a combat zone, or

(2) was hospitalized as a result of wounds, disease, or injury incurred while serving in a combat zone; but this paragraph shall not apply for any month beginning more than 2 years after the date of the termination of combatant activities in such zone.


With respect to service in the combat zone designated for purposes of the Vietnam conflict, paragraph (2) shall not apply to any month after January 1978.

(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) The term “commissioned officer” does not include a commissioned warrant officer.

(2) The term “combat zone” means any area which the President of the United States by Executive Order designates, for purposes of this section or corresponding provisions of prior income tax laws, as an area in which Armed Forces of the United States are or have engaged in combat.

(3) Service is performed in a combat zone only if performed on or after the date designated by the President by Exe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enlisted personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enlisted personnel Gross income does not include compensation received for active service as a member below the grade of commissioned officer in the Armed Forces of the United States for any month during any part of which such member— With respect to service in the combat zone designated for purposes of the Vietnam conflict, paragraph (2) shall not apply to any month after January 1978.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commissioned officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commissioned officers Gross income does not include so much of the compensation as does not exceed the maximum enlisted amount received for active service as a commissioned officer in the Armed Forces of the United States for any month during any part of which such officer— With respect to service in the combat zone designated for purposes of the Vietnam conflict, paragraph (2) shall not apply to any month after January 1978.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_112_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prisoners of war, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prisoners of war, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>