<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/115" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/115/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/115/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_115"><akn:num>115</akn:num><akn:heading>Income of States, municipalities, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 115. Income of States, municipalities, etc.
Gross income does not include—(1) income derived from any public utility or the exercise of any essential governmental function and accruing to a State or any political subdivision thereof, or the District of Columbia; or

(2) income accruing to the government of any possession of the United States, or any political subdivision thereof.

(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 35; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1901(a)(19), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1766.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–455 struck out “(a) General rule” before “Gross income does not include”, struck out subsecs. (b) and (c) which related to contracts concerning public utilities made before Sept. 8, 1916, and contracts concerning bridge acquisition made before May 29, 1928, respectively, and in par. (1) of former subsec. (a), struck out “or territory” after “accruing to a State”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1976 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 94–455 applicable with respect to taxable years beginning after Dec. 31, 1976, see section 1901(d) of Pub. L. 94–455, set out as a note under section 2 of this title.

Tax Treatment of State Ownership of Railroad Real Estate Investment TrustPub. L. 109–59, title XI, § 11146, Aug. 10, 2005, 119 Stat. 1966, provided that:
“(a) In General.—If a State owns all of the outstanding stock of a corporation—“(1) which is a real estate investment trust on the date of the enactment of this Act [Aug. 10, 2005],

“(2) which is a non-operating class III railroad, and

“(3) substantially all of the activities of which consist of the ownership, leasing, and operation by such corporation of facilities, equipment, and other property used by the corporation or other persons for railroad transportation and for economic development purposes for the benefit of the State and its citizens, then, to the extent such activities are of a type which are an essential governmental function within the meaning of sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) income derived from any public utility or the exercise of any essential governmental function and accruing to a State or any political subdivision thereof, or the District of Columbia; or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) income accruing to the government of any possession of the United States, or any political subdivision thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>