<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1212"><akn:num>1212</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital loss carrybacks and carryovers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1212. Capital loss carrybacks and carryovers(a) Corporations(1) In generalIf a corporation has a net capital loss for any taxable year (hereinafter in this paragraph referred to as the “loss year”), the amount thereof shall be—(A) a capital loss carryback to each of the 3 taxable years preceding the loss year, but only to the extent—(i) such loss is not attributable to a foreign expropriation capital loss, and

(ii) the carryback of such loss does not increase or produce a net operating loss (as defined in section 172(c)) for the taxable year to which it is being carried back;


(B) except as provided in subparagraph (C), a capital loss carryover to each of the 5 taxable years succeeding the loss year; and

(C) a capital loss carryover to each of the 10 taxable years succeeding the loss year, but only to the extent such loss is attributable to a foreign expropriation loss,


and shall be treated as a short-term capital loss in each such taxable year. The entire amount of the net capital loss for any taxable year shall be carried to the earliest of the taxable years to which such loss may be carried, and the portion of such loss which shall be carried to each of the other taxable years to which such loss may be carried shall be the excess, if any, of such loss over the total of the capital gain net income for each of the prior taxable years to which such loss may be carried. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the capital gain net income for any such prior taxable year shall be computed without regard to the net capital loss for the loss year or for any taxable year thereafter. In the case of any net capital loss which cannot be carried back in full to a preceding taxable year by reason of clause (ii) of subparagraph (A), the capital gain net income for such prior taxable year shall in no case be treated as greater than the amount of such loss which can be carried back to such preceding taxable year upon the application of such clause (ii).

(2) Definitions and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Corporations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other taxpayers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other taxpayers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1212_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryback of losses from section 1256 contracts to offset prior gains from such contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Carryback of losses from section 1256 contracts to offset prior gains from such contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>