<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1223" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1223/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1223/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1223"><akn:num>1223</akn:num><akn:heading>Holding period of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1223. Holding period of property
For purposes of this subtitle—(1) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held property received in an exchange, there shall be included the period for which he held the property exchanged if, under this chapter, the property has, for the purpose of determining gain or loss from a sale or exchange, the same basis in whole or in part in his hands as the property exchanged, and, in the case of such exchanges the property exchanged at the time of such exchange was a capital asset as defined in section 1221 or property described in section 1231. For purposes of this paragraph—(A) an involuntary conversion described in section 1033 shall be considered an exchange of the property converted for the property acquired, and

(B) a distribution to which section 355 (or so much of section 356 as relates to section 355) applies shall be treated as an exchange.


(2) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held property however acquired there shall be included the period for which such property was held by any other person, if under this chapter such property has, for the purpose of determining gain or loss from a sale or exchange, the same basis in whole or in part in his hands as it would have in the hands of such other person.

(3) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held stock or securities the acquisition of which (or the contract or option to acquire which) resulted in the nondeductibility (under section 1091 relating to wash sales) of the loss from the sale or other disposition of substantially identical stock or securities, there shall be included the period for which he held the stock or securities the loss from the sale or other disposition of which was not deductible.

(4) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held stock or rights to acquire stock received on a distribution, if the basis of such stock or rights is determined under section 307, there shall (under regulations pre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held property received in an exchange, there shall be included the period for which he held the property exchanged if, under this chapter, the property has, for the purpose of determining gain or loss from a sale or exchange, the same basis in whole or in part in his hands as the property exchanged, and, in the case of such exchanges the property exchanged at the time of such exchange was a capital asset as defined in section 1221 or property described in section 1231. For purposes of this paragraph—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held property however acquired there shall be included the period for which such property was held by any other person, if under this chapter such property has, for the purpose of determining gain or loss from a sale or exchange, the same basis in whole or in part in his hands as it would have in the hands of such other person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held stock or securities the acquisition of which (or the contract or option to acquire which) resulted in the nondeductibility (under section 1091 relating to wash sales) of the loss from the sale or other disposition of substantially identical stock or securities, there shall be included the period for which he held the stock or securities the loss from the sale or other disposition of which was not deductible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held stock or rights to acquire stock received on a distribution, if the basis of such stock or rights is determined under section 307, there shall (under regulations prescribed by the Secretary) be included the period for which he held the stock in the distributing corporation before the receipt of such stock or rights upon such distribution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held stock or securities acquired from a corporation by the exercise of rights to acquire such stock or securities, there shall be included only the period beginning with the date on which the right to acquire was exercised.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(6) Repealed. Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(80)(C), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 4049.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) In determining the period for which the taxpayer has held a commodity acquired in satisfaction of a commodity futures contract (other than a commodity futures contract to which section 1256 applies) there shall be included the period for which he held the commodity futures contract if such commodity futures contract was a capital asset in his hands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(8) Repealed. Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(80)(C), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 4049.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) In the case of a person acquiring property from a decedent or to whom property passed from a decedent (within the meaning of section 1014(b)), if— then such person shall be considered to have held such property for more than 1 year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1223_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) If— then the person making such sale or other disposition shall be considered to have held such property for more than 1 year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>