<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1253" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1253/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1253/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1253"><akn:num>1253</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers of franchises, trademarks, and trade names</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1253. Transfers of franchises, trademarks, and trade names(a) General ruleA transfer of a franchise, trademark, or trade name shall not be treated as a sale or exchange of a capital asset if the transferor retains any significant power, right, or continuing interest with respect to the subject matter of the franchise, trademark, or trade name.


(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) FranchiseThe term “franchise” includes an agreement which gives one of the parties to the agreement the right to distribute, sell, or provide goods, services, or facilities, within a specified area.


(2) Significant power, right, or continuing interestThe term “significant power, right, or continuing interest” includes, but is not limited to, the following rights with respect to the interest transferred:(A) A right to disapprove any assignment of such interest, or any part thereof.

(B) A right to terminate at will.

(C) A right to prescribe the standards of quality of products used or sold, or of services furnished, and of the equipment and facilities used to promote such products or services.

(D) A right to require that the transferee sell or advertise only products or services of the transferor.

(E) A right to require that the transferee purchase substantially all of his supplies and equipment from the transferor.

(F) A right to payments contingent on the productivity, use, or disposition of the subject matter of the interest transferred, if such payments constitute a substantial element under the transfer agreement.


(3) TransferThe term “transfer” includes the renewal of a franchise, trademark, or trade name.



(c) Treatment of contingent payments by transferorAmounts received or accrued on account of a transfer, sale, or other disposition of a franchise, trademark, or trade name which are contingent on the productivity, use, or disposition of the franchise, trademark, or trade name transferred shall be treated as amounts received or accrued from the sale or other </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1253_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule A transfer of a franchise, trademark, or trade name shall not be treated as a sale or exchange of a capital asset if the transferor retains any significant power, right, or continuing interest with respect to the subject matter of the franchise, trademark, or trade name.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1253_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1253_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of contingent payments by transferor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of contingent payments by transferor Amounts received or accrued on account of a transfer, sale, or other disposition of a franchise, trademark, or trade name which are contingent on the productivity, use, or disposition of the franchise, trademark, or trade name transferred shall be treated as amounts received or accrued from the sale or other disposition of property which is not a capital asset.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1253_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of payments by transferee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of payments by transferee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>