<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1274A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1274A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1274A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1274A"><akn:num>1274A</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for certain transactions where stated principal amount does not exceed $2,800,000</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1274A. Special rules for certain transactions where stated principal amount does not exceed $2,800,000(a) Lower discount rateIn the case of any qualified debt instrument, the discount rate used for purposes of sections 483 and 1274 shall not exceed 9 percent, compounded semiannually.


(b) Qualified debt instrument definedFor purposes of this section, the term “qualified debt instrument” means any debt instrument given in consideration for the sale or exchange of property (other than new section 38 property within the meaning of section 48(b), as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) if the stated principal amount of such instrument does not exceed $2,800,000.


(c) Election to use cash method where stated principal amount does not exceed $2,000,000(1) In generalIn the case of any cash method debt instrument—(A) section 1274 shall not apply, and

(B) interest on such debt instrument shall be taken into account by both the borrower and the lender under the cash receipts and disbursements method of accounting.


(2) Cash method debt instrumentFor purposes of paragraph (1), the term “cash method debt instrument” means any qualified debt instrument if—(A) the stated principal amount does not exceed $2,000,000,

(B) the lender does not use an accrual method of accounting and is not a dealer with respect to the property sold or exchanged,

(C) section 1274 would have applied to such instrument but for an election under this subsection, and

(D) an election under this subsection is jointly made with respect to such debt instrument by the borrower and lender.


(3) Successors bound by election(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), paragraph (1) shall apply to any successor to the borrower or lender with respect to a cash method debt instrument.


(B) Exception where lender transfers debt instrument to accrual method taxpayerIf the lender (or any successor) transfers any cash method debt instrument t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lower discount rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Lower discount rate In the case of any qualified debt instrument, the discount rate used for purposes of sections 483 and 1274 shall not exceed 9 percent, compounded semiannually.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified debt instrument defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified debt instrument defined For purposes of this section, the term “qualified debt instrument” means any debt instrument given in consideration for the sale or exchange of property (other than new section 38 property within the meaning of section 48(b), as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) if the stated principal amount of such instrument does not exceed $2,800,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to use cash method where stated principal amount does not exceed $2,000,000</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Election to use cash method where stated principal amount does not exceed $2,000,000</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1274A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>