<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1286" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1286/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1286/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1286"><akn:num>1286</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of stripped bonds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1286. Tax treatment of stripped bonds(a) Inclusion in income as if bond and coupons were original issue discount bondsIf any person purchases a stripped bond or a stripped coupon, then such bond or coupon while held by such purchaser (or by any other person whose basis is determined by reference to the basis in the hands of such purchaser) shall be treated for purposes of this part as a bond originally issued on the purchase date and having an original issue discount equal to the excess (if any) of—(1) the stated redemption price at maturity (or, in the case of coupon, the amount payable on the due date of such coupon), over

(2) such bond’s or coupon’s ratable share of the purchase price.


For purposes of paragraph (2), ratable shares shall be determined on the basis of their respective fair market values on the date of purchase.

(b) Tax treatment of person stripping bondFor purposes of this subtitle, if any person strips 1 or more coupons from a bond and disposes of the bond or such coupon—(1) such person shall include in gross income an amount equal to the sum of—(A) the interest accrued on such bond while held by such person and before the time such coupon or bond was disposed of (to the extent such interest has not theretofore been included in such person’s gross income), and

(B) the accrued market discount on such bond determined as of the time such coupon or bond was disposed of (to the extent such discount has not theretofore been included in such person’s gross income),


(2) the basis of the bond and coupons shall be increased by the amount included in gross income under paragraph (1),

(3) the basis of the bond and coupons immediately before the disposition (as adjusted pursuant to paragraph (2)) shall be allocated among the items retained by such person and the items disposed of by such person on the basis of their respective fair market values, and

(4) for purposes of subsection (a), such person shall be treated as having purchased on the date of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1286_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion in income as if bond and coupons were original issue discount bonds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Inclusion in income as if bond and coupons were original issue discount bonds If any person purchases a stripped bond or a stripped coupon, then such bond or coupon while held by such purchaser (or by any other person whose basis is determined by reference to the basis in the hands of such purchaser) shall be treated for purposes of this part as a bond originally issued on the purchase date and having an original issue discount equal to the excess (if any) of— For purposes of paragraph (2), ratable shares shall be determined on the basis of their respective fair market values on the date of purchase.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1286_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of person stripping bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tax treatment of person stripping bond For purposes of this subtitle, if any person strips 1 or more coupons from a bond and disposes of the bond or such coupon— A rule similar to the rule of paragraph (4) shall apply in the case of any person whose basis in any bond or coupon is determined by reference to the basis of the person described in the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1286_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for tax-exempt obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules for tax-exempt obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1286_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1286_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of stripped interests in bond and preferred stock funds, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of stripped interests in bond and preferred stock funds, etc. In the case of an account or entity substantially all of the assets of which consist of bonds, preferred stock, or a combination thereof, the Secretary may by regulations provide that rules similar to the rules of this section and section 305(e), as appropriate, shall apply to interests in such account or entity to which (but for this subsection) this section or section 305(e), as the case may be, would not apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1286_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulation authority The Secretary may prescribe regulations providing that where, by reason of varying rates of interest, put or call options, or other circumstances, the tax treatment under this section does not accurately reflect the income of the holder of a stripped coupon or stripped bond, or of the person disposing of such bond or coupon, as the case may be, for any period, such treatment shall be modified to require that the proper amount of income be included for such period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>