<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1296" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1296/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1296/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1296"><akn:num>1296</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of mark to market for marketable stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1296. Election of mark to market for marketable stock(a) General ruleIn the case of marketable stock in a passive foreign investment company which is owned (or treated under subsection (g) as owned) by a United States person at the close of any taxable year of such person, at the election of such person—(1) If the fair market value of such stock as of the close of such taxable year exceeds its adjusted basis, such United States person shall include in gross income for such taxable year an amount equal to the amount of such excess.

(2) If the adjusted basis of such stock exceeds the fair market value of such stock as of the close of such taxable year, such United States person shall be allowed a deduction for such taxable year equal to the lesser of—(A) the amount of such excess, or

(B) the unreversed inclusions with respect to such stock.



(b) Basis adjustments(1) In generalThe adjusted basis of stock in a passive foreign investment company—(A) shall be increased by the amount included in the gross income of the United States person under subsection (a)(1) with respect to such stock, and

(B) shall be decreased by the amount allowed as a deduction to the United States person under subsection (a)(2) with respect to such stock.


(2) Special rule for stock constructively ownedIn the case of stock in a passive foreign investment company which the United States person is treated as owning under subsection (g)—(A) the adjustments under paragraph (1) shall apply to such stock in the hands of the person actually holding such stock but only for purposes of determining the subsequent treatment under this chapter of the United States person with respect to such stock, and

(B) similar adjustments shall be made to the adjusted basis of the property by reason of which the United States person is treated as owning such stock.



(c) Character and source rules(1) Ordinary treatment(A) GainAny amount included in gross income under subsection (a)(1), and any gain on the sale </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of marketable stock in a passive foreign investment company which is owned (or treated under subsection (g) as owned) by a United States person at the close of any taxable year of such person, at the election of such person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Basis adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Character and source rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Character and source rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unreversed inclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Unreversed inclusions For purposes of this section, the term “unreversed inclusions” means, with respect to any stock in a passive foreign investment company, the excess (if any) of— The amount referred to in paragraph (1) shall include any amount which would have been included in gross income under subsection (a)(1) with respect to such stock for any prior taxable year but for section 1291. In the case of a regulated investment company which elected to mark to market the stock held by such company as of the last day of the taxable year preceding such company’s first taxable year for which such company elects the application of this section, the amount referred to in paragraph (1) shall include amounts included in gross income under such mark to market with respect to such stock for prior taxable years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marketable stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Marketable stock For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of controlled foreign corporations which are shareholders in passive foreign investment companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of controlled foreign corporations which are shareholders in passive foreign investment companies In the case of a foreign corporation which is a controlled foreign corporation and which owns (or is treated under subsection (g) as owning) stock in a passive foreign investment company—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stock owned through certain foreign entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Stock owned through certain foreign entities Except as provided in regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with section 851(b)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Coordination with section 851(b) For purposes of section 851(b)(2), any amount included in gross income under subsection (a) shall be treated as a dividend.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stock acquired from a decedent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Stock acquired from a decedent In the case of stock of a passive foreign investment company which is acquired by bequest, devise, or inheritance (or by the decedent’s estate) and with respect to which an election under this section was in effect as of the date of the decedent’s death, notwithstanding section 1014, the basis of such stock in the hands of the person so acquiring it shall be the adjusted basis of such stock in the hands of the decedent immediately before his death (or, if lesser, the basis which would have been determined under section 1014 without regard to this subsection).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1296_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with section 1291 for first year of election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Coordination with section 1291 for first year of election</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>