<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/133" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/133/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/133/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_133"><akn:num>133</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1602(a), Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1833]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[§ 133. Repealed. Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1602(a), Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1833]

Section, added Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title V, § 543(a), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 891; amended Pub. L. 99–514, title XI, § 1173(b)(1)(A), (2), title XVIII, § 1854(c)(2)(A), (C), (D), Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2515, 2879; Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1011B(h)(1), (2), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3490; Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7301(a)–(c), Dec. 19, 1989, 103 Stat. 2346, 2347, prior to repeal, read as follows:
§ 133. Interest on certain loans used to acquire employer securities


(a) In general


Gross income does not include 50 percent of the interest received by—


(1) a bank (within the meaning of section 581),


(2) an insurance company to which subchapter L applies,


(3) a corporation actively engaged in the business of lending money, or


(4) a regulated investment company (as defined in section 851),
with respect to a securities acquisition loan.


(b) Securities acquisition loan
(1) In general


For purposes of this section, the term “securities acquisition loan” means—


(A) any loan to a corporation or to an employee stock ownership plan to the extent that the proceeds are used to acquire employer securities for the plan, or


(B) any loan to a corporation to the extent that, within 30 days, employer securities are transferred to the plan in an amount equal to the proceeds of such loan and such securities are allocable to accounts of plan participants within 1 year of the date of such loan.
For purposes of this paragraph, the term “employer securities” has the meaning given such term by section 409(l). The term “securities acquisition loan” shall not include a loan with a term greater than 15 years.
(2) Loans between related persons


The term “securities acquisition loan” shall not include—


(A) any loan made between corporations which are members of the same controlled group of corporations, or


(B) any loan made between an employee stock ownership plan and any person </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>