<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1355" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1355/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1355/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1355"><akn:num>1355</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1355. Definitions and special rules(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this subchapter—(1) Electing corporationThe term “electing corporation” means any corporation for which an election is in effect under this subchapter.


(2) Electing group; controlled group(A) Electing groupThe term “electing group” means a controlled group of which one or more members is an electing corporation.


(B) Controlled groupThe term “controlled group” means any group which would be treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52 if paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 52(a) did not apply.



(3) Qualifying vessel operatorThe term “qualifying vessel operator” means any corporation—(A) who operates one or more qualifying vessels, and

(B) who meets the shipping activity requirement in subsection (c).


(4) Qualifying vesselThe term “qualifying vessel” means a self-propelled (or a combination self-propelled and non-self-propelled) United States flag vessel of not less than 6,000 deadweight tons used exclusively in the United States foreign trade during the period that the election under this subchapter is in effect.


(5) United States flag vesselThe term “United States flag vessel” means any vessel documented under the laws of the United States.


(6) United States domestic tradeThe term “United States domestic trade” means the transportation of goods or passengers between places in the United States.


(7) United States foreign tradeThe term “United States foreign trade” means the transportation of goods or passengers between a place in the United States and a foreign place or between foreign places.



(b) Operating a vesselFor purposes of this subchapter—(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), a person is treated as operating any vessel during any period if—(A)(i) such vessel is owned by, or chartered (including a time charter) to, the person, or

(ii) the person provides services for such vessel pursuant to an operating agreement, and


(B) such vessel is</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1355_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1355_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operating a vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Operating a vessel For purposes of this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1355_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shipping activity requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Shipping activity requirement For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1355_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities carried on partnerships, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities carried on partnerships, etc. In applying this subchapter to a partner in a partnership— A similar rule shall apply with respect to other pass-thru entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1355_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of temporarily ceasing to operate a qualifying vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect of temporarily ceasing to operate a qualifying vessel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1355_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of temporarily operating a qualifying vessel in the United States domestic trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect of temporarily operating a qualifying vessel in the United States domestic trade</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1355_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Great Lakes domestic shipping to not disqualify vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Great Lakes domestic shipping to not disqualify vessel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1355_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>