<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1368" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1368/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1368/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1368"><akn:num>1368</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1368. Distributions(a) General ruleA distribution of property made by an S corporation with respect to its stock to which (but for this subsection) section 301(c) would apply shall be treated in the manner provided in subsection (b) or (c), whichever applies.


(b) S corporation having no earnings and profitsIn the case of a distribution described in subsection (a) by an S corporation which has no accumulated earnings and profits—(1) Amount applied against basisThe distribution shall not be included in gross income to the extent that it does not exceed the adjusted basis of the stock.


(2) Amount in excess of basisIf the amount of the distribution exceeds the adjusted basis of the stock, such excess shall be treated as gain from the sale or exchange of property.



(c) S corporation having earnings and profitsIn the case of a distribution described in subsection (a) by an S corporation which has accumulated earnings and profits—(1) Accumulated adjustments accountThat portion of the distribution which does not exceed the accumulated adjustments account shall be treated in the manner provided by subsection (b).


(2) DividendThat portion of the distribution which remains after the application of paragraph (1) shall be treated as a dividend to the extent it does not exceed the accumulated earnings and profits of the S corporation.


(3) Treatment of remainderAny portion of the distribution remaining after the application of paragraph (2) of this subsection shall be treated in the manner provided by subsection (b).



Except to the extent provided in regulations, if the distributions during the taxable year exceed the amount in the accumulated adjustments account at the close of the taxable year, for purposes of this subsection, the balance of such account shall be allocated among such distributions in proportion to their respective sizes.

(d) Certain adjustments taken into accountSubsections (b) and (c) shall be applied by taking into account (to the extent proper)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule A distribution of property made by an S corporation with respect to its stock to which (but for this subsection) section 301(c) would apply shall be treated in the manner provided in subsection (b) or (c), whichever applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>S corporation having no earnings and profits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) S corporation having no earnings and profits In the case of a distribution described in subsection (a) by an S corporation which has no accumulated earnings and profits—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>S corporation having earnings and profits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) S corporation having earnings and profits In the case of a distribution described in subsection (a) by an S corporation which has accumulated earnings and profits— Except to the extent provided in regulations, if the distributions during the taxable year exceed the amount in the accumulated adjustments account at the close of the taxable year, for purposes of this subsection, the balance of such account shall be allocated among such distributions in proportion to their respective sizes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain adjustments taken into account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certain adjustments taken into account Subsections (b) and (c) shall be applied by taking into account (to the extent proper)— In the case of any distribution made during any taxable year, the adjusted basis of the stock shall be determined with regard to the adjustments provided in paragraph (1) of section 1367(a) for the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restricted bank director stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Restricted bank director stock If a director receives a distribution (not in part or full payment in exchange for stock) from an S corporation with respect to any restricted bank director stock (as defined in section 1361(f)), the amount of such distribution—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>