<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1379" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1379/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1379/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1379"><akn:num>1379</akn:num><akn:heading>Transitional rules on enactment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1379. Transitional rules on enactment(a) Old electionsAny election made under section 1372(a) (as in effect before the enactment of the Subchapter S Revision Act of 1982) shall be treated as an election made under section 1362.


(b) References to prior law includedAny references in this title to a provision of this subchapter shall, to the extent not inconsistent with the purposes of this subchapter, include a reference to the corresponding provision as in effect before the enactment of the Subchapter S Revision Act of 1982.


(c) Distributions of undistributed taxable incomeIf a corporation was an electing small business corporation for the last preenactment year, subsections (f) and (d) of section 1375 (as in effect before the enactment of the Subchapter S Revision Act of 1982) shall continue to apply with respect to distributions of undistributed taxable income for any taxable year beginning before January 1, 1983.


(d) CarryforwardsIf a corporation was an electing small business corporation for the last preenactment year and is an S corporation for the 1st postenactment year, any carryforward to the 1st post­enactment year which arose in a taxable year for which the corporation was an electing small business corporation shall be treated as arising in the 1st postenactment year.


(e) Preenactment and postenactment years definedFor purposes of this subsection—(1) Last preenactment yearThe term “last preenactment year” means the last taxable year of a corporation which begins before January 1, 1983.


(2) 1st postenactment yearThe term “1st postenactment year” means the 1st taxable year of a corporation which begins after December 31, 1982.



(Added Pub. L. 97–354, § 2, Oct. 19, 1982, 96 Stat. 1686; amended Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 721(n), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 969.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe enactment of the Subchapter S Revision Act of 1982, referred to in subsecs. (a) to (c), is the enactment of Pub. L. 97–354, which was approve</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1379_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Old elections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Old elections Any election made under section 1372(a) (as in effect before the enactment of the Subchapter S Revision Act of 1982) shall be treated as an election made under section 1362.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1379_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>References to prior law included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) References to prior law included Any references in this title to a provision of this subchapter shall, to the extent not inconsistent with the purposes of this subchapter, include a reference to the corresponding provision as in effect before the enactment of the Subchapter S Revision Act of 1982.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1379_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions of undistributed taxable income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distributions of undistributed taxable income If a corporation was an electing small business corporation for the last preenactment year, subsections (f) and (d) of section 1375 (as in effect before the enactment of the Subchapter S Revision Act of 1982) shall continue to apply with respect to distributions of undistributed taxable income for any taxable year beginning before January 1, 1983.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1379_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryforwards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Carryforwards If a corporation was an electing small business corporation for the last preenactment year and is an S corporation for the 1st postenactment year, any carryforward to the 1st post­enactment year which arose in a taxable year for which the corporation was an electing small business corporation shall be treated as arising in the 1st postenactment year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1379_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preenactment and postenactment years defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preenactment and postenactment years defined For purposes of this subsection—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>