<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1388" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1388/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1388/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1388"><akn:num>1388</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions; special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1388. Definitions; special rules(a) Patronage dividendFor purposes of this subchapter, the term “patronage dividend” means an amount paid to a patron by an organization to which part I of this subchapter applies—(1) on the basis of quantity or value of business done with or for such patron,

(2) under an obligation of such organization to pay such amount, which obligation existed before the organization received the amount so paid, and

(3) which is determined by reference to the net earnings of the organization from business done with or for its patrons.


Such term does not include any amount paid to a patron to the extent that (A) such amount is out of earnings other than from business done with or for patrons, or (B) such amount is out of earnings from business done with or for other patrons to whom no amounts are paid, or to whom smaller amounts are paid, with respect to substantially identical transactions. For purposes of paragraph (3), net earnings shall not be reduced by amounts paid during the year as dividends on capital stock or other proprietary capital interests of the organization to the extent that the articles of incorporation or bylaws of such organization or other contract with patrons provide that such dividends are in addition to amounts otherwise payable to patrons which are derived from business done with or for patrons during the taxable year.

(b) Written notice of allocationFor purposes of this subchapter, the term “written notice of allocation” means any capital stock, revolving fund certificate, retain certificate, certificate of indebtedness, letter of advice, or other written notice, which discloses to the recipient the stated dollar amount allocated to him by the organization and the portion thereof, if any, which constitutes a patronage dividend.


(c) Qualified written notice of allocation(1) DefinedFor purposes of this subchapter, the term “qualified written notice of allocation” means—(A) a written notice of allocation which may </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Patronage dividend</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Patronage dividend For purposes of this subchapter, the term “patronage dividend” means an amount paid to a patron by an organization to which part I of this subchapter applies— Such term does not include any amount paid to a patron to the extent that (A) such amount is out of earnings other than from business done with or for patrons, or (B) such amount is out of earnings from business done with or for other patrons to whom no amounts are paid, or to whom smaller amounts are paid, with respect to substantially identical transactions. For purposes of paragraph (3), net earnings shall not be reduced by amounts paid during the year as dividends on capital stock or other proprietary capital interests of the organization to the extent that the articles of incorporation or bylaws of such organization or other contract with patrons provide that such dividends are in addition to amounts otherwise payable to patrons which are derived from business done with or for patrons during the taxabl</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written notice of allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Written notice of allocation For purposes of this subchapter, the term “written notice of allocation” means any capital stock, revolving fund certificate, retain certificate, certificate of indebtedness, letter of advice, or other written notice, which discloses to the recipient the stated dollar amount allocated to him by the organization and the portion thereof, if any, which constitutes a patronage dividend.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified written notice of allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualified written notice of allocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonqualified written notice of allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nonqualified written notice of allocation For purposes of this subchapter, the term “nonqualified written notice of allocation” means a written notice of allocation which is not described in subsection (c) or a qualified check which is not cashed on or before the 90th day after the close of the payment period for the taxable year for which the distribution of which it is a part is paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of amount paid or received</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Determination of amount paid or received For purposes of this subchapter, in determining amounts paid or received—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Per-unit retain allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Per-unit retain allocation For purposes of this subchapter, the term “per-unit retain allocation” means any allocation, by an organization to which part I of this subchapter applies, to a patron with respect to products marketed for him, the amount of which is fixed without reference to the net earnings of the organization pursuant to an agreement between the organization and the patron.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Per-unit retain certificate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Per-unit retain certificate For purposes of this subchapter, the term “per-unit retain certificate” means any written notice which discloses to the recipient the stated dollar amount of a per-unit retain allocation to him by the organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified per-unit retain certificate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Qualified per-unit retain certificate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonqualified per-unit retain certificate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nonqualified per-unit retain certificate For purposes of this subchapter, the term “nonqualified per-unit retain certificate” means a per-unit retain certificate which is not described in subsection (h).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1388_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for the netting of gains and losses by cooperatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Special rules for the netting of gains and losses by cooperatives For purposes of this subchapter, in the case of any organization to which part I of this subchapter applies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>