<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1391" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1391/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1391/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1391"><akn:num>1391</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1391. Designation procedure(a) In generalFrom among the areas nominated for designation under this section, the appropriate Secretaries may designate empowerment zones and enterprise communities.


(b) Number of designations(1) Enterprise communitiesThe appropriate Secretaries may designate in the aggregate 95 nominated areas as enterprise communities under this section, subject to the availability of eligible nominated areas. Of that number, not more than 65 may be designated in urban areas and not more than 30 may be designated in rural areas.


(2) Empowerment zonesThe appropriate Secretaries may designate in the aggregate 11 nominated areas as empowerment zones under this section, subject to the availability of eligible nominated areas. Of that number, not more than 8 may be designated in urban areas and not more than 3 may be designated in rural areas. If 8 empowerment zones are designated in urban areas, no less than 1 shall be designated in an urban area the most populous city of which has a population of 500,000 or less and no less than 1 shall be a nominated area which includes areas in 2 States and which has a population of 50,000 or less. The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall designate empowerment zones located in urban areas in such a manner that the aggregate population of all such zones does not exceed 1,000,000.



(c) Period designations may be madeA designation may be made under subsection (a) only after 1993 and before 1996.


(d) Period for which designation is in effect(1) In generalAny designation under this section shall remain in effect during the period beginning on the date of the designation and ending on the earliest of—(A)(i) in the case of an empowerment zone, December 31, 2025, or

(ii) in the case of an enterprise community, the close of the 10th calendar year beginning on or after such date of designation,


(B) the termination date designated by the State and local governments as provided for in their nomination, or
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general From among the areas nominated for designation under this section, the appropriate Secretaries may designate empowerment zones and enterprise communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number of designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Number of designations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period designations may be made</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Period designations may be made A designation may be made under subsection (a) only after 1993 and before 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period for which designation is in effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Period for which designation is in effect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations on designations No area may be designated under this section unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application No area may be designated under this section unless the application for such designation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional designations permitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Additional designations permitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1391_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional designations permitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Additional designations permitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>