<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1398" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1398/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1398/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1398"><akn:num>1398</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules relating to individuals’ title 11 cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1398. Rules relating to individuals’ title 11 cases(a) Cases to which section appliesExcept as provided in subsection (b), this section shall apply to any case under chapter 7 (relating to liquidations) or chapter 11 (relating to reorganizations) of title 11 of the United States Code in which the debtor is an individual.


(b) Exceptions where case is dismissed, etc.(1) Section does not apply where case is dismissedThis section shall not apply if the case under chapter 7 or 11 of title 11 of the United States Code is dismissed.


(2) Section does not apply at partnership levelFor purposes of subsection (a), a partnership shall not be treated as an individual, but the interest in a partnership of a debtor who is an individual shall be taken into account under this section in the same manner as any other interest of the debtor.



(c) Computation and payment of tax; basic standard deduction(1) Computation and payment of taxExcept as otherwise provided in this section, the taxable income of the estate shall be computed in the same manner as for an individual. The tax shall be computed on such taxable income and shall be paid by the trustee.


(2) Tax ratesThe tax on the taxable income of the estate shall be determined under subsection (d) of section 1.


(3) Basic standard deductionIn the case of an estate which does not itemize deductions, the basic standard deduction for the estate for the taxable year shall be the same as for a married individual filing a separate return for such year.



(d) Taxable year of debtors(1) General ruleExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the taxable year of the debtor shall be determined without regard to the case under title 11 of the United States Code to which this section applies.


(2) Election to terminate debtor’s year when case commences(A) In generalNotwithstanding section 442, the debtor may (without the approval of the Secretary) elect to treat the debtor’s taxable year which includes the commencement date as 2 taxable year</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cases to which section applies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cases to which section applies Except as provided in subsection (b), this section shall apply to any case under chapter 7 (relating to liquidations) or chapter 11 (relating to reorganizations) of title 11 of the United States Code in which the debtor is an individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions where case is dismissed, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions where case is dismissed, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation and payment of tax; basic standard deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Computation and payment of tax; basic standard deduction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable year of debtors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Taxable year of debtors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of income, deductions, and credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of income, deductions, and credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of transfers between debtor and estate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of transfers between debtor and estate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estate succeeds to tax attributes of debtor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Estate succeeds to tax attributes of debtor The estate shall succeed to and take into account the following items (determined as of the first day of the debtor’s taxable year in which the case commences) of the debtor—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration, liquidation, and reorganization expenses; carryovers and carrybacks of certain excess expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administration, liquidation, and reorganization expenses; carryovers and carrybacks of certain excess expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Debtor succeeds to tax attributes of estate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Debtor succeeds to tax attributes of estate In the case of a termination of an estate, the debtor shall succeed to and take into account the items referred to in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6) of subsection (g) in a manner similar to that provided in such paragraphs (but taking into account that the transfer is from the estate to the debtor instead of from the debtor to the estate). In addition, the debtor shall succeed to and take into account the other tax attributes of the estate, to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary as necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Other special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>