<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/139F" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/139F/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/139F/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_139F"><akn:num>139F</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain amounts received by wrongfully incarcerated individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 139F. Certain amounts received by wrongfully incarcerated individuals(a) Exclusion from gross incomeIn the case of any wrongfully incarcerated individual, gross income shall not include any civil damages, restitution, or other monetary award (including compensatory or statutory damages and restitution imposed in a criminal matter) relating to the incarceration of such individual for the covered offense for which such individual was convicted.


(b) Wrongfully incarcerated individualFor purposes of this section, the term “wrongfully incarcerated individual” means an individual—(1) who was convicted of a covered offense,

(2) who served all or part of a sentence of imprisonment relating to that covered offense, and

(3)(A) who was pardoned, granted clemency, or granted amnesty for that covered offense because that individual was innocent of that covered offense, or

(B)(i) for whom the judgment of conviction for that covered offense was reversed or vacated, and

(ii) for whom the indictment, information, or other accusatory instrument for that covered offense was dismissed or who was found not guilty at a new trial after the judgment of conviction for that covered offense was reversed or vacated.




(c) Covered offenseFor purposes of this section, the term “covered offense” means any criminal offense under Federal or State law, and includes any criminal offense arising from the same course of conduct as that criminal offense.


(Added Pub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title III, § 304(a), Dec. 18, 2015, 129 Stat. 3087.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title III, § 304(c), Dec. 18, 2015, 129 Stat. 3088, provided that: “The amendments made by this section [enacting this section] shall apply to taxable years beginning before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [Dec. 18, 2015].”


Waiver of LimitationsPub. L. 114–113, div. Q, title III, § 304(d), Dec. 18, 2015, 129 Stat. 3088, as amended by Pub. L. 115–123, div. D</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_139F_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion from gross income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Exclusion from gross income In the case of any wrongfully incarcerated individual, gross income shall not include any civil damages, restitution, or other monetary award (including compensatory or statutory damages and restitution imposed in a criminal matter) relating to the incarceration of such individual for the covered offense for which such individual was convicted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_139F_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wrongfully incarcerated individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Wrongfully incarcerated individual For purposes of this section, the term “wrongfully incarcerated individual” means an individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_139F_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered offense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Covered offense For purposes of this section, the term “covered offense” means any criminal offense under Federal or State law, and includes any criminal offense arising from the same course of conduct as that criminal offense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>