<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/139K" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/139K/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/139K/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_139K"><akn:num>139K</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarships for qualified elementary or secondary education expenses of eligible students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 139K. Scholarships for qualified elementary or secondary education expenses of eligible students(a) In generalIn the case of an individual, gross income shall not include any amounts provided to such individual or any dependent of such individual pursuant to a scholarship for qualified elementary or secondary education expenses of an eligible student which is provided by a scholarship granting organization.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section, the terms “qualified elementary or secondary education expense”, “eligible student”, and “scholarship granting organization” have the same meaning given such terms under section 25F(c).


(Added Pub. L. 119–21, title VII, § 70411(b)(1), July 4, 2025, 139 Stat. 217.)

Delayed Effective Date of SectionFor delayed effective date of section, see Effective Date note below.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable to amounts received after Dec. 31, 2026, in taxable years ending after such date, see section 70411(c)(2) of Pub. L. 119–21, set out in an Effective Date of 2025 Amendment note under section 25 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_139K_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of an individual, gross income shall not include any amounts provided to such individual or any dependent of such individual pursuant to a scholarship for qualified elementary or secondary education expenses of an eligible student which is provided by a scholarship granting organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_139K_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section, the terms “qualified elementary or secondary education expense”, “eligible student”, and “scholarship granting organization” have the same meaning given such terms under section 25F(c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>