<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/143" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/143/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/143/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_143"><akn:num>143</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage revenue bonds: qualified mortgage bond and qualified veterans’ mortgage bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 143. Mortgage revenue bonds: qualified mortgage bond and qualified veterans’ mortgage bond(a) Qualified mortgage bond(1) Qualified mortgage bond definedFor purposes of this title, the term “qualified mortgage bond” means a bond which is issued as part of a qualified mortgage issue.


(2) Qualified mortgage issue defined(A) DefinitionFor purposes of this title, the term “qualified mortgage issue” means an issue by a State or political subdivision thereof of 1 or more bonds, but only if—(i) all proceeds of such issue (exclusive of issuance costs and a reasonably required reserve) are to be used to finance owner-occupied residences,

(ii) such issue meets the requirements of subsections (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), and (m)(7),

(iii) such issue does not meet the private business tests of paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 141(b), and

(iv) except as provided in subparagraph (D)(ii), repayments of principal on financing provided by the issue are used not later than the close of the 1st semiannual period beginning after the date the prepayment (or complete repayment) is received to redeem bonds which are part of such issue.


Clause (iv) shall not apply to amounts received within 10 years after the date of issuance of the issue (or, in the case of refunding bond, the date of issuance of the original bond).

(B) Good faith effort to comply with mortgage eligibility requirementsAn issue which fails to meet 1 or more of the requirements of subsections (c), (d), (e), (f), and (i) shall be treated as meeting such requirements if—(i) the issuer in good faith attempted to meet all such requirements before the mortgages were executed,

(ii) 95 percent or more of the proceeds devoted to owner-financing was devoted to residences with respect to which (at the time the mortgages were executed) all such requirements were met, and

(iii) any failure to meet the requirements of such subsections is corrected within a reasonable period after such failure is first discovered.


(C)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified mortgage bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Qualified mortgage bond</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified veterans’ mortgage bond defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified veterans’ mortgage bond defined For purposes of this part, the term “qualified veterans’ mortgage bond” means any bond— Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (B) and (C) of subsection (a)(2) shall apply to the requirements specified in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Residence requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Residence requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>3-year requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) 3-year requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase price requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Purchase price requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Income requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements related to arbitrage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Requirements related to arbitrage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Portion of loans required to be placed in targeted areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Portion of loans required to be placed in targeted areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Other requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_143_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Targeted area residences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Targeted area residences</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>