<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1445" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1445/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1445/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1445"><akn:num>1445</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding of tax on dispositions of United States real property interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1445. Withholding of tax on dispositions of United States real property interests(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in this section, in the case of any disposition of a United States real property interest (as defined in section 897(c)) by a foreign person, the transferee shall be required to deduct and withhold a tax equal to 15 percent of the amount realized on the disposition.


(b) Exemptions(1) In generalNo person shall be required to deduct and withhold any amount under subsection (a) with respect to a disposition if paragraph (2), (3), (4), (5), or (6) applies to the transaction.


(2) Transferor furnishes nonforeign affidavitExcept as provided in paragraph (7), this paragraph applies to the disposition if the transferor furnishes to the transferee an affidavit by the transferor stating, under penalty of perjury, the transferor’s United States taxpayer identification number and that the transferor is not a foreign person.


(3) Nonpublicly traded domestic corporation furnishes affidavit that interests in corporation not United States real property interestsExcept as provided in paragraph (7), this paragraph applies in the case of a disposition of any interest in any domestic corporation if the domestic corporation furnishes to the transferee an affidavit by the domestic corporation stating, under penalty of perjury, that—(A) the domestic corporation is not and has not been a United States real property holding corporation (as defined in section 897(c)(2)) during the applicable period specified in section 897(c)(1)(A)(ii), or

(B) as of the date of the disposition, interests in such corporation are not United States real property interests by reason of section 897(c)(1)(B).


(4) Transferee receives qualifying statement(A) In generalThis paragraph applies to the disposition if the transferee receives a qualifying statement at such time, in such manner, and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.


(B) Qua</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided in this section, in the case of any disposition of a United States real property interest (as defined in section 897(c)) by a foreign person, the transferee shall be required to deduct and withhold a tax equal to 15 percent of the amount realized on the disposition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on amount required to be withheld</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations on amount required to be withheld</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of transferor’s agents, transferee’s agents, or qualified substitutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Liability of transferor’s agents, transferee’s agents, or qualified substitutes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules relating to distributions, etc., by corporations, partnerships, trusts, or estates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules relating to distributions, etc., by corporations, partnerships, trusts, or estates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>