<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/146" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/146/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/146/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_146"><akn:num>146</akn:num><akn:heading>Volume cap</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 146. Volume cap(a) General ruleA private activity bond issued as part of an issue meets the requirements of this section if the aggregate face amount of the private activity bonds issued pursuant to such issue, when added to the aggregate face amount of tax-exempt private activity bonds previously issued by the issuing authority during the calendar year, does not exceed such authority’s volume cap for such calendar year.


(b) Volume cap for State agenciesFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe volume cap for any agency of the State authorized to issue tax-exempt private activity bonds for any calendar year shall be 50 percent of the State ceiling for such calendar year.


(2) Special rule where State has more than 1 agencyIf more than 1 agency of the State is authorized to issue tax-exempt private activity bonds, all such agencies shall be treated as a single agency.



(c) Volume cap for other issuersFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe volume cap for any issuing authority (other than a State agency) for any calendar year shall be an amount which bears the same ratio to 50 percent of the State ceiling for such calendar year as—(A) the population of the jurisdiction of such issuing authority, bears to

(B) the population of the entire State.


(2) Overlapping jurisdictionsFor purposes of paragraph (1)(A), if an area is within the jurisdiction of 2 or more governmental units, such area shall be treated as only within the jurisdiction of the unit having jurisdiction over the smallest geographical area unless such unit agrees to surrender all or part of such jurisdiction for such calendar year to the unit with overlapping jurisdiction which has the next smallest geographical area.



(d) State ceilingFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe State ceiling applicable to any State for any calendar year shall be the greater of—(A) an amount equal to $75 ($62.50 in the case of calendar year 2001) multiplied by the State population, or

(B) $225,000</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule A private activity bond issued as part of an issue meets the requirements of this section if the aggregate face amount of the private activity bonds issued pursuant to such issue, when added to the aggregate face amount of tax-exempt private activity bonds previously issued by the issuing authority during the calendar year, does not exceed such authority’s volume cap for such calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Volume cap for State agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Volume cap for State agencies For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Volume cap for other issuers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Volume cap for other issuers For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State ceiling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State ceiling For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State may provide for different allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State may provide for different allocation For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elective carryforward of unused limitation for specified purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Elective carryforward of unused limitation for specified purpose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for certain bonds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exception for certain bonds Only for purposes of this section, the term “private activity bond” shall not include— Paragraphs (4) and (5) shall be applied without regard to “75 percent of” if all of the property to be financed by the net proceeds of the issue is to be owned by a governmental unit (within the meaning of section 142(b)(1)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for government-owned solid waste disposal facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exception for government-owned solid waste disposal facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of refunding issues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Treatment of refunding issues For purposes of the volume cap imposed by this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_146_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Population</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Population For purposes of this section, determinations of the population of any State (or issuing authority) shall be made with respect to any calendar year on the basis of the most recent census estimate of the resident population of such State (or issuing authority) released by the Bureau of Census before the beginning of such calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>