<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1474" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1474/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1474/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1474"><akn:num>1474</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1474. Special rules(a) Liability for withheld taxEvery person required to deduct and withhold any tax under this chapter is hereby made liable for such tax and is hereby indemnified against the claims and demands of any person for the amount of any payments made in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.


(b) Credits and refunds(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the determination of whether any tax deducted and withheld under this chapter results in an overpayment by the beneficial owner of the payment to which such tax is attributable shall be made as if such tax had been deducted and withheld under subchapter A of chapter 3.


(2) Special rule where foreign financial institution is beneficial owner of payment(A) In generalIn the case of any tax properly deducted and withheld under section 1471 from a specified financial institution payment—(i) if the foreign financial institution referred to in subparagraph (B) with respect to such payment is entitled to a reduced rate of tax with respect to such payment by reason of any treaty obligation of the United States—(I) the amount of any credit or refund with respect to such tax shall not exceed the amount of credit or refund attributable to such reduction in rate, and

(II) no interest shall be allowed or paid with respect to such credit or refund, and


(ii) if such foreign financial institution is not so entitled, no credit or refund shall be allowed or paid with respect to such tax.


(B) Specified financial institution paymentThe term “specified financial institution payment” means any payment if the beneficial owner of such payment is a foreign financial institution.



(3) Requirement to identify substantial United States ownersNo credit or refund shall be allowed or paid with respect to any tax properly deducted and withheld under this chapter unless the beneficial owner of the payment provides the Secretary such information as the Secretary may require to determine whether such benefic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for withheld tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liability for withheld tax Every person required to deduct and withhold any tax under this chapter is hereby made liable for such tax and is hereby indemnified against the claims and demands of any person for the amount of any payments made in accordance with the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credits and refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Credits and refunds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Confidentiality of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other withholding provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination with other withholding provisions The Secretary shall provide for the coordination of this chapter with other withholding provisions under this title, including providing for the proper crediting of amounts deducted and withheld under this chapter against amounts required to be deducted and withheld under such other provisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of withholding under agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of withholding under agreements Any tax deducted and withheld pursuant to an agreement described in section 1471(b) shall be treated for purposes of this title as a tax deducted and withheld by a withholding agent under section 1471(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1474_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of, and prevent the avoidance of, this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>