<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/148" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/148/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/148/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_148"><akn:num>148</akn:num><akn:heading>Arbitrage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 148. Arbitrage(a) Arbitrage bond definedFor purposes of section 103, the term “arbitrage bond” means any bond issued as part of an issue any portion of the proceeds of which are reasonably expected (at the time of issuance of the bond) to be used directly or indirectly—(1) to acquire higher yielding investments, or

(2) to replace funds which were used directly or indirectly to acquire higher yielding investments.


For purposes of this subsection, a bond shall be treated as an arbitrage bond if the issuer intentionally uses any portion of the proceeds of the issue of which such bond is a part in a manner described in paragraph (1) or (2).

(b) Higher yielding investmentsFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “higher yielding investments” means any investment property which produces a yield over the term of the issue which is materially higher than the yield on the issue.


(2) Investment propertyThe term “investment property” means—(A) any security (within the meaning of section 165(g)(2)(A) or (B)),

(B) any obligation,

(C) any annuity contract,

(D) any investment-type property, or

(E) in the case of a bond other than a private activity bond, any residential rental property for family units which is not located within the jurisdiction of the issuer and which is not acquired to implement a court ordered or approved housing desegregation plan.


(3) Alternative minimum tax bonds treated as investment property in certain cases(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “investment property” does not include any tax-exempt bond.


(B) ExceptionWith respect to an issue other than an issue a part of which is a specified private activity bond (as defined in section 57(a)(5)(C)), the term “investment property” includes a specified private activity bond (as so defined).



(4) Safe harbor for prepaid natural gas(A) In generalThe term “investment-type property” does not include a prepayment under a qualified natural gas supply contract.
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_148_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Arbitrage bond defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Arbitrage bond defined For purposes of section 103, the term “arbitrage bond” means any bond issued as part of an issue any portion of the proceeds of which are reasonably expected (at the time of issuance of the bond) to be used directly or indirectly— For purposes of this subsection, a bond shall be treated as an arbitrage bond if the issuer intentionally uses any portion of the proceeds of the issue of which such bond is a part in a manner described in paragraph (1) or (2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_148_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Higher yielding investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Higher yielding investments For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_148_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary period exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Temporary period exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_148_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for reasonably required reserve or replacement fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules for reasonably required reserve or replacement fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_148_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minor portion may be invested in higher yielding investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Minor portion may be invested in higher yielding investments Notwithstanding subsections (a), (c), and (d), a bond issued as part of an issue shall not be treated as an arbitrage bond solely by reason of the fact that an amount of the proceeds of such issue (in addition to the amounts under subsections (c) and (d)) is invested in higher yielding investments if such amount does not exceed the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_148_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required rebate to the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Required rebate to the United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_148_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student loan incentive payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Student loan incentive payments Except to the extent otherwise provided in regulations, payments made by the Secretary of Education pursuant to section 438 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 are not to be taken into account, for purposes of subsection (a)(1), in determining yields on student loan notes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_148_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations of yield</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Determinations of yield For purposes of this section, the yield on an issue shall be determined on the basis of the issue price (within the meaning of sections 1273 and 1274).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_148_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>