<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1502"><akn:num>1502</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1502. Regulations
The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as he may deem necessary in order that the tax liability of any affiliated group of corporations making a consolidated return and of each corporation in the group, both during and after the period of affiliation, may be returned, determined, computed, assessed, collected, and adjusted, in such manner as clearly to reflect the income-tax liability and the various factors necessary for the determination of such liability, and in order to prevent avoidance of such tax liability. In carrying out the preceding sentence, the Secretary may prescribe rules that are different from the provisions of chapter 1 that would apply if such corporations filed separate returns.
(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 367; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b) (13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834; Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 844(a), Oct. 22, 2004, 118 Stat. 1600.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2004—Pub. L. 108–357 inserted at end “In carrying out the preceding sentence, the Secretary may prescribe rules that are different from the provisions of chapter 1 that would apply if such corporations filed separate returns.”
1976—Pub. L. 94–455 struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2004 AmendmentPub. L. 108–357, title VIII, § 844(c), Oct. 22, 2004, 118 Stat. 1600, provided that: “This section [amending this section], and the amendment made by this section, shall apply to taxable years beginning before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act [Oct. 22, 2004].”


Dual Resident CompaniesPub. L. 100–647, title VI, § 6126, Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3713, provided that:
“(a) General Rule.—In the case of a transaction which—“(1) involves the transfer after the date of the enactment of this Act [Nov. 10, 1988] by a domestic corporation, with respect to which there is a qualified excess loss account, of its assets and liabilities to a foreign corporation in exchan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>