<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/1503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1503"><akn:num>1503</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation and payment of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1503. Computation and payment of tax(a) [General rule] 11 Subsec. (a) heading editorially supplied.In any case in which a consolidated return is made or is required to be made, the tax shall be determined, computed, assessed, collected, and adjusted in accordance with the regulations under section 1502 prescribed before the last day prescribed by law for the filing of such return.


[(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 94–455, title X, § 1052(c)(5), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1648]

(c) Special rule for application of certain losses against income of insurance companies taxed under section 801(1) In generalIf an election under section 1504(c)(2) is in effect for the taxable year and the consolidated taxable income of the members of the group not taxed under section 801 results in a consolidated net operating loss for such taxable year, then under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the amount of such loss which cannot be absorbed in the applicable carry-back periods against the taxable income of such members not taxed under section 801 shall be taken into account in determining the consolidated taxable income of the affiliated group for such taxable year to the extent of 35 percent of such loss or 35 percent of the taxable income of the members taxed under section 801, whichever is less. The unused portion of such loss shall be available as a carryover, subject to the same limitations (applicable to the sum of the loss for the carryover year and the loss (or losses) carried over to such year), in applicable carryover years.


(2) Losses of recent nonlife affiliatesNotwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1), a net operating loss for a taxable year of a member of the group not taxed under section 801 shall not be taken into account in determining the taxable income of a member taxed under section 801 (either for the taxable year or as a carryover or carryback) if such taxable year precedes the sixth taxable year such members have been members of the same affiliated group (d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>[General rule] 11 Subsec. (a) heading editorially supplied.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) [General rule] In any case in which a consolidated return is made or is required to be made, the tax shall be determined, computed, assessed, collected, and adjusted in accordance with the regulations under section 1502 prescribed before the last day prescribed by law for the filing of such return.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 94–455, title X, § 1052(c)(5), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1648]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for application of certain losses against income of insurance companies taxed under section 801</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule for application of certain losses against income of insurance companies taxed under section 801</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1503_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dual consolidated loss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Dual consolidated loss</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1503_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for determining adjustments to basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rule for determining adjustments to basis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1503_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of group losses to offset income of subsidiary paying preferred dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on use of group losses to offset income of subsidiary paying preferred dividends</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>