<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/163" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/163/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/163/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_163"><akn:num>163</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 163. Interest(a) General ruleThere shall be allowed as a deduction all interest paid or accrued within the taxable year on indebtedness.


(b) Installment purchases where interest charge is not separately stated(1) General ruleIf personal property or educational services are purchased under a contract—(A) which provides that payment of part or all of the purchase price is to be made in installments, and

(B) in which carrying charges are separately stated but the interest charge cannot be ascertained,


then the payments made during the taxable year under the contract shall be treated for purposes of this section as if they included interest equal to 6 percent of the average unpaid balance under the contract during the taxable year. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the average unpaid balance is the sum of the unpaid balance outstanding on the first day of each month beginning during the taxable year, divided by 12. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “educational services” means any service (including lodging) which is purchased from an educational organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A)(ii) and which is provided for a student of such organization.

(2) LimitationIn the case of any contract to which paragraph (1) applies, the amount treated as interest for any taxable year shall not exceed the aggregate carrying charges which are properly attributable to such taxable year.



(c) Redeemable ground rentsFor purposes of this subtitle, any annual or periodic rental under a redeemable ground rent (excluding amounts in redemption thereof) shall be treated as interest on an indebtedness secured by a mortgage.


(d) Limitation on investment interest(1) In generalIn the case of a taxpayer other than a corporation, the amount allowed as a deduction under this chapter for investment interest for any taxable year shall not exceed the net investment income of the taxpayer for the taxable year.


(2) Carryforward of disallowed interestThe amount not allowed </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule There shall be allowed as a deduction all interest paid or accrued within the taxable year on indebtedness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Installment purchases where interest charge is not separately stated</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Installment purchases where interest charge is not separately stated</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redeemable ground rents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Redeemable ground rents For purposes of this subtitle, any annual or periodic rental under a redeemable ground rent (excluding amounts in redemption thereof) shall be treated as interest on an indebtedness secured by a mortgage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on investment interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on investment interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Original issue discount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Original issue discount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of deduction for interest on certain obligations not in registered form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Denial of deduction for interest on certain obligations not in registered form</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of deduction where section 25 credit taken</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reduction of deduction where section 25 credit taken The amount of the deduction under this section for interest paid or accrued during any taxable year on indebtedness with respect to which a mortgage credit certificate has been issued under section 25 shall be reduced by the amount of the credit allowable with respect to such interest under section 25 (determined without regard to section 26).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowance of deduction for personal interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Disallowance of deduction for personal interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable high yield discount obligation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Applicable high yield discount obligation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_163_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on business interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Limitation on business interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>