<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/164" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/164/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/164/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_164"><akn:num>164</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 164. Taxes(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in this section, the following taxes shall be allowed as a deduction for the taxable year within which paid or accrued:(1) State and local, and foreign, real property taxes.

(2) State and local personal property taxes.

(3) State and local, and foreign, income, war profits, and excess profits taxes.

(4) The GST tax imposed on income distributions.


In addition, there shall be allowed as a deduction State and local, and foreign, taxes not described in the preceding sentence which are paid or accrued within the taxable year in carrying on a trade or business or an activity described in section 212 (relating to expenses for production of income). Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, any tax (not described in the first sentence of this subsection) which is paid or accrued by the taxpayer in connection with an acquisition or disposition of property shall be treated as part of the cost of the acquired property or, in the case of a disposition, as a reduction in the amount realized on the disposition.

(b) Definitions and special rulesFor purposes of this section—(1) Personal property taxesThe term “personal property tax” means an ad valorem tax which is imposed on an annual basis in respect of personal property.


(2) State or local taxesA State or local tax includes only a tax imposed by a State, a possession of the United States, or a political subdivision of any of the foregoing, or by the District of Columbia.


(3) Foreign taxesA foreign tax includes only a tax imposed by the authority of a foreign country.


(4) Special rules for GST tax(A) In generalThe GST tax imposed on income distributions is—(i) the tax imposed by section 2601, and

(ii) any State tax described in section 2604 (as in effect before its repeal),


but only to the extent such tax is imposed on a transfer which is included in the gross income of the distributee and to which section 666 does not apply.

(B) Special rule for tax paid befo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided in this section, the following taxes shall be allowed as a deduction for the taxable year within which paid or accrued: In addition, there shall be allowed as a deduction State and local, and foreign, taxes not described in the preceding sentence which are paid or accrued within the taxable year in carrying on a trade or business or an activity described in section 212 (relating to expenses for production of income). Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, any tax (not described in the first sentence of this subsection) which is paid or accrued by the taxpayer in connection with an acquisition or disposition of property shall be treated as part of the cost of the acquired property or, in the case of a disposition, as a reduction in the amount realized on the disposition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction denied in case of certain taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deduction denied in case of certain taxes No deduction shall be allowed for the following taxes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment of taxes on real property between seller and purchaser</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Apportionment of taxes on real property between seller and purchaser</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxes of shareholder paid by corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Taxes of shareholder paid by corporation Where a corporation pays a tax imposed on a shareholder on his interest as a shareholder, and where the shareholder does not reimburse the corporation, then—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction for one-half of self-employment taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Deduction for one-half of self-employment taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_164_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>