<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/165" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/165/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/165/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_165"><akn:num>165</akn:num><akn:heading>Losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 165. Losses(a) General ruleThere shall be allowed as a deduction any loss sustained during the taxable year and not compensated for by insurance or otherwise.


(b) Amount of deductionFor purposes of subsection (a), the basis for determining the amount of the deduction for any loss shall be the adjusted basis provided in section 1011 for determining the loss from the sale or other disposition of property.


(c) Limitation on losses of individualsIn the case of an individual, the deduction under subsection (a) shall be limited to—(1) losses incurred in a trade or business;

(2) losses incurred in any transaction entered into for profit, though not connected with a trade or business; and

(3) except as provided in subsection (h), losses of property not connected with a trade or business or a transaction entered into for profit, if such losses arise from fire, storm, shipwreck, or other casualty, or from theft.


(d) Wagering losses(1) In generalFor purposes of losses from wagering transactions, the amount allowed as a deduction for any taxable year—(A) shall be equal to 90 percent of the amount of such losses during such taxable year, and

(B) shall be allowed only to the extent of the gains from such transactions during such taxable year.


(2) Special ruleFor purposes of paragraph (1), the term “losses from wagering transactions” includes any deduction otherwise allowable under this chapter incurred in carrying on any wagering transaction.



(e) Theft lossesFor purposes of subsection (a), any loss arising from theft shall be treated as sustained during the taxable year in which the taxpayer discovers such loss.


(f) Capital lossesLosses from sales or exchanges of capital assets shall be allowed only to the extent allowed in sections 1211 and 1212.


(g) Worthless securities(1) General ruleIf any security which is a capital asset becomes worthless during the taxable year, the loss resulting therefrom shall, for purposes of this subtitle, be treated as a loss from</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule There shall be allowed as a deduction any loss sustained during the taxable year and not compensated for by insurance or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of deduction For purposes of subsection (a), the basis for determining the amount of the deduction for any loss shall be the adjusted basis provided in section 1011 for determining the loss from the sale or other disposition of property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on losses of individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on losses of individuals In the case of an individual, the deduction under subsection (a) shall be limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wagering losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Wagering losses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Theft losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Theft losses For purposes of subsection (a), any loss arising from theft shall be treated as sustained during the taxable year in which the taxpayer discovers such loss.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Capital losses Losses from sales or exchanges of capital assets shall be allowed only to the extent allowed in sections 1211 and 1212.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Worthless securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Worthless securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of casualty gains and losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Treatment of casualty gains and losses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disaster losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Disaster losses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_165_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of deduction for losses on certain obligations not in registered form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Denial of deduction for losses on certain obligations not in registered form</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>