<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/170" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/170/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/170/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_170"><akn:num>170</akn:num><akn:heading>Charitable, etc., contributions and gifts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 170. Charitable, etc., contributions and gifts(a) Allowance of deduction(1) General ruleThere shall be allowed as a deduction any charitable contribution (as defined in subsection (c)) payment of which is made within the taxable year. A charitable contribution shall be allowable as a deduction only if verified under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(2) Corporations on accrual basisIn the case of a corporation reporting its taxable income on the accrual basis, if—(A) the board of directors authorizes a charitable contribution during any taxable year, and

(B) payment of such contribution is made after the close of such taxable year and on or before the 15th day of the fourth month following the close of such taxable year,


then the taxpayer may elect to treat such contribution as paid during such taxable year. The election may be made only at the time of the filing of the return for such taxable year, and shall be signified in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe.

(3) Future interests in tangible personal propertyFor purposes of this section, payment of a charitable contribution which consists of a future interest in tangible personal property shall be treated as made only when all intervening interests in, and rights to the actual possession or enjoyment of, the property have expired or are held by persons other than the taxpayer or those standing in a relationship to the taxpayer described in section 267(b) or 707(b). For purposes of the preceding sentence, a fixture which is intended to be severed from the real property shall be treated as tangible personal property.



(b) Percentage limitations(1) IndividualsIn the case of an individual, the deduction provided in subsection (a) shall be limited as provided in the succeeding subparagraphs.(A) General ruleAny charitable contribution to—(i) a church or a convention or association of churches,

(ii) an educational organization which normally maintains a regular faculty and curric</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of deduction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Percentage limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Percentage limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charitable contribution defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Charitable contribution defined For purposes of this section, the term “charitable contribution” means a contribution or gift to or for the use of— For purposes of this section, the term “charitable contribution” also means an amount treated under subsection (g) as paid for the use of an organization described in paragraph (2), (3), or (4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryovers of excess contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Carryovers of excess contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain contributions of ordinary income and capital gain property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certain contributions of ordinary income and capital gain property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowance of deduction in certain cases and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disallowance of deduction in certain cases and special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts paid to maintain certain students as members of taxpayer’s household</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Amounts paid to maintain certain students as members of taxpayer’s household</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified conservation contribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Qualified conservation contribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard mileage rate for use of passenger automobile</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Standard mileage rate for use of passenger automobile For purposes of computing the deduction under this section for use of a passenger automobile, the standard mileage rate shall be 14 cents per mile.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of deduction for certain travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Denial of deduction for certain travel expenses No deduction shall be allowed under this section for traveling expenses (including amounts expended for meals and lodging) while away from home, whether paid directly or by reimbursement, unless there is no significant element of personal pleasure, recreation, or vacation in such travel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>