<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/171" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/171/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/171/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_171"><akn:num>171</akn:num><akn:heading>Amortizable bond premium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 171. Amortizable bond premium(a) General ruleIn the case of any bond, as defined in subsection (d), the following rules shall apply to the amortizable bond premium (determined under subsection (b)) on the bond:(1) Taxable bondsIn the case of a bond (other than a bond the interest on which is excludable from gross income), the amount of the amortizable bond premium for the taxable year shall be allowed as a deduction.


(2) Tax-exempt bondsIn the case of any bond the interest on which is excludable from gross income, no deduction shall be allowed for the amortizable bond premium for the taxable year.


(3) Cross referenceFor adjustment to basis on account of amortizable bond premium, see section 1016(a)(5).



(b) Amortizable bond premium(1) Amount of bond premiumFor purposes of paragraph (2), the amount of bond premium, in the case of the holder of any bond, shall be determined—(A) with reference to the amount of the basis (for determining loss on sale or exchange) of such bond,

(B)(i) with reference to the amount payable on maturity (or if it results in a smaller amortizable bond premium attributable to the period before the call date, with reference to the amount payable on the earlier call date), in the case of a bond described in subsection (a)(1), and

(ii) with reference to the amount payable on maturity or on an earlier call date, in the case of a bond described in subsection (a)(2).


(C) with adjustments proper to reflect unamortized bond premium, with respect to the bond, for the period before the date as of which subsection (a) becomes applicable with respect to the taxpayer with respect to such bond.


In no case shall the amount of bond premium on a convertible bond include any amount attributable to the conversion features of the bond.

(2) Amount amortizableThe amortizable bond premium of the taxable year shall be the amount of the bond premium attributable to such year. In the case of a bond to which paragraph (1)(B)(i) applies and which has a cal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_171_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of any bond, as defined in subsection (d), the following rules shall apply to the amortizable bond premium (determined under subsection (b)) on the bond:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_171_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amortizable bond premium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amortizable bond premium</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_171_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election as to taxable bonds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Election as to taxable bonds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_171_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Bond defined For purposes of this section, the term “bond” means any bond, debenture, note, or certificate or other evidence of indebtedness, but does not include any such obligation which constitutes stock in trade of the taxpayer or any such obligation of a kind which would properly be included in the inventory of the taxpayer if on hand at the close of the taxable year, or any such obligation held by the taxpayer primarily for sale to customers in the ordinary course of his trade or business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_171_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as offset to interest payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment as offset to interest payments Except as provided in regulations, in the case of any taxable bond— For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “taxable bond” means any bond the interest of which is not excludable from gross income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_171_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dealers in tax-exempt securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Dealers in tax-exempt securities For special rules applicable, in the case of dealers in securities, with respect to premium attributable to certain wholly tax-exempt securities, see section 75.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>