<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/179B" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/179B/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/179B/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_179B"><akn:num>179B</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction for capital costs incurred in complying with Environmental Protection Agency sulfur regula</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 179B. Deduction for capital costs incurred in complying with Environmental Protection Agency sulfur regulations(a) Allowance of deductionIn the case of a small business refiner (as defined in section 45H(c)(1)) which elects the application of this section, there shall be allowed as a deduction an amount equal to 75 percent of qualified costs (as defined in section 45H(c)(2)) which are paid or incurred by the taxpayer during the taxable year and which are properly chargeable to capital account.


(b) Reduced percentageIn the case of a small business refiner with average daily domestic refinery runs for the 1-year period ending on December 31, 2002, in excess of 155,000 barrels, the number of percentage points described in subsection (a) shall be reduced (not below zero) by the product of such number (before the application of this subsection) and the ratio of such excess to 50,000 barrels.


(c) Basis reduction(1) In generalFor purposes of this title, the basis of any property shall be reduced by the portion of the cost of such property taken into account under subsection (a).


(2) Ordinary income recaptureFor purposes of section 1245, the amount of the deduction allowable under subsection (a) with respect to any property which is of a character subject to the allowance for depreciation shall be treated as a deduction allowed for depreciation under section 167.



(d) Coordination with other provisionsSection 280B shall not apply to amounts which are treated as expenses under this section.


(e) Election to allocate deduction to cooperative owner(1) In generalIf—(A) a small business refiner to which subsection (a) applies is an organization to which part I of subchapter T applies, and

(B) one or more persons directly holding an ownership interest in the refiner are organizations to which part I of subchapter T apply,


the refiner may elect to allocate all or a portion of the deduction allowable under subsection (a) to such persons. Such allocation shall be equal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179B_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of deduction In the case of a small business refiner (as defined in section 45H(c)(1)) which elects the application of this section, there shall be allowed as a deduction an amount equal to 75 percent of qualified costs (as defined in section 45H(c)(2)) which are paid or incurred by the taxpayer during the taxable year and which are properly chargeable to capital account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179B_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduced percentage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reduced percentage In the case of a small business refiner with average daily domestic refinery runs for the 1-year period ending on December 31, 2002, in excess of 155,000 barrels, the number of percentage points described in subsection (a) shall be reduced (not below zero) by the product of such number (before the application of this subsection) and the ratio of such excess to 50,000 barrels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179B_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Basis reduction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179B_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination with other provisions Section 280B shall not apply to amounts which are treated as expenses under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179B_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to allocate deduction to cooperative owner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Election to allocate deduction to cooperative owner</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>