<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/183" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/183/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/183/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_183"><akn:num>183</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities not engaged in for profit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 183. Activities not engaged in for profit(a) General ruleIn the case of an activity engaged in by an individual or an S corporation, if such activity is not engaged in for profit, no deduction attributable to such activity shall be allowed under this chapter except as provided in this section.


(b) Deductions allowableIn the case of an activity not engaged in for profit to which subsection (a) applies, there shall be allowed—(1) the deductions which would be allowable under this chapter for the taxable year without regard to whether or not such activity is engaged in for profit, and

(2) a deduction equal to the amount of the deductions which would be allowable under this chapter for the taxable year only if such activity were engaged in for profit, but only to the extent that the gross income derived from such activity for the taxable year exceeds the deductions allowable by reason of paragraph (1).


(c) Activity not engaged in for profit definedFor purposes of this section, the term “activity not engaged in for profit” means any activity other than one with respect to which deductions are allowable for the taxable year under section 162 or under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 212.


(d) PresumptionIf the gross income derived from an activity for 3 or more of the taxable years in the period of 5 consecutive taxable years which ends with the taxable year exceeds the deductions attributable to such activity (determined without regard to whether or not such activity is engaged in for profit), then, unless the Secretary establishes to the contrary, such activity shall be presumed for purposes of this chapter for such taxable year to be an activity engaged in for profit. In the case of an activity which consists in major part of the breeding, training, showing, or racing of horses, the preceding sentence shall be applied by substituting “2” for “3” and “7” for “5”.


(e) Special rule(1) In generalA determination as to whether the presumption provided by subsection </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of an activity engaged in by an individual or an S corporation, if such activity is not engaged in for profit, no deduction attributable to such activity shall be allowed under this chapter except as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductions allowable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deductions allowable In the case of an activity not engaged in for profit to which subsection (a) applies, there shall be allowed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activity not engaged in for profit defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activity not engaged in for profit defined For purposes of this section, the term “activity not engaged in for profit” means any activity other than one with respect to which deductions are allowable for the taxable year under section 162 or under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 212.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Presumption If the gross income derived from an activity for 3 or more of the taxable years in the period of 5 consecutive taxable years which ends with the taxable year exceeds the deductions attributable to such activity (determined without regard to whether or not such activity is engaged in for profit), then, unless the Secretary establishes to the contrary, such activity shall be presumed for purposes of this chapter for such taxable year to be an activity engaged in for profit. In the case of an activity which consists in major part of the breeding, training, showing, or racing of horses, the preceding sentence shall be applied by substituting “2” for “3” and “7” for “5”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>