<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/194" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/194/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/194/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_194"><akn:num>194</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of reforestation expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 194. Treatment of reforestation expenditures(a) Allowance of deductionIn the case of any qualified timber property with respect to which the taxpayer has made (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary) an election under this subsection, the taxpayer shall be entitled to a deduction with respect to the amortization of the amortizable basis of qualified timber property based on a period of 84 months. Such amortization deduction shall be an amount, with respect to each month of such period within the taxable year, equal to the amortizable basis at the end of such month divided by the number of months (including the month for which the deduction is computed) remaining in the period. Such amortizable basis at the end of the month shall be computed without regard to the amortization deduction for such month. The 84-month period shall begin on the first day of the first month of the second half of the taxable year in which the amortizable basis is acquired.


(b) Treatment as expenses(1) Election to treat certain reforestation expenditures as expenses(A) In generalIn the case of any qualified timber property with respect to which the taxpayer has made (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary) an election under this subsection, the taxpayer shall treat reforestation expenditures which are paid or incurred during the taxable year with respect to such property as an expense which is not chargeable to capital account. The reforestation expenditures so treated shall be allowed as a deduction.


(B) Dollar limitationThe aggregate amount of reforestation expenditures which may be taken into account under subparagraph (A) with respect to each qualified timber property for any taxable year shall not exceed—(i) except as provided in clause (ii) or (iii), $10,000,

(ii) in the case of a separate return by a married individual (as defined in section 7703), $5,000, and

(iii) in the case of a trust, zero.



(2) Allocation of dollar limit(A) Contr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_194_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of deduction In the case of any qualified timber property with respect to which the taxpayer has made (in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary) an election under this subsection, the taxpayer shall be entitled to a deduction with respect to the amortization of the amortizable basis of qualified timber property based on a period of 84 months. Such amortization deduction shall be an amount, with respect to each month of such period within the taxable year, equal to the amortizable basis at the end of such month divided by the number of months (including the month for which the deduction is computed) remaining in the period. Such amortizable basis at the end of the month shall be computed without regard to the amortization deduction for such month. The 84-month period shall begin on the first day of the first month of the second half of the taxable year in which the amortizable basis is acquired.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_194_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treatment as expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_194_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions and special rule For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_194_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life tenant and remainderman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Life tenant and remainderman In the case of property held by one person for life with remainder to another person, the deduction under this section shall be computed as if the life tenant were the absolute owner of the property and shall be allowed to the life tenant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>