<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/198" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/198/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/198/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_198"><akn:num>198</akn:num><akn:heading>Expensing of environmental remediation costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 198. Expensing of environmental remediation costs(a) In generalA taxpayer may elect to treat any qualified environmental remediation expenditure which is paid or incurred by the taxpayer as an expense which is not chargeable to capital account. Any expenditure which is so treated shall be allowed as a deduction for the taxable year in which it is paid or incurred.


(b) Qualified environmental remediation expenditureFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “qualified environmental remediation expenditure” means any expenditure—(A) which is otherwise chargeable to capital account, and

(B) which is paid or incurred in connection with the abatement or control of hazardous substances at a qualified contaminated site.


(2) Special rule for expenditures for depreciable propertySuch term shall not include any expenditure for the acquisition of property of a character subject to the allowance for depreciation which is used in connection with the abatement or control of hazardous substances at a qualified contaminated site; except that the portion of the allowance under section 167 for such property which is otherwise allocated to such site shall be treated as a qualified environmental remediation expenditure.



(c) Qualified contaminated siteFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “qualified contaminated site” means any area—(A) which is held by the taxpayer for use in a trade or business or for the production of income, or which is property described in section 1221(a)(1) in the hands of the taxpayer, and

(B) at or on which there has been a release (or threat of release) or disposal of any hazardous substance.


(2) National priorities listed sites not includedSuch term shall not include any site which is on, or proposed for, the national priorities list under section 105(a)(8)(B) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this section).


(3) Taxpayer must </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_198_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A taxpayer may elect to treat any qualified environmental remediation expenditure which is paid or incurred by the taxpayer as an expense which is not chargeable to capital account. Any expenditure which is so treated shall be allowed as a deduction for the taxable year in which it is paid or incurred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_198_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified environmental remediation expenditure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified environmental remediation expenditure For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_198_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified contaminated site</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualified contaminated site For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_198_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous substance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hazardous substance For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_198_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction recaptured as ordinary income on sale, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deduction recaptured as ordinary income on sale, etc. Solely for purposes of section 1245, in the case of property to which a qualified environmental remediation expenditure would have been capitalized but for this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_198_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with other provisions Sections 280B and 468 shall not apply to amounts which are treated as expenses under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_198_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_198_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Termination This section shall not apply to expenditures paid or incurred after December 31, 2011.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>