<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2013" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2013/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2013/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2013"><akn:num>2013</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for tax on prior transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2013. Credit for tax on prior transfers(a) General ruleThe tax imposed by section 2001 shall be credited with all or a part of the amount of the Federal estate tax paid with respect to the transfer of property (including property passing as a result of the exercise or non-exercise of a power of appointment) to the decedent by or from a person (herein designated as a “transferor”) who died within 10 years before, or within 2 years after, the decedent’s death. If the transferor died within 2 years of the death of the decedent, the credit shall be the amount determined under subsections (b) and (c). If the transferor predeceased the decedent by more than 2 years, the credit shall be the following percentage of the amount so determined—(1) 80 percent, if within the third or fourth years preceding the decedent’s death;

(2) 60 percent, if within the fifth or sixth years preceding the decedent’s death;

(3) 40 percent, if within the seventh or eighth years preceding the decedent’s death; and

(4) 20 percent, if within the ninth or tenth years preceding the decedent’s death.


(b) Computation of creditSubject to the limitation prescribed in subsection (c), the credit provided by this section shall be an amount which bears the same ratio to the estate tax paid (adjusted as indicated hereinafter) with respect to the estate of the transferor as the value of the property transferred bears to the taxable estate of the transferor (determined for purposes of the estate tax) decreased by any death taxes paid with respect to such estate. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the estate tax paid shall be the Federal estate tax paid increased by any credits allowed against such estate tax under section 2012, or corresponding provisions of prior laws, on account of gift tax, and for any credits allowed against such estate tax under this section on account of prior transfers where the transferor acquired property from a person who died within 10 years before the death of the decede</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2013_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule The tax imposed by section 2001 shall be credited with all or a part of the amount of the Federal estate tax paid with respect to the transfer of property (including property passing as a result of the exercise or non-exercise of a power of appointment) to the decedent by or from a person (herein designated as a “transferor”) who died within 10 years before, or within 2 years after, the decedent’s death. If the transferor died within 2 years of the death of the decedent, the credit shall be the amount determined under subsections (b) and (c). If the transferor predeceased the decedent by more than 2 years, the credit shall be the following percentage of the amount so determined—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2013_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Computation of credit Subject to the limitation prescribed in subsection (c), the credit provided by this section shall be an amount which bears the same ratio to the estate tax paid (adjusted as indicated hereinafter) with respect to the estate of the transferor as the value of the property transferred bears to the taxable estate of the transferor (determined for purposes of the estate tax) decreased by any death taxes paid with respect to such estate. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the estate tax paid shall be the Federal estate tax paid increased by any credits allowed against such estate tax under section 2012, or corresponding provisions of prior laws, on account of gift tax, and for any credits allowed against such estate tax under this section on account of prior transfers where the transferor acquired property from a person who died within 10 years before the death of the decedent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2013_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2013_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation of property transferred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Valuation of property transferred The value of property transferred to the decedent shall be the value used for the purpose of determining the Federal estate tax liability of the estate of the transferor but—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2013_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Property defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Property defined For purposes of this section, the term “property” includes any beneficial interest in property, including a general power of appointment (as defined in section 2041).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2013_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of additional tax imposed under section 2032A</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of additional tax imposed under section 2032A If section 2032A applies to any property included in the gross estate of the transferor and an additional tax is imposed with respect to such property under section 2032A(c) before the date which is 2 years after the date of the decedent’s death, for purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>