<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2032A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2032A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2032A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2032A"><akn:num>2032A</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation of certain farm, etc., real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2032A. Valuation of certain farm, etc., real property(a) Value based on use under which property qualifies(1) General ruleIf—(A) the decedent was (at the time of his death) a citizen or resident of the United States, and

(B) the executor elects the application of this section and files the agreement referred to in subsection (d)(2),


then, for purposes of this chapter, the value of qualified real property shall be its value for the use under which it qualifies, under subsection (b), as qualified real property.

(2) Limitation on aggregate reduction in fair market valueThe aggregate decrease in the value of qualified real property taken into account for purposes of this chapter which results from the application of paragraph (1) with respect to any decedent shall not exceed $750,000.


(3) Inflation adjustmentIn the case of estates of decedents dying in a calendar year after 1998, the $750,000 amount contained in paragraph (2) shall be increased by an amount equal to—(A) $750,000, multiplied by

(B) the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting “calendar year 1997” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.


If any amount as adjusted under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $10,000, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $10,000.


(b) Qualified real property(1) In generalFor purposes of this section, the term “qualified real property” means real property located in the United States which was acquired from or passed from the decedent to a qualified heir of the decedent and which, on the date of the decedent’s death, was being used for a qualified use by the decedent or a member of the decedent’s family, but only if—(A) 50 percent or more of the adjusted value of the gross estate consists of the adjusted value of real or personal property which—(i) on the date of the decedent’s death, was being used for a qualified use by the decedent or a member of the decedent’</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value based on use under which property qualifies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Value based on use under which property qualifies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified real property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of dispositions and failures to use for qualified use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tax treatment of dispositions and failures to use for qualified use</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election; agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Election; agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions; special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions; special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statute of limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Statute of limitations If qualified real property is disposed of or ceases to be used for a qualified use, then—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of this section and section 6324B to interests in partnerships, corporations, and trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application of this section and section 6324B to interests in partnerships, corporations, and trusts The Secretary shall prescribe regulations setting forth the application of this section and section 6324B in the case of an interest in a partnership, corporation, or trust which, with respect to the decedent, is an interest in a closely held business (within the meaning of paragraph (1) of section 6166(b)). For purposes of the preceding sentence, an interest in a discretionary trust all the beneficiaries of which are qualified heirs shall be treated as a present interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032A_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for involuntary conversions of qualified real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rules for involuntary conversions of qualified real property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2032A_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchanges of qualified real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Exchanges of qualified real property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>