<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2104"><akn:num>2104</akn:num><akn:heading>Property within the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2104. Property within the United States(a) Stock in corporationFor purposes of this subchapter shares of stock owned and held by a nonresident not a citizen of the United States shall be deemed property within the United States only if issued by a domestic corporation.


(b) Revocable transfers and transfers within 3 years of deathFor purposes of this subchapter, any property of which the decedent has made a transfer, by trust or otherwise, within the meaning of sections 2035 to 2038, inclusive, shall be deemed to be situated in the United States, if so situated either at the time of the transfer or at the time of the decedent’s death.


(c) Debt obligationsFor purposes of this subchapter, debt obligations of—(1) a United States person, or

(2) the United States, a State or any political subdivision thereof, or the District of Columbia,


owned and held by a nonresident not a citizen of the United States shall be deemed property within the United States. Deposits with a domestic branch of a foreign corporation, if such branch is engaged in the commercial banking business, shall, for purposes of this subchapter, be deemed property within the United States. This subsection shall not apply to a debt obligation to which section 2105(b) applies.

(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 397; Pub. L. 89–809, title I, § 108(c), Nov. 13, 1966, 80 Stat. 1572; Pub. L. 91–172, title IV, § 435(b), Dec. 30, 1969, 83 Stat. 625; Pub. L. 93–17, § 3(a)(1), Apr. 10, 1973, 87 Stat. 12; Pub. L. 93–625, § 9(b), Jan. 3, 1975, 88 Stat. 2116; Pub. L. 94–455, title XX, § 2001(c)(1)(L), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1853; Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1012(q)(11), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3525; Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1704(t)(38), Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1889; Pub. L. 111–226, title II, § 217(c)(3), Aug. 10, 2010, 124 Stat. 2402; Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(98), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 4051.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2014—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 113–295 substituted “Deposits” for “Wi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stock in corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Stock in corporation For purposes of this subchapter shares of stock owned and held by a nonresident not a citizen of the United States shall be deemed property within the United States only if issued by a domestic corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocable transfers and transfers within 3 years of death</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Revocable transfers and transfers within 3 years of death For purposes of this subchapter, any property of which the decedent has made a transfer, by trust or otherwise, within the meaning of sections 2035 to 2038, inclusive, shall be deemed to be situated in the United States, if so situated either at the time of the transfer or at the time of the decedent’s death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Debt obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Debt obligations For purposes of this subchapter, debt obligations of— owned and held by a nonresident not a citizen of the United States shall be deemed property within the United States. Deposits with a domestic branch of a foreign corporation, if such branch is engaged in the commercial banking business, shall, for purposes of this subchapter, be deemed property within the United States. This subsection shall not apply to a debt obligation to which section 2105(b) applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>