<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2105"><akn:num>2105</akn:num><akn:heading>Property without the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2105. Property without the United States(a) Proceeds of life insuranceFor purposes of this subchapter, the amount receivable as insurance on the life of a nonresident not a citizen of the United States shall not be deemed property within the United States.


(b) Bank deposits and certain other debt obligationsFor purposes of this subchapter, the following shall not be deemed property within the United States—(1) amounts described in section 871(i)(3), if any interest thereon would not be subject to tax by reason of section 871(i)(1) were such interest received by the decedent at the time of his death,

(2) deposits with a foreign branch of a domestic corporation or domestic partnership, if such branch is engaged in the commercial banking business,

(3) debt obligations, if, without regard to whether a statement meeting the requirements of section 871(h)(5) has been received, any interest thereon would be eligible for the exemption from tax under section 871(h)(1) were such interest received by the decedent at the time of his death, and

(4) obligations which would be original issue discount obligations as defined in section 871(g)(1) but for subparagraph (B)(i) thereof, if any interest thereon (were such interest received by the decedent at the time of his death) would not be effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.


Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, if any portion of the interest on an obligation referred to in paragraph (3) would not be eligible for the exemption referred to in paragraph (3) by reason of section 871(h)(4) if the interest were received by the decedent at the time of his death, then an appropriate portion (as determined in a manner prescribed by the Secretary) of the value (as determined for purposes of this chapter) of such debt obligation shall be deemed property within the United States.

(c) Works of art on loan for exhibitionFor purposes of this subchapter, works of art owned by a nonresid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeds of life insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proceeds of life insurance For purposes of this subchapter, the amount receivable as insurance on the life of a nonresident not a citizen of the United States shall not be deemed property within the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bank deposits and certain other debt obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Bank deposits and certain other debt obligations For purposes of this subchapter, the following shall not be deemed property within the United States— Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, if any portion of the interest on an obligation referred to in paragraph (3) would not be eligible for the exemption referred to in paragraph (3) by reason of section 871(h)(4) if the interest were received by the decedent at the time of his death, then an appropriate portion (as determined in a manner prescribed by the Secretary) of the value (as determined for purposes of this chapter) of such debt obligation shall be deemed property within the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Works of art on loan for exhibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Works of art on loan for exhibition For purposes of this subchapter, works of art owned by a nonresident not a citizen of the United States shall not be deemed property within the United States if such works of art are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2105_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stock in a RIC</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Stock in a RIC</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>