<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/217" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/217/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/217/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_217"><akn:num>217</akn:num><akn:heading>Moving expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 217. Moving expenses(a) Deduction allowedThere shall be allowed as a deduction moving expenses paid or incurred during the taxable year in connection with the commencement of work by the taxpayer as an employee or as a self-employed individual at a new principal place of work.


(b) Definition of moving expenses(1) In generalFor purposes of this section, the term “moving expenses” means only the reasonable expenses—(A) of moving household goods and personal effects from the former residence to the new residence, and

(B) of traveling (including lodging) from the former residence to the new place of residence.


Such term shall not include any expenses for meals.

(2) Individuals other than taxpayerIn the case of any individual other than the taxpayer, expenses referred to in paragraph (1) shall be taken into account only if such individual has both the former residence and the new residence as his principal place of abode and is a member of the taxpayer’s household.



(c) Conditions for allowanceNo deduction shall be allowed under this section unless—(1) the taxpayer’s new principal place of work—(A) is at least 50 miles farther from his former residence than was his former principal place of work, or

(B) if he had no former principal place of work, is at least 50 miles from his former residence, and


(2) either—(A) during the 12-month period immediately following his arrival in the general location of his new principal place of work, the taxpayer is a full-time employee, in such general location, during at least 39 weeks, or

(B) during the 24-month period immediately following his arrival in the general location of his new principal place of work, the taxpayer is a full-time employee or performs services as a self-employed individual on a full-time basis, in such general location, during at least 78 weeks, of which not less than 39 weeks are during the 12-month period referred to in subparagraph (A).


For purposes of paragraph (1), the distance between two p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction allowed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deduction allowed There shall be allowed as a deduction moving expenses paid or incurred during the taxable year in connection with the commencement of work by the taxpayer as an employee or as a self-employed individual at a new principal place of work.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of moving expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definition of moving expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for allowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Conditions for allowance No deduction shall be allowed under this section unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules for application of subsection (c)(2)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rules for application of subsection (c)(2)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13213(a)(2)(A), Aug. 10, 1993, 107 Stat. 473]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-employed individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Self-employed individual For purposes of this section, the term “self-employed individual” means an individual who performs personal services—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules for members of the Armed Forces of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rules for members of the Armed Forces of the United States In the case of a member of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty who moves pursuant to a military order and incident to a permanent change of station—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for foreign moves</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rules for foreign moves</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of deductions in case of retirees or decedents who were working abroad</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Allowance of deductions in case of retirees or decedents who were working abroad</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_217_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>