<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2207A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2207A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2207A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2207A"><akn:num>2207A</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of recovery in the case of certain marital deduction property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2207A. Right of recovery in the case of certain marital deduction property(a) Recovery with respect to estate tax(1) In generalIf any part of the gross estate consists of property the value of which is includible in the gross estate by reason of section 2044 (relating to certain property for which marital deduction was previously allowed), the decedent’s estate shall be entitled to recover from the person receiving the property the amount by which—(A) the total tax under this chapter which has been paid, exceeds

(B) the total tax under this chapter which would have been payable if the value of such property had not been included in the gross estate.


(2) Decedent may otherwise directParagraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any property to the extent that the decedent in his will (or a revocable trust) specifically indicates an intent to waive any right of recovery under this subchapter with respect to such property.



(b) Recovery with respect to gift taxIf for any calendar year tax is paid under chapter 12 with respect to any person by reason of property treated as transferred by such person under section 2519, such person shall be entitled to recover from the person receiving the property the amount by which—(1) the total tax for such year under chapter 12, exceeds

(2) the total tax which would have been payable under such chapter for such year if the value of such property had not been taken into account for purposes of chapter 12.


(c) More than one recipient of propertyFor purposes of this section, if there is more than one person receiving the property, the right of recovery shall be against each such person.


(d) Taxes and interestIn the case of penalties and interest attributable to additional taxes described in subsections (a) and (b), rules similar to subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall apply.


(Added Pub. L. 97–34, title IV, § 403(d)(4)(A), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 304; amended Pub. L. 105–34, title XIII, § 1302(a), Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 10</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery with respect to estate tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recovery with respect to estate tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery with respect to gift tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recovery with respect to gift tax If for any calendar year tax is paid under chapter 12 with respect to any person by reason of property treated as transferred by such person under section 2519, such person shall be entitled to recover from the person receiving the property the amount by which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>More than one recipient of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) More than one recipient of property For purposes of this section, if there is more than one person receiving the property, the right of recovery shall be against each such person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2207A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxes and interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Taxes and interest In the case of penalties and interest attributable to additional taxes described in subsections (a) and (b), rules similar to subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>