<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/23" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/23/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/23/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_23"><akn:num>23</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 23. Adoption expenses(a) Allowance of credit(1) In generalIn the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter the amount of the qualified adoption expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer.


(2) Year credit allowedThe credit under paragraph (1) with respect to any expense shall be allowed—(A) in the case of any expense paid or incurred before the taxable year in which such adoption becomes final, for the taxable year following the taxable year during which such expense is paid or incurred, and

(B) in the case of an expense paid or incurred during or after the taxable year in which such adoption becomes final, for the taxable year in which such expense is paid or incurred.


(3) $10,000 credit for adoption of child with special needs regardless of expensesIn the case of an adoption of a child with special needs which becomes final during a taxable year, the taxpayer shall be treated as having paid during such year qualified adoption expenses with respect to such adoption in an amount equal to the excess (if any) of $10,000 over the aggregate qualified adoption expenses actually paid or incurred by the taxpayer with respect to such adoption during such taxable year and all prior taxable years.


(4) Portion of credit refundableSo much of the credit allowed under paragraph (1) as does not exceed $5,000 shall be treated as a credit allowed under subpart C and not as a credit allowed under this subpart.



(b) Limitations(1) Dollar limitationThe aggregate amount of qualified adoption expenses which may be taken into account under subsection (a) for all taxable years with respect to the adoption of a child by the taxpayer shall not exceed $10,000.


(2) Income limitation(A) In generalThe amount allowable as a credit under subsection (a) for any taxable year (determined without regard to subsection (c)) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount so allowable (determine</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryforwards of unused credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Carryforwards of unused credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for foreign adoptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for foreign adoptions In the case of an adoption of a child who is not a citizen or resident of the United States (as defined in section 217(h)(3))—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Filing requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Basis adjustments For purposes of this subtitle, if a credit is allowed under this section for any expenditure with respect to any property, the increase in the basis of such property which would (but for this subsection) result from such expenditure shall be reduced by the amount of the credit so allowed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments for inflation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Adjustments for inflation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_23_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be appropriate to carry out this section and section 137, including regulations which treat unmarried individuals who pay or incur qualified adoption expenses with respect to the same child as 1 taxpayer for purposes of applying the dollar amounts in subsections (a)(3) and (b)(1) of this section and in section 137(b)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>