<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/245A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/245A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/245A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_245A"><akn:num>245A</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction for foreign source-portion of dividends received by domestic corporations from specified 1</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 245A. Deduction for foreign source-portion of dividends received by domestic corporations from specified 10-percent owned foreign corporations(a) In generalIn the case of any dividend received from a specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation by a domestic corporation which is a United States shareholder with respect to such foreign corporation, there shall be allowed as a deduction an amount equal to the foreign-source portion of such dividend.


(b) Specified 10-percent owned foreign corporationFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation” means any foreign corporation with respect to which any domestic corporation is a United States shareholder with respect to such corporation.


(2) Exclusion of passive foreign investment companiesSuch term shall not include any corporation which is a passive foreign investment company (as defined in section 1297) with respect to the shareholder and which is not a controlled foreign corporation.



(c) Foreign-source portionFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe foreign-source portion of any dividend from a specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation is an amount which bears the same ratio to such dividend as—(A) the undistributed foreign earnings of the specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation, bears to

(B) the total undistributed earnings of such foreign corporation.


(2) Undistributed earningsThe term “undistributed earnings” means the amount of the earnings and profits of the specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation (computed in accordance with sections 964(a) and 986)—(A) as of the close of the taxable year of the specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation in which the dividend is distributed, and

(B) without diminution by reason of dividends distributed during such taxable year.


(3) Undistributed foreign earningsThe term “undistributed foreign earnings” means the portion of the undistributed earnings which is attributable to neithe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of any dividend received from a specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation by a domestic corporation which is a United States shareholder with respect to such foreign corporation, there shall be allowed as a deduction an amount equal to the foreign-source portion of such dividend.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Specified 10-percent owned foreign corporation For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign-source portion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Foreign-source portion For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowance of foreign tax credit, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disallowance of foreign tax credit, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for hybrid dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for hybrid dividends</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for purging distributions of passive foreign investment companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rule for purging distributions of passive foreign investment companies Any amount which is treated as a dividend under section 1291(d)(2)(B) shall not be treated as a dividend for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this section, including regulations for the treatment of United States shareholders owning stock of a specified 10 percent 11 So in original. Probably should be “10-percent”. owned foreign corporation through a partnership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>