<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/246" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/246/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/246/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_246"><akn:num>246</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules applying to deductions for dividends received</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 246. Rules applying to deductions for dividends received(a) Deduction not allowed for dividends from certain corporations(1) In generalThe deductions allowed by sections 243 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. 245, and 245A shall not apply to any dividend from a corporation which, for the taxable year of the corporation in which the distribution is made, or for the next preceding taxable year of the corporation, is a corporation exempt from tax under section 501 (relating to certain charitable, etc., organizations) or section 521 (relating to farmers’ cooperative associations).


(2) Subsection not to apply to certain dividends of Federal Home Loan Banks(A) Dividends out of current earnings and profitsIn the case of any dividend paid by any FHLB out of earnings and profits of the FHLB for the taxable year in which such dividend was paid, paragraph (1) shall not apply to that portion of such dividend which bears the same ratio to the total dividend as—(i) the dividends received by the FHLB from the FHLMC during such taxable year, bears to

(ii) the total earnings and profits of the FHLB for such taxable year.


(B) Dividends out of accumulated earnings and profitsIn the case of any dividend which is paid out of any accumulated earnings and profits of any FHLB, paragraph (1) shall not apply to that portion of the dividend which bears the same ratio to the total dividend as—(i) the amount of dividends received by such FHLB from the FHLMC which are out of earnings and profits of the FHLMC—(I) for taxable years ending after December 31, 1984, and

(II) which were not previously treated as distributed under subparagraph (A) or this subparagraph, bears to


(ii) the total accumulated earnings and profits of the FHLB as of the time such dividend is paid.


For purposes of clause (ii), the accumulated earnings and profits of the FHLB as of January 1, 1985, shall be treated as equal to its retained earnings as of such date.

(C) Coordination with sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction not allowed for dividends from certain corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deduction not allowed for dividends from certain corporations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on aggregate amount of deductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on aggregate amount of deductions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of certain dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusion of certain dividends</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dividends from a DISC or former DISC</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Dividends from a DISC or former DISC No deduction shall be allowed under section 243 in respect of a dividend from a corporation which is a DISC or former DISC (as defined in section 992(a)) to the extent such dividend is paid out of the corporation’s accumulated DISC income or previously taxed income, or is a deemed distribution pursuant to section 995(b)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>