<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/246A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/246A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/246A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_246A"><akn:num>246A</akn:num><akn:heading>Dividends received deduction reduced where portfolio stock is debt financed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 246A. Dividends received deduction reduced where portfolio stock is debt financed(a) General ruleIn the case of any dividend on debt-financed portfolio stock, there shall be substituted for the percentage which (but for this subsection) would be used in determining the amount of the deduction allowable under section 243 or 245(a) a percentage equal to the product of—(1) 50 percent (65 percent in the case of any dividend from a 20-percent owned corporation as defined in section 243(c)(2)), and

(2) 100 percent minus the average indebtedness percentage.


(b) Section not to apply to dividends for which 100 percent dividends received deduction allowableSubsection (a) shall not apply to—(1) qualifying dividends (as defined in section 243(b)), and

(2) dividends received by a small business investment company operating under the Small Business Investment Act of 1958.


(c) Debt financed portfolio stockFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “debt financed portfolio stock” means any portfolio stock if at some time during the base period there is portfolio indebtedness with respect to such stock.


(2) Portfolio stockThe term “portfolio stock” means any stock of a corporation unless—(A) as of the beginning of the ex-dividend date, the taxpayer owns stock of such corporation—(i) possessing at least 50 percent of the total voting power of the stock of such corporation, and

(ii) having a value equal to at least 50 percent of the total value of the stock of such corporation, or


(B) as of the beginning of the ex-dividend date—(i) the taxpayer owns stock of such corporation which would meet the requirements of subparagraph (A) if “20 percent” were substituted for “50 percent” each place it appears in such subparagraph, and

(ii) stock meeting the requirements of subparagraph (A) is owned by 5 or fewer corporate shareholders.



(3) Special rule for stock in a bank or bank holding company(A) In generalIf, as of the beginning of the ex-dividend date, the taxpayer </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of any dividend on debt-financed portfolio stock, there shall be substituted for the percentage which (but for this subsection) would be used in determining the amount of the deduction allowable under section 243 or 245(a) a percentage equal to the product of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section not to apply to dividends for which 100 percent dividends received deduction allowable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Section not to apply to dividends for which 100 percent dividends received deduction allowable Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Debt financed portfolio stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Debt financed portfolio stock For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Average indebtedness percentage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Average indebtedness percentage For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction in dividends received deduction not to exceed allocable interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reduction in dividends received deduction not to exceed allocable interest Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, any reduction under this section in the amount allowable as a deduction under section 243 or 245 with respect to any dividend shall not exceed the amount of any interest deduction (including any deductible short sale expense) allocable to such dividend.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_246A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The regulations prescribed for purposes of this section under section 7701(f) shall include regulations providing for the disallowance of interest deductions or other appropriate treatment (in lieu of reducing the dividend received deduction) where the obligor of the indebtedness is a person other than the person receiving the dividend.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>