<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/247" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/247/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/247/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247"><akn:num>247</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions to Alaska Native Settlement Trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247. Contributions to Alaska Native Settlement Trusts(a) In generalIn the case of a Native Corporation, there shall be allowed a deduction for any contributions made by such Native Corporation to a Settlement Trust (regardless of whether an election under section 646 is in effect for such Settlement Trust) for which the Native Corporation has made an annual election under subsection (e).


(b) Amount of deductionThe amount of the deduction under subsection (a) shall be equal to—(1) in the case of a cash contribution (regardless of the method of payment, including currency, coins, money order, or check), the amount of such contribution, or

(2) in the case of a contribution not described in paragraph (1), the lesser of—(A) the Native Corporation’s adjusted basis in the property contributed, or

(B) the fair market value of the property contributed.



(c) Limitation and carryover(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the deduction allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year shall not exceed the taxable income (as determined without regard to such deduction) of the Native Corporation for the taxable year in which the contribution was made.


(2) CarryoverIf the aggregate amount of contributions described in subsection (a) for any taxable year exceeds the limitation under paragraph (1), such excess shall be treated as a contribution described in subsection (a) in each of the 15 succeeding years in order of time.



(d) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the terms “Native Corporation” and “Settlement Trust” have the same meaning given such terms under section 646(h).


(e) Manner of making election(1) In generalFor each taxable year, a Native Corporation may elect to have this section apply for such taxable year on the income tax return or an amendment or supplement to the return of the Native Corporation, with such election to have effect solely for such taxable year.


(2) RevocationAny election made by a Native Corporation pursuant to this subsection m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of a Native Corporation, there shall be allowed a deduction for any contributions made by such Native Corporation to a Settlement Trust (regardless of whether an election under section 646 is in effect for such Settlement Trust) for which the Native Corporation has made an annual election under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of deduction The amount of the deduction under subsection (a) shall be equal to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation and carryover</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation and carryover</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section, the terms “Native Corporation” and “Settlement Trust” have the same meaning given such terms under section 646(h).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of making election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Manner of making election</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election by Settlement Trust to defer income recognition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Election by Settlement Trust to defer income recognition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>