<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2503"><akn:num>2503</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable gifts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2503. Taxable gifts(a) General definitionThe term “taxable gifts” means the total amount of gifts made during the calendar year, less the deductions provided in subchapter C (section 2522 and following).


(b) Exclusions from gifts(1) In generalIn the case of gifts (other than gifts of future interests in property) made to any person by the donor during the calendar year, the first $10,000 of such gifts to such person shall not, for purposes of subsection (a), be included in the total amount of gifts made during such year. Where there has been a transfer to any person of a present interest in property, the possibility that such interest may be diminished by the exercise of a power shall be disregarded in applying this subsection, if no part of such interest will at any time pass to any other person.


(2) Inflation adjustmentIn the case of gifts made in a calendar year after 1998, the $10,000 amount contained in paragraph (1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—(A) $10,000, multiplied by

(B) the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting “calendar year 1997” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.


If any amount as adjusted under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $1,000, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $1,000.


(c) Transfer for the benefit of minorNo part of a gift to an individual who has not attained the age of 21 years on the date of such transfer shall be considered a gift of a future interest in property for purposes of subsection (b) if the property and the income therefrom—(1) may be expended by, or for the benefit of, the donee before his attaining the age of 21 years, and

(2) will to the extent not so expended—(A) pass to the donee on his attaining the age of 21 years, and

(B) in the event the donee dies before attaining the age of 21 years, be payable to the estate of the donee or as he may appoint under a general power of appointment </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General definition The term “taxable gifts” means the total amount of gifts made during the calendar year, less the deductions provided in subchapter C (section 2522 and following).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions from gifts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exclusions from gifts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer for the benefit of minor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer for the benefit of minor No part of a gift to an individual who has not attained the age of 21 years on the date of such transfer shall be considered a gift of a future interest in property for purposes of subsection (b) if the property and the income therefrom—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 97–34, title III, § 311(h)(5), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 282]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion for certain transfers for educational expenses or medical expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusion for certain transfers for educational expenses or medical expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of certain pension rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Waiver of certain pension rights If any individual waives, before the death of a participant, any survivor benefit, or right to such benefit, under section 401(a)(11) or 417, such waiver shall not be treated as a transfer of property by gift for purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2503_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain loans of artworks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Treatment of certain loans of artworks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>