<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2523" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2523/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2523/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2523"><akn:num>2523</akn:num><akn:heading>Gift to spouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2523. Gift to spouse(a) Allowance of deductionWhere a donor transfers during the calendar year by gift an interest in property to a donee who at the time of the gift is the donor’s spouse, there shall be allowed as a deduction in computing taxable gifts for the calendar year an amount with respect to such interest equal to its value.


(b) Life estate or other terminable interestWhere, on the lapse of time, on the occurrence of an event or contingency, or on the failure of an event or contingency to occur, such interest transferred to the spouse will terminate or fail, no deduction shall be allowed with respect to such interest—(1) if the donor retains in himself, or transfers or has transferred (for less than an adequate and full consideration in money or money’s worth) to any person other than such donee spouse (or the estate of such spouse), an interest in such property, and if by reason of such retention or transfer the donor (or his heirs or assigns) or such person (or his heirs or assigns) may possess or enjoy any part of such property after such termination or failure of the interest transferred to the donee spouse; or

(2) if the donor immediately after the transfer to the donee spouse has a power to appoint an interest in such property which he can exercise (either alone or in conjunction with any person) in such manner that the appointee may possess or enjoy any part of such property after such termination or failure of the interest transferred to the donee spouse. For purposes of this paragraph, the donor shall be considered as having immediately after the transfer to the donee spouse such power to appoint even though such power cannot be exercised until after the lapse of time, upon the occurrence of an event or contingency, or on the failure of an event or contingency to occur.


An exercise or release at any time by the donor, either alone or in conjunction with any person, of a power to appoint an interest in property, even though not otherwise a tr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of deduction Where a donor transfers during the calendar year by gift an interest in property to a donee who at the time of the gift is the donor’s spouse, there shall be allowed as a deduction in computing taxable gifts for the calendar year an amount with respect to such interest equal to its value.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life estate or other terminable interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Life estate or other terminable interest Where, on the lapse of time, on the occurrence of an event or contingency, or on the failure of an event or contingency to occur, such interest transferred to the spouse will terminate or fail, no deduction shall be allowed with respect to such interest— An exercise or release at any time by the donor, either alone or in conjunction with any person, of a power to appoint an interest in property, even though not otherwise a transfer, shall, for purposes of paragraph (1), be considered as a transfer by him. Except as provided in subsection (e), where at the time of the transfer it is impossible to ascertain the particular person or persons who may receive from the donor an interest in property so transferred by him, such interest shall, for purposes of paragraph (1), be considered as transferred to a person other than the donee spouse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest in unidentified assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interest in unidentified assets Where the assets out of which, or the proceeds of which, the interest transferred to the donee spouse may be satisfied include a particular asset or assets with respect to which no deduction would be allowed if such asset or assets were transferred from the donor to such spouse, then the value of the interest transferred to such spouse shall, for purposes of subsection (a), be reduced by the aggregate value of such particular assets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Joint interests If the interest is transferred to the donee spouse as sole joint tenant with the donor or as tenant by the entirety, the interest of the donor in the property which exists solely by reason of the possibility that the donor may survive the donee spouse, or that there may occur a severance of the tenancy, shall not be considered for purposes of subsection (b) as an interest retained by the donor in himself.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life estate with power of appointment in donee spouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Life estate with power of appointment in donee spouse Where the donor transfers an interest in property, if by such transfer his spouse is entitled for life to all of the income from the entire interest, or all the income from a specific portion thereof, payable annually or at more frequent intervals, with power in the donee spouse to appoint the entire interest, or such specific portion (exercisable in favor of such donee spouse, or of the estate of such donee spouse, or in favor of either, whether or not in each case the power is exercisable in favor of others), and with no power in any other person to appoint any part of such interest, or such portion, to any person other than the donee spouse— This subsection shall apply only if, by such transfer, such power in the donee spouse to appoint the interest, or such portion, whether exercisable by will or during life, is exercisable by such spouse alone and in all events. For purposes of this subsection, the term “specific portion” o</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election with respect to life estate for donee spouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Election with respect to life estate for donee spouse</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for charitable remainder trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rule for charitable remainder trusts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of double deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Denial of double deduction Nothing in this section or any other provision of this chapter shall allow the value of any interest in property to be deducted under this chapter more than once with respect to the same donor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowance of marital deduction where spouse not citizen</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Disallowance of marital deduction where spouse not citizen If the spouse of the donor is not a citizen of the United States— This subsection shall not apply to any transfer resulting from the acquisition of rights under a joint and survivor annuity described in subsection (f)(6).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>