<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/25A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/25A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/25A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_25A"><akn:num>25A</akn:num><akn:heading>American Opportunity and Lifetime Learning credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 25A. American Opportunity and Lifetime Learning credits(a) Allowance of creditIn the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year the amount equal to the sum of—(1) the American Opportunity Tax Credit, plus

(2) the Lifetime Learning Credit.


(b) American Opportunity Tax Credit(1) Per student creditIn the case of any eligible student for whom an election is in effect under this section for any taxable year, the American Opportunity Tax Credit is an amount equal to the sum of—(A) 100 percent of so much of the qualified tuition and related expenses paid by the taxpayer during the taxable year (for education furnished to the eligible student during any academic period beginning in such taxable year) as does not exceed $2,000, plus

(B) 25 percent of such expenses so paid as exceeds $2,000 but does not exceed $4,000.


(2) Limitations applicable to American Opportunity Tax Credit(A) Credit allowed only for 4 taxable yearsAn election to have this section apply with respect to any eligible student for purposes of the American Opportunity Tax Credit under subsection (a)(1) may not be made for any taxable year if such an election (by the taxpayer or any other individual) is in effect with respect to such student for any 4 prior taxable years.


(B) Credit allowed for year only if individual is at least ½ time student for portion of yearThe American Opportunity Tax Credit under subsection (a)(1) shall not be allowed for a taxable year with respect to the qualified tuition and related expenses of an individual unless such individual is an eligible student for at least one academic period which begins during such year.


(C) Credit allowed only for first 4 years of postsecondary educationThe American Opportunity Tax Credit under subsection (a)(1) shall not be allowed for a taxable year with respect to the qualified tuition and related expenses of an eligible student if the student has completed (befor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of credit In the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year the amount equal to the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>American Opportunity Tax Credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) American Opportunity Tax Credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lifetime Learning Credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Lifetime Learning Credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations based on modified adjusted gross income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations based on modified adjusted gross income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election not to have section apply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Election not to have section apply A taxpayer may elect not to have this section apply with respect to the qualified tuition and related expenses of an individual for any taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 116–260, div. EE, title I, § 104(a)(2), Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 3041]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(h) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Portion of American Opportunity Tax Credit made refundable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Portion of American Opportunity Tax Credit made refundable Forty percent of so much of the credit allowed under subsection (a) as is attributable to the American Opportunity Tax Credit (determined after application of subsection (d) and without regard to this paragraph 22 So in original. Probably should be “this subsection”. and section 26(a)) shall be treated as a credit allowable under subpart C (and not allowed under subsection (a)). The preceding sentence shall not apply to any taxpayer for any taxable year if such taxpayer is a child to whom subsection (g) of section 1 applies for such taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25A_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations The Secretary may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out this section, including regulations providing for a recapture of the credit allowed under this section in cases where there is a refund in a subsequent taxable year of any amount which was taken into account in determining the amount of such credit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>