<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2613" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2613/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2613/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2613"><akn:num>2613</akn:num><akn:heading>Skip person and non-skip person defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2613. Skip person and non-skip person defined(a) Skip personFor purposes of this chapter, the term “skip person” means—(1) a natural person assigned to a generation which is 2 or more generations below the generation assignment of the transferor, or

(2) a trust—(A) if all interests in such trust are held by skip persons, or

(B) if—(i) there is no person holding an interest in such trust, and

(ii) at no time after such transfer may a distribution (including distributions on termination) be made from such trust to a nonskip person.




(b) Non-skip personFor purposes of this chapter, the term “non-skip person” means any person who is not a skip person.


(Added Pub. L. 94–455, title XX, § 2006(a), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1884; amended Pub. L. 95–600, title VII, § 702(n)(2), (3), Nov. 6, 1978, 92 Stat. 2935, 2936; Pub. L. 96–222, title I, § 107(a)(2)(B), Apr. 1, 1980, 94 Stat. 222; Pub. L. 99–514, title XIV, § 1431(a), Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2720; Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1014(g)(5)(A), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3564.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1988—Subsec. (a)(1). Pub. L. 100–647 inserted “natural” before “person”.
1986—Pub. L. 99–514 amended section generally, substituting definitions of “skip person” and “non-skip person” for former provisions which defined and applied the terms “taxable distribution”, “taxable termination”, “younger generation beneficiary”, and “related or subordinate trustee”.
1980—Subsec. (e)(2)(A)(i). Pub. L. 96–222, § 107(a)(2)(B)(i), inserted “(other than as a potential appointee under a power of appointment held by another)” after “trust”.
Subsec. (e)(2)(B). Pub. L. 96–222, § 107(a)(2)(B)(ii), redesignated cls. (iii) to (v) as (iv) to (vi), added cl. (iii), and struck out cl. (vi) which related to an employee of a corporation in which the grantor or any beneficiary of the trust is an executive.
1978—Subsec. (b)(2)(B). Pub. L. 95–600, § 702(n)(3), substituted “a present interest and a present power” for “an interest and a power” and “</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Skip person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Skip person For purposes of this chapter, the term “skip person” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-skip person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Non-skip person For purposes of this chapter, the term “non-skip person” means any person who is not a skip person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>