<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/263" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/263/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/263/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_263"><akn:num>263</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 263. Capital expenditures(a) General ruleNo deduction shall be allowed for—(1) Any amount paid out for new buildings or for permanent improvements or betterments made to increase the value of any property or estate. This paragraph shall not apply to—(A) expenditures for the development of mines or deposits deductible under section 616,

(B) research and experimental expenditures deductible under section 174 or 174A,

(C) soil and water conservation expenditures deductible under section 175,

(D) expenditures by farmers for fertilizer, etc., deductible under section 180,

(E) expenditures for removal of architectural and transportation barriers to the handicapped and elderly which the taxpayer elects to deduct under section 190,

(F) expenditures for tertiary injectants with respect to which a deduction is allowed under section 193,

(G) expenditures for which a deduction is allowed under section 179,

(H) expenditures for which a deduction is allowed under section 179B,

(I) expenditures for which a deduction is allowed under section 179C,

(J) expenditures for which a deduction is allowed under section 179D, or

(K) expenditures for which a deduction is allowed under section 179E.


(2) Any amount expended in restoring property or in making good the exhaustion thereof for which an allowance is or has been made.


[(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11801(a)(16), Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1388–520]

(c) Intangible drilling and development costs in the case of oil and gas wells and geothermal wellsNotwithstanding subsection (a), and except as provided in subsection (i), regulations shall be prescribed by the Secretary under this subtitle corresponding to the regulations which granted the option to deduct as expenses intangible drilling and development costs in the case of oil and gas wells and which were recognized and approved by the Congress in House Concurrent Resolution 50, Seventy-ninth Congress. Such regulations shall also grant the option to deduct as </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule No deduction shall be allowed for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11801(a)(16), Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1388–520]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intangible drilling and development costs in the case of oil and gas wells and geothermal wells</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Intangible drilling and development costs in the case of oil and gas wells and geothermal wells Notwithstanding subsection (a), and except as provided in subsection (i), regulations shall be prescribed by the Secretary under this subtitle corresponding to the regulations which granted the option to deduct as expenses intangible drilling and development costs in the case of oil and gas wells and which were recognized and approved by the Congress in House Concurrent Resolution 50, Seventy-ninth Congress. Such regulations shall also grant the option to deduct as expenses intangible drilling and development costs in the case of wells drilled for any geothermal deposit (as defined in section 613(e)(2)) to the same extent and in the same manner as such expenses are deductible in the case of oil and gas wells. This subsection shall not apply with respect to any costs to which any deduction is allowed under section 59(e) or 291.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures in connection with certain railroad rolling stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expenditures in connection with certain railroad rolling stock In the case of expenditures in connection with the rehabilitation of a unit of railroad rolling stock (except a locomotive) used by a domestic common carrier by railroad which would, but for this subsection, be properly chargeable to capital account, such expenditures, if during any 12-month period they do not exceed an amount equal to 20 percent of the basis of such unit in the hands of the taxpayer, shall, at the election of the taxpayer, be treated (notwithstanding subsection (a)) as deductible repairs under section 162 or 212. An election under this subsection shall be made for any taxable year at such time and in such manner as the Secretary prescribes by regulations. An election may not be made under this subsection for any taxable year to which an election under subsection (e) applies to railroad rolling stock (other than locomotives).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 97–34, title II, § 201(c), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 219]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Railroad ties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Railroad ties In the case of a domestic common carrier by rail (including a railroad switching or terminal company) which uses the retirement-replacement method of accounting for depreciation of its railroad track, expenditures for acquiring and installing replacement ties of any material (and fastenings related to such ties) shall be accorded the same tax accounting treatment as expenditures for replacement ties of wood (and fastenings related to such ties).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain interest and carrying costs in the case of straddles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certain interest and carrying costs in the case of straddles</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments in lieu of dividends in connection with short sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Payments in lieu of dividends in connection with short sales</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for intangible drilling and development costs incurred outside the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Special rules for intangible drilling and development costs incurred outside the United States In the case of intangible drilling and development costs paid or incurred with respect to an oil, gas, or geothermal well located outside the United States— This subsection shall not apply to costs paid or incurred with respect to a nonproductive well.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>