<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2631"><akn:num>2631</akn:num><akn:heading>GST exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2631. GST exemption(a) General ruleFor purposes of determining the inclusion ratio, every individual shall be allowed a GST exemption amount which may be allocated by such individual (or his executor) to any property with respect to which such individual is the transferor.


(b) Allocations irrevocableAny allocation under subsection (a), once made, shall be irrevocable.


(c) GST exemption amountFor purposes of subsection (a), the GST exemption amount for any calendar year shall be equal to the basic exclusion amount under section 2010(c) for such calendar year.


(Added Pub. L. 99–514, title XIV, § 1431(a), Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2721; amended Pub. L. 105–34, title V, § 501(d), Aug. 5, 1997, 111 Stat. 846; Pub. L. 105–206, title VI, § 6007(a)(1), July 22, 1998, 112 Stat. 806; Pub. L. 107–16, title V, § 521(c), June 7, 2001, 115 Stat. 72; Pub. L. 111–312, title III, § 303(b)(2), Dec. 17, 2010, 124 Stat. 3303.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2010—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 111–312 substituted “the basic exclusion amount” for “the applicable exclusion amount”.
2001—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 107–16, § 521(c)(1), substituted “amount” for “of $1,000,000”.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 107–16, § 521(c)(2), amended heading and text of subsec. (c) generally, substituting provisions relating to the GST exemption amount for any calendar year for provisions which related to inflation adjustment of the $1,000,000 amount contained in subsec. (a) in the case of any calendar year after 1998 and applicability of any increase for any such calendar year.
1998—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 105–206 reenacted heading without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “In the case of an individual who dies in any calendar year after 1998, the $1,000,000 amount contained in subsection (a) shall be increased by an amount equal to—
“(1) $1,000,000, multiplied by
“(2) the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting ‘calendar year 199</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule For purposes of determining the inclusion ratio, every individual shall be allowed a GST exemption amount which may be allocated by such individual (or his executor) to any property with respect to which such individual is the transferor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations irrevocable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocations irrevocable Any allocation under subsection (a), once made, shall be irrevocable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>GST exemption amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) GST exemption amount For purposes of subsection (a), the GST exemption amount for any calendar year shall be equal to the basic exclusion amount under section 2010(c) for such calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>