<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/264" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/264/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/264/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_264"><akn:num>264</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain amounts paid in connection with insurance contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 264. Certain amounts paid in connection with insurance contracts(a) General ruleNo deduction shall be allowed for—(1) Premiums on any life insurance policy, or endowment or annuity contract, if the taxpayer is directly or indirectly a beneficiary under the policy or contract.

(2) Any amount paid or accrued on indebtedness incurred or continued to purchase or carry a single premium life insurance, endowment, or annuity contract.

(3) Except as provided in subsection (d), any amount paid or accrued on indebtedness incurred or continued to purchase or carry a life insurance, endowment, or annuity contract (other than a single premium contract or a contract treated as a single premium contract) pursuant to a plan of purchase which contemplates the systematic direct or indirect borrowing of part or all of the increases in the cash value of such contract (either from the insurer or otherwise).

(4) Except as provided in subsection (e), any interest paid or accrued on any indebtedness with respect to 1 or more life insurance policies owned by the taxpayer covering the life of any individual, or any endowment or annuity contracts owned by the taxpayer covering any individual.


Paragraph (2) shall apply in respect of annuity contracts only as to contracts purchased after March 1, 1954. Paragraph (3) shall apply only in respect of contracts purchased after August 6, 1963. Paragraph (4) shall apply with respect to contracts purchased after June 20, 1986.

(b) Exceptions to subsection (a)(1)Subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to—(1) any annuity contract described in section 72(s)(5), and

(2) any annuity contract to which section 72(u) applies.


(c) Contracts treated as single premium contractsFor purposes of subsection (a)(2), a contract shall be treated as a single premium contract—(1) if substantially all the premiums on the contract are paid within a period of 4 years from the date on which the contract is purchased, or

(2) if an amount is deposited after March 1, 1954,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_264_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule No deduction shall be allowed for— Paragraph (2) shall apply in respect of annuity contracts only as to contracts purchased after March 1, 1954. Paragraph (3) shall apply only in respect of contracts purchased after August 6, 1963. Paragraph (4) shall apply with respect to contracts purchased after June 20, 1986.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_264_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions to subsection (a)(1)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions to subsection (a)(1) Subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_264_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts treated as single premium contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contracts treated as single premium contracts For purposes of subsection (a)(2), a contract shall be treated as a single premium contract—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_264_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exceptions Subsection (a)(3) shall not apply to any amount paid or accrued by a person during a taxable year on indebtedness incurred or continued as part of a plan referred to in subsection (a)(3)— For purposes of applying paragraph (1), if there is a substantial increase in the premiums on a contract, a new 7-year period described in such paragraph with respect to such contract shall commence on the date the first such increased premium is paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_264_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for application of subsection (a)(4)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for application of subsection (a)(4)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_264_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pro rata allocation of interest expense to policy cash values</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Pro rata allocation of interest expense to policy cash values</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>