<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2642" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2642/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/2642/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2642"><akn:num>2642</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion ratio</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2642. Inclusion ratio(a) Inclusion ratio definedFor purposes of this chapter—(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this section, the inclusion ratio with respect to any property transferred in a generation-skipping transfer shall be the excess (if any) of 1 over—(A) except as provided in subparagraph (B), the applicable fraction determined for the trust from which such transfer is made, or

(B) in the case of a direct skip, the applicable fraction determined for such skip.


(2) Applicable fractionFor purposes of paragraph (1), the applicable fraction is a fraction—(A) the numerator of which is the amount of the GST exemption allocated to the trust (or in the case of a direct skip, allocated to the property transferred in such skip), and

(B) the denominator of which is—(i) the value of the property transferred to the trust (or involved in the direct skip), reduced by

(ii) the sum of—(I) any Federal estate tax or State death tax actually recovered from the trust attributable to such property, and

(II) any charitable deduction allowed under section 2055 or 2522 with respect to such property.




(3) Severing of trusts(A) In generalIf a trust is severed in a qualified severance, the trusts resulting from such severance shall be treated as separate trusts thereafter for purposes of this chapter.


(B) Qualified severanceFor purposes of subparagraph (A)—(i) In generalThe term “qualified severance” means the division of a single trust and the creation (by any means available under the governing instrument or under local law) of two or more trusts if—(I) the single trust was divided on a fractional basis, and

(II) the terms of the new trusts, in the aggregate, provide for the same succession of interests of beneficiaries as are provided in the original trust.


(ii) Trusts with inclusion ratio greater than zeroIf a trust has an inclusion ratio of greater than zero and less than 1, a severance is a qualified severance only if the single trust is divided into t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion ratio defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Inclusion ratio defined For purposes of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation rules, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Valuation rules, etc. Except as provided in subsection (f)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain direct skips which are nontaxable gifts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of certain direct skips which are nontaxable gifts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules where more than 1 transfer made to trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules where more than 1 transfer made to trust</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for charitable lead annuity trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for charitable lead annuity trusts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for certain inter vivos transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rules for certain inter vivos transfers Except as provided in regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relief provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Relief provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>