<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/267" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/267/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/267/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_267"><akn:num>267</akn:num><akn:heading>Losses, expenses, and interest with respect to transactions between related taxpayers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 267. Losses, expenses, and interest with respect to transactions between related taxpayers(a) In general(1) Deduction for losses disallowedNo deduction shall be allowed in respect of any loss from the sale or exchange of property, directly or indirectly, between persons specified in any of the paragraphs of subsection (b). The preceding sentence shall not apply to any loss of the distributing corporation (or the distributee) in the case of a distribution in complete liquidation.


(2) Matching of deduction and payee income item in the case of expenses and interestIf—(A) by reason of the method of accounting of the person to whom the payment is to be made, the amount thereof is not (unless paid) includible in the gross income of such person, and

(B) at the close of the taxable year of the taxpayer for which (but for this paragraph) the amount would be deductible under this chapter, both the taxpayer and the person to whom the payment is to be made are persons specified in any of the paragraphs of subsection (b),


then any deduction allowable under this chapter in respect of such amount shall be allowable as of the day as of which such amount is includible in the gross income of the person to whom the payment is made (or, if later, as of the day on which it would be so allowable but for this paragraph). For purposes of this paragraph, in the case of a personal service corporation (within the meaning of section 441(i)(2)), such corporation and any employee-owner (within the meaning of section 269A(b)(2), as modified by section 441(i)(2)) shall be treated as persons specified in subsection (b).

(3) Payments to foreign persons(A) In generalThe Secretary shall by regulations apply the matching principle of paragraph (2) in cases in which the person to whom the payment is to be made is not a United States person.


(B) Special rule for certain foreign entities(i) In generalNotwithstanding subparagraph (A), in the case of any item payable to a controlled foreign corpor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_267_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_267_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relationships The persons referred to in subsection (a) are:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_267_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Constructive ownership of stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Constructive ownership of stock For purposes of determining, in applying subsection (b), the ownership of stock—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_267_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of gain where loss previously disallowed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of gain where loss previously disallowed</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_267_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for pass-thru entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for pass-thru entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_267_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Controlled group defined; special rules applicable to controlled groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Controlled group defined; special rules applicable to controlled groups</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_267_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with section 1041</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coordination with section 1041 Subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to any transfer described in section 1041(a) (relating to transfers of property between spouses or incident to divorce).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>