<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/274" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/274/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/274/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_274"><akn:num>274</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowance of certain entertainment, etc., expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 274. Disallowance of certain entertainment, etc., expenses(a) Entertainment, amusement, recreation, or qualified transportation fringes(1) In generalNo deduction otherwise allowable under this chapter shall be allowed for any item—(A) ActivityWith respect to an activity which is of a type generally considered to constitute entertainment, amusement, or recreation, or


(B) FacilityWith respect to a facility used in connection with an activity referred to in subparagraph (A).



(2) Special rulesFor purposes of applying paragraph (1)—(A) Dues or fees to any social, athletic, or sporting club or organization shall be treated as items with respect to facilities.

(B) An activity described in section 212 shall be treated as a trade or business.


(3) Denial of deduction for club duesNotwithstanding the preceding provisions of this subsection, no deduction shall be allowed under this chapter for amounts paid or incurred for membership in any club organized for business, pleasure, recreation, or other social purpose.


(4) Qualified transportation fringesNo deduction shall be allowed under this chapter for the expense of any qualified transportation fringe (as defined in section 132(f)) provided to an employee of the taxpayer.



(b) Gifts(1) LimitationNo deduction shall be allowed under section 162 or section 212 for any expense for gifts made directly or indirectly to any individual to the extent that such expense, when added to prior expenses of the taxpayer for gifts made to such individual during the same taxable year, exceeds $25. For purposes of this section, the term “gift” means any item excludable from gross income of the recipient under section 102 which is not excludable from his gross income under any other provision of this chapter, but such term does not include—(A) an item having a cost to the taxpayer not in excess of $4.00 on which the name of the taxpayer is clearly and permanently imprinted and which is one of a number of identical items distributed g</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entertainment, amusement, recreation, or qualified transportation fringes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Entertainment, amusement, recreation, or qualified transportation fringes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gifts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Gifts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain foreign travel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certain foreign travel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantiation required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Substantiation required No deduction or credit shall be allowed— unless the taxpayer substantiates by adequate records or by sufficient evidence corroborating the taxpayer’s own statement (A) the amount of such expense or other item, (B) the time and place of the travel or the date and description of the gift, (C) the business purpose of the expense or other item, and (D) the business relationship to the taxpayer of the person receiving the benefit. The Secretary may by regulations provide that some or all of the requirements of the preceding sentence shall not apply in the case of an expense which does not exceed an amount prescribed pursuant to such regulations. This subsection shall not apply to any qualified nonpersonal use vehicle (as defined in subsection (i)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specific exceptions to application of subsection (a)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Specific exceptions to application of subsection (a) Subsection (a) shall not apply to— For purposes of this subsection, any item referred to in subsection (a) shall be treated as an expense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest, taxes, casualty losses, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Interest, taxes, casualty losses, etc. This section shall not apply to any deduction allowable to the taxpayer without regard to its connection with his trade or business (or with his income-producing activity). In the case of a taxpayer which is not an individual, the preceding sentence shall be applied as if it were an individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of entertainment, etc., type facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Treatment of entertainment, etc., type facility For purposes of this chapter, if deductions are disallowed under subsection (a) with respect to any portion of a facility, such portion shall be treated as an asset which is used for personal, living, and family purposes (and not as an asset used in the trade or business).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attendance at conventions, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Attendance at conventions, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified nonpersonal use vehicle</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Qualified nonpersonal use vehicle For purposes of subsection (d), the term “qualified nonpersonal use vehicle” means any vehicle which, by reason of its nature, is not likely to be used more than a de minimis amount for personal purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee achievement awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Employee achievement awards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>