<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/280A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/280A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/280A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280A"><akn:num>280A</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowance of certain expenses in connection with business use of home, rental of vacation homes, </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280A. Disallowance of certain expenses in connection with business use of home, rental of vacation homes, etc.(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in this section, in the case of a taxpayer who is an individual or an S corporation, no deduction otherwise allowable under this chapter shall be allowed with respect to the use of a dwelling unit which is used by the taxpayer during the taxable year as a residence.


(b) Exception for interest, taxes, casualty losses, etc.Subsection (a) shall not apply to any deduction allowable to the taxpayer without regard to its connection with his trade or business (or with his income-producing activity).


(c) Exceptions for certain business or rental use; limitation on deductions for such use(1) Certain business useSubsection (a) shall not apply to any item to the extent such item is allocable to a portion of the dwelling unit which is exclusively used on a regular basis—(A) as the principal place of business for any trade or business of the taxpayer,

(B) as a place of business which is used by patients, clients, or customers in meeting or dealing with the taxpayer in the normal course of his trade or business, or

(C) in the case of a separate structure which is not attached to the dwelling unit, in connection with the taxpayer’s trade or business.


In the case of an employee, the preceding sentence shall apply only if the exclusive use referred to in the preceding sentence is for the convenience of his employer. For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “principal place of business” includes a place of business which is used by the taxpayer for the administrative or management activities of any trade or business of the taxpayer if there is no other fixed location of such trade or business where the taxpayer conducts substantial administrative or management activities of such trade or business.

(2) Certain storage useSubsection (a) shall not apply to any item to the extent such item is allocable to space within the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided in this section, in the case of a taxpayer who is an individual or an S corporation, no deduction otherwise allowable under this chapter shall be allowed with respect to the use of a dwelling unit which is used by the taxpayer during the taxable year as a residence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for interest, taxes, casualty losses, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception for interest, taxes, casualty losses, etc. Subsection (a) shall not apply to any deduction allowable to the taxpayer without regard to its connection with his trade or business (or with his income-producing activity).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions for certain business or rental use; limitation on deductions for such use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions for certain business or rental use; limitation on deductions for such use</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use as residence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use as residence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses attributable to rental</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Expenses attributable to rental</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions and special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for certain rental use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rule for certain rental use Notwithstanding any other provision of this section or section 183, if a dwelling unit is used during the taxable year by the taxpayer as a residence and such dwelling unit is actually rented for less than 15 days during the taxable year, then—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>