<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/280C" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/280C/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/280C/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280C"><akn:num>280C</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain expenses for which credits are allowable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280C. Certain expenses for which credits are allowable(a) Rule for employment creditsNo deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the wages or salaries paid or incurred for the taxable year which is equal to the sum of the credits determined for the taxable year under sections 45A(a), 45P(a), 45S(a)(1)(A), 51(a), and 1396(a). No deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the premiums paid or incurred for the taxable year which is equal to that portion of the paid family and medical leave credit which is determined for the taxable year under section 45S(a)(1)(B). In the case of a corporation which is a member of a controlled group of corporations (within the meaning of section 52(a)) or a trade or business which is treated as being under common control with other trades or businesses (within the meaning of section 52(b)), this subsection shall be applied under rules prescribed by the Secretary similar to the rules applicable under subsections (a) and (b) of section 52.


(b) Credit for qualified clinical testing expenses for certain drugs(1) In generalNo deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the qualified clinical testing expenses (as defined in section 45C(b)) otherwise allowable as a deduction for the taxable year which is equal to the amount of the credit allowable for the taxable year under section 45C (determined without regard to section 38(c)).


(2) Similar rule where taxpayer capitalizes rather than deducts expensesIf—(A) the amount of the credit allowable for the taxable year under section 45C (determined without regard to section 38(c)), exceeds

(B) the amount allowable as a deduction for the taxable year for qualified clinical testing expenses (determined without regard to paragraph (1)),


the amount chargeable to capital account for the taxable year for such expenses shall be reduced by the amount of such excess.

(3) Election of reduced credit(A) In generalIn the case of any taxable year for which an election is made under this par</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280C_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule for employment credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rule for employment credits No deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the wages or salaries paid or incurred for the taxable year which is equal to the sum of the credits determined for the taxable year under sections 45A(a), 45P(a), 45S(a)(1)(A), 51(a), and 1396(a). No deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the premiums paid or incurred for the taxable year which is equal to that portion of the paid family and medical leave credit which is determined for the taxable year under section 45S(a)(1)(B). In the case of a corporation which is a member of a controlled group of corporations (within the meaning of section 52(a)) or a trade or business which is treated as being under common control with other trades or businesses (within the meaning of section 52(b)), this subsection shall be applied under rules prescribed by the Secretary similar to the rules applicable under subsections (a) and (b) of section 52.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280C_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for qualified clinical testing expenses for certain drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Credit for qualified clinical testing expenses for certain drugs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280C_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for increasing research activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Credit for increasing research activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280C_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for low sulfur diesel fuel production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Credit for low sulfur diesel fuel production The deductions otherwise allowed under this chapter for the taxable year shall be reduced by the amount of the credit determined for the taxable year under section 45H(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280C_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mine rescue team training credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Mine rescue team training credit No deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the expenses otherwise allowable as a deduction for the taxable year which is equal to the amount of the credit determined for the taxable year under section 45N(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280C_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for security of agricultural chemicals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Credit for security of agricultural chemicals No deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the expenses otherwise allowable as a deduction taken into account in determining the credit under section 45O for the taxable year which is equal to the amount of the credit determined for such taxable year under section 45O(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280C_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for health insurance premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Credit for health insurance premiums No deduction shall be allowed for the portion of the premiums paid by the taxpayer for coverage of 1 or more individuals under a qualified health plan which is equal to the amount of the credit determined for the taxable year under section 36B(a) with respect to such premiums.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280C_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for employee health insurance expenses of small employers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Credit for employee health insurance expenses of small employers No deduction shall be allowed for that portion of the premiums for qualified health plans (as defined in section 1301(a) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act), or for health insurance coverage in the case of taxable years beginning in 2010, 2011, 2012, or 2013, paid by an employer which is equal to the amount of the credit determined under section 45R(a) with respect to the premiums.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>