<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/280F" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/280F/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/280F/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280F"><akn:num>280F</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on depreciation for luxury automobiles; limitation where certain property used for person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280F. Limitation on depreciation for luxury automobiles; limitation where certain property used for personal purposes(a) Limitation on amount of depreciation for luxury automobiles(1) Depreciation(A) LimitationThe amount of the depreciation deduction for any taxable year for any passenger automobile shall not exceed—(i) $10,000 for the 1st taxable year in the recovery period,

(ii) $16,000 for the 2nd taxable year in the recovery period,

(iii) $9,600 for the 3rd taxable year in the recovery period, and

(iv) $5,760 for each succeeding taxable year in the recovery period.


(B) Disallowed deductions allowed for years after recovery period(i) In generalExcept as provided in clause (ii), the unrecovered basis of any passenger automobile shall be treated as an expense for the 1st taxable year after the recovery period. Any excess of the unrecovered basis over the limitation of clause (ii) shall be treated as an expense in the succeeding taxable year.


(ii) $5,760 limitationThe amount treated as an expense under clause (i) for any taxable year shall not exceed $5,760.


(iii) Property must be depreciableNo amount shall be allowable as a deduction by reason of this subparagraph with respect to any property for any taxable year unless a depreciation deduction would be allowable with respect to such property for such taxable year.


(iv) Amount treated as depreciation deductionFor purposes of this subtitle, any amount allowable as a deduction by reason of this subparagraph shall be treated as a depreciation deduction allowable under section 168.




(2) Coordination with reductions in amount allowable by reason of personal use, etc.This subsection shall be applied before—(A) the application of subsection (b), and

(B) the application of any other reduction in the amount of any depreciation deduction allowable under section 168 by reason of any use not qualifying the property for such credit or depreciation deduction.



(b) Limitation where business use of listed proper</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280F_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on amount of depreciation for luxury automobiles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitation on amount of depreciation for luxury automobiles</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280F_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation where business use of listed property not greater than 50 percent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation where business use of listed property not greater than 50 percent</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280F_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of leases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of leases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280F_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280F_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations with respect to items properly included in, or excluded from, the adjusted basis of any listed property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>