<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/291" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/291/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/291/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_291"><akn:num>291</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules relating to corporate preference items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 291. Special rules relating to corporate preference items(a) Reduction in certain preference items, etc.For purposes of this subtitle, in the case of a corporation—(1) Section 1250 capital gain treatmentIn the case of section 1250 property which is disposed of during the taxable year, 20 percent of the excess (if any) of—(A) the amount which would be treated as ordinary income if such property was section 1245 property, over

(B) the amount treated as ordinary income under section 1250 (determined without regard to this paragraph),


shall be treated as gain which is ordinary income under section 1250 and shall be recognized notwithstanding any other provision of this title. Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the provisions of this paragraph shall not apply to the disposition of any property to the extent section 1250(a) does not apply to such disposition by reason of section 1250(d).

(2) Reduction in percentage depletionIn the case of iron ore and coal (including lignite), the amount allowable as a deduction under section 613 with respect to any property (as defined in section 614) shall be reduced by 20 percent of the amount of the excess (if any) of—(A) the amount of the deduction allowable under section 613 for the taxable year (determined without regard to this paragraph), over

(B) the adjusted basis of the property at the close of the taxable year (determined without regard to the depletion deduction for the taxable year).


(3) Certain financial institution preference itemsThe amount allowable as a deduction under this chapter (determined without regard to this section) with respect to any financial institution preference item shall be reduced by 20 percent.


(4) Amortization of pollution control facilitiesIf an election is made under section 169 with respect to any certified pollution control facility, the amortizable basis of such facility for purposes of such section shall be reduced by 20 percent.



(b) Special rules for treatment of int</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction in certain preference items, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reduction in certain preference items, etc. For purposes of this subtitle, in the case of a corporation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for treatment of intangible drilling costs and mineral exploration and development costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rules for treatment of intangible drilling costs and mineral exploration and development costs For purposes of this subtitle, in the case of a corporation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules relating to pollution control facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules relating to pollution control facilities For purposes of this subtitle—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for real estate investment trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rule for real estate investment trusts In the case of a real estate investment trust (as defined in section 856), the difference between the amounts described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1) shall be reduced to the extent that a capital gain dividend (as defined in section 857(b)(3)(C),11 See References in Text note below. applied without regard to this section) is treated as paid out of such difference. Any capital gain dividend treated as having been paid out of such difference to a shareholder which is an applicable corporation retains its character in the hands of the shareholder as gain from the disposition of section 1250 property for purposes of applying subsection (a)(1) to such shareholder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>