<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_302"><akn:num>302</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions in redemption of stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 302. Distributions in redemption of stock(a) General ruleIf a corporation redeems its stock (within the meaning of section 317(b)), and if paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), or (5) of subsection (b) applies, such redemption shall be treated as a distribution in part or full payment in exchange for the stock.


(b) Redemptions treated as exchanges(1) Redemptions not equivalent to dividendsSubsection (a) shall apply if the redemption is not essentially equivalent to a dividend.


(2) Substantially disproportionate redemption of stock(A) In generalSubsection (a) shall apply if the distribution is substantially disproportionate with respect to the shareholder.


(B) LimitationThis paragraph shall not apply unless immediately after the redemption the shareholder owns less than 50 percent of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock entitled to vote.


(C) DefinitionsFor purposes of this paragraph, the distribution is substantially disproportionate if—(i) the ratio which the voting stock of the corporation owned by the shareholder immediately after the redemption bears to all of the voting stock of the corporation at such time,


is less than 80 percent of—
(ii) the ratio which the voting stock of the corporation owned by the shareholder immediately before the redemption bears to all of the voting stock of the corporation at such time.


For purposes of this paragraph, no distribution shall be treated as substantially disproportionate unless the shareholder’s ownership of the common stock of the corporation (whether voting or nonvoting) after and before redemption also meets the 80 percent requirement of the preceding sentence. For purposes of the preceding sentence, if there is more than one class of common stock, the determinations shall be made by reference to fair market value.

(D) Series of redemptionsThis paragraph shall not apply to any redemption made pursuant to a plan the purpose or effect of which is a series of redemptions resulting in a distributi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule If a corporation redeems its stock (within the meaning of section 317(b)), and if paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), or (5) of subsection (b) applies, such redemption shall be treated as a distribution in part or full payment in exchange for the stock.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redemptions treated as exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Redemptions treated as exchanges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Constructive ownership of stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Constructive ownership of stock</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redemptions treated as distributions of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Redemptions treated as distributions of property Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, if a corporation redeems its stock (within the meaning of section 317(b)), and if subsection (a) of this section does not apply, such redemption shall be treated as a distribution of property to which section 301 applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partial liquidation defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Partial liquidation defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cross references For special rules relating to redemption—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>