<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_304"><akn:num>304</akn:num><akn:heading>Redemption through use of related corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 304. Redemption through use of related corporations(a) Treatment of certain stock purchases(1) Acquisition by related corporation (other than subsidiary)For purposes of sections 302 and 303, if—(A) one or more persons are in control of each of two corporations, and

(B) in return for property, one of the corporations acquires stock in the other corporation from the person (or persons) so in control,


then (unless paragraph (2) applies) such property shall be treated as a distribution in redemption of the stock of the corporation acquiring such stock. To the extent that such distribution is treated as a distribution to which section 301 applies, the transferor and the acquiring corporation shall be treated in the same manner as if the transferor had transferred the stock so acquired to the acquiring corporation in exchange for stock of the acquiring corporation in a transaction to which section 351(a) applies, and then the acquiring corporation had redeemed the stock it was treated as issuing in such transaction.

(2) Acquisition by subsidiaryFor purposes of sections 302 and 303, if—(A) in return for property, one corporation acquires from a shareholder of another corporation stock in such other corporation, and

(B) the issuing corporation controls the acquiring corporation,


then such property shall be treated as a distribution in redemption of the stock of the issuing corporation.


(b) Special rules for application of subsection (a)(1) Rules for determinations under section 302(b)In the case of any acquisition of stock to which subsection (a) of this section applies, determinations as to whether the acquisition is, by reason of section 302(b), to be treated as a distribution in part or full payment in exchange for the stock shall be made by reference to the stock of the issuing corporation. In applying section 318(a) (relating to constructive ownership of stock) with respect to section 302(b) for purposes of this paragraph, sections 318(a)(2)(C) and 318(a)(3)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain stock purchases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Treatment of certain stock purchases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for application of subsection (a)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rules for application of subsection (a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Control</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>