<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/30B" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/30B/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/30B/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30B"><akn:num>30B</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative motor vehicle credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30B. Alternative motor vehicle credit(a) Allowance of creditThere shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to the sum of—(1) the new qualified fuel cell motor vehicle credit determined under subsection (b),

(2) the new advanced lean burn technology motor vehicle credit determined under subsection (c),

(3) the new qualified hybrid motor vehicle credit determined under subsection (d),

(4) the new qualified alternative fuel motor vehicle credit determined under subsection (e), and

(5) the plug-in conversion credit determined under subsection (i).


(b) New qualified fuel cell motor vehicle credit(1) In generalFor purposes of subsection (a), the new qualified fuel cell motor vehicle credit determined under this subsection with respect to a new qualified fuel cell motor vehicle placed in service by the taxpayer during the taxable year is—(A) $8,000 ($4,000 in the case of a vehicle placed in service after December 31, 2009), if such vehicle has a gross vehicle weight rating of not more than 8,500 pounds,

(B) $10,000, if such vehicle has a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 8,500 pounds but not more than 14,000 pounds,

(C) $20,000, if such vehicle has a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 14,000 pounds but not more than 26,000 pounds, and

(D) $40,000, if such vehicle has a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 26,000 pounds.


(2) Increase for fuel efficiency(A) In generalThe amount determined under paragraph (1)(A) with respect to a new qualified fuel cell motor vehicle which is a passenger automobile or light truck shall be increased by—(i) $1,000, if such vehicle achieves at least 150 percent but less than 175 percent of the 2002 model year city fuel economy,

(ii) $1,500, if such vehicle achieves at least 175 percent but less than 200 percent of the 2002 model year city fuel economy,

(iii) $2,000, if such vehicle achieves at least 200 percent but less than 225 percent of the 2002 m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of credit There shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>New qualified fuel cell motor vehicle credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) New qualified fuel cell motor vehicle credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>New advanced lean burn technology motor vehicle credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) New advanced lean burn technology motor vehicle credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>New qualified hybrid motor vehicle credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) New qualified hybrid motor vehicle credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>New qualified alternative fuel motor vehicle credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) New qualified alternative fuel motor vehicle credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on number of new qualified hybrid and advanced lean-burn technology vehicles eligible for credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on number of new qualified hybrid and advanced lean-burn technology vehicles eligible for credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application with other credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application with other credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Other definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 117–169, title I, § 13401(i)(2)(B), Aug. 16, 2022, 136 Stat. 1961]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30B_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>