<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/312" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/312/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/312/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_312"><akn:num>312</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on earnings and profits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 312. Effect on earnings and profits(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in this section, on the distribution of property by a corporation with respect to its stock, the earnings and profits of the corporation (to the extent thereof) shall be decreased by the sum of—(1) the amount of money,

(2) the principal amount of the obligations of such corporation (or, in the case of obligations having original issue discount, the aggregate issue price of such obligations), and

(3) the adjusted basis of the other property, so distributed.


(b) Distributions of appreciated propertyOn the distribution by a corporation, with respect to its stock, of any property (other than an obligation of such corporation) the fair market value of which exceeds the adjusted basis thereof—(1) the earnings and profits of the corporation shall be increased by the amount of such excess, and

(2) subsection (a)(3) shall be applied by substituting “fair market value” for “adjusted basis”.


For purposes of this subsection and subsection (a), the adjusted basis of any property is its adjusted basis as determined for purposes of computing earnings and profits.

(c) Adjustments for liabilitiesIn making the adjustments to the earnings and profits of a corporation under subsection (a) or (b), proper adjustment shall be made for—(1) the amount of any liability to which the property distributed is subject, and

(2) the amount of any liability of the corporation assumed by a shareholder in connection with the distribution.


(d) Certain distributions of stock and securities(1) In generalThe distribution to a distributee by or on behalf of a corporation of its stock or securities, of stock or securities in another corporation, or of property, in a distribution to which this title applies, shall not be considered a distribution of the earnings and profits of any corporation—(A) if no gain to such distributee from the receipt of such stock or securities, or property, was recognized under this title,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided in this section, on the distribution of property by a corporation with respect to its stock, the earnings and profits of the corporation (to the extent thereof) shall be decreased by the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions of appreciated property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Distributions of appreciated property On the distribution by a corporation, with respect to its stock, of any property (other than an obligation of such corporation) the fair market value of which exceeds the adjusted basis thereof— For purposes of this subsection and subsection (a), the adjusted basis of any property is its adjusted basis as determined for purposes of computing earnings and profits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments for liabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adjustments for liabilities In making the adjustments to the earnings and profits of a corporation under subsection (a) or (b), proper adjustment shall be made for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain distributions of stock and securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certain distributions of stock and securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 61(a)(2)(B), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 581]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on earnings and profits of gain or loss and of receipt of tax-free distributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect on earnings and profits of gain or loss and of receipt of tax-free distributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Earnings and profits—increase in value accrued before March 1, 1913</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Earnings and profits—increase in value accrued before</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation in certain corporate separations and reorganizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Allocation in certain corporate separations and reorganizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of proceeds of loan insured by the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Distribution of proceeds of loan insured by the United States If a corporation distributes property with respect to its stock and if, at the time of distribution— then the earnings and profits of the corporation shall be increased by the amount of such excess, and (immediately after the distribution) shall be decreased by the amount of such excess. For purposes of paragraph (2), the adjusted basis of the property at the time of distribution shall be determined without regard to any adjustment under section 1016(a)(2) (relating to adjustment for depreciation, etc.). For purposes of this subsection, a commitment to make, guarantee, or insure a loan shall be treated as the making, guaranteeing, or insuring of a loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 108–357, title IV, § 413(c)(4), Oct. 22, 2004, 118 Stat. 1507]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(j) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>