<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3132" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3132/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3132/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3132"><akn:num>3132</akn:num><akn:heading>Payroll credit for paid family leave</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3132. Payroll credit for paid family leave(a) In generalIn the case of an employer, there shall be allowed as a credit against applicable employment taxes for each calendar quarter an amount equal to 100 percent of the qualified family leave wages paid by such employer with respect to such calendar quarter.


(b) Limitations and refundability(1) Wages taken into accountThe amount of qualified family leave wages taken into account under subsection (a), plus any increases under subsection (e), with respect to any individual shall not exceed—(A) for any day (or portion thereof) for which the individual is paid qualified family leave wages, $200, and

(B) in the aggregate with respect to all calendar quarters, $12,000.


(2) Credit limited to certain employment taxesThe credit allowed by subsection (a) with respect to any calendar quarter shall not exceed the applicable employment taxes for such calendar quarter (reduced by any credits allowed under section 3131) on the wages paid with respect to the employment of all employees of the employer.


(3) Refundability of excess credit(A) Credit is refundableIf the amount of the credit under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation of paragraph (2) for any calendar quarter, such excess shall be treated as an overpayment that shall be refunded under sections 6402(a) and 6413(b).


(B) Advancing creditIn anticipation of the credit, including the refundable portion under subparagraph (A), the credit shall be advanced, according to forms and instructions provided by the Secretary, up to an amount calculated under subsection (a), subject to the limits under paragraph (1) and (2), all calculated through the end of the most recent payroll period in the quarter.




(c) Qualified family leave wages(1) In generalFor purposes of this section, the term “qualified family leave wages” means wages paid by an employer which would be required to be paid by reason of the Emergency Family and Medical Leave Expansion Act (including the amendmen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of an employer, there shall be allowed as a credit against applicable employment taxes for each calendar quarter an amount equal to 100 percent of the qualified family leave wages paid by such employer with respect to such calendar quarter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations and refundability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations and refundability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified family leave wages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualified family leave wages</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of credit for certain health plan expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allowance of credit for certain health plan expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of credit for amounts paid under certain collectively bargained agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allowance of credit for amounts paid under certain collectively bargained agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions and special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Application of section This section shall apply only to wages paid with respect to the period beginning on April 1, 2021, and ending on September 30, 2021.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Treatment of deposits The Secretary shall waive any penalty under section 6656 for any failure to make a deposit of applicable employment taxes if the Secretary determines that such failure was due to the anticipation of the credit allowed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3132_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-discrimination requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Non-discrimination requirement No credit shall be allowed under this section to any employer for any calendar quarter if such employer, with respect to the availability of the provision of qualified family leave wages to which this section otherwise applies for such calendar quarter, discriminates in favor of highly compensated employees (within the meaning of section 414(q)), full-time employees, or employees on the basis of employment tenure with such employer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>