<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3134" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3134/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3134/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3134"><akn:num>3134</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee retention credit for employers subject to closure due to COVID–19</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3134. Employee retention credit for employers subject to closure due to COVID–19(a) In generalIn the case of an eligible employer, there shall be allowed as a credit against applicable employment taxes for each calendar quarter an amount equal to 70 percent of the qualified wages with respect to each employee of such employer for such calendar quarter.


(b) Limitations and refundability(1) In general(A) Wages taken into accountThe amount of qualified wages with respect to any employee which may be taken into account under subsection (a) by the eligible employer for any calendar quarter shall not exceed $10,000.


(B) Recovery startup businessesIn the case of an eligible employer which is a recovery startup business (as defined in subsection (c)(5)), the amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) (after application of subparagraph (A)) for any calendar quarter shall not exceed $50,000.



(2) Credit limited to employment taxesThe credit allowed by subsection (a) with respect to any calendar quarter shall not exceed the applicable employment taxes (reduced by any credits allowed under sections 3131 and 3132) on the wages paid with respect to the employment of all the employees of the eligible employer for such calendar quarter.


(3) Refundability of excess creditIf the amount of the credit under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation of paragraph (2) for any calendar quarter, such excess shall be treated as an overpayment that shall be refunded under sections 6402(a) and 6413(b).



(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) Applicable employment taxesThe term “applicable employment taxes” means the following:(A) The taxes imposed under section 3111(b).

(B) So much of the taxes imposed under section 3221(a) as are attributable to the rate in effect under section 3111(b).


(2) Eligible employer(A) In generalThe term “eligible employer” means any employer—(i) which was carrying on a trade or business during the calendar quarter for which the credit is d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of an eligible employer, there shall be allowed as a credit against applicable employment taxes for each calendar quarter an amount equal to 70 percent of the qualified wages with respect to each employee of such employer for such calendar quarter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations and refundability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations and refundability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aggregation rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Aggregation rule All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414, shall be treated as one employer for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain rules to apply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certain rules to apply For purposes of this section, rules similar to the rules of sections 51(i)(1) and 280C(a) shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain governmental employers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certain governmental employers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to not take certain wages into account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Election to not take certain wages into account This section shall not apply to so much of the qualified wages paid by an eligible employer as such employer elects (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) to not take into account for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with certain programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Coordination with certain programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Third party payors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Third party payors Any credit allowed under this section shall be treated as a credit described in section 3511(d)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3134_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Advance payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>