<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/318" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/318/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/318/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_318"><akn:num>318</akn:num><akn:heading>Constructive ownership of stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 318. Constructive ownership of stock(a) General ruleFor purposes of those provisions of this subchapter to which the rules contained in this section are expressly made applicable—(1) Members of family(A) In generalAn individual shall be considered as owning the stock owned, directly or indirectly, by or for—(i) his spouse (other than a spouse who is legally separated from the individual under a decree of divorce or separate maintenance), and

(ii) his children, grandchildren, and parents.


(B) Effect of adoptionFor purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), a legally adopted child of an individual shall be treated as a child of such individual by blood.



(2) Attribution from partnerships, estates, trusts, and corporations(A) From partnerships and estatesStock owned, directly or indirectly, by or for a partnership or estate shall be considered as owned proportionately by its partners or beneficiaries.


(B) From trusts(i) Stock owned, directly or indirectly, by or for a trust (other than an employees’ trust described in section 401(a) which is exempt from tax under section 501(a)) shall be considered as owned by its beneficiaries in proportion to the actuarial interest of such beneficiaries in such trust.

(ii) Stock owned, directly or indirectly, by or for any portion of a trust of which a person is considered the owner under subpart E of part I of subchapter J (relating to grantors and others treated as substantial owners) shall be considered as owned by such person.


(C) From corporationsIf 50 percent or more in value of the stock in a corporation is owned, directly or indirectly, by or for any person, such person shall be considered as owning the stock owned, directly or indirectly, by or for such corporation, in that proportion which the value of the stock which such person so owns bears to the value of all the stock in such corporation.



(3) Attribution to partnerships, estates, trusts, and corporations(A) To partnerships and estatesStock owned, directly or indi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_318_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule For purposes of those provisions of this subchapter to which the rules contained in this section are expressly made applicable—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_318_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cross references For provisions to which the rules contained in subsection (a) apply, see—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>