<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3302"><akn:num>3302</akn:num><akn:heading>Credits against tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3302. Credits against tax(a) Contributions to State unemployment funds(1) The taxpayer may, to the extent provided in this subsection and subsection (c), credit against the tax imposed by section 3301 the amount of contributions paid by him into an unemployment fund maintained during the taxable year under the unemployment compensation law of a State which is certified as provided in section 3304 for the 12-month period ending on October 31 of such year.

(2) The credit shall be permitted against the tax for the taxable year only for the amount of contributions paid with respect to such taxable year.

(3) The credit against the tax for any taxable year shall be permitted only for contributions paid on or before the last day upon which the taxpayer is required under section 6071 to file a return for such year; except that credit shall be permitted for contributions paid after such last day, but such credit shall not exceed 90 percent of the amount which would have been allowable as credit on account of such contributions had they been paid on or before such last day.

(4) Upon the payment of contributions into the unemployment fund of a State which are required under the unemployment compensation law of that State with respect to remuneration on the basis of which, prior to such payment into the proper fund, the taxpayer erroneously paid an amount as contributions under another unemployment compensation law, the payment into the proper fund shall, for purposes of credit against the tax, be deemed to have been made at the time of the erroneous payment. If, by reason of such other law, the taxpayer was entitled to cease paying contributions with respect to services subject to such other law, the payment into the proper fund shall, for purposes of credit against the tax, be deemed to have been made on the date the return for the taxable year was filed under section 6071.

(5) In the case of wages paid by the trustee of an estate under title 11 of the United States Cod</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions to State unemployment funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contributions to State unemployment funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional credit In addition to the credit allowed under subsection (a), a taxpayer may credit against the tax imposed by section 3301 for any taxable year an amount, with respect to the unemployment compensation law of each State certified as provided in section 3303 for the 12-month period ending on October 31 of such year, or with respect to any provisions thereof so certified, equal to the amount, if any, by which the contributions required to be paid by him with respect to the taxable year were less than the contributions such taxpayer would have been required to pay if throughout the taxable year he had been subject under such State law to the highest rate applied thereunder in such 12-month period to any person having individuals in his employ, or to a rate of 5.4 percent, whichever rate is lower.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limit on total credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limit on total credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules relating to subsection (c)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions and special rules relating to subsection (c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Successor employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Successor employer Subject to the limits provided by subsection (c), if— then, for the calendar year in which the acquisition takes place, in addition to the credits allowed under subsections (a) and (b), such employer may credit against the tax imposed by section 3301 for such year an amount equal to the credits which (without regard to subsection (c)) would have been allowable to such other person under subsections (a) and (b) and this subsection for such year, if such other person had been an employer, with respect to remuneration subject to contributions under the unemployment compensation law of a State paid by such other person to the individual or individuals described in paragraph (1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on credit reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on credit reduction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit reduction not to apply when State makes certain repayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Credit reduction not to apply when State makes certain repayments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3302_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certified professional employer organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Treatment of certified professional employer organizations If a certified professional employer organization (as defined in section 7705), or a customer of such organization, makes a contribution to the State’s unemployment fund with respect to wages paid to a work site employee, such certified professional employer organization shall be eligible for the credits available under this section with respect to such contribution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>