<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3306"><akn:num>3306</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3306. Definitions(a) EmployerFor purposes of this chapter—(1) In generalThe term “employer” means, with respect to any calendar year, any person who—(A) during any calendar quarter in the calendar year or the preceding calendar year paid wages of $1,500 or more, or

(B) on each of some 20 days during the calendar year or during the preceding calendar year, each day being in a different calendar week, employed at least one individual in employment for some portion of the day.


For purposes of this paragraph, there shall not be taken into account any wages paid to, or employment of, an employee performing domestic services referred to in paragraph (3).

(2) Agricultural laborIn the case of agricultural labor, the term “employer” means, with respect to any calendar year, any person who—(A) during any calendar quarter in the calendar year or the preceding calendar year paid wages of $20,000 or more for agricultural labor, or

(B) on each of some 20 days during the calendar year or during the preceding calendar year, each day being in a different calendar week, employed at least 10 individuals in employment in agricultural labor for some portion of the day.


(3) Domestic serviceIn the case of domestic service in a private home, local college club, or local chapter of a college fraternity or sorority, the term “employer” means, with respect to any calendar year, any person who during any calendar quarter in the calendar year or the preceding calendar year paid wages in cash of $1,000 or more for such service.


(4) Special ruleA person treated as an employer under paragraph (3) shall not be treated as an employer with respect to wages paid for any service other than domestic service referred to in paragraph (3) unless such person is treated as an employer under paragraph (1) or (2) with respect to such other service.



(b) WagesFor purposes of this chapter, the term “wages” means all remuneration for employment, including the cash value of all remuneration (including</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employer For purposes of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Wages For purposes of this chapter, the term “wages” means all remuneration for employment, including the cash value of all remuneration (including benefits) paid in any medium other than cash; except that such term shall not include— Except as otherwise provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, any third party which makes a payment included in wages solely by reason of the parenthetical matter contained in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2) shall be treated for purposes of this chapter and chapter 22 as the employer with respect to such wages. Nothing in the regulations prescribed for purposes of chapter 24 (relating to income tax withholding) which provides an exclusion from “wages” as used in such chapter shall be construed to require a similar exclusion from “wages” in the regulations prescribed for purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Employment For purposes of this chapter, the term “employment” means any service performed prior to 1955, which was employment for purposes of subchapter C of chapter 9 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 under the law applicable to the period in which such service was performed, and (A) any service, of whatever nature, performed after 1954 by an employee for the person employing him, irrespective of the citizenship or residence of either, (i) within the United States, or (ii) on or in connection with an American vessel or American aircraft under a contract of service which is entered into within the United States or during the performance of which and while the employee is employed on the vessel or aircraft it touches at a port in the United States, if the employee is employed on and in connection with such vessel or aircraft when outside the United States, and (B) any service, of whatever nature, performed after 1971 outside the United States (except in a contiguous country with</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Included and excluded service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Included and excluded service For purposes of this chapter, if the services performed during one-half or more of any pay period by an employee for the person employing him constitute employment, all the services of such employee for such period shall be deemed to be employment; but if the services performed during more than one-half of any such pay period by an employee for the person employing him do not constitute employment, then none of the services of such employee for such period shall be deemed to be employment. As used in this subsection, the term “pay period” means a period (of not more than 31 consecutive days) for which a payment of remuneration is ordinarily made to the employee by the person employing him. This subsection shall not be applicable with respect to services performed in a pay period by an employee for the person employing him, where any of such service is excepted by subsection (c)(9).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State agency For purposes of this chapter, the term “State agency” means any State officer, board, or other authority, designated under a State law to administer the unemployment fund in such State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unemployment fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Unemployment fund For purposes of this chapter, the term “unemployment fund” means a special fund, established under a State law and administered by a State agency, for the payment of compensation. Any sums standing to the account of the State agency in the Unemployment Trust Fund established by section 904 of the Social Security Act, as amended (42 U.S.C. 1104), shall be deemed to be a part of the unemployment fund of the State, and no sums paid out of the Unemployment Trust Fund to such State agency shall cease to be a part of the unemployment fund of the State until expended by such State agency. An unemployment fund shall be deemed to be maintained during a taxable year only if throughout such year, or such portion of the year as the unemployment fund was in existence, no part of the moneys of such fund was expended for any purpose other than the payment of compensation (exclusive of expenses of administration) and for refunds of sums erroneously paid into such fund and refunds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Contributions For purposes of this chapter, the term “contributions” means payments required by a State law to be made into an unemployment fund by any person on account of having individuals in his employ, to the extent that such payments are made by him without being deducted or deductible from the remuneration of individuals in his employ.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Compensation For purposes of this chapter, the term “compensation” means cash benefits payable to individuals with respect to their unemployment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Employee For purposes of this chapter, the term “employee” has the meaning assigned to such term by section 3121(d), except that paragraph (4) and subparagraphs (B) and (C) of paragraph (3) shall not apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3306_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>State, United States, and American employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) State, United States, and American employer For purposes of this chapter— An individual who is a citizen of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or the Virgin Islands (but not otherwise a citizen of the United States) shall be considered, for purposes of this section, as a citizen of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>