<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/331" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/331/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/331/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_331"><akn:num>331</akn:num><akn:heading>Gain or loss to shareholder in corporate liquidations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 331. Gain or loss to shareholder in corporate liquidations(a) Distributions in complete liquidation treated as exchangesAmounts received by a shareholder in a distribution in complete liquidation of a corporation shall be treated as in full payment in exchange for the stock.


(b) Nonapplication of section 301Section 301 (relating to effects on shareholder of distributions of property) shall not apply to any distribution of property (other than a distribution referred to in paragraph (2)(B) of section 316(b)) in complete liquidation.


(c) Cross referenceFor general rule for determination of the amount of gain or loss recognized, see section 1001.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 101; Pub. L. 88–272, title II, § 225(f)(2), Feb. 26, 1964, 78 Stat. 88; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1901(b)(28)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1799; Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 222(a), (e)(1)(B), Sept. 3, 1982, 96 Stat. 478, 480; Pub. L. 115–141, div. U, title IV, § 401(a)(63), Mar. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 1187.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–141 substituted “shareholder” for “shareholders” in section catchline.
1982—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 97–248, § 222(a), substituted provisions that amounts received by a shareholder in a distribution in complete liquidation of a corporation shall be treated as in full payment in exchange for the stock for provisions that, in complete liquidations, amounts distributed shall be treated as in full payment in exchange for the stock, while amounts distributed in partial liquidation shall be treated as in part or full payment in exchange for the stock.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 97–248, § 222(e)(1)(B), struck out “partial or” before “complete liquidation”.
1976—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 94–455 substituted “reference” for “references” in heading and struck out cross reference relating to general rule for determination of the amount of gain or loss to the distributee and substituted “section 1001” for “section 1002”.
1964—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 88–272 inserted “(ot</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions in complete liquidation treated as exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Distributions in complete liquidation treated as exchanges Amounts received by a shareholder in a distribution in complete liquidation of a corporation shall be treated as in full payment in exchange for the stock.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplication of section 301</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nonapplication of section 301 Section 301 (relating to effects on shareholder of distributions of property) shall not apply to any distribution of property (other than a distribution referred to in paragraph (2)(B) of section 316(b)) in complete liquidation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cross reference For general rule for determination of the amount of gain or loss recognized, see section 1001.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>