<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/336" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/336/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/336/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_336"><akn:num>336</akn:num><akn:heading>Gain or loss recognized on property distributed in complete liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 336. Gain or loss recognized on property distributed in complete liquidation(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in this section or section 337, gain or loss shall be recognized to a liquidating corporation on the distribution of property in complete liquidation as if such property were sold to the distributee at its fair market value.


(b) Treatment of liabilitiesIf any property distributed in the liquidation is subject to a liability or the shareholder assumes a liability of the liquidating corporation in connection with the distribution, for purposes of subsection (a) and section 337, the fair market value of such property shall be treated as not less than the amount of such liability.


(c) Exception for liquidations which are part of a reorganizationFor provision providing that this subpart does not apply to distributions in pursuance of a plan of reorganization, see section 361(c)(4).


(d) Limitations on recognition of loss(1) No loss recognized in certain distributions to related persons(A) In generalNo loss shall be recognized to a liquidating corporation on the distribution of any property to a related person (within the meaning of section 267) if—(i) such distribution is not pro rata, or

(ii) such property is disqualified prop­erty.


(B) Disqualified propertyFor purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “disqualified property” means any property which is acquired by the liquidating corporation in a transaction to which section 351 applied, or as a contribution to capital, during the 5-year period ending on the date of the distribution. Such term includes any property if the adjusted basis of such property is determined (in whole or in part) by reference to the adjusted basis of property described in the preceding sentence.



(2) Special rule for certain property acquired in certain carryover basis transactions(A) In generalFor purposes of determining the amount of loss recognized by any liquidating corporation on any sale, exchange, or distribu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_336_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided in this section or section 337, gain or loss shall be recognized to a liquidating corporation on the distribution of property in complete liquidation as if such property were sold to the distributee at its fair market value.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_336_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of liabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treatment of liabilities If any property distributed in the liquidation is subject to a liability or the shareholder assumes a liability of the liquidating corporation in connection with the distribution, for purposes of subsection (a) and section 337, the fair market value of such property shall be treated as not less than the amount of such liability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_336_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for liquidations which are part of a reorganization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception for liquidations which are part of a reorganization For provision providing that this subpart does not apply to distributions in pursuance of a plan of reorganization, see section 361(c)(4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_336_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on recognition of loss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations on recognition of loss</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_336_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain stock sales and distributions may be treated as asset transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certain stock sales and distributions may be treated as asset transfers Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, if— an election may be made to treat such sale, exchange, or distribution as a disposition of all of the assets of such other corporation, and no gain or loss shall be recognized on the sale, exchange, or distribution of such stock.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>