<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3401"><akn:num>3401</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3401. Definitions(a) WagesFor purposes of this chapter, the term “wages” means all remuneration (other than fees paid to a public official) for services performed by an employee for his employer, including the cash value of all remuneration (including benefits) paid in any medium other than cash; except that such term shall not include remuneration paid—(1) for active service performed in a month for which such employee is entitled to the benefits of section 112 (relating to certain combat zone compensation of members of the Armed Forces of the United States) to the extent remuneration for such service is excludable from gross income under such section,

(2) for agricultural labor (as defined in section 3121(g)) unless the remuneration paid for such labor is wages (as defined in section 3121(a)),

(3) for domestic service in a private home, local college club, or local chapter of a college fraternity or sorority,

(4) for service not in the course of the employer’s trade or business performed in any calendar quarter by an employee, unless the cash remuneration paid for such service is $50 or more and such service is performed by an individual who is regularly employed by such employer to perform such service. For purposes of this paragraph, an individual shall be deemed to be regularly employed by an employer during a calendar quarter only if—(A) on each of some 24 days during such quarter such individual performs for such employer for some portion of the day service not in the course of the employer’s trade or business, or

(B) such individual was regularly employed (as determined under subparagraph (A)) by such employer in the performance of such service during the preceding calendar quarter,


(5) for services by a citizen or resident of the United States for a foreign government or an international organization,

(6) for such services, performed by a nonresident alien individual, as may be designated by regulations prescribed by the Secretary,

[(7) Repealed. </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Wages For purposes of this chapter, the term “wages” means all remuneration (other than fees paid to a public official) for services performed by an employee for his employer, including the cash value of all remuneration (including benefits) paid in any medium other than cash; except that such term shall not include remuneration paid— The term “wages” includes any amount includible in gross income of an employee under section 409A and payment of such amount shall be treated as having been made in the taxable year in which the amount is so includible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payroll period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payroll period For purposes of this chapter, the term “payroll period” means a period for which a payment of wages is ordinarily made to the employee by his employer, and the term “miscellaneous payroll period” means a payroll period other than a daily, weekly, biweekly, semimonthly, monthly, quarterly, semiannual, or annual payroll period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Employee For purposes of this chapter, the term “employee” includes an officer, employee, or elected official of the United States, a State, or any political subdivision thereof, or the District of Columbia, or any agency or instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing. The term “employee” also includes an officer of a corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Employer For purposes of this chapter, the term “employer” means the person for whom an individual performs or performed any service, of whatever nature, as the employee of such person, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 11041(c)(2)(A), Dec. 22, 2017, 131 Stat. 2082]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tips</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Tips For purposes of subsection (a), the term “wages” includes tips received by an employee in the course of his employment. Such wages shall be deemed to be paid at the time a written statement including such tips is furnished to the employer pursuant to section 6053(a) or (if no statement including such tips is so furnished) at the time received.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crew leader rules to apply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Crew leader rules to apply Rules similar to the rules of section 3121(o) shall apply for purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Differential wage payments to active duty members of the uniformed services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Differential wage payments to active duty members of the uniformed services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified stock for which an election is in effect under section 83(i)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Qualified stock for which an election is in effect under section 83(i) For purposes of subsection (a), qualified stock (as defined in section 83(i)) with respect to which an election is made under section 83(i) shall be treated as wages—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>