<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3402"><akn:num>3402</akn:num><akn:heading>Income tax collected at source</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3402. Income tax collected at source(a) Requirement of withholding(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this section, every employer making payment of wages shall deduct and withhold upon such wages a tax determined in accordance with tables or computational procedures prescribed by the Secretary. Any tables or procedures prescribed under this paragraph shall—(A) apply with respect to the amount of wages paid during such periods as the Secretary may prescribe, and

(B) be in such form, and provide for such amounts to be deducted and withheld, as the Secretary determines to be most appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter and to reflect the provisions of chapter 1 applicable to such periods.


(2) Amount of wagesFor purposes of applying tables or procedures prescribed under paragraph (1), the term “the amount of wages” means the amount by which the wages exceed the taxpayer’s withholding allowance, prorated to the payroll period.



(b) Percentage method of withholding(1) If wages are paid with respect to a period which is not a payroll period, the withholding allowance allowable with respect to each payment of such wages shall be the allowance allowed for a miscellaneous payroll period containing a number of days (including Sundays and holidays) equal to the number of days in the period with respect to which such wages are paid.

(2) In any case in which wages are paid by an employer without regard to any payroll period or other period, the withholding allowance allowable with respect to each payment of such wages shall be the allowance allowed for a miscellaneous payroll period containing a number of days equal to the number of days (including Sundays and holidays) which have elapsed since the date of the last payment of such wages by such employer during the calendar year, or the date of commencement of employment with such employer during such year, or January 1 of such year, whichever is the later.

(3) In any case in which the period, or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of withholding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement of withholding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Percentage method of withholding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Percentage method of withholding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wage bracket withholding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Wage bracket withholding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax paid by recipient</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tax paid by recipient If the employer, in violation of the provisions of this chapter, fails to deduct and withhold the tax under this chapter, and thereafter the tax against which such tax may be credited is paid, the tax so required to be deducted and withheld shall not be collected from the employer; but this subsection shall in no case relieve the employer from liability for any penalties or additions to the tax otherwise applicable in respect of such failure to deduct and withhold.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Included and excluded wages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Included and excluded wages If the remuneration paid by an employer to an employee for services performed during one-half or more of any payroll period of not more than 31 consecutive days constitutes wages, all the remuneration paid by such employer to such employee for such period shall be deemed to be wages; but if the remuneration paid by an employer to an employee for services performed during more than one-half of any such payroll period does not constitute wages, then none of the remuneration paid by such employer to such employee for such period shall be deemed to be wages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding allowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Withholding allowance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overlapping pay periods, and payment by agent or fiduciary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Overlapping pay periods, and payment by agent or fiduciary If a payment of wages is made to an employee by an employer— the manner of withholding and the amount to be deducted and withheld under this chapter shall be determined in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary under which the withholding allowance allowed to the employee in any calendar year shall approximate the withholding allowance allowable with respect to an annual payroll period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative methods of computing amount to be withheld</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Alternative methods of computing amount to be withheld The Secretary may, under regulations prescribed by him, authorize—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes in withholding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Changes in withholding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3402_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncash remuneration to retail commission salesman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Noncash remuneration to retail commission salesman In the case of remuneration paid in any medium other than cash for services performed by an individual as a retail salesman for a person, where the service performed by such individual for such person is ordinarily performed for remuneration solely by way of cash commission an employer shall not be required to deduct or withhold any tax under this subchapter with respect to such remuneration, provided that such employer files with the Secretary such information with respect to such remuneration as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>