<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_351"><akn:num>351</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to corporation controlled by transferor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 351. Transfer to corporation controlled by transferor(a) General ruleNo gain or loss shall be recognized if property is transferred to a corporation by one or more persons solely in exchange for stock in such corporation and immediately after the exchange such person or persons are in control (as defined in section 368(c)) of the corporation.


(b) Receipt of propertyIf subsection (a) would apply to an exchange but for the fact that there is received, in addition to the stock permitted to be received under subsection (a), other property or money, then—(1) gain (if any) to such recipient shall be recognized, but not in excess of—(A) the amount of money received, plus

(B) the fair market value of such other property received; and


(2) no loss to such recipient shall be recognized.


(c) Special rules where distribution to shareholders(1) In generalIn determining control for purposes of this section, the fact that any corporate transferor distributes part or all of the stock in the corporation which it receives in the exchange to its shareholders shall not be taken into account.


(2) Special rule for section 355If the requirements of section 355 (or so much of section 356 as relates to section 355) are met with respect to a distribution described in paragraph (1), then, solely for purposes of determining the tax treatment of the transfers of property to the controlled corporation by the distributing corporation, the fact that the shareholders of the distributing corporation dispose of part or all of the distributed stock, or the fact that the corporation whose stock was distributed issues additional stock, shall not be taken into account in determining control for purposes of this section.



(d) Services, certain indebtedness, and accrued interest not treated as propertyFor purposes of this section, stock issued for—(1) services,

(2) indebtedness of the transferee corporation which is not evidenced by a security, or

(3) interest on indebtedness of the transfere</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule No gain or loss shall be recognized if property is transferred to a corporation by one or more persons solely in exchange for stock in such corporation and immediately after the exchange such person or persons are in control (as defined in section 368(c)) of the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipt of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Receipt of property If subsection (a) would apply to an exchange but for the fact that there is received, in addition to the stock permitted to be received under subsection (a), other property or money, then—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules where distribution to shareholders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules where distribution to shareholders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services, certain indebtedness, and accrued interest not treated as property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Services, certain indebtedness, and accrued interest not treated as property For purposes of this section, stock issued for— shall not be considered as issued in return for property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exceptions This section shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of controlled corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of controlled corporation If— section 311 shall apply to any transfer in such exchange by the controlled corporation in the same manner as if such transfer were a distribution to which subpart A of part I applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonqualified preferred stock not treated as stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nonqualified preferred stock not treated as stock</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>