<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3510" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3510/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/3510/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3510"><akn:num>3510</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of collection of domestic service employment taxes with collection of income taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3510. Coordination of collection of domestic service employment taxes with collection of income taxes(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in this section—(1) returns with respect to domestic service employment taxes shall be made on a calendar year basis,

(2) any such return for any calendar year shall be filed on or before the 15th day of the fourth month following the close of the employer’s taxable year which begins in such calendar year, and

(3) no requirement to make deposits (or to pay installments under section 6157) shall apply with respect to such taxes.


(b) Domestic service employment taxes subject to estimated tax provisions(1) In generalSolely for purposes of section 6654, domestic service employment taxes imposed with respect to any calendar year shall be treated as a tax imposed by chapter 2 for the taxable year of the employer which begins in such calendar year.


(2) Employers not otherwise required to make estimated paymentsParagraph (1) shall not apply to any employer for any calendar year if—(A) no credit for wage withholding is allowed under section 31 to such employer for the taxable year of the employer which begins in such calendar year, and

(B) no addition to tax would (but for this section) be imposed under section 6654 for such taxable year by reason of section 6654(e).


(3) AnnualizationUnder regulations prescribed by the Secretary, appropriate adjustments shall be made in the application of section 6654(d)(2) in respect of the amount treated as tax under paragraph (1).



(c) Domestic service employment taxesFor purposes of this section, the term “domestic service employment taxes” means—(1) any taxes imposed by chapter 21 or 23 on remuneration paid for domestic service in a private home of the employer, and

(2) any amount withheld from such remuneration pursuant to an agreement under section 3402(p).


For purposes of this subsection, the term “domestic service in a private home of the employer” includes domestic service</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3510_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3510_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic service employment taxes subject to estimated tax provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Domestic service employment taxes subject to estimated tax provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3510_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic service employment taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Domestic service employment taxes For purposes of this section, the term “domestic service employment taxes” means— For purposes of this subsection, the term “domestic service in a private home of the employer” includes domestic service described in section 3121(g)(5).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3510_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception where employer liable for other employment taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exception where employer liable for other employment taxes To the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, this section shall not apply to any employer for any calendar year if such employer is liable for any tax under this subtitle with respect to remuneration for services other than domestic service in a private home of the employer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3510_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>General regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) General regulatory authority The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section. Such regulations may treat domestic service employment taxes as taxes imposed by chapter 1 for purposes of coordinating the assessment and collection of such employment taxes with the assessment and collection of domestic employers’ income taxes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3510_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to enter into agreements to collect State unemployment taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authority to enter into agreements to collect State unemployment taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>