<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/358" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/358/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/358/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_358"><akn:num>358</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis to distributees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 358. Basis to distributees(a) General ruleIn the case of an exchange to which section 351, 354, 355, 356, or 361 applies—(1) Nonrecognition propertyThe basis of the property permitted to be received under such section without the recognition of gain or loss shall be the same as that of the property exchanged—(A) decreased by—(i) the fair market value of any other property (except money) received by the taxpayer,

(ii) the amount of any money received by the taxpayer, and

(iii) the amount of loss to the taxpayer which was recognized on such exchange, and


(B) increased by—(i) the amount which was treated as a dividend, and

(ii) the amount of gain to the taxpayer which was recognized on such exchange (not including any portion of such gain which was treated as a dividend).



(2) Other propertyThe basis of any other property (except money) received by the taxpayer shall be its fair market value.



(b) Allocation of basis(1) In generalUnder regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the basis determined under subsection (a)(1) shall be allocated among the properties permitted to be received without the recognition of gain or loss.


(2) Special rule for section 355In the case of an exchange to which section 355 (or so much of section 356 as relates to section 355) applies, then in making the allocation under paragraph (1) of this subsection, there shall be taken into account not only the property so permitted to be received without the recognition of gain or loss, but also the stock or securities (if any) of the distributing corporation which are retained, and the allocation of basis shall be made among all such properties.



(c) Section 355 transactions which are not exchangesFor purposes of this section, a distribution to which section 355 (or so much of section 356 as relates to section 355) applies shall be treated as an exchange, and for such purposes the stock and securities of the distributing corporation which are retained shall be treated as surrendered, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of an exchange to which section 351, 354, 355, 356, or 361 applies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocation of basis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section 355 transactions which are not exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Section 355 transactions which are not exchanges For purposes of this section, a distribution to which section 355 (or so much of section 356 as relates to section 355) applies shall be treated as an exchange, and for such purposes the stock and securities of the distributing corporation which are retained shall be treated as surrendered, and received back, in the exchange.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assumption of liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assumption of liability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exception This section shall not apply to property acquired by a corporation by the exchange of its stock or securities (or the stock or securities of a corporation which is in control of the acquiring corporation) as consideration in whole or in part for the transfer of the property to it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of nonrecognition property in case of section 361 exchange</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definition of nonrecognition property in case of section 361 exchange For purposes of this section, the property permitted to be received under section 361 without the recognition of gain or loss shall be treated as consisting only of stock or securities in another corporation a party to the reorganization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments in intragroup transactions involving section 355</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Adjustments in intragroup transactions involving section 355 In the case of a distribution to which section 355 (or so much of section 356 as relates to section 355) applies and which involves the distribution of stock from 1 member of an affiliated group (as defined in section 1504(a) without regard to subsection (b) thereof) to another member of such group, the Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of this section, provide adjustments to the adjusted basis of any stock which— to appropriately reflect the proper treatment of such distribution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for assumption of liabilities to which subsection (d) does not apply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rules for assumption of liabilities to which subsection (d) does not apply</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>