<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/36" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/36/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/36/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_36"><akn:num>36</akn:num><akn:heading>First-time homebuyer credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 36. First-time homebuyer credit(a) Allowance of creditIn the case of an individual who is a first-time homebuyer of a principal residence in the United States during a taxable year, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this subtitle for such taxable year an amount equal to 10 percent of the purchase price of the residence.


(b) Limitations(1) Dollar limitation(A) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this paragraph, the credit allowed under subsection (a) shall not exceed $8,000.


(B) Married individuals filing separatelyIn the case of a married individual filing a separate return, subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting “$4,000” for “$8,000”.


(C) Other individualsIf two or more individuals who are not married purchase a principal residence, the amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) shall be allocated among such individuals in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe, except that the total amount of the credits allowed to all such individuals shall not exceed $8,000.


(D) Special rule for long-time residents of same principal residenceIn the case of a taxpayer to whom a credit under subsection (a) is allowed by reason of subsection (c)(6), subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) shall be applied by substituting “$6,500” for “$8,000” and “$3,250” for “$4,000”.



(2) Limitation based on modified adjusted gross income(A) In generalThe amount allowable as a credit under subsection (a) (determined without regard to this paragraph) for the taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount which bears the same ratio to the amount which is so allowable as—(i) the excess (if any) of—(I) the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income for such taxable year, over

(II) $125,000 ($225,000 in the case of a joint return), bears to


(ii) $20,000.


(B) Modified adjusted gross incomeFor purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “modified adjusted gross income” means the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for the tax</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of credit In the case of an individual who is a first-time homebuyer of a principal residence in the United States during a taxable year, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this subtitle for such taxable year an amount equal to 10 percent of the purchase price of the residence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exceptions No credit under subsection (a) shall be allowed to any taxpayer for any taxable year with respect to the purchase of a residence if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporting If the Secretary requires information reporting under section 6045 by a person described in subsection (e)(2) thereof to verify the eligibility of taxpayers for the credit allowable by this section, the exception provided by section 6045(e) shall not apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recapture of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Recapture of credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to treat purchase in prior year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Election to treat purchase in prior year In the case of a purchase of a principal residence after December 31, 2008, a taxpayer may elect to treat such purchase as made on December 31 of the calendar year preceding such purchase for purposes of this section (other than subsections (b)(4), (c), (f)(4)(D), and (h)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Application of section</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>