<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/382" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/382/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/382/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_382"><akn:num>382</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on net operating loss carryforwards and certain built-in losses following ownership chang</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 382. Limitation on net operating loss carryforwards and certain built-in losses following ownership change(a) General ruleThe amount of the taxable income of any new loss corporation for any post-change year which may be offset by pre-change losses shall not exceed the section 382 limitation for such year.


(b) Section 382 limitationFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this section, the section 382 limitation for any post-change year is an amount equal to—(A) the value of the old loss corporation, multiplied by

(B) the long-term tax-exempt rate.


(2) Carryforward of unused limitationIf the section 382 limitation for any post-change year exceeds the taxable income of the new loss corporation for such year which was offset by pre-change losses, the section 382 limitation for the next post-change year shall be increased by the amount of such excess.


(3) Special rule for post-change year which includes change dateIn the case of any post-change year which includes the change date—(A) Limitation does not apply to taxable income before changeSubsection (a) shall not apply to the portion of the taxable income for such year which is allocable to the period in such year on or before the change date. Except as provided in subsection (h)(5) and in regulations, taxable income shall be allocated ratably to each day in the year.


(B) Limitation for period after changeFor purposes of applying the limitation of subsection (a) to the remainder of the taxable income for such year, the section 382 limitation shall be an amount which bears the same ratio to such limitation (determined without regard to this paragraph) as—(i) the number of days in such year after the change date, bears to

(ii) the total number of days in such year.




(c) Carryforwards disallowed if continuity of business requirements not met(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), if the new loss corporation does not continue the business enterprise of the old lo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule The amount of the taxable income of any new loss corporation for any post-change year which may be offset by pre-change losses shall not exceed the section 382 limitation for such year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section 382 limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Section 382 limitation For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryforwards disallowed if continuity of business requirements not met</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Carryforwards disallowed if continuity of business requirements not met</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pre-change loss and post-change year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Pre-change loss and post-change year For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value of old loss corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Value of old loss corporation For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Long-term tax-exempt rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Long-term tax-exempt rate For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ownership change</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Ownership change For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for built-in gains and losses and section 338 gains</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rules for built-in gains and losses and section 338 gains For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Testing period For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Change date For purposes of this section, the change date is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>