<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/384" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/384/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/384/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_384"><akn:num>384</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of preacquisition losses to offset built-in gains</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 384. Limitation on use of preacquisition losses to offset built-in gains(a) General ruleIf—(1)(A) a corporation acquires directly (or through 1 or more other corporations) control of another corporation, or

(B) the assets of a corporation are acquired by another corporation in a reorganization described in subparagraph (A), (C), or (D) of section 368(a)(1), and


(2) either of such corporations is a gain corporation,


income for any recognition period taxable year (to the extent attributable to recognized built-in gains) shall not be offset by any preacquisition loss (other than a preacquisition loss of the gain corporation).

(b) Exception where corporations under common control(1) In generalSubsection (a) shall not apply to the preacquisition loss of any corporation if such corporation and the gain corporation were members of the same controlled group at all times during the 5-year period ending on the acquisition date.


(2) Controlled groupFor purposes of this subsection, the term “controlled group” means a controlled group of corporations (as defined in section 1563(a)); except that—(A) “more than 50 percent” shall be substituted for “at least 80 percent” each place it appears,

(B) the ownership requirements of section 1563(a) must be met both with respect to voting power and value, and

(C) the determination shall be made without regard to subsection (a)(4) of section 1563.


(3) Shorter period where corporations not in existence for 5 yearsIf either of the corporations referred to in paragraph (1) was not in existence throughout the 5-year period referred to in paragraph (1), the period during which such corporation was in existence (or if both, the shorter of such periods) shall be substituted for such 5-year period.



(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) Recognized built-in gain(A) In generalThe term “recognized built-in gain” means any gain recognized during the recognition period on the disposition of any asset except to the extent the ga</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule If— income for any recognition period taxable year (to the extent attributable to recognized built-in gains) shall not be offset by any preacquisition loss (other than a preacquisition loss of the gain corporation).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception where corporations under common control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception where corporations under common control</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation also to apply to excess credits or net capital losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation also to apply to excess credits or net capital losses Rules similar to the rules of subsection (a) shall also apply in the case of any excess credit (as defined in section 383(a)(2)) or net capital loss.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ordering rules for net operating losses, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Ordering rules for net operating losses, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations to ensure that the purposes of this section may not be circumvented through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>