<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/40" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/40/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/40/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40"><akn:num>40</akn:num><akn:heading>Alcohol, etc., used as fuel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40. Alcohol, etc., used as fuel(a) General ruleFor purposes of section 38, the alcohol fuels credit determined under this section for the taxable year is an amount equal to the sum of—(1) the alcohol mixture credit,

(2) the alcohol credit,

(3) in the case of an eligible small ethanol producer, the small ethanol producer credit, plus

(4) the second generation biofuel producer credit.


(b) Definition of alcohol mixture credit, alcohol credit, and small ethanol producer creditFor purposes of this section, and except as provided in subsection (h)—(1) Alcohol mixture credit(A) In generalThe alcohol mixture credit of any taxpayer for any taxable year is 60 cents for each gallon of alcohol used by the taxpayer in the production of a qualified mixture.


(B) Qualified mixtureThe term “qualified mixture” means a mixture of alcohol and gasoline or of alcohol and a special fuel which—(i) is sold by the taxpayer producing such mixture to any person for use as a fuel, or

(ii) is used as a fuel by the taxpayer producing such mixture.


(C) Sale or use must be in trade or business, etc.Alcohol used in the production of a qualified mixture shall be taken into account—(i) only if the sale or use described in subparagraph (B) is in a trade or business of the taxpayer, and

(ii) for the taxable year in which such sale or use occurs.


(D) Casual off-farm production not eligibleNo credit shall be allowed under this section with respect to any casual off-farm production of a qualified mixture.



(2) Alcohol credit(A) In generalThe alcohol credit of any taxpayer for any taxable year is 60 cents for each gallon of alcohol which is not in a mixture with gasoline or a special fuel (other than any denaturant) and which during the taxable year—(i) is used by the taxpayer as a fuel in a trade or business, or

(ii) is sold by the taxpayer at retail to a person and placed in the fuel tank of such person’s vehicle.


(B) User credit not to apply to alcohol sold at retailNo credit shall be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule For purposes of section 38, the alcohol fuels credit determined under this section for the taxable year is an amount equal to the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of alcohol mixture credit, alcohol credit, and small ethanol producer credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definition of alcohol mixture credit, alcohol credit, and small ethanol producer credit For purposes of this section, and except as provided in subsection (h)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with exemption from excise tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination with exemption from excise tax The amount of the credit determined under this section with respect to any alcohol shall, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be properly reduced to take into account any benefit provided with respect to such alcohol solely by reason of the application of section 4041(b)(2), section 6426, or section 6427(e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to have alcohol fuels credit not apply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Election to have alcohol fuels credit not apply</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules for eligible small ethanol producer credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions and special rules for eligible small ethanol producer credit For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduced credit for ethanol blenders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reduced credit for ethanol blenders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>