<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_401"><akn:num>401</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified pension, profit-sharing, and stock bonus plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 401. Qualified pension, profit-sharing, and stock bonus plans(a) Requirements for qualificationA trust created or organized in the United States and forming part of a stock bonus, pension, or profit-sharing plan of an employer for the exclusive benefit of his employees or their beneficiaries shall constitute a qualified trust under this section—(1) if contributions are made to the trust by such employer, or employees, or both, or by another employer who is entitled to deduct his contributions under section 404(a)(3)(B) (relating to deduction for contributions to profit-sharing and stock bonus plans), or by a charitable remainder trust pursuant to a qualified gratuitous transfer (as defined in section 664(g)(1)), for the purpose of distributing to such employees or their beneficiaries the corpus and income of the fund accumulated by the trust in accordance with such plan;

(2) if under the trust instrument it is impossible, at any time prior to the satisfaction of all liabilities with respect to employees and their beneficiaries under the trust, for any part of the corpus or income to be (within the taxable year or thereafter) used for, or diverted to, purposes other than for the exclusive benefit of his employees or their beneficiaries (but this paragraph shall not be construed, in the case of a multiemployer plan, to prohibit the return of a contribution within 6 months after the plan administrator determines that the contribution was made by a mistake of fact or law (other than a mistake relating to whether the plan is described in section 401(a) or the trust which is part of such plan is exempt from taxation under section 501(a), or the return of any withdrawal liability payment determined to be an overpayment within 6 months of such determination));

(3) if the plan of which such trust is a part satisfies the requirements of section 410 (relating to minimum participation standards); and

(4) if the contributions or benefits provided under the plan do not discr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for qualification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements for qualification A trust created or organized in the United States and forming part of a stock bonus, pension, or profit-sharing plan of an employer for the exclusive benefit of his employees or their beneficiaries shall constitute a qualified trust under this section— Paragraphs (11), (12), (13), (14), (15), (19), and (20) shall apply only in the case of a plan to which section 411 (relating to minimum vesting standards) applies without regard to subsection (e)(2) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain plan amendments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certain plan amendments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and rules relating to self-employed individuals and owner-employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions and rules relating to self-employed individuals and owner-employees For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contribution limit on owner-employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contribution limit on owner-employees A trust forming part of a pension or profit-sharing plan which provides contributions or benefits for employees some or all of whom are owner-employees shall constitute a qualified trust under this section only if, in addition to meeting the requirements of subsection (a), the plan provides that contributions on behalf of any owner-employee may be made only with respect to the earned income of such owner-employee which is derived from the trade or business with respect to which such plan is established.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 713(d)(3), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 958]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain custodial accounts and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certain custodial accounts and contracts For purposes of this title, a custodial account, an annuity contract, or a contract (other than a life, health or accident, property, casualty, or liability insurance contract) issued by an insurance company qualified to do business in a State shall be treated as a qualified trust under this section if— For purposes of this title, in the case of a custodial account or contract treated as a qualified trust under this section by reason of this subsection, the person holding the assets of such account or holding such contract shall be treated as the trustee thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuity defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Annuity defined For purposes of this section and sections 402, 403, and 404, the term “annuity” includes a face-amount certificate, as defined in section 2(a)(15) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (15 U.S.C., sec. 80a–2); but does not include any contract or certificate issued after December 31, 1962, which is transferable, if any person other than the trustee of a trust described in section 401(a) which is exempt from tax under section 501(a) is the owner of such contract or certificate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical, etc., benefits for retired employees and their spouses and dependents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Medical, etc., benefits for retired employees and their spouses and dependents Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, and subject to the provisions of section 420, a pension or annuity plan may provide for the payment of benefits for sickness, accident, hospitalization, and medical expenses of retired employees, their spouses and their dependents, but only if— For purposes of paragraph (6), the term “key employee” means any employee, who at any time during the plan year or any preceding plan year during which contributions were made on behalf of such employee, is or was a key employee as defined in section 416(i). In no event shall the requirements of paragraph (1) be treated as met if the aggregate actual contributions for medical benefits, when added to actual contributions for life insurance protection under the plan, exceed 25 percent of the total actual contributions to the plan (other than contributions to fund past service credits) after the date on which the account</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain union-negotiated pension plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Certain union-negotiated pension plans In the case of a trust forming part of a pension plan which has been determined by the Secretary to constitute a qualified trust under subsection (a) and to be exempt from taxation under section 501(a) for a period beginning after contributions were first made to or for such trust, if it is shown to the satisfaction of the Secretary that— then such trust shall be considered as having constituted a qualified trust under subsection (a) and as having been exempt from taxation under section 501(a) for the period beginning on the date on which contributions were first made to or for such trust and ending on the date such trust first constituted (without regard to this subsection) a qualified trust under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_401_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 97–248, title II, § 238(b), Sept. 3, 1982, 96 Stat. 512]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(j) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>