<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_402"><akn:num>402</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxability of beneficiary of employees’ trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 402. Taxability of beneficiary of employees’ trust(a) Taxability of beneficiary of exempt trustExcept as otherwise provided in this section, any amount actually distributed to any distributee by any employees’ trust described in section 401(a) which is exempt from tax under section 501(a) shall be taxable to the distributee, in the taxable year of the distributee in which distributed, under section 72 (relating to annuities).


(b) Taxability of beneficiary of nonexempt trust(1) ContributionsContributions to an employees’ trust made by an employer during a taxable year of the employer which ends with or within a taxable year of the trust for which the trust is not exempt from tax under section 501(a) shall be included in the gross income of the employee in accordance with section 83 (relating to property transferred in connection with performance of services), except that the value of the employee’s interest in the trust shall be substituted for the fair market value of the property for purposes of applying such section.


(2) DistributionsThe amount actually distributed or made available to any distributee by any trust described in paragraph (1) shall be taxable to the distributee, in the taxable year in which so distributed or made available, under section 72 (relating to annuities), except that distributions of income of such trust before the annuity starting date (as defined in section 72(c)(4)) shall be included in the gross income of the employee without regard to section 72(e)(5) (relating to amounts not received as annuities).


(3) Grantor trustsA beneficiary of any trust described in paragraph (1) shall not be considered the owner of any portion of such trust under subpart E of part I of subchapter J (relating to grantors and others treated as substantial owners).


(4) Failure to meet requirements of section 410(b)(A) Highly compensated employeesIf 1 of the reasons a trust is not exempt from tax under section 501(a) is the failure of the plan of which i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxability of beneficiary of exempt trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Taxability of beneficiary of exempt trust Except as otherwise provided in this section, any amount actually distributed to any distributee by any employees’ trust described in section 401(a) which is exempt from tax under section 501(a) shall be taxable to the distributee, in the taxable year of the distributee in which distributed, under section 72 (relating to annuities).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxability of beneficiary of nonexempt trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Taxability of beneficiary of nonexempt trust</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules applicable to rollovers from exempt trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rules applicable to rollovers from exempt trusts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxability of beneficiary of certain foreign situs trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Taxability of beneficiary of certain foreign situs trusts For purposes of subsections (a), (b), and (c), a stock bonus, pension, or profit-sharing trust which would qualify for exemption from tax under section 501(a) except for the fact that it is a trust created or organized outside the United States shall be treated as if it were a trust exempt from tax under section 501(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other rules applicable to exempt trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other rules applicable to exempt trusts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written explanation to recipients of distributions eligible for rollover treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Written explanation to recipients of distributions eligible for rollover treatment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on exclusion for elective deferrals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on exclusion for elective deferrals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for simplified employee pensions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rules for simplified employee pensions For purposes of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of self-employed individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Treatment of self-employed individuals For purposes of this section, except as otherwise provided in subsection (e)(4)(D)(i), the term “employee” includes a self-employed individual (as defined in section 401(c)(1)(B)) and the employer of such individual shall be the person treated as his employer under section 401(c)(4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of disposition of stock by plan on net unrealized appreciation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Effect of disposition of stock by plan on net unrealized appreciation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>