<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/404" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/404/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/404/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_404"><akn:num>404</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction for contributions of an employer to an employees’ trust or annuity plan and compensation u</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 404. Deduction for contributions of an employer to an employees’ trust or annuity plan and compensation under a deferred-payment plan(a) General ruleIf contributions are paid by an employer to or under a stock bonus, pension, profit-sharing, or annuity plan, or if compensation is paid or accrued on account of any employee under a plan deferring the receipt of such compensation, such contributions or compensation shall not be deductible under this chapter; but, if they would otherwise be deductible, they shall be deductible under this section, subject, however, to the following limitations as to the amounts deductible in any year:(1) Pension trusts(A) In generalIn the taxable year when paid, if the contributions are paid into a pension trust (other than a trust to which paragraph (3) applies), and if such taxable year ends within or with a taxable year of the trust for which the trust is exempt under section 501(a), in the case of a defined benefit plan other than a multiemployer plan, in an amount determined under subsection (o), and in the case of any other plan in an amount determined as follows:(i) the amount necessary to satisfy the minimum funding standard provided by section 412(a) for plan years ending within or with such taxable year (or for any prior plan year), if such amount is greater than the amount determined under clause (ii) or (iii) (whichever is applicable with respect to the plan),

(ii) the amount necessary to provide with respect to all of the employees under the trust the remaining unfunded cost of their past and current service credits distributed as a level amount, or a level percentage of compensation, over the remaining future service of each such employee, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, but if such remaining unfunded cost with respect to any 3 individuals is more than 50 percent of such remaining unfunded cost, the amount of such unfunded cost attributable to such individuals shall be distributed over a peri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule If contributions are paid by an employer to or under a stock bonus, pension, profit-sharing, or annuity plan, or if compensation is paid or accrued on account of any employee under a plan deferring the receipt of such compensation, such contributions or compensation shall not be deductible under this chapter; but, if they would otherwise be deductible, they shall be deductible under this section, subject, however, to the following limitations as to the amounts deductible in any year:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of contributions, etc., having the effect of a plan; certain deferred benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Method of contributions, etc., having the effect of a plan; certain deferred benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain negotiated plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certain negotiated plans If contributions are paid by an employer— such contributions shall not be deductible under this section nor be made nondeductible by this section, but the deductibility thereof shall be governed solely by section 162 (relating to trade or business expenses). For purposes of this chapter and subtitle B, in the case of any individual who before July 1, 1974, was a participant in a plan described in the preceding sentence— Section 277 (relating to deductions incurred by certain membership organizations in transactions with members) does not apply to any trust described in this subsection. The first and third sentences of this subsection shall have no application with respect to amounts contributed to a trust on or after any date on which such trust is qualified for exemption from tax under section 501(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductibility of payments of deferred compensation, etc., to independent contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deductibility of payments of deferred compensation, etc., to independent contractors If a plan would be described in so much of subsection (a) as precedes paragraph (1) thereof (as modified by subsection (b)) but for the fact that there is no employer-employee relationship, the contributions or compensation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions allocable to life insurance protection for self-employed individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contributions allocable to life insurance protection for self-employed individuals In the case of a self-employed individual described in section 401(c)(1), contributions which are allocable (determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary) to the purchase of life, accident, health, or other insurance shall not be taken into account under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 713(b)(3), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 957]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(f) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain employer liability payments considered as contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certain employer liability payments considered as contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for simplified employee pensions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rules for simplified employee pensions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 99–514, title XI, § 1171(b)(6), Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2513]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_404_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules relating to application with section 415</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Special rules relating to application with section 415</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>