<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/407" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/407/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/407/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_407"><akn:num>407</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain employees of domestic subsidiaries engaged in business outside the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 407. Certain employees of domestic subsidiaries engaged in business outside the United States(a) Treatment as employees of domestic parent corporation(1) In generalFor purposes of applying this part with respect to a pension, profit-sharing, or stock bonus plan described in section 401(a) or an annuity plan described in section 403(a), of a domestic parent corporation, an individual who is a citizen or resident of the United States and who is an employee of a domestic subsidiary (within the meaning of paragraph (2)) of such domestic parent corporation shall be treated as an employee of such domestic parent corporation, if—(A) the plan of such domestic parent corporation expressly provides for contributions or benefits for individuals who are citizens or residents of the United States and who are employees of its domestic subsidiaries; and

(B) contributions under a funded plan of deferred compensation (whether or not a plan described in section 401(a) or 403(a)) are not provided by any other person with respect to the remuneration paid to such individual by the domestic subsidiary.


(2) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(A) Domestic subsidiaryA corporation shall be treated as a domestic subsidiary for any taxable year only if—(i) such corporation is a domestic corporation 80 percent or more of the outstanding voting stock of which is owned by another domestic corporation;

(ii) 95 percent or more of its gross income for the three-year period immediately preceding the close of its taxable year which ends on or before the close of the taxable year of such other domestic corporation (or for such part of such period during which the corporation was in existence), was derived from sources without the United States; and

(iii) 90 percent or more of its gross income for such period (or such part) was derived from the active conduct of a trade or business.


If for the period (or part thereof) referred to in clauses (ii) and (iii) such corporation has no gross inco</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_407_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as employees of domestic parent corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Treatment as employees of domestic parent corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_407_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for application of section 401(a)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rules for application of section 401(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_407_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–188, title I, § 1401(b)(8), Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1789]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_407_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductibility of contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deductibility of contributions For purposes of applying section 404 with respect to contributions made to or under a pension, profit-sharing, stock bonus, or annuity plan by a domestic parent corporation, or by another corporation which is entitled to deduct its contributions under section 404(a)(3)(B), on behalf of an individual who is treated as an employee of such domestic corporation under subsection (a)— Any amount deductible by a domestic subsidiary under this subsection shall be deductible for its taxable year with or within which the taxable year of such domestic parent corporation ends.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_407_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as employee under related provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment as employee under related provisions An individual who is treated as an employee of a domestic parent corporation under subsection (a) shall also be treated as an employee of such domestic parent corporation, with respect to the plan described in subsection (a)(1)(A), for purposes of applying the following provisions of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>