<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4072" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4072/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4072/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4072"><akn:num>4072</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4072. Definitions(a) Taxable tireFor purposes of this chapter, the term “taxable tire” means any tire of the type used on highway vehicles if wholly or in part made of rubber and if marked pursuant to Federal regulations for highway use.


(b) RubberFor purposes of this chapter, the term “rubber” includes synthetic and substitute rubber.


(c) Tires of the type used on highway vehiclesFor purposes of this part, the term “tires of the type used on highway vehicles” means tires of the type used on—(1) motor vehicles which are highway vehicles, or

(2) vehicles of the type used in connection with motor vehicles which are highway vehicles.


Such term shall not include tires of a type used exclusively on vehicles described in section 4053(8).

(d) BiasplyFor purposes of this part, the term “biasply tire” means a pneumatic tire on which the ply cords that extend to the beads are laid at alternate angles substantially less than 90 degrees to the centerline of the tread.


(e) Super single tireFor purposes of this part, the term “super single tire” means a single tire greater than 13 inches in cross section width designed to replace 2 tires in a dual fitment. Such term shall not include any tire designed for steering.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 482; June 29, 1956, ch. 462, title II, § 204(b), 70 Stat. 389; Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 735(c)(3), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 982; Pub. L. 108–357, title VIII, §§ 851(c)(1), 869(b), Oct. 22, 2004, 118 Stat. 1608, 1623; Pub. L. 109–58, title XIII, § 1364(a), Aug. 8, 2005, 119 Stat. 1060.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2005—Subsec. (e). Pub. L. 109–58 inserted at end “Such term shall not include any tire designed for steering.”
2004—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 108–357, § 869(b), added subsec. (a) and redesignated former subsec. (a) as (b).
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 108–357, § 869(b), redesignated subsec. (a) as (b). Former subsec. (b) redesignated (c).
Pub. L. 108–357, § 851(c)(1), which directed amendment of par. (2) by inserti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4072_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable tire</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Taxable tire For purposes of this chapter, the term “taxable tire” means any tire of the type used on highway vehicles if wholly or in part made of rubber and if marked pursuant to Federal regulations for highway use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4072_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rubber</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rubber For purposes of this chapter, the term “rubber” includes synthetic and substitute rubber.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4072_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tires of the type used on highway vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tires of the type used on highway vehicles For purposes of this part, the term “tires of the type used on highway vehicles” means tires of the type used on— Such term shall not include tires of a type used exclusively on vehicles described in section 4053(8).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4072_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biasply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Biasply For purposes of this part, the term “biasply tire” means a pneumatic tire on which the ply cords that extend to the beads are laid at alternate angles substantially less than 90 degrees to the centerline of the tread.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4072_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Super single tire</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Super single tire For purposes of this part, the term “super single tire” means a single tire greater than 13 inches in cross section width designed to replace 2 tires in a dual fitment. Such term shall not include any tire designed for steering.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>