<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/408" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/408/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/408/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_408"><akn:num>408</akn:num><akn:heading>Individual retirement accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 408. Individual retirement accounts(a) Individual retirement accountFor purposes of this section, the term “individual retirement account” means a trust created or organized in the United States for the exclusive benefit of an individual or his beneficiaries, but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements:(1) Except in the case of a rollover contribution described in subsection (d)(3) or in section 402(c), 403(a)(4), 403(b)(8), or 457(e)(16), no contribution will be accepted unless it is in cash, and contributions will not be accepted for the taxable year on behalf of any individual in excess of the amount in effect for such taxable year under section 219(b)(1)(A).

(2) The trustee is a bank (as defined in subsection (n)) or such other person who demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the manner in which such other person will administer the trust will be consistent with the requirements of this section.

(3) No part of the trust funds will be invested in life insurance contracts.

(4) The interest of an individual in the balance in his account is nonforfeitable.

(5) The assets of the trust will not be commingled with other property except in a common trust fund or common investment fund.

(6) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, rules similar to the rules of section 401(a)(9) and the incidental death benefit requirements of section 401(a) shall apply to the distribution of the entire interest of an individual for whose benefit the trust is maintained.


(b) Individual retirement annuityFor purposes of this section, the term “individual retirement annuity” means an annuity contract, or an endowment contract (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary), issued by an insurance company which meets the following requirements:(1) The contract is not transferable by the owner.

(2) Under the contract—(A) the premiums are not fixed,

(B) the annual premium on behalf of any indiv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individual retirement account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Individual retirement account For purposes of this section, the term “individual retirement account” means a trust created or organized in the United States for the exclusive benefit of an individual or his beneficiaries, but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individual retirement annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Individual retirement annuity For purposes of this section, the term “individual retirement annuity” means an annuity contract, or an endowment contract (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary), issued by an insurance company which meets the following requirements: Such term does not include such an annuity contract for any taxable year of the owner in which it is disqualified on the application of subsection (e) or for any subsequent taxable year. For purposes of this subsection, no contract shall be treated as an endowment contract if it matures later than the taxable year in which the individual in whose name such contract is purchased attains the applicable age (determined under section 401(a)(9)(C)(v) for the calendar year in which such taxable year begins); if it is not for the exclusive benefit of the individual in whose name it is purchased or his beneficiaries; or if the aggregate annual premiums under all such contracts purchased in the name of such i</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounts established by employers and certain associations of employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Accounts established by employers and certain associations of employees A trust created or organized in the United States by an employer for the exclusive benefit of his employees or their beneficiaries, or by an association of employees (which may include employees within the meaning of section 401(c)(1)) for the exclusive benefit of its members or their beneficiaries, shall be treated as an individual retirement account (described in subsection (a)), but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements: The assets of the trust may be held in a common fund for the account of all individuals who have an interest in the trust.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of distributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tax treatment of distributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of accounts and annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Tax treatment of accounts and annuities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 99–514, title XI, § 1123(d)(2), Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2475]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(f) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community property laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Community property laws This section shall be applied without regard to any community property laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Custodial accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Custodial accounts For purposes of this section, a custodial account shall be treated as a trust if the assets of such account are held by a bank (as defined in subsection (n)) or another person who demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that the manner in which he will administer the account will be consistent with the requirements of this section, and if the custodial account would, except for the fact that it is not a trust, constitute an individual retirement account described in subsection (a). For purposes of this title, in the case of a custodial account treated as a trust by reason of the preceding sentence, the custodian of such account shall be treated as the trustee thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reports The trustee of an individual retirement account and the issuer of an endowment contract described in subsection (b) or an individual retirement annuity shall make such reports regarding such account, contract, or annuity to the Secretary and to the individuals for whom the account, contract, or annuity is, or is to be, maintained with respect to contributions (and the years to which they relate), distributions aggregating $10 or more in any calendar year, and such other matters as the Secretary may require. The reports required by this subsection— In the case of a simple retirement account under subsection (p), only one report under this subsection shall be required to be submitted each calendar year to the Secretary (at the time provided under paragraph (2)) but, in addition to the report under this subsection, there shall be furnished, within 31 days after each calendar year, to the individual on whose behalf the account is maintained a statement with respect to the accou</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_408_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increase in maximum limitations for simplified employee pensions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Increase in maximum limitations for simplified employee pensions In the case of any simplified employee pension, subsections (a)(1) and (b)(2) of this section shall be applied by increasing the amounts contained therein by the amount of the limitation in effect under section 415(c)(1)(A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>