<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4082" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4082/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4082/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4082"><akn:num>4082</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions for diesel fuel and kerosene</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4082. Exemptions for diesel fuel and kerosene(a) In generalThe tax imposed by section 4081 shall not apply to diesel fuel and kerosene—(1) which the Secretary determines is destined for a nontaxable use,

(2) which is indelibly dyed by mechanical injection in accordance with regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe, and

(3) which meets such marking requirements (if any) as may be prescribed by the Secretary in regulations.


Such regulations shall allow an individual choice of dye color approved by the Secretary or chosen from any list of approved dye colors that the Secretary may publish.

(b) Nontaxable useFor purposes of this section, the term “nontaxable use” means—(1) any use which is exempt from the tax imposed by section 4041(a)(1) other than by reason of a prior imposition of tax,

(2) any use in a train, and

(3) any use described in section 4041(a)(1)(C)(iii)(II).


The term “nontaxable use” does not include the use of kerosene in an aircraft and such term shall not include any use described in section 6421(e)(2)(C).

(c) Exception to dyeing requirementsParagraph (2) of subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any diesel fuel and kerosene—(1) removed, entered, or sold in a State for ultimate sale or use in an area of such State during the period such area is exempted from the fuel dyeing requirements under subsection (i) of section 211 of the Clean Air Act (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this subsection) by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under paragraph (4) of such subsection (i) (as so in effect), and

(2) the use of which is certified pursuant to regulations issued by the Secretary.


(d) Additional exceptions to dyeing requirements for kerosene(1) Use for non-fuel feedstock purposesSubsection (a)(2) shall not apply to kerosene—(A) received by pipeline or vessel for use by the person receiving the kerosene in the manufacture or production of any substance (other than gasoline, diesel fuel, or specia</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The tax imposed by section 4081 shall not apply to diesel fuel and kerosene— Such regulations shall allow an individual choice of dye color approved by the Secretary or chosen from any list of approved dye colors that the Secretary may publish.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nontaxable use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nontaxable use For purposes of this section, the term “nontaxable use” means— The term “nontaxable use” does not include the use of kerosene in an aircraft and such term shall not include any use described in section 6421(e)(2)(C).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception to dyeing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception to dyeing requirements Paragraph (2) of subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any diesel fuel and kerosene—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional exceptions to dyeing requirements for kerosene</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional exceptions to dyeing requirements for kerosene</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Kerosene removed into an aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Kerosene removed into an aircraft In the case of kerosene (other than kerosene with respect to which tax is imposed under section 4043) which is exempt from the tax imposed by section 4041(c) (other than by reason of a prior imposition of tax) and which is removed from any refinery or terminal directly into the fuel tank of an aircraft— For purposes of this subsection, any removal described in section 4081(a)(3)(A) shall be treated as a removal from a terminal but only if such terminal is located within a secure area of an airport.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exception for Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section, including regulations requiring the conspicuous labeling of retail diesel fuel and kerosene pumps and other delivery facilities to assure that persons are aware of which fuel is available only for nontaxable uses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4082_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cross reference For tax on train and certain bus uses of fuel purchased tax-free, see subsections (a)(1) and (d)(3) of section 4041.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>