<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/409" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/409/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/409/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_409"><akn:num>409</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications for tax credit employee stock ownership plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 409. Qualifications for tax credit employee stock ownership plans(a) Tax credit employee stock ownership plan definedExcept as otherwise provided in this title, for purposes of this title, the term “tax credit employee stock ownership plan” means a defined contribution plan which—(1) meets the requirements of section 401(a),

(2) is designed to invest primarily in employer securities, and

(3) meets the requirements of subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), and (o) of this section.


(b) Required allocation of employer securities(1) In generalA plan meets the requirements of this subsection if—(A) the plan provides for the allocation for the plan year of all employer securities transferred to it or purchased by it (because of the requirements of section 41(c)(1)(B)) 11 See References in Text note below. to the accounts of all participants who are entitled to share in such allocation, and

(B) for the plan year the allocation to each participant so entitled is an amount which bears substantially the same proportion to the amount of all such securities allocated to all such participants in the plan for that year as the amount of compensation paid to such participant during that year bears to the compensation paid to all such participants during that year.


(2) Compensation in excess of $100,000 disregardedFor purposes of paragraph (1), compensation of any participant in excess of the first $100,000 per year shall be disregarded.


(3) Determination of compensationFor purposes of this subsection, the amount of compensation paid to a participant for any period is the amount of such participant’s compensation (within the meaning of section 415(c)(3)) for such period.


(4) Suspension of allocation in certain casesNotwithstanding paragraph (1), the allocation to the account of any participant which is attributable to the basic employee plan credit or the credit allowed under section 41 1 (relating to the employee stock ownership credit) may be extended over wha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax credit employee stock ownership plan defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Tax credit employee stock ownership plan defined Except as otherwise provided in this title, for purposes of this title, the term “tax credit employee stock ownership plan” means a defined contribution plan which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required allocation of employer securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required allocation of employer securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participants must have nonforfeitable rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Participants must have nonforfeitable rights A plan meets the requirements of this subsection only if it provides that each participant has a nonforfeitable right to any employer security allocated to his account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer securities must stay in the plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Employer securities must stay in the plan A plan meets the requirements of this subsection only if it provides that no employer security allocated to a participant’s account under subsection (b) (or allocated to a participant’s account in connection with matched employer and employee contributions) may be distributed from that account before the end of the 84th month beginning after the month in which the security is allocated to the account. To the extent provided in the plan, the preceding sentence shall not apply in the case of— This subsection shall not apply to any distribution required under section 401(a)(9) or to any distribution or reinvestment required under section 401(a)(28).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Voting rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan must be established before employer’s due date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Plan must be established before employer’s due date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transferred amounts must stay in plan even though investment credit is redetermined or recaptured</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transferred amounts must stay in plan even though investment credit is redetermined or recaptured A plan meets the requirement of this subsection only if it provides that amounts which are transferred to the plan (because of the requirements of section 48(n)(1) or 41(c)(1)(B)) 1 shall remain in the plan (and, if allocated under the plan, shall remain so allocated) even though part or all of the employee plan credit or the credit allowed under section 41 1 (relating to employee stock ownership credit) is recaptured or redetermined. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the references to section 48(n)(1) 1 and the employee plan credit shall refer to such section and credit as in effect before the enactment of the Tax Reform Act of 1984.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to demand employer securities; put option</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Right to demand employer securities; put option</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement for expenses of establishing and administering plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reimbursement for expenses of establishing and administering plan A plan which otherwise meets the requirements of this section shall not be treated as failing to meet such requirements merely because it provides that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditional contributions to the plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Conditional contributions to the plan A plan which otherwise meets the requirements of this section shall not be treated as failing to satisfy such requirements (or as failing to satisfy the requirements of section 401(a) of this title or of section 403(c)(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974) merely because of the return of a contribution (or a provision permitting such a return) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>