<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/409A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/409A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/409A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_409A"><akn:num>409A</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion in gross income of deferred compensation under nonqualified deferred compensation plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 409A. Inclusion in gross income of deferred compensation under nonqualified deferred compensation plans(a) Rules relating to constructive receipt(1) Plan failures(A) Gross income inclusion(i) In generalIf at any time during a taxable year a nonqualified deferred compensation plan—(I) fails to meet the requirements of paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), or

(II) is not operated in accordance with such requirements,



 all compensation deferred under the plan for the taxable year and all preceding taxable years shall be includible in gross income for the taxable year to the extent not subject to a substantial risk of forfeiture and not previously included in gross income.
(ii) Application only to affected participantsClause (i) shall only apply with respect to all compensation deferred under the plan for participants with respect to whom the failure relates.



(B) Interest and additional tax payable with respect to previously deferred compensation(i) In generalIf compensation is required to be included in gross income under subparagraph (A) for a taxable year, the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year shall be increased by the sum of—(I) the amount of interest determined under clause (ii), and

(II) an amount equal to 20 percent of the compensation which is required to be included in gross income.


(ii) InterestFor purposes of clause (i), the interest determined under this clause for any taxable year is the amount of interest at the underpayment rate plus 1 percentage point on the underpayments that would have occurred had the deferred compensation been includible in gross income for the taxable year in which first deferred or, if later, the first taxable year in which such deferred compensation is not subject to a substantial risk of forfeiture.




(2) Distributions(A) In generalThe requirements of this paragraph are met if the plan provides that compensation deferred under the plan may not be distributed earlier than—(i) separation from service as determi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules relating to constructive receipt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules relating to constructive receipt</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules relating to funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rules relating to funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No inference on earlier income inclusion or requirement of later inclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No inference on earlier income inclusion or requirement of later inclusion Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the inclusion of amounts in gross income under any other provision of this chapter or any other rule of law earlier than the time provided in this section. Any amount included in gross income under this section shall not be required to be included in gross income under any other provision of this chapter or any other rule of law later than the time provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other definitions and special rules For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_409A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>