<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/412" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/412/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/412/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_412"><akn:num>412</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum funding standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 412. Minimum funding standards(a) Requirement to meet minimum funding standard(1) In generalA plan to which this section applies shall satisfy the minimum funding standard applicable to the plan for any plan year.


(2) Minimum funding standardFor purposes of paragraph (1), a plan shall be treated as satisfying the minimum funding standard for a plan year if—(A) in the case of a defined benefit plan which is not a multiemployer plan or a CSEC plan, the employer makes contributions to or under the plan for the plan year which, in the aggregate, are not less than the minimum required contribution determined under section 430 for the plan for the plan year,

(B) in the case of a money purchase plan which is not a multiemployer plan, the employer makes contributions to or under the plan for the plan year which are required under the terms of the plan,

(C) in the case of a multiemployer plan, the employers make contributions to or under the plan for any plan year which, in the aggregate, are sufficient to ensure that the plan does not have an accumulated funding deficiency under section 431 as of the end of the plan year, and

(D) in the case of a CSEC plan, the employers make contributions to or under the plan for any plan year which, in the aggregate, are sufficient to ensure that the plan does not have an accumulated funding deficiency under section 433 as of the end of the plan year.



(b) Liability for contributions(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the amount of any contribution required by this section (including any required installments under paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 430(j) or under section 433(f)) shall be paid by the employer responsible for making contributions to or under the plan.


(2) Joint and several liability where employer member of controlled groupIf the employer referred to in paragraph (1) is a member of a controlled group, each member of such group shall be jointly and severally liable for payment of such contributions</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to meet minimum funding standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement to meet minimum funding standard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Liability for contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Variance from minimum funding standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Variance from minimum funding standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Miscellaneous rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans to which section applies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Plans to which section applies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>