<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/414" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/414/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/414/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_414"><akn:num>414</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 414. Definitions and special rules(a) Service for predecessor employerFor purposes of this part—(1) in any case in which the employer maintains a plan of a predecessor employer, service for such predecessor shall be treated as service for the employer, and

(2) in any case in which the employer maintains a plan which is not the plan maintained by a predecessor employer, service for such predecessor shall, to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be treated as service for the employer.


(b) Employees of controlled group of corporations(1) In generalFor purposes of sections 401, 408(k), 408(p), 410, 411, 415, and 416, all employees of all corporations which are members of a controlled group of corporations (within the meaning of section 1563(a), determined without regard to section 1563(a)(4) and (e)(3)(C)) shall be treated as employed by a single employer. With respect to a plan adopted by more than one such corporation, the applicable limitations provided by section 404(a) shall be determined as if all such employers were a single employer, and allocated to each employer in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(2) Special rules for applying family attributionFor purposes of applying the attribution rules under section 1563 with respect to paragraph (1), the following rules apply:(A) Community property laws shall be disregarded for purposes of determining ownership.

(B) Except as provided by the Secretary, stock of an individual not attributed under section 1563(e)(5) to such individual’s spouse shall not be attributed to such spouse by reason of the combined application of paragraphs (1) and (6)(A) of section 1563(e).

(C) Except as provided by the Secretary, in the case of stock in different corporations that is attributed to a child under section 1563(e)(6)(A) from each parent, and is not attributed to such parents as spouses under section 1563(e)(5), such attribution to the child shall not by itself result in su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service for predecessor employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Service for predecessor employer For purposes of this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees of controlled group of corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Employees of controlled group of corporations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees of partnerships, proprietorships, etc., which are under common control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Employees of partnerships, proprietorships, etc., which are under common control</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governmental plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Governmental plan For purposes of this part, the term “governmental plan” means a plan established and maintained for its employees by the Government of the United States, by the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, or by any agency or instrumentality of any of the foregoing. The term “governmental plan” also includes any plan to which the Railroad Retirement Act of 1935 or 1937 applies and which is financed by contributions required under that Act and any plan of an international organization which is exempt from taxation by reason of the International Organizations Immunities Act (59 Stat. 669). The term “governmental plan” includes a plan which is established and maintained by an Indian tribal government (as defined in section 7701(a)(40)), a subdivision of an Indian tribal government (determined in accordance with section 7871(d)), or an agency or instrumentality of either, and all of the participants of which are employees of such entity substantially all </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Church plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Church plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiemployer plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Multiemployer plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Plan administrator For purposes of this part, the term “plan administrator” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of certain contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Tax treatment of certain contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defined contribution plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Defined contribution plan For purposes of this part, the term “defined contribution plan” means a plan which provides for an individual account for each participant and for benefits based solely on the amount contributed to the participant’s account, and any income, expenses, gains and losses, and any forfeitures of accounts of other participants which may be allocated to such participant’s account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defined benefit plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Defined benefit plan For purposes of this part, the term “defined benefit plan” means any plan which is not a defined contribution plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>