<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4161" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4161/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4161/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4161"><akn:num>4161</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4161. Imposition of tax(a) Sport fishing equipment(1) Imposition of tax(A) In generalThere is hereby imposed on the sale of any article of sport fishing equipment by the manufacturer, producer, or importer a tax equal to 10 percent of the price for which so sold.


(B) Limitation on tax imposed on fishing rods and polesThe tax imposed by subparagraph (A) on any fishing rod or pole shall not exceed $10.



(2) 3 percent rate of tax for electric outboard motorsIn the case of an electric outboard motor, paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting “3 percent” for “10 percent”.


(3) 3 percent rate of tax for tackle boxesIn the case of fishing tackle boxes, paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting “3 percent” for “10 percent”.


(4) Parts or accessories sold in connection with taxable saleIn the case of any sale by the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any article of sport fishing equipment, such article shall be treated as including any parts or accessories of such article sold on or in connection therewith or with the sale thereof.



(b) Bows and arrows, etc.(1) Bows(A) In generalThere is hereby imposed on the sale by the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any bow which has a peak draw weight of 30 pounds or more, a tax equal to 11 percent of the price for which so sold.


(B) Archery equipmentThere is hereby imposed on the sale by the manufacturer, producer, or importer—(i) of any part or accessory suitable for inclusion in or attachment to a bow described in subparagraph (A), and

(ii) of any quiver, broadhead, or point suitable for use with an arrow described in paragraph (2),


a tax equal to 11 percent of the price for which so sold.


(2) Arrows(A) In generalThere is hereby imposed on the first sale by the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any shaft (whether sold separately or incorporated as part of a finished or unfinished product) of a type used in the manufacture of any arrow which after its assembly—(i) measures 18 inches overall or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4161_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sport fishing equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sport fishing equipment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4161_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bows and arrows, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Bows and arrows, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>