<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/418E" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/418E/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/418E/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_418E"><akn:num>418E</akn:num><akn:heading>Insolvent plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 418E. Insolvent plans(a) Suspension of certain benefit paymentsNotwithstanding section 411, in any case in which benefit payments under an insolvent multiemployer plan exceed the resource benefit level, any such payments of benefits which are not basic benefits shall be suspended, in accordance with this section, to the extent necessary to reduce the sum of such payments and the payments of such basic benefits to the greater of the resource benefit level or the level of basic benefits, unless an alternative procedure is prescribed by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation under section 4022A(g)(5) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.


(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, for a plan year—(1) InsolvencyA multiemployer plan is insolvent if the plan’s available resources are not sufficient to pay benefits under the plan when due for the plan year, or if the plan is determined to be insolvent under subsection (d).


(2) Resource benefit levelThe term “resource benefit level” means the level of monthly benefits determined under subsections (c)(1) and (3) and (d)(3) to be the highest level which can be paid out of the plan’s available resources.


(3) Available resourcesThe term “available resources” means the plan’s cash, marketable assets, contributions, withdrawal liability payments, and earnings, less reasonable administrative expenses and amounts owed for such plan year to the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation under section 4261(b)(2) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.


(4) Insolvency yearThe term “insolvency year” means a plan year in which a plan is insolvent.



(c) Benefit payments under insolvent plans(1) Determination of resource benefit levelThe plan sponsor of a plan in critical status, as described in section 432(b)(2), shall determine in writing the plan’s resource benefit level for each insolvency year, based on the plan sponsor’s reasonable projection of the plan’s available resources and the benefit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418E_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of certain benefit payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Suspension of certain benefit payments Notwithstanding section 411, in any case in which benefit payments under an insolvent multiemployer plan exceed the resource benefit level, any such payments of benefits which are not basic benefits shall be suspended, in accordance with this section, to the extent necessary to reduce the sum of such payments and the payments of such basic benefits to the greater of the resource benefit level or the level of basic benefits, unless an alternative procedure is prescribed by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation under section 4022A(g)(5) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418E_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section, for a plan year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418E_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefit payments under insolvent plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Benefit payments under insolvent plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418E_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan sponsor determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Plan sponsor determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418E_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418E_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418E_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Financial assistance Any amount of any financial assistance from the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation to any plan, and any repayment of such amount, shall be taken into account under this subpart in such manner as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418E_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Subsections (a) and (c) shall not apply to a plan that, for the plan year, is operating under section 432(e)(9), regarding benefit suspensions by certain multiemployer plans in critical and declining status.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>