<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/419" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/419/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/419/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_419"><akn:num>419</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of funded welfare benefit plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 419. Treatment of funded welfare benefit plans(a) General ruleContributions paid or accrued by an employer to a welfare benefit fund—(1) shall not be deductible under this chapter, but

(2) if they would otherwise be deductible, shall (subject to the limitation of subsection (b)) be deductible under this section for the taxable year in which paid.


(b) LimitationThe amount of the deduction allowable under subsection (a)(2) for any taxable year shall not exceed the welfare benefit fund’s qualified cost for the taxable year.


(c) Qualified costFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this subsection, the term “qualified cost” means, with respect to any taxable year, the sum of—(A) the qualified direct cost for such taxable year, and

(B) subject to the limitation of section 419A(b), any addition to a qualified asset account for the taxable year.


(2) Reduction for funds after-tax incomeIn the case of any welfare benefit fund, the qualified cost for any taxable year shall be reduced by such fund’s after-tax income for such taxable year.


(3) Qualified direct cost(A) In generalThe term “qualified direct cost” means, with respect to any taxable year, the aggregate amount (including administrative expenses) which would have been allowable as a deduction to the employer with respect to the benefits provided during the taxable year, if—(i) such benefits were provided directly by the employer, and

(ii) the employer used the cash receipts and disbursements method of accounting.


(B) Time when benefits providedFor purposes of subparagraph (A), a benefit shall be treated as provided when such benefit would be includible in the gross income of the employee if provided directly by the employer (or would be so includible but for any provision of this chapter excluding such benefit from gross income).


(C) 60-month amortization of child care facilities(i) In generalIn determining qualified direct costs with respect to any child care facili</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_419_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Contributions paid or accrued by an employer to a welfare benefit fund—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_419_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation The amount of the deduction allowable under subsection (a)(2) for any taxable year shall not exceed the welfare benefit fund’s qualified cost for the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_419_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified cost</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualified cost For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_419_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryover of excess contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Carryover of excess contributions If— such excess shall be treated as an amount paid by the employer to such fund during the succeeding taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_419_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Welfare benefit fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Welfare benefit fund For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_419_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of contributions, etc., having the effect of a plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Method of contributions, etc., having the effect of a plan If— this section shall apply as if there were a plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_419_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension to plans for independent contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Extension to plans for independent contractors If any fund would be a welfare benefit fund (as modified by subsection (f)) but for the fact that there is no employee-employer relationship—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>