<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4216" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4216/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4216/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4216"><akn:num>4216</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4216. Definition of price(a) Containers, packing and transportation charges.In determining, for the purposes of this chapter, the price for which an article is sold, there shall be included any charge for coverings and containers of whatever nature, and any charge incident to placing the article in condition packed ready for shipment, but there shall be excluded the amount of tax imposed by this chapter, whether or not stated as a separate charge. A transportation, delivery, insurance, installation, or other charge (not required by the foregoing sentence to be included) shall be excluded from the price only if the amount thereof is established to the satisfaction of the Secretary in accordance with the regulations.


(b) Constructive sale price(1) In generalIf an article is—(A) sold at retail,

(B) sold on consignment, or

(C) sold (otherwise than through an arm’s length transaction) at less than the fair market price,


the tax under this chapter shall (if based on the price for which the article is sold) be computed on the price for which such articles are sold, in the ordinary course of trade, by manufacturers or producers thereof, as determined by the Secretary. In the case of an article sold at retail, the computation under the preceding sentence shall be on whichever of the following prices is the lower: (i) the price for which such article is sold, or (ii) the highest price for which such articles are sold to wholesale distributors, in the ordinary course of trade, by manufacturers or producers thereof, as determined by the Secretary. This paragraph shall not apply if paragraph (2) applies.

(2) Special ruleIf an article is sold at retail or to a retailer, and if—(A) the manufacturer, producer, or importer of such article regularly sells such articles at retail or to retailers, as the case may be,

(B) the manufacturer, producer, or importer of such article regularly sells such articles to one or more wholesale distributors in arm’s length transactions and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4216_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Containers, packing and transportation charges.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Containers, packing and transportation charges. In determining, for the purposes of this chapter, the price for which an article is sold, there shall be included any charge for coverings and containers of whatever nature, and any charge incident to placing the article in condition packed ready for shipment, but there shall be excluded the amount of tax imposed by this chapter, whether or not stated as a separate charge. A transportation, delivery, insurance, installation, or other charge (not required by the foregoing sentence to be included) shall be excluded from the price only if the amount thereof is established to the satisfaction of the Secretary in accordance with the regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4216_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Constructive sale price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Constructive sale price</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4216_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partial payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Partial payments In the case of— there shall be paid upon each payment with respect to the article a percentage of such payment equal to the rate of tax in effect on the date such payment is due.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4216_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales of installment accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Sales of installment accounts If installment accounts, with respect to payments on which tax is being computed as provided in subsection (c), are sold or otherwise disposed of, then subsection (c) shall not apply with respect to any subsequent payments on such accounts (other than subsequent payments on returned accounts with respect to which credit or refund is allowable by reason of section 6416(b)(5)), but instead— The sum of the amounts payable under this subsection and subsection (c) in respect of the sale of any article shall not exceed the total tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4216_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of local advertising charge from sale price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusion of local advertising charge from sale price</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>