<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4221" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4221/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4221/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4221"><akn:num>4221</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain tax-free sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4221. Certain tax-free sales(a) General ruleUnder regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under this chapter (other than under section 4121 or 4081) on the sale by the manufacturer (or under subchapter C of chapter 31 on the first retail sale) of an article—(1) for use by the purchaser for further manufacture, or for resale by the purchaser to a second purchaser for use by such second purchaser in further manufacture,

(2) for export, or for resale by the purchaser to a second purchaser for export,

(3) for use by the purchaser as supplies for vessels or aircraft,

(4) to a State or local government for the exclusive use of a State or local government,

(5) to a nonprofit educational organization for its exclusive use, or

(6) to a qualified blood collector organization (as defined in section 7701(a)(49)) for such organization’s exclusive use in the collection, storage, or transportation of blood,


but only if such exportation or use is to occur before any other use. Paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) shall not apply to the tax imposed by section 4064. In the case of taxes imposed by section 4051 or 4071, paragraphs (4) and (5) shall not apply on and after October 1, 2028. In the case of the tax imposed by section 4131, paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) shall not apply and paragraph (2) shall apply only if the use of the exported vaccine meets such requirements as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe. In the case of taxes imposed by subchapter C or D, paragraph (6) shall not apply.

(b) Proof of resale for further manufacture; proof of exportWhere an article has been sold free of tax under subsection (a)—(1) for resale by the purchaser to a second purchaser for use by such second purchaser in further manufacture, or

(2) for export, or for resale by the purchaser to a second purchaser for export,


subsection (a) shall cease to apply in respect of such sale of such article unless, within the 6-month period which begins on the date of the sale </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4221_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under this chapter (other than under section 4121 or 4081) on the sale by the manufacturer (or under subchapter C of chapter 31 on the first retail sale) of an article— but only if such exportation or use is to occur before any other use. Paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) shall not apply to the tax imposed by section 4064. In the case of taxes imposed by section 4051 or 4071, paragraphs (4) and (5) shall not apply on and after October 1, 2028. In the case of the tax imposed by section 4131, paragraphs (3), (4), and (5) shall not apply and paragraph (2) shall apply only if the use of the exported vaccine meets such requirements as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe. In the case of taxes imposed by subchapter C or D, paragraph (6) shall not apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4221_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proof of resale for further manufacture; proof of export</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Proof of resale for further manufacture; proof of export Where an article has been sold free of tax under subsection (a)— subsection (a) shall cease to apply in respect of such sale of such article unless, within the 6-month period which begins on the date of the sale by the manufacturer (or, if earlier, on the date of shipment by the manufacturer), the manufacturer receives proof that the article has been exported or resold for use in further manufacture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4221_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturer relieved from liability in certain cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Manufacturer relieved from liability in certain cases In the case of any article sold free of tax under this section (other than a sale to which subsection (b) applies), and in the case of any article sold free of tax under section 4053(6), if the manufacturer in good faith accepts a certification by the purchaser that the article will be used in accordance with the applicable provisions of law, no tax shall thereafter be imposed under this chapter in respect of such sale by such manufacturer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4221_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4221_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>