<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/424" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/424/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/424/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_424"><akn:num>424</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 424. Definitions and special rules(a) Corporate reorganizations, liquidations, etc.For purposes of this part, the term “issuing or assuming a stock option in a transaction to which section 424(a) applies” means a substitution of a new option for the old option, or an assumption of the old option, by an employer corporation, or a parent or subsidiary of such corporation, by reason of a corporate merger, consolidation, acquisition of property or stock, separation, reorganization, or liquidation, if—(1) the excess of the aggregate fair market value of the shares subject to the option immediately after the substitution or assumption over the aggregate option price of such shares is not more than the excess of the aggregate fair market value of all shares subject to the option immediately before such substitution or assumption over the aggregate option price of such shares, and

(2) the new option or the assumption of the old option does not give the employee additional benefits which he did not have under the old option.


For purposes of this subsection, the parent-subsidiary relationship shall be determined at the time of any such transaction under this subsection.

(b) Acquisition of new stockFor purposes of this part, if stock is received by an individual in a distribution to which section 305, 354, 355, 356, or 1036 (or so much of section 1031 as relates to section 1036) applies, and such distribution was made with respect to stock transferred to him upon his exercise of the option, such stock shall be considered as having been transferred to him on his exercise of such option. A similar rule shall be applied in the case of a series of such distributions.


(c) Disposition(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), for purposes of this part, the term “disposition” includes a sale, exchange, gift, or a transfer of legal title, but does not include—(A) a transfer from a decedent to an estate or a transfer by bequest or inheritance;

(B) an exc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporate reorganizations, liquidations, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Corporate reorganizations, liquidations, etc. For purposes of this part, the term “issuing or assuming a stock option in a transaction to which section 424(a) applies” means a substitution of a new option for the old option, or an assumption of the old option, by an employer corporation, or a parent or subsidiary of such corporation, by reason of a corporate merger, consolidation, acquisition of property or stock, separation, reorganization, or liquidation, if— For purposes of this subsection, the parent-subsidiary relationship shall be determined at the time of any such transaction under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of new stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acquisition of new stock For purposes of this part, if stock is received by an individual in a distribution to which section 305, 354, 355, 356, or 1036 (or so much of section 1031 as relates to section 1036) applies, and such distribution was made with respect to stock transferred to him upon his exercise of the option, such stock shall be considered as having been transferred to him on his exercise of such option. A similar rule shall be applied in the case of a series of such distributions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disposition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attribution of stock ownership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Attribution of stock ownership For purposes of this part, in applying the percentage limitations of sections 422(b)(6) and 423(b)(3)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Parent corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Parent corporation For purposes of this part, the term “parent corporation” means any corporation (other than the employer corporation) in an unbroken chain of corporations ending with the employer corporation if, at the time of the granting of the option, each of the corporations other than the employer corporation owns stock possessing 50 percent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock in one of the other corporations in such chain.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsidiary corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Subsidiary corporation For purposes of this part, the term “subsidiary corporation” means any corporation (other than the employer corporation) in an unbroken chain of corporations beginning with the employer corporation if, at the time of the granting of the option, each of the corporations other than the last corporation in the unbroken chain owns stock possessing 50 percent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock in one of the other corporations in such chain.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for applying subsections (e) and (f)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rule for applying subsections (e) and (f) In applying subsections (e) and (f) for purposes of sections 422(a)(2) and 423(a)(2), there shall be substituted for the term “employer corporation” wherever it appears in subsections (e) and (f) the term “grantor corporation” or the term “corporation issuing or assuming a stock option in a transaction to which section 424(a) applies”, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification, extension, or renewal of option</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Modification, extension, or renewal of option</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stockholder approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Stockholder approval For purposes of this part, if the grant of an option is subject to approval by stockholders, the date of grant of the option shall be determined as if the option had not been subject to such approval.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_424_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cross references For provisions requiring the reporting of certain acts with respect to a qualified stock option, an incentive stock option, options granted under employer stock purchase plans, or a restricted stock option, see section 6039.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>