<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4253" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4253/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4253/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4253"><akn:num>4253</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4253. Exemptions(a) Certain coin-operated serviceService paid for by inserting coins in coin-operated telephones available to the public shall not be subject to the tax imposed by section 4251 with respect to local telephone service, or with respect to toll telephone service if the charge for such toll telephone service is less than 25 cents; except that where such coin-operated telephone service is furnished for a guaranteed amount, the amounts paid under such guarantee plus any fixed monthly or other periodic charge shall be subject to the tax.


(b) News servicesNo tax shall be imposed under section 4251, except with respect to local telephone service, on any payment received from any person for services used in the collection of news for the public press, or a news ticker service furnishing a general news service similar to that of the public press, or radio broadcasting, or in the dissemination of news through the public press, or a news ticker service furnishing a general news service similar to that of the public press, or by means of radio broadcasting, if the charge for such service is billed in writing to such person.


(c) International, etc., organizationsNo tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any payment received for services furnished to an international organization, or to the American National Red Cross.


(d) Servicemen in combat zoneNo tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any payment received for any toll telephone service which originates within a combat zone, as defined in section 112, from a member of the Armed Forces of the United States performing service in such combat zone, as determined under such section, provided a certificate, setting forth such facts as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, is furnished to the person receiving such payment.


(e) Items otherwise taxedOnly one payment of tax under section 4251 shall be required with respect to the tax on any service, notwithstanding the lines or stations of one or mo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain coin-operated service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Certain coin-operated service Service paid for by inserting coins in coin-operated telephones available to the public shall not be subject to the tax imposed by section 4251 with respect to local telephone service, or with respect to toll telephone service if the charge for such toll telephone service is less than 25 cents; except that where such coin-operated telephone service is furnished for a guaranteed amount, the amounts paid under such guarantee plus any fixed monthly or other periodic charge shall be subject to the tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>News services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) News services No tax shall be imposed under section 4251, except with respect to local telephone service, on any payment received from any person for services used in the collection of news for the public press, or a news ticker service furnishing a general news service similar to that of the public press, or radio broadcasting, or in the dissemination of news through the public press, or a news ticker service furnishing a general news service similar to that of the public press, or by means of radio broadcasting, if the charge for such service is billed in writing to such person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>International, etc., organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) International, etc., organizations No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any payment received for services furnished to an international organization, or to the American National Red Cross.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Servicemen in combat zone</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Servicemen in combat zone No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any payment received for any toll telephone service which originates within a combat zone, as defined in section 112, from a member of the Armed Forces of the United States performing service in such combat zone, as determined under such section, provided a certificate, setting forth such facts as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, is furnished to the person receiving such payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Items otherwise taxed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Items otherwise taxed Only one payment of tax under section 4251 shall be required with respect to the tax on any service, notwithstanding the lines or stations of one or more persons are used in furnishing such service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common carriers and communications companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Common carriers and communications companies No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on the amount paid for any toll telephone service described in section 4252(b)(2) to the extent that the amount so paid is for use by a common carrier, telephone or telegraph company, or radio broadcasting station or network in the conduct of its business as such.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Installation charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Installation charges No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on so much of any amount paid for the installation of any instrument, wire, pole, switchboard, apparatus, or equipment as is properly attributable to such installation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonprofit hospitals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Nonprofit hospitals No tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any amount paid by a nonprofit hospital for services furnished to such organization. For purposes of this subsection, the term “nonprofit hospital” means a hospital referred to in section 170(b)(1)(A)(iii) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local governmental exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) State and local governmental exemption Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under section 4251 upon any payment received for services or facilities furnished to the government of any State, or any political subdivision thereof, or the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for nonprofit educational organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exemption for nonprofit educational organizations Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no tax shall be imposed under section 4251 on any amount paid by a nonprofit educational organization for services or facilities furnished to such organization. For purposes of this subsection, the term “nonprofit educational organization” means an educational organization described in section 170(b)(1)(A)(ii) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a). The term also includes a school operated as an activity of an organization described in section 501(c)(3) which is exempt from income tax under section 501(a), if such school normally maintains a regular faculty and curriculum and normally has a regularly enrolled body of pupils or students in attendance at the place where its educational activities are regularly carried on.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>