<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4261" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4261/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4261/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4261"><akn:num>4261</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4261. Imposition of tax(a) In generalThere is hereby imposed on the amount paid for taxable transportation of any person a tax equal to 7.5 percent of the amount so paid.


(b) Domestic segments of taxable transportation(1) In generalThere is hereby imposed on the amount paid for each domestic segment of taxable transportation by air a tax in the amount of $3.00.


(2) Domestic segmentFor purposes of this section, the term “domestic segment” means any segment consisting of 1 takeoff and 1 landing and which is taxable transportation described in section 4262(a)(1).


(3) Changes in segments by reason of reroutingIf—(A) transportation is purchased between 2 locations on specified flights, and

(B) there is a change in the route taken between such 2 locations which changes the number of domestic segments, but there is no change in the amount charged for such transportation,


the tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall be determined without regard to such change in route.


(c) Use of international travel facilities(1) In generalThere is hereby imposed a tax of $12.00 on any amount paid (whether within or without the United States) for any transportation of any person by air, if such transportation begins or ends in the United States.


(2) Exception for transportation entirely taxable under subsection (a)This subsection shall not apply to any transportation all of which is taxable under subsection (a) (determined without regard to sections 4281 and 4282).


(3) Special rule for Alaska and HawaiiIn any case in which the tax imposed by paragraph (1) applies to a domestic segment beginning or ending in Alaska or Hawaii, such tax shall apply only to departures and shall be at the rate of $6.



(d) By whom paidExcept as provided in section 4263(a), the taxes imposed by this section shall be paid by the person making the payment subject to the tax.


(e) Special rules(1) Segments to and from rural airports(A) Exception from segment taxThe tax imposed by subsection (b)(1) shal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is hereby imposed on the amount paid for taxable transportation of any person a tax equal to 7.5 percent of the amount so paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic segments of taxable transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Domestic segments of taxable transportation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of international travel facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of international travel facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>By whom paid</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) By whom paid Except as provided in section 4263(a), the taxes imposed by this section shall be paid by the person making the payment subject to the tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for certain uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemption for certain uses No tax shall be imposed under subsection (a) or (b) on air transportation— but only if the helicopter or fixed-wing aircraft does not take off from, or land at, a facility eligible for assistance under the Airport and Airway Development Act of 1970, or otherwise use services provided pursuant to section 44509 or 44913(b) or subchapter I of chapter 471 of title 49, United States Code, during such use. In the case of helicopter transportation described in paragraph (1), this subsection shall be applied by treating each flight segment as a distinct flight.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for air ambulances providing certain emergency medical transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exemption for air ambulances providing certain emergency medical transportation No tax shall be imposed under this section or section 4271 on any air transportation for the purpose of providing emergency medical services—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for skydiving uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exemption for skydiving uses No tax shall be imposed by this section or section 4271 on any air transportation exclusively for the purpose of skydiving.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for seaplanes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Exemption for seaplanes No tax shall be imposed by this section or section 4271 on any air transportation by a seaplane with respect to any segment consisting of a takeoff from, and a landing on, water, but only if the places at which such takeoff and landing occur have not received and are not receiving financial assistance from the Airport and Airways Trust Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4261_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for aircraft in fractional ownership aircraft programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exemption for aircraft in fractional ownership aircraft programs No tax shall be imposed by this section or section 4271 on any air transportation if tax is imposed under section 4043 with respect to the fuel used in such transportation. This subsection shall not apply after September 30, 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>