<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4371" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4371/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4371/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4371"><akn:num>4371</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4371. Imposition of tax
There is hereby imposed, on each policy of insurance, indemnity bond, annuity contract, or policy of reinsurance issued by any foreign insurer or reinsurer, a tax at the following rates:(1) Casualty insurance and indemnity bonds4 cents on each dollar, or fractional part thereof, of the premium paid on the policy of casualty insurance or the indemnity bond, if issued to or for, or in the name of, an insured as defined in section 4372(d);


(2) Life insurance, sickness, and accident policies, and annuity contracts1 cent on each dollar, or fractional part thereof, of the premium paid on the policy of life, sickness, or accident insurance, or annuity contract; and


(3) Reinsurance1 cent on each dollar, or fractional part thereof, of the premium paid on the policy of reinsurance covering any of the contracts taxable under paragraph (1) or (2).


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 521; Mar. 13, 1956, ch. 83, § 5(9), 70 Stat. 49; Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 141(a), Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1300; Pub. L. 86–69, § 3(f)(3), June 25, 1959, 73 Stat. 140; Pub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 804(b), June 21, 1965, 79 Stat. 160; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1904(a)(12), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1812; Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title II, § 211(b)(23), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 757; Pub. L. 100–203, title X, § 10242(c)(3), Dec. 22, 1987, 101 Stat. 1330–423; Pub. L. 101–239, title VII, § 7811(i)(11), Dec. 19, 1989, 103 Stat. 2411.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1989—Par. (2). Pub. L. 101–239 struck out “, unless the insurer is subject to tax under section 842(b)” after “or annuity contract”.
1987—Par. (2). Pub. L. 100–203 substituted “section 842(b)” for “section 813”.
1984—Par. (2). Pub. L. 98–369 substituted “section 813” for “section 819”.
1976—Pub. L. 94–455 substituted in par. (1) “4 cents” for “four cents” and “premium paid” for “premium charged”, in pars. (2) and (3) “1 cent” for “one cent” and “premium paid” for “premium charged”, and struck out provision following pa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4371_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Casualty insurance and indemnity bonds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Casualty insurance and indemnity bonds 4 cents on each dollar, or fractional part thereof, of the premium paid on the policy of casualty insurance or the indemnity bond, if issued to or for, or in the name of, an insured as defined in section 4372(d);</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4371_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life insurance, sickness, and accident policies, and annuity contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Life insurance, sickness, and accident policies, and annuity contracts 1 cent on each dollar, or fractional part thereof, of the premium paid on the policy of life, sickness, or accident insurance, or annuity contract; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4371_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reinsurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Reinsurance 1 cent on each dollar, or fractional part thereof, of the premium paid on the policy of reinsurance covering any of the contracts taxable under paragraph (1) or (2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>