<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4373" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4373/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4373/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4373"><akn:num>4373</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4373. Exemptions
The tax imposed by section 4371 shall not apply to—(1) Effectively connected itemsAny amount which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States unless such amount is exempt from the application of section 882(a) pursuant to a treaty obligation of the United States.


(2) Indemnity bondAny indemnity bond required to be filed by any person to secure payment of any pension, allowance, allotment, relief, or insurance by the United States, or to secure a duplicate for, or the payment of, any bond, note, certificate of indebtedness, war-saving certificate, warrant or check, issued by the United States.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 522; Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 141(a), Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1301; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1904(a)(12), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1813; Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1012(q)(13)(A), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3525.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1988—Par. (1). Pub. L. 100–647 amended par. (1) generally, substituting provisions relating to effectively connected items for provisions relating to domestic agent.
1976—Par. (1). Pub. L. 94–455 substituted “State, or in the District of Columbia, within” for “State, Territory, or District of the United States within”.
1958—Pub. L. 85–859 reenacted section without change.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1988 AmendmentPub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1012(q)(13)(B), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3525, provided that: “The amendment made by subparagraph (A) [amending this section] shall apply with respect to premiums paid after the date 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [Nov. 10, 1988].”


Effective Date of 1976 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 94–455 effective on first day of first month which begins more than 90 days after Oct. 4, 1976, see section 1904(d) of Pub. L. 94–455, set out as a note under section 4041 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4373_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effectively connected items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Effectively connected items Any amount which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States unless such amount is exempt from the application of section 882(a) pursuant to a treaty obligation of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4373_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indemnity bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Indemnity bond Any indemnity bond required to be filed by any person to secure payment of any pension, allowance, allotment, relief, or insurance by the United States, or to secure a duplicate for, or the payment of, any bond, note, certificate of indebtedness, war-saving certificate, warrant or check, issued by the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>