<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4374" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4374/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4374/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4374"><akn:num>4374</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4374. Liability for tax
The tax imposed by this chapter shall be paid, on the basis of a return, by any person who makes, signs, issues, or sells any of the documents and instruments subject to the tax, or for whose use or benefit the same are made, signed, issued, or sold. The United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof shall not be liable for the tax.
(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 522; Pub. L. 85–859, title I, § 141(a), Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1301; Pub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 804(a)(1), (2), June 21, 1965, 79 Stat. 160; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1904(a)(12), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1813.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsFor provisions of prior sections 4375, 4381 to 4384, see Prior Provisions note preceding section 4371 of this title.

Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–455 substituted in section catchline “Liability for tax” for “Payment of tax” and in text provisions relating to payment of tax on basis of a return and to tax-exempt status of United States and its agencies and instrumentalities for provisions relating to placing of stamps on any policy, indemnity bond, or annuity contract referred to in section 4371 and to regulation by Secretary that tax be paid on basis of a return.
1965—Pub. L. 89–44 substituted “Payment of tax” for “Affixing of stamps” in section catchline, and inserted sentence authorizing Secretary or his delegate to provide by regulation for payment on basis of a return of tax imposed by section 4371.
1958—Pub. L. 85–859 reenacted section without change.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1976 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 94–455 effective on first day of first month which begins more than 90 days after Oct. 4, 1976, see section 1904(d) of Pub. L. 94–455, set out as a note under section 4041 of this title.

Effective Date of 1965 AmendmentPub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 804(c), June 21, 1965, 79 Stat. 160, provided that: “The amendments made by subsection (a) [amending this section] shall take effect on </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>