<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4375" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4375/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4375/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4375"><akn:num>4375</akn:num><akn:heading>Health insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4375. Health insurance(a) Imposition of feeThere is hereby imposed on each specified health insurance policy for each policy year ending after September 30, 2012, a fee equal to the product of $2 ($1 in the case of policy years ending during fiscal year 2013) multiplied by the average number of lives covered under the policy.


(b) Liability for feeThe fee imposed by subsection (a) shall be paid by the issuer of the policy.


(c) Specified health insurance policyFor purposes of this section:(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this section, the term “specified health insurance policy” means any accident or health insurance policy (including a policy under a group health plan) issued with respect to individuals residing in the United States.


(2) Exemption for certain policiesThe term “specified health insurance policy” does not include any insurance if substantially all of its coverage is of excepted benefits described in section 9832(c).


(3) Treatment of prepaid health coverage arrangements(A) In generalIn the case of any arrangement described in subparagraph (B), such arrangement shall be treated as a specified health insurance policy, and the person referred to in such subparagraph shall be treated as the issuer.


(B) Description of arrangementsAn arrangement is described in this subparagraph if under such arrangement fixed payments or premiums are received as consideration for any person’s agreement to provide or arrange for the provision of accident or health coverage to residents of the United States, regardless of how such coverage is provided or arranged to be provided.




(d) Adjustments for increases in health care spendingIn the case of any policy year ending in any fiscal year beginning after September 30, 2014, the dollar amount in effect under subsection (a) for such policy year shall be equal to the sum of such dollar amount for policy years ending in the previous fiscal year (determined after the application of this subsection), plus </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4375_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Imposition of fee There is hereby imposed on each specified health insurance policy for each policy year ending after September 30, 2012, a fee equal to the product of $2 ($1 in the case of policy years ending during fiscal year 2013) multiplied by the average number of lives covered under the policy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4375_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Liability for fee The fee imposed by subsection (a) shall be paid by the issuer of the policy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4375_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specified health insurance policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Specified health insurance policy For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4375_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments for increases in health care spending</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adjustments for increases in health care spending In the case of any policy year ending in any fiscal year beginning after September 30, 2014, the dollar amount in effect under subsection (a) for such policy year shall be equal to the sum of such dollar amount for policy years ending in the previous fiscal year (determined after the application of this subsection), plus an amount equal to the product of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4375_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination This section shall not apply to policy years ending after September 30, 2029.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>