<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/443" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/443/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/443/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_443"><akn:num>443</akn:num><akn:heading>Returns for a period of less than 12 months</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 443. Returns for a period of less than 12 months(a) Returns for short periodA return for a period of less than 12 months (referred to in this section as “short period”) shall be made under any of the following circumstances:(1) Change of annual accounting periodWhen the taxpayer, with the approval of the Secretary, changes his annual accounting period. In such a case, the return shall be made for the short period beginning on the day after the close of the former taxable year and ending at the close of the day before the day designated as the first day of the new taxable year.


(2) Taxpayer not in existence for entire taxable yearWhen the taxpayer is in existence during only part of what would otherwise be his taxable year.



(b) Computation of tax on change of annual accounting period(1) General ruleIf a return is made under paragraph (1) of subsection (a), the taxable income for the short period shall be placed on an annual basis by multiplying the modified taxable income for such short period by 12, dividing the result by the number of months in the short period. The tax shall be the same part of the tax computed on the annual basis as the number of months in the short period is of 12 months.


(2) Exception(A) Computation based on 12-month periodIf the taxpayer applies for the benefits of this paragraph and establishes the amount of this taxable income for the 12-month period described in subparagraph (B), computed as if that period were a taxable year and under the law applicable to that year, then the tax for the short period, computed under paragraph (1), shall be reduced to the greater of the following:(i) an amount which bears the same ratio to the tax computed on the taxable income for the 12-month period as the modified taxable income computed on the basis of the short period bears to the modified taxable income for the 12-month period; or

(ii) the tax computed on the modified taxable income for the short period.


The taxpayer (other than a taxpayer</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_443_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Returns for short period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Returns for short period A return for a period of less than 12 months (referred to in this section as “short period”) shall be made under any of the following circumstances:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_443_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of tax on change of annual accounting period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Computation of tax on change of annual accounting period</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_443_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment in deduction for personal exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adjustment in deduction for personal exemption In the case of a taxpayer other than a corporation, if a return is made for a short period by reason of subsection (a)(1) and if the tax is not computed under subsection (b)(2), then the exemptions allowed as a deduction under section 151 (and any deduction in lieu thereof) shall be reduced to amounts which bear the same ratio to the full exemptions as the number of months in the short period bears to 12.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_443_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment in computing minimum tax and tax preferences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adjustment in computing minimum tax and tax preferences If a return is made for a short period by reason of subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_443_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cross references For inapplicability of subsection (b) in computing— For returns for a period of less than 12 months in the case of a debtor’s election to terminate a taxable year, see section 1398(d)(2)(E).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>