<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/446" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/446/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/446/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_446"><akn:num>446</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule for methods of accounting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 446. General rule for methods of accounting(a) General ruleTaxable income shall be computed under the method of accounting on the basis of which the taxpayer regularly computes his income in keeping his books.


(b) ExceptionsIf no method of accounting has been regularly used by the taxpayer, or if the method used does not clearly reflect income, the computation of taxable income shall be made under such method as, in the opinion of the Secretary, does clearly reflect income.


(c) Permissible methodsSubject to the provisions of subsections (a) and (b), a taxpayer may compute taxable income under any of the following methods of accounting—(1) the cash receipts and disbursements method;

(2) an accrual method;

(3) any other method permitted by this chapter; or

(4) any combination of the foregoing methods permitted under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(d) Taxpayer engaged in more than one businessA taxpayer engaged in more than one trade or business may, in computing taxable income, use a different method of accounting for each trade or business.


(e) Requirement respecting change of accounting methodExcept as otherwise expressly provided in this chapter, a taxpayer who changes the method of accounting on the basis of which he regularly computes his income in keeping his books shall, before computing his taxable income under the new method, secure the consent of the Secretary.


(f) Failure to request change of method of accountingIf the taxpayer does not file with the Secretary a request to change the method of accounting, the absence of the consent of the Secretary to a change in the method of accounting shall not be taken into account—(1) to prevent the imposition of any penalty, or the addition of any amount to tax, under this title, or

(2) to diminish the amount of such penalty or addition to tax.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 151; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906 (b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834; Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_446_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Taxable income shall be computed under the method of accounting on the basis of which the taxpayer regularly computes his income in keeping his books.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_446_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions If no method of accounting has been regularly used by the taxpayer, or if the method used does not clearly reflect income, the computation of taxable income shall be made under such method as, in the opinion of the Secretary, does clearly reflect income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_446_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permissible methods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Permissible methods Subject to the provisions of subsections (a) and (b), a taxpayer may compute taxable income under any of the following methods of accounting—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_446_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxpayer engaged in more than one business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Taxpayer engaged in more than one business A taxpayer engaged in more than one trade or business may, in computing taxable income, use a different method of accounting for each trade or business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_446_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement respecting change of accounting method</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirement respecting change of accounting method Except as otherwise expressly provided in this chapter, a taxpayer who changes the method of accounting on the basis of which he regularly computes his income in keeping his books shall, before computing his taxable income under the new method, secure the consent of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_446_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to request change of method of accounting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Failure to request change of method of accounting If the taxpayer does not file with the Secretary a request to change the method of accounting, the absence of the consent of the Secretary to a change in the method of accounting shall not be taken into account—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>