<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4462" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4462/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4462/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4462"><akn:num>4462</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4462. Definitions and special rules(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this subchapter—(1) Port useThe term “port use” means—(A) the loading of commercial cargo on, or

(B) the unloading of commercial cargo from,


a commercial vessel at a port.

(2) Port(A) In generalThe term “port” means any channel or harbor (or component thereof) in the United States, which—(i) is not an inland waterway, and

(ii) is open to public navigation.


(B) Exception for certain facilitiesThe term “port” does not include any channel or harbor with respect to which no Federal funds have been used since 1977 for construction, maintenance, or operation, or which was deauthorized by Federal law before 1985.


(C) Special rule for Columbia RiverThe term “port” shall include the channels of the Columbia River in the States of Oregon and Washington only up to the downstream side of Bonneville lock and dam.



(3) Commercial cargo(A) In generalThe term “commercial cargo” means any cargo transported on a commercial vessel, including passengers transported for compensation or hire.


(B) Certain items not includedThe term “commercial cargo” does not include—(i) bunker fuel, ship’s stores, sea stores, or the legitimate equipment necessary to the operation of a vessel, or

(ii) fish or other aquatic animal life caught and not previously landed on shore.



(4) Commercial vessel(A) In generalThe term “commercial vessel” means any vessel used—(i) in transporting cargo by water for compensation or hire, or

(ii) in transporting cargo by water in the business of the owner, lessee, or operator of the vessel.


(B) Exclusion of ferries(i) In generalThe term “commercial vessel” does not include any ferry engaged primarily in the ferrying of passengers (including their vehicles) between points within the United States, or between the United States and contiguous countries.


(ii) FerryThe term “ferry” means any vessel which arrives in the United States on a regular schedule during its operating season at inte</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4462_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4462_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for Alaska, Hawaii, and possessions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rule for Alaska, Hawaii, and possessions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4462_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of tax where transportation subject to tax imposed by section 4042</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination of tax where transportation subject to tax imposed by section 4042 No tax shall be imposed under this subchapter with respect to the loading or unloading of any cargo on or from a vessel if any fuel of such vessel has been (or will be) subject to the tax imposed by section 4042 (relating to tax on fuel used in commercial transportation on inland waterways).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4462_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of tax to exports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nonapplicability of tax to exports The tax imposed by section 4461(a) shall not apply to any port use with respect to any commercial cargo to be exported from the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4462_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemption for United States No tax shall be imposed under this subchapter on the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4462_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of provisions of law applicable to customs duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Extension of provisions of law applicable to customs duty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4462_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rules Except as provided by regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4462_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for humanitarian and development assistance cargos</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exemption for humanitarian and development assistance cargos No tax shall be imposed under this subchapter on any nonprofit organization or cooperative for cargo which is owned or financed by such nonprofit organization or cooperative and which is certified by the United States Customs Service as intended for use in humanitarian or development assistance overseas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4462_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Secretary may prescribe such additional regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter including, but not limited to, regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>