<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/447" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/447/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/447/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_447"><akn:num>447</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of accounting for corporations engaged in farming</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 447. Method of accounting for corporations engaged in farming(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided by law, the taxable income from farming of—(1) a corporation engaged in the trade or business of farming, or

(2) a partnership engaged in the trade or business of farming, if a corporation is a partner in such partnership,


shall be computed on an accrual method of accounting. This section shall not apply to the trade or business of operating a nursery or sod farm or to the raising or harvesting of trees (other than fruit and nut trees).

(b) Preproductive period expensesFor rules requiring capitalization of certain preproductive period expenses, see section 263A.


(c) Exception for certain corporationsFor purposes of subsection (a), a corporation shall be treated as not being a corporation for any taxable year if it is—(1) an S corporation, or

(2) a corporation which meets the gross receipts test of section 448(c) for such taxable year.


(d) Coordination with section 481Any change in method of accounting made pursuant to this section shall be treated for purposes of section 481 as initiated by the taxpayer and made with the consent of the Secretary.


(e) Certain annual accrual accounting methods(1) In generalNotwithstanding subsection (a) or section 263A, if—(A) for its 10 taxable years ending with its first taxable year beginning after December 31, 1975, a corporation or qualified partnership used an annual accrual method of accounting with respect to its trade or business of farming,

(B) such corporation or qualified partnership raises crops which are harvested not less than 12 months after planting, and

(C) such corporation or qualified partnership has used such method of accounting for all taxable years intervening between its first taxable year beginning after December 31, 1975, and the taxable year,


such corporation or qualified partnership may continue to employ such method of accounting for the taxable year with respect to its qualified farm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_447_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided by law, the taxable income from farming of— shall be computed on an accrual method of accounting. This section shall not apply to the trade or business of operating a nursery or sod farm or to the raising or harvesting of trees (other than fruit and nut trees).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_447_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preproductive period expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preproductive period expenses For rules requiring capitalization of certain preproductive period expenses, see section 263A.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_447_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for certain corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception for certain corporations For purposes of subsection (a), a corporation shall be treated as not being a corporation for any taxable year if it is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_447_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with section 481</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination with section 481 Any change in method of accounting made pursuant to this section shall be treated for purposes of section 481 as initiated by the taxpayer and made with the consent of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_447_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain annual accrual accounting methods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certain annual accrual accounting methods</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>