<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/453B" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/453B/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/453B/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_453B"><akn:num>453B</akn:num><akn:heading>Gain or loss on disposition of installment obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 453B. Gain or loss on disposition of installment obligations(a) General ruleIf an installment obligation is satisfied at other than its face value or distributed, transmitted, sold, or otherwise disposed of, gain or loss shall result to the extent of the difference between the basis of the obligation and—(1) the amount realized, in the case of satisfaction at other than face value or a sale or exchange, or

(2) the fair market value of the obligation at the time of distribution, transmission, or disposition, in the case of the distribution, transmission, or disposition otherwise than by sale or exchange.


any gain or loss so resulting shall be considered as resulting from the sale or exchange of the property in respect of which the installment obligation was received.

(b) Basis of obligationThe basis of an installment obligation shall be the excess of the face value of the obligation over an amount equal to the income which would be returnable were the obligation satisfied in full.


(c) Special rule for transmission at deathExcept as provided in section 691 (relating to recipients of income in respect of decedents), this section shall not apply to the transmission of installment obligations at death.


(d) Exception for distributions to which section 337(a) appliesSubsection (a) shall not apply to any distribution to which section 337(a) applies.


(e) Life insurance companies(1) In generalIn the case of a disposition of an installment obligation by any person other than a life insurance company (as defined in section 816(a)) to such an insurance company or to a partnership of which such an insurance company is a partner, no provision of this subtitle providing for the nonrecognition of gain shall apply with respect to any gain resulting under subsection (a). If a corporation which is a life insurance company for the taxable year was (for the preceding taxable year) a corporation which was not a life insurance company, such corporation shall, for purposes of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453B_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule If an installment obligation is satisfied at other than its face value or distributed, transmitted, sold, or otherwise disposed of, gain or loss shall result to the extent of the difference between the basis of the obligation and— any gain or loss so resulting shall be considered as resulting from the sale or exchange of the property in respect of which the installment obligation was received.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453B_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis of obligation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Basis of obligation The basis of an installment obligation shall be the excess of the face value of the obligation over an amount equal to the income which would be returnable were the obligation satisfied in full.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453B_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for transmission at death</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule for transmission at death Except as provided in section 691 (relating to recipients of income in respect of decedents), this section shall not apply to the transmission of installment obligations at death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453B_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for distributions to which section 337(a) applies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exception for distributions to which section 337(a) applies Subsection (a) shall not apply to any distribution to which section 337(a) applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453B_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life insurance companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Life insurance companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453B_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation becomes unenforceable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Obligation becomes unenforceable For purposes of this section, if any installment obligation is canceled or otherwise becomes unenforceable—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453B_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers between spouses or incident to divorce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transfers between spouses or incident to divorce In the case of any transfer described in subsection (a) of section 1041 (other than a transfer in trust)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453B_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain liquidating distributions by S corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Certain liquidating distributions by S corporations If— then, except for purposes of any tax imposed by subchapter S, no gain or loss with respect to the distribution of the obligation shall be recognized by the distributing corporation. Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the character of the gain or loss to the shareholder shall be determined in accordance with the principles of section 1366(b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>