<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/456" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/456/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/456/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_456"><akn:num>456</akn:num><akn:heading>Prepaid dues income of certain membership organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 456. Prepaid dues income of certain membership organizations(a) Year in which includedPrepaid dues income to which this section applies shall be included in gross income for the taxable years during which the liability described in subsection (e)(2) exists.


(b) Where taxpayer’s liability ceasesIn the case of any prepaid dues income to which this section applies—(1) If the liability described in subsection (e)(2) ends, then so much of such income as was not includible in gross income under subsection (a) for preceding taxable years shall be included in gross income for the taxable year in which the liability ends.

(2) If the taxpayer ceases to exist, then so much of such income as was not includible in gross income under subsection (a) for preceding taxable years shall be included in gross income for the taxable year in which such cessation of existence occurs.


(c) Prepaid dues income to which this section applies(1) Election of benefitsThis section shall apply to prepaid dues income if and only if the taxpayer makes an election under this section with respect to the trade or business in connection with which such income is received. The election shall be made in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe. No election may be made with respect to a trade or business if in computing taxable income the cash receipts and disbursements method of accounting is used with respect to such trade or business.


(2) Scope of electionAn election made under this section shall apply to all prepaid dues income received in connection with the trade or business with respect to which the taxpayer has made the election; except that the taxpayer may, to the extent permitted under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, include in gross income for the taxable year of receipt the entire amount of any prepaid dues income if the liability from which it arose is to end within 12 months after the date of receipt. Except as provided in subsection (d), and election made un</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_456_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Year in which included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Year in which included Prepaid dues income to which this section applies shall be included in gross income for the taxable years during which the liability described in subsection (e)(2) exists.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_456_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Where taxpayer’s liability ceases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Where taxpayer’s liability ceases In the case of any prepaid dues income to which this section applies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_456_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prepaid dues income to which this section applies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prepaid dues income to which this section applies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_456_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transitional rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transitional rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_456_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>