<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/45K" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/45K/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/45K/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_45K"><akn:num>45K</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for producing fuel from a nonconventional source</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 45K. Credit for producing fuel from a nonconventional source(a) Allowance of creditFor purposes of section 38, the nonconventional source production credit determined under this section for the taxable year is an amount equal to—(1) $3, multiplied by

(2) the barrel-of-oil equivalent of qualified fuels—(A) sold by the taxpayer to an unrelated person during the taxable year, and

(B) the production of which is attributable to the taxpayer.



(b) Limitations and adjustments(1) Phaseout of creditThe amount of the credit allowable under subsection (a) shall be reduced by an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount of the credit (determined without regard to this paragraph) as—(A) the amount by which the reference price for the calendar year in which the sale occurs exceeds $23.50, bears to

(B) $6.


(2) Credit and phaseout adjustment based on inflationThe $3 amount in subsection (a) and the $23.50 and $6 amounts in paragraph (1) shall each be adjusted by multiplying such amount by the inflation adjustment factor for the calendar year in which the sale occurs. In the case of gas from a tight formation, the $3 amount in subsection (a) shall not be adjusted.


(3) Credit reduced for grants, tax-exempt bonds, and subsidized energy financing(A) In generalThe amount of the credit allowable under subsection (a) with respect to any project for any taxable year (determined after the application of paragraphs (1) and (2)) shall be reduced by the amount which is the product of the amount so determined for such year and a fraction—(i) the numerator of which is the sum, for the taxable year and all prior taxable years, of—(I) grants provided by the United States, a State, or a political subdivision of a State for use in connection with the project,

(II) proceeds of any issue of State or local government obligations used to provide financing for the project the interest on which is exempt from tax under section 103, and

(III) the aggregate amount of subsidized energy fin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45K_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of credit For purposes of section 38, the nonconventional source production credit determined under this section for the taxable year is an amount equal to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45K_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations and adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations and adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45K_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of qualified fuels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definition of qualified fuels For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45K_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45K_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application of section This section shall apply with respect to qualified fuels—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45K_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension for certain facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Extension for certain facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45K_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension for facilities producing coke or coke gas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Extension for facilities producing coke or coke gas Notwithstanding subsection (e)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>