<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/45O" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/45O/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/45O/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_45O"><akn:num>45O</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural chemicals security credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 45O. Agricultural chemicals security credit(a) In generalFor purposes of section 38, in the case of an eligible agricultural business, the agricultural chemicals security credit determined under this section for the taxable year is 30 percent of the qualified security expenditures for the taxable year.


(b) Facility limitationThe amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) with respect to any facility for any taxable year shall not exceed—(1) $100,000, reduced by

(2) the aggregate amount of credits determined under subsection (a) with respect to such facility for the 5 prior taxable years.


(c) Annual limitationThe amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed $2,000,000.


(d) Qualified chemical security expenditureFor purposes of this section, the term “qualified chemical security expenditure” means, with respect to any eligible agricultural business for any taxable year, any amount paid or incurred by such business during such taxable year for—(1) employee security training and background checks,

(2) limitation and prevention of access to controls of specified agricultural chemicals stored at the facility,

(3) tagging, locking tank valves, and chemical additives to prevent the theft of specified agricultural chemicals or to render such chemicals unfit for illegal use,

(4) protection of the perimeter of specified agricultural chemicals,

(5) installation of security lighting, cameras, recording equipment, and intrusion detection sensors,

(6) implementation of measures to increase computer or computer network security,

(7) conducting a security vulnerability assessment,

(8) implementing a site security plan, and

(9) such other measures for the protection of specified agricultural chemicals as the Secretary may identify in regulation.


Amounts described in the preceding sentence shall be taken into account only to the extent that such amounts are paid or incurred for the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45O_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For purposes of section 38, in the case of an eligible agricultural business, the agricultural chemicals security credit determined under this section for the taxable year is 30 percent of the qualified security expenditures for the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45O_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facility limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Facility limitation The amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) with respect to any facility for any taxable year shall not exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45O_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual limitation The amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed $2,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45O_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified chemical security expenditure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Qualified chemical security expenditure For purposes of this section, the term “qualified chemical security expenditure” means, with respect to any eligible agricultural business for any taxable year, any amount paid or incurred by such business during such taxable year for— Amounts described in the preceding sentence shall be taken into account only to the extent that such amounts are paid or incurred for the purpose of protecting specified agricultural chemicals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45O_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible agricultural business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligible agricultural business For purposes of this section, the term “eligible agricultural business” means any person in the trade or business of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45O_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specified agricultural chemical</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Specified agricultural chemical For purposes of this section, the term “specified agricultural chemical” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45O_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Controlled groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Controlled groups Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 41(f) shall apply for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45O_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Secretary may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45O_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination This section shall not apply to any amount paid or incurred after December 31, 2012.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>