<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4611"><akn:num>4611</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4611. Imposition of tax(a) General RuleThere is hereby imposed a tax at the rate specified in subsection (c) on—(1) crude oil received at a United States refinery, and

(2) petroleum products entered into the United States for consumption, use, or warehousing.


(b) Tax on certain uses and exportation(1) In generalIf—(A) any domestic crude oil is used in or exported from the United States, and

(B) before such use or exportation, no tax was imposed on such crude oil under subsection (a),


then a tax at the rate specified in subsection (c) is hereby imposed on such crude oil.

(2) Exception for use on premises where producedParagraph (1) shall not apply to any use of crude oil for extracting oil or natural gas on the premises where such crude oil was produced.



(c) Rate of tax(1) In generalThe rate of the taxes imposed by this section is the sum of—(A) the Hazardous Substance Superfund financing rate, and

(B) the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund financing rate.


(2) RatesFor purposes of paragraph (1)—(A) the Hazardous Substance Superfund financing rate is 16.4 cents a barrel, and

(B) the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund financing rate is—(i) in the case of crude oil received or petroleum products entered before January 1, 2017, 8 cents a barrel, and

(ii) in the case of crude oil received or petroleum products entered after December 31, 2016, 9 cents a barrel.



(3) Adjustment for inflation(A) In generalIn the case of a year beginning after 2023, the amount in paragraph (2)(A) shall be increased by an amount equal to—(i) such amount, multiplied by

(ii) the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year, determined by substituting “calendar year 2022” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.


(B) RoundingIf any amount as adjusted under subparagraph (A) is not a multiple of $0.01, such amount shall be rounded to the next lowest multiple of $0.01.




(d) Persons liable for tax(1) Crude oil received at refineryTh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4611_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General Rule There is hereby imposed a tax at the rate specified in subsection (c) on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4611_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax on certain uses and exportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tax on certain uses and exportation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4611_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rate of tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4611_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons liable for tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Persons liable for tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4611_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 117–169, title I, § 13601(a)(1), Aug. 16, 2022, 136 Stat. 1981]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4611_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund financing rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application of Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund financing rate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>