<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/468B" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/468B/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/468B/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_468B"><akn:num>468B</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for designated settlement funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 468B. Special rules for designated settlement funds(a) In generalFor purposes of section 461(h), economic performance shall be deemed to occur as qualified payments are made by the taxpayer to a designated settlement fund.


(b) Taxation of designated settlement fund(1) In generalThere is imposed on the gross income of any designated settlement fund for any taxable year a tax at a rate equal to the maximum rate in effect for such taxable year under section 1(e).


(2) Certain expenses allowedFor purposes of paragraph (1), gross income for any taxable year shall be reduced by the amount of any administrative costs (including State and local taxes) and other incidental expenses of the designated settlement fund (including legal, accounting, and actuarial expenses)—(A) which are incurred in connection with the operation of the fund, and

(B) which would be deductible under this chapter for purposes of determining the taxable income of a corporation.


No other deduction shall be allowed to the fund.

(3) Transfers to the fundIn the case of any qualified payment made to the fund—(A) the amount of such payment shall not be treated as income of the designated settlement fund,

(B) the basis of the fund in any property which constitutes a qualified payment shall be equal to the fair market value of such property at the time of payment, and

(C) the fund shall be treated as the owner of the property in the fund (and any earnings thereon).


(4) Tax in lieu of other taxationThe tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall be in lieu of any other taxation under this subtitle of income from assets in the designated settlement fund.


(5) Coordination with subtitle FFor purposes of subtitle F—(A) a designated settlement fund shall be treated as a corporation, and

(B) any tax imposed by this subsection shall be treated as a tax imposed by section 11.



(c) Deductions not allowed for transfer of insurance amountsNo deduction shall be allowable for any qualified payment by the taxpayer </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_468B_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For purposes of section 461(h), economic performance shall be deemed to occur as qualified payments are made by the taxpayer to a designated settlement fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_468B_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxation of designated settlement fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Taxation of designated settlement fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_468B_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductions not allowed for transfer of insurance amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deductions not allowed for transfer of insurance amounts No deduction shall be allowable for any qualified payment by the taxpayer of any amounts received from the settlement of any insurance claim to the extent such amounts are excluded from the gross income of the taxpayer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_468B_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_468B_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nonapplicability of section This section (other than subsection (g)) shall not apply with respect to any liability of the taxpayer arising under any workers’ compensation Act or any contested liability of the taxpayer within the meaning of section 461(f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_468B_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other funds Except as provided in regulations, any payment in respect of a liability described in subsection (d)(2)(D) (and not described in subsection (e)) to a trust fund or escrow fund which is not a designated settlement fund shall not be treated as constituting economic performance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_468B_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification of taxation of certain funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Clarification of taxation of certain funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>