<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/469" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/469/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/469/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_469"><akn:num>469</akn:num><akn:heading>Passive activity losses and credits limited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 469. Passive activity losses and credits limited(a) Disallowance(1) In generalIf for any taxable year the taxpayer is described in paragraph (2), neither—(A) the passive activity loss, nor

(B) the passive activity credit,


for the taxable year shall be allowed.

(2) Persons describedThe following are described in this paragraph:(A) any individual, estate, or trust,

(B) any closely held C corporation, and

(C) any personal service corporation.



(b) Disallowed loss or credit carried to next yearExcept as otherwise provided in this section, any loss or credit from an activity which is disallowed under subsection (a) shall be treated as a deduction or credit allocable to such activity in the next taxable year.


(c) Passive activity definedFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “passive activity” means any activity—(A) which involves the conduct of any trade or business, and

(B) in which the taxpayer does not materially participate.


(2) Passive activity includes any rental activityExcept as provided in paragraph (7), the term “passive activity” includes any rental activity.


(3) Working interests in oil and gas property(A) In generalThe term “passive activity” shall not include any working interest in any oil or gas property which the taxpayer holds directly or through an entity which does not limit the liability of the taxpayer with respect to such interest.


(B) Income in subsequent yearsIf any taxpayer has any loss for any taxable year from a working interest in any oil or gas property which is treated as a loss which is not from a passive activity, then any net income from such property (or any property the basis of which is determined in whole or in part by reference to the basis of such property) for any succeeding taxable year shall be treated as income of the taxpayer which is not from a passive activity. If the preceding sentence applies to the net income from any property for any taxable year, any credits allowable under subpart B (oth</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disallowance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowed loss or credit carried to next year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disallowed loss or credit carried to next year Except as otherwise provided in this section, any loss or credit from an activity which is disallowed under subsection (a) shall be treated as a deduction or credit allocable to such activity in the next taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Passive activity defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Passive activity defined For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Passive activity loss and credit defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Passive activity loss and credit defined For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for determining income or loss from a passive activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for determining income or loss from a passive activity For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of former passive activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of former passive activities For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispositions of entire interest in passive activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Dispositions of entire interest in passive activity If during the taxable year a taxpayer disposes of his entire interest in any passive activity (or former passive activity), the following rules shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Material participation defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Material participation defined For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>$25,000 offset for rental real estate activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) $25,000 offset for rental real estate activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_469_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Other definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>