<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/470" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/470/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/470/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_470"><akn:num>470</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on deductions allocable to property used by governments or other tax-exempt entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 470. Limitation on deductions allocable to property used by governments or other tax-exempt entities(a) Limitation on lossesExcept as otherwise provided in this section, a tax-exempt use loss for any taxable year shall not be allowed.


(b) Disallowed loss carried to next yearAny tax-exempt use loss with respect to any tax-exempt use property which is disallowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year shall be treated as a deduction with respect to such property in the next taxable year.


(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) Tax-exempt use lossThe term “tax-exempt use loss” means, with respect to any taxable year, the amount (if any) by which—(A) the sum of—(i) the aggregate deductions (other than interest) directly allocable to a tax-exempt use property, plus

(ii) the aggregate deductions for interest properly allocable to such property, exceed


(B) the aggregate income from such property.


(2) Tax-exempt use property(A) In generalThe term “tax-exempt use property” has the meaning given to such term by section 168(h), except that such section shall be applied—(i) without regard to paragraphs (1)(C) and (3) thereof, and

(ii) as if section 197 intangible property (as defined in section 197), and property described in paragraph (1)(B) or (2) of section 167(f), were tangible property.


(B) Exception for partnershipsSuch term shall not include any property which would (but for this subparagraph) be tax-exempt use property solely by reason of section 168(h)(6).


(C) Cross referenceFor treatment of partnerships as leases to which section 168(h) applies, see section 7701(e).




(d) Exception for certain leasesThis section shall not apply to any lease of property which meets the requirements of all of the following paragraphs:(1) Availability of funds(A) In generalA lease of property meets the requirements of this paragraph if (at all times during the lease term) not more than an allowable amount of funds are—(i) subject to any arrangement referred to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitation on losses Except as otherwise provided in this section, a tax-exempt use loss for any taxable year shall not be allowed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowed loss carried to next year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disallowed loss carried to next year Any tax-exempt use loss with respect to any tax-exempt use property which is disallowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year shall be treated as a deduction with respect to such property in the next taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for certain leases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exception for certain leases This section shall not apply to any lease of property which meets the requirements of all of the following paragraphs:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_470_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>