<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/475" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/475/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/475/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_475"><akn:num>475</akn:num><akn:heading>Mark to market accounting method for dealers in securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 475. Mark to market accounting method for dealers in securities(a) General ruleNotwithstanding any other provision of this subpart, the following rules shall apply to securities held by a dealer in securities:(1) Any security which is inventory in the hands of the dealer shall be included in inventory at its fair market value.

(2) In the case of any security which is not inventory in the hands of the dealer and which is held at the close of any taxable year—(A) the dealer shall recognize gain or loss as if such security were sold for its fair market value on the last business day of such taxable year, and

(B) any gain or loss shall be taken into account for such taxable year.


Proper adjustment shall be made in the amount of any gain or loss subsequently realized for gain or loss taken into account under the preceding sentence. The Secretary may provide by regulations for the application of this paragraph at times other than the times provided in this paragraph.


(b) Exceptions(1) In generalSubsection (a) shall not apply to—(A) any security held for investment,

(B)(i) any security described in subsection (c)(2)(C) which is acquired (including originated) by the taxpayer in the ordinary course of a trade or business of the taxpayer and which is not held for sale, and (ii) any obligation to acquire a security described in clause (i) if such obligation is entered into in the ordinary course of such trade or business and is not held for sale, and


(C) any security which is a hedge with respect to—(i) a security to which subsection (a) does not apply, or

(ii) a position, right to income, or a liability which is not a security in the hands of the taxpayer.



To the extent provided in regulations, subparagraph (C) shall not apply to any security held by a person in its capacity as a dealer in securities.

(2) Identification requiredA security shall not be treated as described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1), as the case may be, unless such secur</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Notwithstanding any other provision of this subpart, the following rules shall apply to securities held by a dealer in securities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of mark to market for dealers in commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Election of mark to market for dealers in commodities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of mark to market for traders in securities or commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Election of mark to market for traders in securities or commodities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_475_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulatory authority The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including rules—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>