<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/48A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/48A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/48A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_48A"><akn:num>48A</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying advanced coal project credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 48A. Qualifying advanced coal project credit(a) In generalFor purposes of section 46, the qualifying advanced coal project credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to—(1) 20 percent of the qualified investment for such taxable year in the case of projects described in subsection (d)(3)(B)(i),

(2) 15 percent of the qualified investment for such taxable year in the case of projects described in subsection (d)(3)(B)(ii), and

(3) 30 percent of the qualified investment for such taxable year in the case of projects described in clause (iii) of subsection (d)(3)(B).


(b) Qualified investment(1) In generalFor purposes of subsection (a), the qualified investment for any taxable year is the basis of eligible property placed in service by the taxpayer during such taxable year which is part of a qualifying advanced coal project—(A)(i) the construction, reconstruction, or erection of which is completed by the taxpayer, or

(ii) which is acquired by the taxpayer if the original use of such property commences with the taxpayer, and


(B) with respect to which depreciation (or amortization in lieu of depreciation) is allowable.


(2) Special rule for certain subsidized propertyRules similar to section 48(a)(4) (without regard to subparagraph (D) thereof) shall apply for purposes of this section.


(3) Certain qualified progress expenditures rules made applicableRules similar to the rules of subsections (c)(4) and (d) of section 46 (as in effect on the day before the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) shall apply for purposes of this section.



(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) Qualifying advanced coal projectThe term “qualifying advanced coal project” means a project which meets the requirements of subsection (e).


(2) Advanced coal-based generation technologyThe term “advanced coal-based generation technology” means a technology which meets the requirements of subsection (f).


(3) Eligible propertyThe term “eligible property” means—(A)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For purposes of section 46, the qualifying advanced coal project credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified investment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified investment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying advanced coal project program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Qualifying advanced coal project program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying advanced coal projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Qualifying advanced coal projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced coal-based generation technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Advanced coal-based generation technology</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applicability No use of technology (or level of emission reduction solely by reason of the use of the technology), and no achievement of any emission reduction by the demonstration of any technology or performance level, by or at one or more facilities with respect to which a credit is allowed under this section, shall be considered to indicate that the technology or performance level is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48A_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive certification awards modification authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Competitive certification awards modification authority In implementing this section or section 48B, the Secretary is directed to modify the terms of any competitive certification award and any associated closing agreement where such modification— unless the Secretary determines that the dollar amount of tax credits available to the taxpayer under such section would increase as a result of the modification or such modification would result in such project not being originally certified. In considering any such modification, the Secretary shall consult with other relevant Federal agencies, including the Department of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48A_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recapture of credit for failure to sequester</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Recapture of credit for failure to sequester The Secretary shall provide for recapturing the benefit of any credit allowable under subsection (a) with respect to any project which fails to attain or maintain the separation and sequestration requirements of subsection (e)(1)(G).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>