<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4901"><akn:num>4901</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4901. Payment of tax(a) Condition precedent to carrying on certain businessNo person shall be engaged in or carry on any trade or business subject to the tax imposed by section 4411 (wagering) until he has paid the special tax therefor.


(b) ComputationAll special taxes shall be imposed as of on the first day of July in each year, or on commencing any trade or business on which such tax is imposed. In the former case the tax shall be reckoned for 1 year, and in the latter case it shall be reckoned proportionately, from the first day of the month in which the liability to a special tax commenced, to and including the 30th day of June following.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 593; Pub. L. 89–44, title IV, § 405(b), June 21, 1965, 79 Stat. 149; Pub. L. 91–513, title III, § 1102(a), Oct. 27, 1970, 84 Stat. 1292; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1904(a)(19), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1814; Pub. L. 95–600, title V, § 521(c)(2), Nov. 6, 1978, 92 Stat. 2884.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1978—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 95–600 struck out “or 4461(a)(1) (coin-operated gaming devices)” after “(wagering)”.
1976—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 94–455 struck out subsec. (c) which provided that all special taxes should be paid by stamp and made reference to subtitle F for authority of the Secretary to make assessments where special taxes have not been duly paid by stamp.
1970—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 91–513 struck out references to tax imposed by sections 4721 (narcotic drugs) and 4751 (marihuana).
1965—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 89–44 substituted “4461(a)(1)” for “4461(2)”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1978 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 95–600 applicable with respect to years beginning after June 30, 1980, see section 521(d)(2) of Pub. L. 95–600, set out as a note under section 4402 of this title.

Effective Date of 1976 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 94–455 effective on first day of first month which begins more than 90 days after Oct. 4, 1976, see section 1904(d) of Pub. L. </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Condition precedent to carrying on certain business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Condition precedent to carrying on certain business No person shall be engaged in or carry on any trade or business subject to the tax imposed by section 4411 (wagering) until he has paid the special tax therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Computation All special taxes shall be imposed as of on the first day of July in each year, or on commencing any trade or business on which such tax is imposed. In the former case the tax shall be reckoned for 1 year, and in the latter case it shall be reckoned proportionately, from the first day of the month in which the liability to a special tax commenced, to and including the 30th day of June following.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>