<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4940" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4940/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4940/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4940"><akn:num>4940</akn:num><akn:heading>Excise tax based on investment income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4940. Excise tax based on investment income(a) Tax-exempt foundationsThere is hereby imposed on each private foundation which is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) for the taxable year, with respect to the carrying on of its activities, a tax equal to 1.39 percent of the net investment income of such foundation for the taxable year.


(b) Taxable foundationsThere is hereby imposed on each private foundation which is not exempt from taxation under section 501(a) for the taxable year, with respect to the carrying on of its activities, a tax equal to—(1) the amount (if any) by which the sum of (A) the tax imposed under subsection (a) (computed as if such subsection applied to such private foundation for the taxable year), plus (B) the amount of the tax which would have been imposed under section 511 for the taxable year if such private foundation had been exempt from taxation under section 501(a), exceeds

(2) the tax imposed under subtitle A on such private foundation for the taxable year.


(c) Net investment income defined(1) In generalFor purposes of subsection (a), the net investment income is the amount by which (A) the sum of the gross investment income and the capital gain net income exceeds (B) the deductions allowed by paragraph (3). Except to the extent inconsistent with the provisions of this section, net investment income shall be determined under the principles of subtitle A.


(2) Gross investment incomeFor purposes of paragraph (1), the term “gross investment income” means the gross amount of income from interest, dividends, rents, payments with respect to securities loans (as defined in section 512(a)(5)), and royalties, but not including any such income to the extent included in computing the tax imposed by section 511. Such term shall also include income from sources similar to those in the preceding sentence.


(3) Deductions(A) In generalFor purposes of paragraph (1), there shall be allowed as a deduction all the ordinary and necessary exp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4940_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax-exempt foundations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Tax-exempt foundations There is hereby imposed on each private foundation which is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) for the taxable year, with respect to the carrying on of its activities, a tax equal to 1.39 percent of the net investment income of such foundation for the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4940_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable foundations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Taxable foundations There is hereby imposed on each private foundation which is not exempt from taxation under section 501(a) for the taxable year, with respect to the carrying on of its activities, a tax equal to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4940_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net investment income defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Net investment income defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4940_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for certain operating foundations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemption for certain operating foundations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>