<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4941" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4941/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4941/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4941"><akn:num>4941</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxes on self-dealing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4941. Taxes on self-dealing(a) Initial taxes(1) On self-dealerThere is hereby imposed a tax on each act of self-dealing between a disqualified person and a private foundation. The rate of tax shall be equal to 10 percent of the amount involved with respect to the act of self-dealing for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any disqualified person (other than a foundation manager acting only as such) who participates in the act of self-dealing. In the case of a government official (as defined in section 4946(c)), a tax shall be imposed by this paragraph only if such disqualified person participates in the act of self-dealing knowing that it is such an act.


(2) On foundation managerIn any case in which a tax is imposed by paragraph (1), there is hereby imposed on the participation of any foundation manager in an act of self-dealing between a disqualified person and a private foundation, knowing that it is such an act, a tax equal to 5 percent of the amount involved with respect to the act of self-dealing for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period, unless such participation is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any foundation manager who participated in the act of self-dealing.



(b) Additional taxes(1) On self-dealerIn any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on an act of self-dealing by a disqualified person with a private foundation and the act is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 200 percent of the amount involved. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any disqualified person (other than a foundation manager acting only as such) who participated in the act of self-dealing.


(2) On foundation managerIn any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if a foundation manager refused to agree to part or all of the correction, there</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4941_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Initial taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4941_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4941_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules For purposes of subsections (a) and (b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4941_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-dealing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Self-dealing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4941_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>