<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4951" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4951/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4951/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4951"><akn:num>4951</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxes on self-dealing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4951. Taxes on self-dealing(a) Initial taxes(1) On self-dealerThere is hereby imposed a tax on each act of self-dealing between a disqualified person and a trust described in section 501(c)(21). The rate of tax shall be equal to 10 percent of the amount involved with respect to the act of self-dealing for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any disqualified person (other than a trustee acting only as a trustee of the trust) who participates in the act of self-dealing.


(2) On trusteeIn any case in which a tax is imposed by paragraph (1), there is hereby imposed on the participation of any trustee of such a trust in an act of self-dealing between a disqualified person and the trust, knowing that it is such an act, a tax equal to 2½ percent of the amount involved with respect to the act of self-dealing for each year (or part thereof) in the taxable period, unless such participation is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any such trustee who participated in the act of self-dealing.



(b) Additional taxes(1) On self-dealerIn any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on an act of self-dealing by a disqualified person with a trust described in section 501(c)(21) and in which the act is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 100 percent of the amount involved. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any disqualified person (other than a trustee acting only as a trustee of such a trust) who participated in the act of self-dealing.


(2) On trusteeIn any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if a trustee of such a trust refused to agree to part or all of the correction, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 50 percent of the amount involved. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any such trustee who refused to agree to part or all of the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4951_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Initial taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4951_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4951_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint and several liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Joint and several liability If more than one person is liable under any paragraph of subsection (a) or (b) with respect to any one act of self-dealing, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4951_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-dealing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Self-dealing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4951_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4951_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Payments of benefits For purposes of this section, a payment, out of assets or income of a trust described in section 501(c)(21), for the purposes described in subclause (I) or (IV) of section 501(c)(21)(A)(i) shall not be considered an act of self-dealing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>