<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4952" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4952/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4952/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4952"><akn:num>4952</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxes on taxable expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4952. Taxes on taxable expenditures(a) Tax imposed(1) On the fundThere is hereby imposed on each taxable expenditure (as defined in subsection (d)) from the assets or income of a trust described in section 501(c)(21) a tax equal to 10 percent of the amount thereof. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the trustee out of the assets of the trust.


(2) On the trusteeThere is hereby imposed on the agreement of any trustee of such a trust to the making of an expenditure, knowing that it is a taxable expenditure, a tax equal to 2½ percent of the amount thereof, unless such agreement is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the trustee who agreed to the making of the expenditure.



(b) Additional taxes(1) On the fundIn any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on a taxable expenditure and such expenditure is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 100 percent of the amount of the expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the trustee out of the assets of the trust.


(2) On the trusteeIn any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if a trustee refused to agree to a part or all of the correction, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 50 percent of the amount of the taxable expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any trustee who refused to agree to part or all of the correction.



(c) Joint and several liabilityFor purposes of subsections (a) and (b), if more than one person is liable under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) with respect to the making of a taxable expenditure, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such expenditure.


(d) Taxable expenditureFor purposes of this section, the term “taxable expenditure” means any amount paid or incurred by a trust described in section 501(c)(21) other than for a purpose specified </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4952_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax imposed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Tax imposed</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4952_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4952_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint and several liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Joint and several liability For purposes of subsections (a) and (b), if more than one person is liable under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) with respect to the making of a taxable expenditure, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such paragraph with respect to such expenditure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4952_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable expenditure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Taxable expenditure For purposes of this section, the term “taxable expenditure” means any amount paid or incurred by a trust described in section 501(c)(21) other than for a purpose specified in such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4952_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>