<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4955" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4955/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4955/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4955"><akn:num>4955</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxes on political expenditures of section 501(c)(3) organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4955. Taxes on political expenditures of section 501(c)(3) organizations(a) Initial taxes(1) On the organizationThere is hereby imposed on each political expenditure by a section 501(c)(3) organization a tax equal to 10 percent of the amount thereof. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the organization.


(2) On the managementThere is hereby imposed on the agreement of any organization manager to the making of any expenditure, knowing that it is a political expenditure, a tax equal to 2½ percent of the amount thereof, unless such agreement is not willful and is due to reasonable cause. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any organization manager who agreed to the making of the expenditure.



(b) Additional taxes(1) On the organizationIn any case in which an initial tax is imposed by subsection (a)(1) on a political expenditure and such expenditure is not corrected within the taxable period, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 100 percent of the amount of the expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by the organization.


(2) On the managementIn any case in which an additional tax is imposed by paragraph (1), if an organization manager refused to agree to part or all of the correction, there is hereby imposed a tax equal to 50 percent of the amount of the political expenditure. The tax imposed by this paragraph shall be paid by any organization manager who refused to agree to part or all of the correction.



(c) Special rulesFor purposes of subsections (a) and (b)—(1) Joint and several liabilityIf more than 1 person is liable under subsection (a)(2) or (b)(2) with respect to the making of a political expenditure, all such persons shall be jointly and severally liable under such subsection with respect to such expenditure.


(2) Limit for managementWith respect to any 1 political expenditure, the maximum amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a)(2) shall not exceed $5,000, and the maximum amount of the tax imp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4955_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Initial taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4955_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4955_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules For purposes of subsections (a) and (b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4955_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Political expenditure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Political expenditure For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4955_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with sections 4945 and 4958</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination with sections 4945 and 4958 If tax is imposed under this section with respect to any political expenditure, such expenditure shall not be treated as a taxable expenditure for purposes of section 4945 or an excess benefit for purposes of section 4958.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4955_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>