<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4968" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4968/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4968/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4968"><akn:num>4968</akn:num><akn:heading>Excise tax based on investment income of private colleges and universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4968. Excise tax based on investment income of private colleges and universities(a) Tax imposedThere is hereby imposed on each applicable educational institution for the taxable year a tax equal to the applicable percentage of the net investment income of such institution for the taxable year.


(b) Applicable percentageFor purposes of this section, the term “applicable percentage” means—(1) 1.4 percent in the case of an institution with a student adjusted endowment of at least $500,000, and not in excess of $750,000,

(2) 4 percent in the case of an institution with a student adjusted endowment in excess of $750,000, and not in excess of $2,000,000, and

(3) 8 percent in the case of an institution with a student adjusted endowment in excess of $2,000,000.


(c) Applicable educational institutionFor purposes of this subchapter, the term “applicable educational institution” means an eligible educational institution (as defined in section 25A(f)(2))—(1) which had at least 3,000 tuition-paying students during the preceding taxable year,

(2) more than 50 percent of the tuition-paying students of which are located in the United States,

(3) the student adjusted endowment of which is at least $500,000, and

(4) which is not described in the first sentence of section 511(a)(2)(B) (relating to State colleges and universities).


(d) Student adjusted endowmentFor purposes of this section, the term “student adjusted endowment” means, with respect to any institution for any taxable year—(1) the aggregate fair market value of the assets of such institution (determined as of the end of the preceding taxable year), other than those assets which are used directly in carrying out the institution’s exempt purpose, divided by

(2) the number of students of such institution.


(e) Determination of number of studentsFor purposes of subsections (c) and (d), the number of students of an institution (including for purposes of determining the number of students at a particular location)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4968_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax imposed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Tax imposed There is hereby imposed on each applicable educational institution for the taxable year a tax equal to the applicable percentage of the net investment income of such institution for the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4968_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable percentage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicable percentage For purposes of this section, the term “applicable percentage” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4968_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable educational institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicable educational institution For purposes of this subchapter, the term “applicable educational institution” means an eligible educational institution (as defined in section 25A(f)(2))—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4968_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student adjusted endowment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Student adjusted endowment For purposes of this section, the term “student adjusted endowment” means, with respect to any institution for any taxable year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4968_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of number of students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Determination of number of students For purposes of subsections (c) and (d), the number of students of an institution (including for purposes of determining the number of students at a particular location) shall be based on the daily average number of full-time students attending such institution (with part-time students taken into account on a full-time student equivalent basis).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4968_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net investment income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Net investment income For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4968_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assets and net investment income of related organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assets and net investment income of related organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4968_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to prevent avoidance of the tax under this section, including regulations or other guidance to prevent avoidance of such tax through the restructuring of endowment funds or other arrangements designed to reduce or eliminate the value of net investment income or assets subject to the tax imposed by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>