<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4973" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4973/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4973/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4973"><akn:num>4973</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax on excess contributions to certain tax-favored accounts and annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4973. Tax on excess contributions to certain tax-favored accounts and annuities(a) Tax imposedIn the case of—(1) an individual retirement account (within the meaning of section 408(a)),

(2) an Archer MSA (within the meaning of section 220(d)),

(3) an individual retirement annuity (within the meaning of section 408(b)), a custodial account treated as an annuity contract under section 403(b)(7)(A) (relating to custodial accounts for regulated investment company stock),

(4) a Coverdell education savings account (as defined in section 530),

(5) a health savings account (within the meaning of section 223(d)), or

(6) an ABLE account (within the meaning of section 529A),


there is imposed for each taxable year a tax in an amount equal to 6 percent of the amount of the excess contributions to such individual’s accounts or annuities (determined as of the close of the taxable year). The amount of such tax for any taxable year shall not exceed 6 percent of the value of the account or annuity (determined as of the close of the taxable year). In the case of an endowment contract described in section 408(b), the tax imposed by this section does not apply to any amount allocable to life, health, accident, or other insurance under such contract. The tax imposed by this subsection shall be paid by such individual.

(b) Excess contributionsFor purposes of this section, in the case of individual retirement accounts or individual retirement annuities, the term “excess contributions” means the sum of—(1) the excess (if any) of—(A) the amount contributed for the taxable year to the accounts or for the annuities (other than a contribution to a Roth IRA or a rollover contribution described in section 402(c), 403(a)(4), 403(b)(8), 408(d)(3), or 457(e)(16)), over

(B) the amount allowable as a deduction under section 219 for such contributions, and


(2) the amount determined under this subsection for the preceding taxable year reduced by the sum of—(A) the distributions out of the a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4973_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax imposed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Tax imposed In the case of— there is imposed for each taxable year a tax in an amount equal to 6 percent of the amount of the excess contributions to such individual’s accounts or annuities (determined as of the close of the taxable year). The amount of such tax for any taxable year shall not exceed 6 percent of the value of the account or annuity (determined as of the close of the taxable year). In the case of an endowment contract described in section 408(b), the tax imposed by this section does not apply to any amount allocable to life, health, accident, or other insurance under such contract. The tax imposed by this subsection shall be paid by such individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4973_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Excess contributions For purposes of this section, in the case of individual retirement accounts or individual retirement annuities, the term “excess contributions” means the sum of— For purposes of this subsection, any contribution which is distributed from the individual retirement account or the individual retirement annuity in a distribution to which section 408(d)(4) applies shall be treated as an amount not contributed. For purposes of paragraphs (1)(B) and (2)(C), the amount allowable as a deduction under section 219 shall be computed without regard to section 219(g). Such term shall not include any designated nondeductible contribution (as defined in subparagraph (C) of section 408(o)(2)) which does not exceed the nondeductible limit under subparagraph (B) thereof by reason of an election under section 408(o)(5).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4973_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section 403(b) contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Section 403(b) contracts For purposes of this section, in the case of a custodial account referred to in subsection (a)(3), the term “excess contributions” means the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4973_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess contributions to Archer MSAs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Excess contributions to Archer MSAs For purposes of this section, in the case of Archer MSAs (within the meaning of section 220(d)), the term “excess contributions” means the sum of— For purposes of this subsection, any contribution which is distributed out of the Archer MSA in a distribution to which section 220(f)(3) or section 138(c)(3) applies shall be treated as an amount not contributed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4973_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess contributions to Coverdell education savings accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Excess contributions to Coverdell education savings accounts For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4973_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess contributions to Roth IRAs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Excess contributions to Roth IRAs For purposes of this section, in the case of contributions to a Roth IRA (within the meaning of section 408A(b)), the term “excess contributions” means the sum of— For purposes of this subsection, any contribution which is distributed from a Roth IRA in a distribution described in section 408(d)(4) shall be treated as an amount not contributed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4973_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess contributions to health savings accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Excess contributions to health savings accounts For purposes of this section, in the case of health savings accounts (within the meaning of section 223(d)), the term “excess contributions” means the sum of— For purposes of this subsection, any contribution which is distributed out of the health savings account in a distribution to which section 223(f)(3) applies shall be treated as an amount not contributed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4973_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess contributions to ABLE account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Excess contributions to ABLE account For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>