<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4980C" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4980C/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4980C/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4980C"><akn:num>4980C</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for issuers of qualified long-term care insurance contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4980C. Requirements for issuers of qualified long-term care insurance contracts(a) General ruleThere is hereby imposed on any person failing to meet the requirements of subsection (c) or (d) a tax in the amount determined under subsection (b).


(b) Amount(1) In generalThe amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a) shall be $100 per insured for each day any requirement of subsection (c) or (d) is not met with respect to each qualified long-term care insurance contract.


(2) WaiverIn the case of a failure which is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, the Secretary may waive part or all of the tax imposed by subsection (a) to the extent that payment of the tax would be excessive relative to the failure involved.



(c) ResponsibilitiesThe requirements of this subsection are as follows:(1) Requirements of model provisions(A) Model regulationThe following requirements of the model regulation must be met:(i) Section 13 (relating to application forms and replacement coverage).

(ii) Section 14 (relating to reporting requirements), except that the issuer shall also report at least annually the number of claims denied during the reporting period for each class of business (expressed as a percentage of claims denied), other than claims denied for failure to meet the waiting period or because of any applicable preexisting condition.

(iii) Section 20 (relating to filing requirements for marketing).

(iv) Section 21 (relating to standards for marketing), including inaccurate completion of medical histories, other than sections 21C(1) and 21C(6) thereof, except that—(I) in addition to such requirements, no person shall, in selling or offering to sell a qualified long-term care insurance contract, misrepresent a material fact; and

(II) no such requirements shall include a requirement to inquire or identify whether a prospective applicant or enrollee for long-term care insurance has accident and sickness insurance.


(v) Section 22 (relating to appropriateness</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980C_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule There is hereby imposed on any person failing to meet the requirements of subsection (c) or (d) a tax in the amount determined under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980C_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980C_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities The requirements of this subsection are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980C_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disclosure The requirements of this subsection are met if the issuer of a long-term care insurance policy discloses in such policy and in the outline of coverage required under subsection (c)(1)(B)(ii) that the policy is intended to be a qualified long-term care insurance contract under section 7702B(b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980C_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified long-term care insurance contract defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Qualified long-term care insurance contract defined For purposes of this section, the term “qualified long-term care insurance contract” has the meaning given such term by section 7702B.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980C_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with State requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with State requirements If a State imposes any requirement which is more stringent than the analogous requirement imposed by this section or section 7702B(g), the requirement imposed by this section or section 7702B(g) shall be treated as met if the more stringent State requirement is met.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>