<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4980B" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4980B/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4980B/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4980B"><akn:num>4980B</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to satisfy continuation coverage requirements of group health plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4980B. Failure to satisfy continuation coverage requirements of group health plans(a) General ruleThere is hereby imposed a tax on the failure of a group health plan to meet the requirements of subsection (f) with respect to any qualified beneficiary.


(b) Amount of tax(1) In generalThe amount of the tax imposed by subsection (a) on any failure with respect to a qualified beneficiary shall be $100 for each day in the noncompliance period with respect to such failure.


(2) Noncompliance periodFor purposes of this section, the term “noncompliance period” means, with respect to any failure, the period—(A) beginning on the date such failure first occurs, and

(B) ending on the earlier of—(i) the date such failure is corrected, or

(ii) the date which is 6 months after the last day in the period applicable to the qualified beneficiary under subsection (f)(2)(B) (determined without regard to clause (iii) thereof).



If a person is liable for tax under subsection (e)(1)(B) by reason of subsection (e)(2)(B) with respect to any failure, the noncompliance period for such person with respect to such failure shall not begin before the 45th day after the written request described in subsection (e)(2)(B) is provided to such person.

(3) Minimum tax for noncompliance period where failure discovered after notice of examinationNotwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c)—(A) In generalIn the case of 1 or more failures with respect to a qualified beneficiary—(i) which are not corrected before the date a notice of examination of income tax liability is sent to the employer, and

(ii) which occurred or continued during the period under examination,


the amount of tax imposed by subsection (a) by reason of such failures with respect to such beneficiary shall not be less than the lesser of $2,500 or the amount of tax which would be imposed by subsection (a) without regard to such paragraphs.

(B) Higher minimum tax where violations are more than de minimisTo the extent </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980B_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule There is hereby imposed a tax on the failure of a group health plan to meet the requirements of subsection (f) with respect to any qualified beneficiary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980B_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980B_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on amount of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations on amount of tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980B_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax not to apply to certain plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tax not to apply to certain plans This section shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980B_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Liability for tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980B_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation coverage requirements of group health plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Continuation coverage requirements of group health plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4980B_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>