<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4982" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4982/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4982/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4982"><akn:num>4982</akn:num><akn:heading>Excise tax on undistributed income of regulated investment companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4982. Excise tax on undistributed income of regulated investment companies(a) Imposition of taxThere is hereby imposed a tax on every regulated investment company for each calendar year equal to 4 percent of the excess (if any) of—(1) the required distribution for such calendar year, over

(2) the distributed amount for such calendar year.


(b) Required distributionFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “required distribution” means, with respect to any calendar year, the sum of—(A) 98 percent of the regulated investment company’s ordinary income for such calendar year, plus

(B) 98.2 percent of the regulated investment company’s capital gain net income for the 1-year period ending on October 31 of such calendar year.


(2) Increase by prior year shortfallThe amount determined under paragraph (1) for any calendar year shall be increased by the excess (if any) of—(A) the grossed up required distribution for the preceding calendar year, over

(B) the distributed amount for such preceding calendar year.


(3) Grossed up required distributionThe grossed up required distribution for any calendar year is the required distribution for such year determined—(A) with the application of paragraph (2) to such taxable year, and

(B) by substituting “100 percent” for each percentage set forth in paragraph (1).



(c) Distributed amountFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “distributed amount” means, with respect to any calendar year, the sum of—(A) the deduction for dividends paid (as defined in section 561) during such calendar year, and

(B) any amount on which tax is imposed under subsection (b)(1) or (b)(3)(A) of section 852 for any taxable year ending in such calendar year.


(2) Increase by prior year overdistributionThe amount determined under paragraph (1) for any calendar year shall be increased by the excess (if any) of—(A) the distributed amount for the preceding calendar year (determined with the application of this paragraph to such prec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4982_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Imposition of tax There is hereby imposed a tax on every regulated investment company for each calendar year equal to 4 percent of the excess (if any) of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4982_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required distribution For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4982_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributed amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distributed amount For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4982_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for payment of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time for payment of tax The tax imposed by this section for any calendar year shall be paid on or before March 15 of the following calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4982_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4982_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for certain regulated investment companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exception for certain regulated investment companies This section shall not apply to any regulated investment company for any calendar year if at all times during such calendar year each shareholder in such company was— For purposes of the preceding sentence, any shares attributable to an investment in the regulated investment company (not exceeding $250,000) made in connection with the organization of such company shall not be taken into account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>