<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4985" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4985/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/4985/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4985"><akn:num>4985</akn:num><akn:heading>Stock compensation of insiders in expatriated corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4985. Stock compensation of insiders in expatriated corporations(a) Imposition of taxIn the case of an individual who is a disqualified individual with respect to any expatriated corporation, there is hereby imposed on such person a tax equal to—(1) the rate of tax specified in section 1(h)(1)(D), multiplied by

(2) the value (determined under subsection (b)) of the specified stock compensation held (directly or indirectly) by or for the benefit of such individual or a member of such individual’s family (as defined in section 267) at any time during the 12-month period beginning on the date which is 6 months before the expatriation date.


(b) ValueFor purposes of subsection (a)—(1) In generalThe value of specified stock compensation shall be—(A) in the case of a stock option (or other similar right) or a stock appreciation right, the fair value of such option or right, and

(B) in any other case, the fair market value of such compensation.


(2) Date for determining valueThe determination of value shall be made—(A) in the case of specified stock compensation held on the expatriation date, on such date,

(B) in the case of such compensation which is canceled during the 6 months before the expatriation date, on the day before such cancellation, and

(C) in the case of such compensation which is granted after the expatriation date, on the date such compensation is granted.



(c) Tax to apply only if shareholder gain recognizedSubsection (a) shall apply to any disqualified individual with respect to an expatriated corporation only if gain (if any) on any stock in such corporation is recognized in whole or part by any shareholder by reason of the acquisition referred to in section 7874(a)(2)(B)(i) with respect to such corporation.


(d) Exception where gain recognized on compensationSubsection (a) shall not apply to—(1) any stock option which is exercised on the expatriation date or during the 6-month period before such date and to the stock acquired in such exercise</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4985_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Imposition of tax In the case of an individual who is a disqualified individual with respect to any expatriated corporation, there is hereby imposed on such person a tax equal to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4985_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Value For purposes of subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4985_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax to apply only if shareholder gain recognized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tax to apply only if shareholder gain recognized Subsection (a) shall apply to any disqualified individual with respect to an expatriated corporation only if gain (if any) on any stock in such corporation is recognized in whole or part by any shareholder by reason of the acquisition referred to in section 7874(a)(2)(B)(i) with respect to such corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4985_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception where gain recognized on compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exception where gain recognized on compensation Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4985_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4985_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4985_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>