<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5000C" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5000C/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5000C/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5000C"><akn:num>5000C</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax on certain foreign procurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5000C. Imposition of tax on certain foreign procurement(a) Imposition of taxThere is hereby imposed on any foreign person that receives a specified Federal procurement payment a tax equal to 2 percent of the amount of such specified Federal procurement payment.


(b) Specified Federal procurement paymentFor purposes of this section, the term “specified Federal procurement payment” means any payment made pursuant to a contract with the Government of the United States for—(1) the provision of goods, if such goods are manufactured or produced in any country which is not a party to an international procurement agreement with the United States, or

(2) the provision of services, if such services are provided in any country which is not a party to an international procurement agreement with the United States.


(c) Foreign personFor purposes of this section, the term “foreign person” means any person other than a United States person.


(d) Administrative provisions(1) WithholdingThe amount deducted and withheld under chapter 3 shall be increased by the amount of tax imposed by this section on such payment.


(2) Other administrative provisionsFor purposes of subtitle F, any tax imposed by this section shall be treated as a tax imposed by subtitle A.



(Added Pub. L. 111–347, title III, § 301(a)(1), Jan. 2, 2011, 124 Stat. 3666.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 111–347, title III, § 301(a)(3), Jan. 2, 2011, 124 Stat. 3666, provided that: “The amendments made by this subsection [enacting this section] shall apply to payments received pursuant to contracts entered into on and after the date of the enactment of this Act [Jan. 2, 2011].”


Prohibition on Reimbursement of FeesPub. L. 111–347, title III, § 301(b), Jan. 2, 2011, 124 Stat. 3666, provided that:
“(1) In general.—The head of each executive agency shall take any and all measures necessary to ensure that no funds are disbursed to any foreign contractor in order to reimburse the tax i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5000C_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Imposition of tax There is hereby imposed on any foreign person that receives a specified Federal procurement payment a tax equal to 2 percent of the amount of such specified Federal procurement payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5000C_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specified Federal procurement payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Specified Federal procurement payment For purposes of this section, the term “specified Federal procurement payment” means any payment made pursuant to a contract with the Government of the United States for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5000C_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Foreign person For purposes of this section, the term “foreign person” means any person other than a United States person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5000C_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>