<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5001" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5001/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5001/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5001"><akn:num>5001</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition, rate, and attachment of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5001. Imposition, rate, and attachment of tax(a) Rate of tax(1) GeneralThere is hereby imposed on all distilled spirits produced in or imported into the United States a tax at the rate of $13.50 on each proof gallon and a proportionate tax at the like rate on all fractional parts of a proof gallon.


(2) Products containing distilled spiritsAll products of distillation, by whatever name known, which contain distilled spirits, on which the tax imposed by law has not been paid, and any alcoholic ingredient added to such products, shall be considered and taxed as distilled spirits.


(3) Wines containing more than 24 percent alcohol by volumeWines containing more than 24 percent of alcohol by volume shall be taxed as distilled spirits.


(4) Distilled spirits withdrawn free of taxAny person who removes, sells, transports, or uses distilled spirits, withdrawn free of tax under section 5214(a) or section 7510, in violation of laws or regulations now or hereafter in force pertaining thereto, and all such distilled spirits shall be subject to all provisions of law relating to distilled spirits subject to tax, including those requiring payment of the tax thereon; and the person so removing, selling, transporting, or using the distilled spirits shall be required to pay such tax.


(5) Denatured distilled spirits or articlesAny person who produces, withdraws, sells, transports, or uses denatured distilled spirits or articles in violation of laws or regulations now or hereafter in force pertaining thereto, and all such denatured distilled spirits or articles shall be subject to all provisions of law pertaining to distilled spirits that are not denatured, including those requiring the payment of tax thereon; and the person so producing, withdrawing, selling, transporting, or using the denatured distilled spirits or articles shall be required to pay such tax.


(6) Fruit-flavor concentratesIf any volatile fruit-flavor concentrate (or any fruit mash or juice from which such con</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5001_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rate of tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5001_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time of attachment on distilled spirits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Time of attachment on distilled spirits The tax shall attach to distilled spirits as soon as this substance is in existence as such, whether it be subsequently separated as pure or impure spirits, or be immediately, or at any subsequent time, transferred into any other substance, either in the process of original production or by any subsequent process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5001_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduced rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reduced rate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5001_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cross reference For provisions relating to the tax on shipments to the United States of taxable articles from Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands, see section 7652.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>