<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5008" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5008/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5008/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5008"><akn:num>5008</akn:num><akn:heading>Abatement, remission, refund, and allowance for loss or destruction of distilled spirits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5008. Abatement, remission, refund, and allowance for loss or destruction of distilled spirits(a) Distilled spirits lost or destroyed in bond(1) Extent of loss allowanceNo tax shall be collected in respect of distilled spirits lost or destroyed while in bond, except that such tax shall be collected—(A) TheftIn the case of loss by theft, unless the Secretary finds that the theft occurred without connivance, collusion, fraud, or negligence on the part of the proprietor of the distilled spirits plant, owner, consignor, consignee, bailee, or carrier, or the employees or agents of any of them;


(B) Voluntary destructionIn the case of voluntary destruction, unless such destruction is carried out as provided in subsection (b); and


(C) Unexplained shortageIn the case of an unexplained shortage of bottled distilled spirits.



(2) Proof of lossIn any case in which distilled spirits are lost or destroyed, whether by theft or otherwise, the Secretary may require the proprietor of the distilled spirits plant or other person liable for the tax to file a claim for relief from the tax and submit proof as to the cause of such loss. In every case where it appears that the loss was by theft, the burden shall be upon the proprietor of the distilled spirits plant or other person responsible for the distilled spirits tax to establish to the satisfaction of the Secretary that such loss did not occur as the result of connivance, collusion, fraud, or negligence on the part of the proprietor of the distilled spirits plant, owner, consignor, consignee, bailee, or carrier, or the employees or agents of any of them.


(3) Refund of taxIn any case where the tax would not be collectible by virtue of paragraph (1), but such tax has been paid, the Secretary shall refund such tax.


(4) LimitationsExcept as provided in paragraph (5), no tax shall be abated, remitted, credited, or refunded under this subsection where the loss occurred after the tax was determined (as provided in section 5006(a)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distilled spirits lost or destroyed in bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Distilled spirits lost or destroyed in bond</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary destruction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Voluntary destruction The proprietor of the distilled spirits plant or other persons liable for the tax imposed by this chapter or by section 7652 with respect to any distilled spirits in bond may voluntarily destroy such spirits, but only if such destruction is under such supervision and under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distilled spirits returned to bonded premises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distilled spirits returned to bonded premises</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distilled spirits withdrawn without payment of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Distilled spirits withdrawn without payment of tax The provisions of subsection (a) shall be applicable to loss of distilled spirits occurring during transportation from bonded premises of a distilled spirits plant to— The provisions of subsection (a) shall be applicable to loss of distilled spirits withdrawn from bonded premises without payment of tax under section 5214(a)(10) for certain research, development, or testing, until such distilled spirits are used as provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other laws applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other laws applicable All provisions of law, including penalties, applicable in respect of the internal revenue tax on distilled spirits, shall, insofar as applicable and not inconsistent with subsection (c), be applicable to the credits or refunds provided for under such subsection to the same extent as if such credits or refunds constituted credits or refunds of such tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5008_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cross reference For provisions relating to allowance for loss in case of wine spirits withdrawn for use in wine production, see section 5373(b)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>