<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5041" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5041/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5041/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5041"><akn:num>5041</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition and rate of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5041. Imposition and rate of tax(a) ImpositionThere is hereby imposed on all wines (including imitation, substandard, or artificial wine, and compounds sold as wine) having not in excess of 24 percent of alcohol by volume, in bond in, produced in, or imported into, the United States, taxes at the rates shown in subsection (b), such taxes to be determined as of the time of removal for consumption or sale. All wines containing more than 24 percent of alcohol by volume shall be classed as distilled spirits and taxed accordingly. Subject to subsection (h), still wines shall include those wines containing not more than 0.392 gram of carbon dioxide per hundred milliliters of wine; except that the Secretary may by regulations prescribe such tolerances to this maximum limitation as may be reasonably necessary in good commercial practice.


(b) Rates of tax(1) On still wines containing not more than 16 percent of alcohol by volume, $1.07 per wine gallon;

(2) On still wines containing more than 16 percent and not exceeding 21 percent of alcohol by volume, $1.57 per wine gallon;

(3) On still wines containing more than 21 percent and not exceeding 24 percent of alcohol by volume, $3.15 per wine gallon;

(4) On champagne and other sparkling wines, $3.40 per wine gallon;

(5) On artificially carbonated wines, $3.30 per wine gallon; and

(6) On hard cider, 22.6 cents per wine gallon.


(c) Credit(1) Allowance of credit(A) In generalThere shall be allowed as a credit against any tax imposed by this title (other than chapters 2, 21, and 22) an amount equal to the sum of—(i) $1 per wine gallon on the first 30,000 wine gallons of wine, plus

(ii) 90 cents per wine gallon on the first 100,000 wine gallons of wine to which clause (i) does not apply, plus

(iii) 53.5 cents per wine gallon on the first 620,000 wine gallons of wine to which clauses (i) and (ii) do not apply,


which are produced by the producer and removed during the calendar year for consumption or sale, or which are </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5041_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Imposition There is hereby imposed on all wines (including imitation, substandard, or artificial wine, and compounds sold as wine) having not in excess of 24 percent of alcohol by volume, in bond in, produced in, or imported into, the United States, taxes at the rates shown in subsection (b), such taxes to be determined as of the time of removal for consumption or sale. All wines containing more than 24 percent of alcohol by volume shall be classed as distilled spirits and taxed accordingly. Subject to subsection (h), still wines shall include those wines containing not more than 0.392 gram of carbon dioxide per hundred milliliters of wine; except that the Secretary may by regulations prescribe such tolerances to this maximum limitation as may be reasonably necessary in good commercial practice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5041_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rates of tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5041_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5041_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wine gallon</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Wine gallon For the purpose of this chapter, the term “wine gallon” means a United States gallon of liquid measure equivalent to the volume of 231 cubic inches. On lesser quantities the tax shall be paid proportionately (fractions of less than one-tenth gallon being converted to the nearest one-tenth gallon, and five-hundredths gallon being converted to the next full one-tenth gallon).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5041_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tolerances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Tolerances Where the Secretary finds that the revenue will not be endangered thereby, he may by regulation prescribe tolerances (but not greater than ½ of 1 percent) for bottles and other containers, and, if such tolerances are prescribed, no assessment shall be made and no tax shall be collected for any excess in any case where the contents of a bottle or other container are within the limit of the applicable tolerance prescribed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5041_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Illegally produced wine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Illegally produced wine Notwithstanding subsection (a), any wine produced in the United States at any place other than the bonded premises provided for in this chapter shall (except as provided in section 5042 in the case of tax-free production) be subject to tax at the rate prescribed in subsection (b) at the time of production and whether or not removed for consumption or sale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5041_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hard cider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Hard cider For purposes of subsection (b)(6), the term “hard cider” means a wine—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5041_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mead and low alcohol by volume wine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Mead and low alcohol by volume wine</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>