<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5053" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5053/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5053/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5053"><akn:num>5053</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5053. Exemptions(a) Removals for exportBeer may be removed from the brewery, without payment of tax, for export, in such containers and under such regulations, and on the giving of such notices, entries, and bonds and other security, as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.


(b) Removals when unfit for beverage useWhen beer has become sour or damaged, so as to be incapable of use as such, a brewer may remove the same from his brewery without payment of tax, for manufacturing purposes, under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.


(c) Removals for laboratory analysisBeer may be removed from the brewery, without payment of tax, for laboratory analysis, subject to such limitations and under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.


(d) Removals for research, development, or testingUnder such conditions and regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, beer may be removed from the brewery without payment of tax for use in research, development, or testing (other than consumer testing or other market analysis) of processes, systems, materials, or equipment relating to beer or brewery operations.


(e) Beer for personal or family useSubject to regulation prescribed by the Secretary, any adult may, without payment of tax, produce beer for personal or family use and not for sale. The aggregate amount of beer exempt from tax under this subsection with respect to any household shall not exceed—(1) 200 gallons per calendar year if there are 2 or more adults in such household, or

(2) 100 gallons per calendar year if there is only 1 adult in such household.


For purposes of this subsection, the term “adult” means an individual who has attained 18 years of age, or the minimum age (if any) established by law applicable in the locality in which the household is situated at which beer may be sold to individuals, whichever is greater.

(f) Removal for use as distilling materialSubject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, beer may be removed</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5053_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removals for export</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Removals for export Beer may be removed from the brewery, without payment of tax, for export, in such containers and under such regulations, and on the giving of such notices, entries, and bonds and other security, as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5053_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removals when unfit for beverage use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Removals when unfit for beverage use When beer has become sour or damaged, so as to be incapable of use as such, a brewer may remove the same from his brewery without payment of tax, for manufacturing purposes, under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5053_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removals for laboratory analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Removals for laboratory analysis Beer may be removed from the brewery, without payment of tax, for laboratory analysis, subject to such limitations and under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5053_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removals for research, development, or testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Removals for research, development, or testing Under such conditions and regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, beer may be removed from the brewery without payment of tax for use in research, development, or testing (other than consumer testing or other market analysis) of processes, systems, materials, or equipment relating to beer or brewery operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5053_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Beer for personal or family use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Beer for personal or family use Subject to regulation prescribed by the Secretary, any adult may, without payment of tax, produce beer for personal or family use and not for sale. The aggregate amount of beer exempt from tax under this subsection with respect to any household shall not exceed— For purposes of this subsection, the term “adult” means an individual who has attained 18 years of age, or the minimum age (if any) established by law applicable in the locality in which the household is situated at which beer may be sold to individuals, whichever is greater.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5053_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal for use as distilling material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Removal for use as distilling material Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, beer may be removed from a brewery without payment of tax to any distilled spirits plant for use as distilling material.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5053_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removals for use of foreign embassies, legations, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Removals for use of foreign embassies, legations, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5053_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removals for destruction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Removals for destruction Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, beer may be removed from the brewery without payment of tax for destruction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5053_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal as supplies for certain vessels and aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Removal as supplies for certain vessels and aircraft For exemption as to supplies for certain vessels and aircraft, see section 309 of the Tariff Act of 1930, as amended (19 U.S.C. 1309).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>