<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5066" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5066/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5066/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5066"><akn:num>5066</akn:num><akn:heading>Distilled spirits for use of foreign embassies, legations, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5066. Distilled spirits for use of foreign embassies, legations, etc.(a) Entry into customs bonded warehouses(1) Bottled distilled spirits withdrawn from bonded premisesUnder such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, bottled distilled spirits may be withdrawn from bonded premises as provided in section 5214(a)(4) for transfer to customs bonded warehouses in which imported distilled spirits are permitted to be stored in bond for entry therein pending withdrawal therefrom as provided in subsection (b). For the purposes of this chapter, the withdrawal of distilled spirits from bonded premises under the provisions of this paragraph shall be treated as a withdrawal for exportation and all provisions of law applicable to distilled spirits withdrawn for exportation under the provisions of section 5214(a)(4) shall apply with respect to spirits withdrawn under this paragraph.


(2) Bottled distilled spirits eligible for export with benefit of drawbackUnder such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, distilled spirits marked especially for export under the provisions of section 5062(b) may be shipped to a customs bonded warehouse in which imported distilled spirits are permitted to be stored, and entered in such warehouses pending withdrawal therefrom as provided in subsection (b), and the provisions of this chapter shall apply in respect of such distilled spirits as if such spirits were for exportation.


(3) Time deemed exportedFor the purposes of this chapter, distilled spirits entered into a customs bonded warehouse as provided in this subsection shall be deemed exported at the time so entered.



(b) Withdrawal from customs bonded warehousesNotwithstanding any other provisions of law, distilled spirits entered into customs bonded warehouses under the provisions of subsection (a) may, under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, be withdrawn from such warehouses for consumption in the United States by and for the official or family use of such fore</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5066_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entry into customs bonded warehouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Entry into customs bonded warehouses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5066_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal from customs bonded warehouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Withdrawal from customs bonded warehouses Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, distilled spirits entered into customs bonded warehouses under the provisions of subsection (a) may, under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, be withdrawn from such warehouses for consumption in the United States by and for the official or family use of such foreign governments, organizations, and individuals who are entitled to withdraw imported distilled spirits from such warehouses free of tax. Distilled spirits transferred to customs bonded warehouses under the provisions of this section shall be entered, stored, and accounted for in such warehouses under such regulations and bonds as the Secretary may prescribe, and may be withdrawn therefrom by such governments, organizations, and individuals free of tax under the same conditions and procedures as imported distilled spirits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5066_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal for domestic use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Withdrawal for domestic use Distilled spirits entered into customs bonded warehouses as authorized by this section may be withdrawn therefrom for domestic use, in which event they shall be treated as American goods exported and returned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5066_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale or unauthorized use prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Sale or unauthorized use prohibited No distilled spirits withdrawn from customs bonded warehouses or otherwise brought into the United States free of tax for the official or family use of such foreign governments, organizations, or individuals as are authorized to obtain distilled spirits free of tax shall be sold, or shall be disposed of or possessed for any use other than an authorized use. The provisions of section 5001(a)(4) are hereby extended and made applicable to any person selling, disposing of, or possessing any distilled spirits in violation of the preceding sentence, and to the distilled spirits involved in any such violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>