<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/508" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/508/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/508/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_508"><akn:num>508</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules with respect to section 501(c)(3) organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 508. Special rules with respect to section 501(c)(3) organizations(a) New organizations must notify Secretary that they are applying for recognition of section 501(c)(3) statusExcept as provided in subsection (c), an organization organized after October 9, 1969, shall not be treated as an organization described in section 501(c)(3)—(1) unless it has given notice to the Secretary in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, that it is applying for recognition of such status, or

(2) for any period before the giving of such notice, if such notice is given after the time prescribed by the Secretary by regulations for giving notice under this subsection.


(b) Presumption that organizations are private foundationsExcept as provided in subsection (c), any organization (including an organization in existence on October 9, 1969) which is described in section 501(c)(3) and which does not notify the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, that it is not a private foundation shall be presumed to be a private foundation.


(c) Exceptions(1) Mandatory exceptionsSubsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to—(A) churches, their integrated auxiliaries, and conventions or associations of churches, or

(B) any organization which is not a private foundation (as defined in section 509(a)) and the gross receipts of which in each taxable year are normally not more than $5,000.


(2) Exceptions by regulationsThe Secretary may by regulations exempt (to the extent and subject to such conditions as may be prescribed in such regulations) from the provisions of subsection (a) or (b) or both—(A) educational organizations described in section 170(b)(1)(A)(ii), and

(B) any other class of organizations with respect to which the Secretary determines that full compliance with the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) is not necessary to the efficient administration of the provisions of this title relating to private foundations.



</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_508_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>New organizations must notify Secretary that they are applying for recognition of section 501(c)(3) status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) New organizations must notify Secretary that they are applying for recognition of section 501(c)(3) status Except as provided in subsection (c), an organization organized after October 9, 1969, shall not be treated as an organization described in section 501(c)(3)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_508_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumption that organizations are private foundations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Presumption that organizations are private foundations Except as provided in subsection (c), any organization (including an organization in existence on October 9, 1969) which is described in section 501(c)(3) and which does not notify the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, that it is not a private foundation shall be presumed to be a private foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_508_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_508_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowance of certain charitable, etc., deductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disallowance of certain charitable, etc., deductions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_508_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governing instruments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Governing instruments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_508_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional provisions relating to sponsoring organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional provisions relating to sponsoring organizations A sponsoring organization (as defined in section 4966(d)(1)) shall give notice to the Secretary (in such manner as the Secretary may provide) whether such organization maintains or intends to maintain donor advised funds (as defined in section 4966(d)(2)) and the manner in which such organization plans to operate such funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>