<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/51" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/51/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/51/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_51"><akn:num>51</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 51. Amount of credit(a) Determination of amountFor purposes of section 38, the amount of the work opportunity credit determined under this section for the taxable year shall be equal to 40 percent of the qualified first-year wages for such year.


(b) Qualified wages definedFor purposes of this subpart—(1) In generalThe term “qualified wages” means the wages paid or incurred by the employer during the taxable year to individuals who are members of a targeted group.


(2) Qualified first-year wagesThe term “qualified first-year wages” means, with respect to any individual, qualified wages attributable to service rendered during the 1-year period beginning with the day the individual begins work for the employer.


(3) Limitation on wages per year taken into accountThe amount of the qualified first-year wages which may be taken into account with respect to any individual shall not exceed $6,000 per year ($12,000 per year in the case of any individual who is a qualified veteran by reason of subsection (d)(3)(A)(ii)(I), $14,000 per year in the case of any individual who is a qualified veteran by reason of subsection (d)(3)(A)(iv), and $24,000 per year in the case of any individual who is a qualified veteran by reason of subsection (d)(3)(A)(ii)(II)).



(c) Wages definedFor purposes of this subpart—(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this subsection and subsection (h)(2), the term “wages” has the meaning given to such term by subsection (b) of section 3306 (determined without regard to any dollar limitation contained in such section).


(2) On-the-job training and work supplementation payments(A) Exclusion for employers receiving on-the-job training paymentsThe term “wages” shall not include any amounts paid or incurred by an employer for any period to any individual for whom the employer receives federally funded payments for on-the-job training of such individual for such period.


(B) Reduction for work supplementation payments to employersThe amount of w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination of amount For purposes of section 38, the amount of the work opportunity credit determined under this section for the taxable year shall be equal to 40 percent of the qualified first-year wages for such year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified wages defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified wages defined For purposes of this subpart—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wages defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Wages defined For purposes of this subpart—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members of targeted groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Members of targeted groups For purposes of this subpart—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for second-year wages for employment of long-term family assistance recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Credit for second-year wages for employment of long-term family assistance recipients</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remuneration must be for trade or business employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Remuneration must be for trade or business employment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States Employment Service to notify employers of availability of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) United States Employment Service to notify employers of availability of credit The United States Employment Service, in consultation with the Internal Revenue Service, shall take such steps as may be necessary or appropriate to keep employers apprised of the availability of the work opportunity credit determined under this subpart.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for agricultural labor and railway labor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rules for agricultural labor and railway labor For purposes of this subpart—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain individuals ineligible</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Certain individuals ineligible</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to have work opportunity credit not apply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Election to have work opportunity credit not apply</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>