<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/511" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/511/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/511/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_511"><akn:num>511</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable, etc., organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 511. Imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable, etc., organizations(a) Charitable, etc., organizations taxable at corporation rates(1) Imposition of taxThere is hereby imposed for each taxable year on the unrelated business taxable income (as defined in section 512) of every organization described in paragraph (2) a tax computed as provided in section 11. In making such computation for purposes of this section, the term “taxable income” as used in section 11 shall be read as “unrelated business taxable income”.


(2) Organizations subject to tax(A) Organizations described in sections 401(a) and 501(c)The tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall apply in the case of any organization (other than a trust described in subsection (b) or an organization described in section 501(c)(1)) which is exempt, except as provided in this part or part II (relating to private foundations), from taxation under this subtitle by reason of section 501(a).


(B) State colleges and universitiesThe tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall apply in the case of any college or university which is an agency or instrumentality of any government or any political subdivision thereof, or which is owned or operated by a government or any political subdivision thereof, or by any agency or instrumentality of one or more governments or political subdivisions. Such tax shall also apply in the case of any corporation wholly owned by one or more such colleges or universities.




(b) Tax on charitable, etc., trusts(1) Imposition of taxThere is hereby imposed for each taxable year on the unrelated business taxable income of every trust described in paragraph (2) a tax computed as provided in section 1(e). In making such computation for purposes of this section, the term “taxable income” as used in section 1 shall be read as “unrelated business taxable income” as defined in section 512.


(2) Charitable, etc., trusts subject to taxThe tax imposed by paragraph (1) shall apply in the case of any trus</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charitable, etc., organizations taxable at corporation rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Charitable, etc., organizations taxable at corporation rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax on charitable, etc., trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tax on charitable, etc., trusts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for section 501(c)(2) corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule for section 501(c)(2) corporations If a corporation described in section 501(c)(2)— such corporation shall be treated, for purposes of the tax imposed by subsection (a), as being organized and operated for the same purposes as such organization, in addition to the purposes described in section 501(c)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>