<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/514" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/514/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/514/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_514"><akn:num>514</akn:num><akn:heading>Unrelated debt-financed income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 514. Unrelated debt-financed income(a) Unrelated debt-financed income and deductionsIn computing under section 512 the unrelated business taxable income for any taxable year—(1) Percentage of income taken into accountThere shall be included with respect to each debt-financed property as an item of gross income derived from an unrelated trade or business an amount which is the same percentage (but not in excess of 100 percent) of the total gross income derived during the taxable year from or on account of such property as (A) the average acquisition indebtedness (as defined in subsection (c)(7)) for the taxable year with respect to the property is of (B) the average amount (determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary) of the adjusted basis of such property during the period it is held by the organization during such taxable year.


(2) Percentage of deductions taken into accountThere shall be allowed as a deduction with respect to each debt-financed property an amount determined by applying (except as provided in the last sentence of this paragraph) the percentage derived under paragraph (1) to the sum determined under paragraph (3). The percentage derived under this paragraph shall not be applied with respect to the deduction of any capital loss resulting from the carryback or carryover of net capital losses under section 1212.


(3) Deductions allowableThe sum referred to in paragraph (2) is the sum of the deductions under this chapter which are directly connected with the debt-financed property or the income therefrom, except that if the debt-financed property is of a character which is subject to the allowance for depreciation provided in section 167, the allowance shall be computed only by use of the straight-line method.



(b) Definition of debt-financed property(1) In generalFor purposes of this section, the term “debt-financed property” means any property which is held to produce income and with respect to which there is an acquisition indebte</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_514_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unrelated debt-financed income and deductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unrelated debt-financed income and deductions In computing under section 512 the unrelated business taxable income for any taxable year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_514_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of debt-financed property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definition of debt-financed property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_514_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition indebtedness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Acquisition indebtedness</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_514_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis of debt-financed property acquired in corporate liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Basis of debt-financed property acquired in corporate liquidation For purposes of this subtitle, if the property was acquired in a complete or partial liquidation of a corporation in exchange for its stock, the basis of the property shall be the same as it would be in the hands of the transferor corporation, increased by the amount of gain recognized to the transferor corporation upon such distribution and by the amount of any gain to the organization which was included, on account of such distribution, in unrelated business taxable income under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_514_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allocation rules Where debt-financed property is held for purposes described in subsection (b)(1)(A), (B), (C), or (D) as well as for other purposes, proper allocation shall be made with respect to basis, indebtedness, and income and deductions. The allocations required by this section shall be made in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary to the extent proper to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_514_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal property leased with real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Personal property leased with real property For purposes of this section, the term “real property” includes personal property of the lessor leased by it to a lessee of its real estate if the lease of such personal property is made under, or in connection with, the lease of such real estate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_514_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations to prevent the circumvention of any provision of this section through the use of segregated asset accounts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>