<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5171" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5171/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5171/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5171"><akn:num>5171</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5171. Establishment(a) Certain operations may be conducted only on bonded premisesExcept as otherwise provided by law, operations as a distiller, warehouseman, or processor may be conducted only on the bonded premises of a distilled spirits plant by a person who is qualified under this subchapter.


(b) Establishment of distilled spirits plantA distilled spirits plant may be established only by a person who intends to conduct at such plant operations as a distiller, as a warehouseman, or as both.


(c) Registration(1) In generalEach person shall, before commencing operations at a distilled spirits plant (and at such other times as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe), make application to the Secretary for, and receive notice of, the registration of such plant.


(2) Application required where new operations are addedNo operation in addition to those set forth in the application made pursuant to paragraph (1) may be conducted at a distilled spirits plant until the person has made application to the Secretary for, and received notice of, the registration of such additional operation.


(3) Secretary may establish minimum capacity and level of activity requirementsThe Secretary may by regulations prescribe for each type of operation minimum capacity and level of activity requirements for qualifying premises as a distilled spirits plant.


(4) Applicant must comply with law and regulationsNo plant (or additional operation) shall be registered under this section until the applicant has complied with the requirements of law and regulations in relation to the qualification of such plant (or additional operation).



(d) Permits(1) RequirementsEach person required to file an application for registration under subsection (c) whose distilled spirits operations (or any part thereof) are not required to be covered by a basic permit under the Federal Alcohol Administration Act (27 U.S.C. secs. 203 and 204) shall, before commencing the operations (or part thereof) not so</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5171_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain operations may be conducted only on bonded premises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Certain operations may be conducted only on bonded premises Except as otherwise provided by law, operations as a distiller, warehouseman, or processor may be conducted only on the bonded premises of a distilled spirits plant by a person who is qualified under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5171_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of distilled spirits plant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of distilled spirits plant A distilled spirits plant may be established only by a person who intends to conduct at such plant operations as a distiller, as a warehouseman, or as both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5171_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Registration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5171_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5171_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>