<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5179" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5179/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5179/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5179"><akn:num>5179</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of stills</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5179. Registration of stills(a) RequirementsEvery person having in his possession or custody, or under his control, any still or distilling apparatus set up, shall register such still or apparatus with the Secretary immediately on its being set up, by subscribing and filing with the Secretary a statement, in writing, setting forth the particular place where such still or distilling apparatus is set up, the kind of still and its capacity, the owner thereof, his place of residence, and the purpose for which said still or distilling apparatus has been or is intended to be used (except that stills or distilling apparatus not used or intended to be used for the distillation, redistillation, or recovery of distilled spirits are not required to be registered under this section).


(b) Cross references(1) For penalty and forfeiture provisions relating to unregistered stills, see sections 5601(a)(1) and 5615(1).

(2) For provisions requiring notification to set up a still, boiler, or other vessel for distilling, see section 5101(a)(2).


(Added Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1355; amended Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, §§ 1905(b)(6)(C), 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1823, 1834; Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 451(b)(1), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 819.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 5179, act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 631, related to “survey of distillery”, prior to the general revision of this chapter by Pub. L. 85–859.
Provisions similar to those comprising this section were contained in prior sections 5174 and 5275(2), act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 630, 651, prior to the general revision of this chapter by Pub. L. 85–859.

Amendments1984—Subsec. (b)(2). Pub. L. 98–369 substituted “notification to set up a still, boiler, or other vessel for distilling, see section 5101(a)(2)” for “permit to set up a still, boiler or other vessel for distilling, see section 5105”.
1976—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 94–455, § 1906(b)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5179_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements Every person having in his possession or custody, or under his control, any still or distilling apparatus set up, shall register such still or apparatus with the Secretary immediately on its being set up, by subscribing and filing with the Secretary a statement, in writing, setting forth the particular place where such still or distilling apparatus is set up, the kind of still and its capacity, the owner thereof, his place of residence, and the purpose for which said still or distilling apparatus has been or is intended to be used (except that stills or distilling apparatus not used or intended to be used for the distillation, redistillation, or recovery of distilled spirits are not required to be registered under this section).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5179_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>