<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5181" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5181/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5181/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5181"><akn:num>5181</akn:num><akn:heading>Distilled spirits for fuel use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5181. Distilled spirits for fuel use(a) In general(1) Purposes for which plant may be establishedOn such application and bond and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe by regulation, a person may establish a distilled spirits plant solely for the purpose of—(A) producing, processing, and storing, and

(B) using or distributing,


distilled spirits to be used exclusively for fuel use.

(2) RegulationsIn prescribing regulations under paragraph (1) and in carrying out the provisions of this section, the Secretary shall, to the greatest extent possible, take steps to—(A) expedite all applications;

(B) establish a minimum bond; and

(C) generally encourage and promote (through regulation or otherwise) the production of alcohol for fuel purposes.



(b) Authority to exemptThe Secretary may by regulation provide for the waiver of any provision of this chapter (other than this section or any provision requiring the payment of tax) for any distilled spirits plant described in subsection (a) if the Secretary finds it necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.


(c) Special rules for small plant production(1) Applications(A) In generalAn application for an operating permit for an eligible distilled spirits plant shall be in such a form and manner, and contain such information, as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe; except that the Secretary shall, to the greatest extent possible, take steps to simplify the application so as to expedite the issuance of such permits.


(B) Receipt of applicationWithin 15 days of receipt of an application under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall send a written notice of receipt to the applicant, together with a statement as to whether the application meets the requirements of subparagraph (A). If such a notice is not sent and the applicant has a receipt indicating that the Secretary has received an application, paragraph (2) shall apply as if a written notice required by the preceding sentence, together with a st</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5181_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5181_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to exempt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to exempt The Secretary may by regulation provide for the waiver of any provision of this chapter (other than this section or any provision requiring the payment of tax) for any distilled spirits plant described in subsection (a) if the Secretary finds it necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5181_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for small plant production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules for small plant production</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5181_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal free of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Withdrawal free of tax Distilled spirits produced under this section may be withdrawn free of tax from the bonded premises (and any premises which are not bonded by reason of subsection (c)(3)) of a distilled spirits plant exclusively for fuel use as provided in section 5214(a)(12).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5181_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited withdrawal, use, sale, or disposition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibited withdrawal, use, sale, or disposition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5181_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of distilled spirits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definition of distilled spirits For purposes of this section, the term “distilled spirits” does not include distilled spirits produced from petroleum, natural gas, or coal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>