<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5204" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5204/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5204/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5204"><akn:num>5204</akn:num><akn:heading>Gauging</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5204. Gauging(a) GeneralThe Secretary may by regulations require the gauging of distilled spirits for such purposes, as he may deem necessary, and all required gauges shall be made at such times and under such conditions as he may by regulations prescribe.


(b) Gauging instrumentsFor the determination of tax and the pre­vention and detection of frauds, the Secretary may prescribe for use such hydrometers, saccharometers, weighing and gauging instruments, or other means or methods for ascertaining the quantity, gravity, and producing capacity of any mash, wort, or beer used, or to be used, in the production of distilled spirits, and the strength and quantity of spirits subject to tax, as he may deem necessary; and he may prescribe regulations to secure a uniform and correct system of inspection, weighing, marking, and gauging of spirits.


(c) Gauging, marking, and branding by proprietorsThe Secretary may by regulations require the proprietor of a distilled spirits plant, at the proprietor’s expense and under such supervision as the Secretary may require, to do such gauging, marking, and branding and such mechanical labor pertaining thereto as the Secretary deems proper and determines may be done without danger to the revenue.


(Added Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1358; amended Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834; Pub. L. 96–39, title VIII, § 807(a)(23), July 26, 1979, 93 Stat. 283; Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 454(c)(4), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 821.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those comprising this section were contained in prior sections of act Aug. 16, 1954, prior to the general revision of this chapter by Pub. L. 85–859, as follows:







Present subsecs.:Prior sections


(a)5193(a), 5194(g), 5245, 5282(b).
(b)5212.
(c)5193(d), 5250(b), 5282(b), 5306.




The prior sections, act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, are set out in 68A Stat. 633, 634, 636, 639, 647, 649, 652,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5204_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General The Secretary may by regulations require the gauging of distilled spirits for such purposes, as he may deem necessary, and all required gauges shall be made at such times and under such conditions as he may by regulations prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5204_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gauging instruments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Gauging instruments For the determination of tax and the pre­vention and detection of frauds, the Secretary may prescribe for use such hydrometers, saccharometers, weighing and gauging instruments, or other means or methods for ascertaining the quantity, gravity, and producing capacity of any mash, wort, or beer used, or to be used, in the production of distilled spirits, and the strength and quantity of spirits subject to tax, as he may deem necessary; and he may prescribe regulations to secure a uniform and correct system of inspection, weighing, marking, and gauging of spirits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5204_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gauging, marking, and branding by proprietors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Gauging, marking, and branding by proprietors The Secretary may by regulations require the proprietor of a distilled spirits plant, at the proprietor’s expense and under such supervision as the Secretary may require, to do such gauging, marking, and branding and such mechanical labor pertaining thereto as the Secretary deems proper and determines may be done without danger to the revenue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>