<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5206" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5206/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5206/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5206"><akn:num>5206</akn:num><akn:heading>Containers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5206. Containers(a) Authority to prescribeThe Secretary shall by regulations prescribe the types or kinds of containers which may be used to contain, store, transfer, convey, remove, or withdraw distilled spirits.


(b) Standards of fillThe Secretary may by regulations prescribe the standards of fill for approved containers.


(c) Marking, branding, or identificationContainers of distilled spirits (and cases containing bottles or other containers of such spirits) shall be marked, branded, or identified in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe.


(d) Effacement of marks and brands on emptied containersEvery person who empties, or causes to be emptied, any container of distilled spirits bearing any mark or brand required by law (or regulations pursuant thereto) shall at the time of emptying such container efface and obliterate such mark or brand; except that the Secretary may, by regulations, waive any requirement of this subsection where he determines that no jeopardy to the revenue will be involved.


(e) ApplicabilityThis section shall be applicable exclusively with respect to containers of distilled spirits for industrial use, with respect to containers of distilled spirits of a capacity of more than one gallon for other than industrial use, and with respect to cases containing bottles or other containers of distilled spirits.


(f) Cross references(1) For other provisions relating to regulation of containers of distilled spirits, see section 5301.

(2) For provisions relating to labeling containers of distilled spirits of one gallon or less for nonindustrial uses, see section 105(e) of the Federal Alcohol Administration Act (27 U.S.C. 205(e)).

(3) For provisions relating to the marking and branding of containers of distilled spirits by proprietors, see section 5204(c).

(4) For penalties and forfeitures relating to marks and brands, see sections 5604 and 5613.


(Added Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1360; amended</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5206_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to prescribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to prescribe The Secretary shall by regulations prescribe the types or kinds of containers which may be used to contain, store, transfer, convey, remove, or withdraw distilled spirits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5206_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards of fill</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards of fill The Secretary may by regulations prescribe the standards of fill for approved containers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5206_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marking, branding, or identification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Marking, branding, or identification Containers of distilled spirits (and cases containing bottles or other containers of such spirits) shall be marked, branded, or identified in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5206_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effacement of marks and brands on emptied containers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effacement of marks and brands on emptied containers Every person who empties, or causes to be emptied, any container of distilled spirits bearing any mark or brand required by law (or regulations pursuant thereto) shall at the time of emptying such container efface and obliterate such mark or brand; except that the Secretary may, by regulations, waive any requirement of this subsection where he determines that no jeopardy to the revenue will be involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5206_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability This section shall be applicable exclusively with respect to containers of distilled spirits for industrial use, with respect to containers of distilled spirits of a capacity of more than one gallon for other than industrial use, and with respect to cases containing bottles or other containers of distilled spirits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5206_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>