<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5212"><akn:num>5212</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of distilled spirits between bonded premises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5212. Transfer of distilled spirits between bonded premises
Bulk distilled spirits on which the internal revenue tax has not been paid or determined as authorized by law may, under such regulations as the Secretary shall prescribe, be transferred in bond between bonded premises in any approved container. For the purposes of this chapter, the removal of bulk distilled spirits for transfer in bond between bonded premises shall not be construed to be a withdrawal from bonded premises. The provisions of this section restricting transfers to bulk distilled spirits shall not apply to alcohol bottled under the provisions of section 5235 which is to be withdrawn for industrial purposes. In the case of distilled spirits transferred in bond after December 31, 2017, between bonded premises belonging to the same person or members of the same controlled group (within the meaning of section 5001(c)(2)) this section shall be applied without regard to whether distilled spirits are bulk distilled spirits. In the case of distilled spirits transferred in bond from the person who distilled or processed such distilled spirits (hereinafter referred to as “transferor”) to another person for bottling or storage of such distilled spirits, and returned to the transferor for removal, this section shall be applied without regard to whether distilled spirits are bulk distilled spirits, but only if the transferor retains title during the entire period between such distillation, or processing, and removal.
(Added Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1362; amended Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834; Pub. L. 96–39, title VIII, § 805(b)(2), July 26, 1979, 93 Stat. 276; Pub. L. 96–598, § 6(d), Dec. 24, 1980, 94 Stat. 3490; Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 13808(a), Dec. 22, 2017, 131 Stat. 2177; Pub. L. 116–94, div. Q, title I, § 144(h)(1), Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 3235; Pub. L. 116–260, div. EE, title I, § 106(h)(1), (2), Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>