<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5215" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5215/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5215/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5215"><akn:num>5215</akn:num><akn:heading>Return of tax determined distilled spirits to bonded premises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5215. Return of tax determined distilled spirits to bonded premises(a) General ruleUnder such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, distilled spirits on which tax has been determined or paid may be returned to the bonded premises of a distilled spirits plant but only for destruction, denaturation, redistillation, reconditioning, or rebottling.


(b) Applicability of chapter to distilled spirits returned to a distilled spirits plantAll provisions of this chapter applicable to distilled spirits in bond shall be applicable to distilled spirits returned to bonded premises under the provisions of this section on such return.


(c) Return of bottled distilled spirits for relabeling and reclosingUnder such regulations as the Secretary shall prescribe, bottled distilled spirits withdrawn from bonded premises may be returned to bonded premises for relabeling or reclosing, and the tax under section 5001 shall not again be collected on such spirits.


(d) Cross referenceFor provisions relating to the abatement, credit, or refund of tax on distilled spirits returned to a distilled spirits plant under this section, see section 5008(c).


(Added Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1364; amended Pub. L. 89–44, title VIII, § 805(c), June 21, 1965, 79 Stat. 161; Pub. L. 91–659, § 2(c), Jan. 8, 1971, 84 Stat. 1964; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834; Pub. L. 95–176, § 2(a), Nov. 14, 1977, 91 Stat. 1363; Pub. L. 96–39, title VIII, § 807(a)(29), July 26, 1979, 93 Stat. 285; Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title IV, § 454(c)(7), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 821.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 5215, act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 640, related to exemption of distillers of fruit brandy from certain requirements, prior to the general revision of this chapter by Pub. L. 85–859. See sections 5201(c), 5312(a), (c), 5373(a) and 5562 of this title.

Amendments1984—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 98–369 substituted “reclosing” </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5215_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, distilled spirits on which tax has been determined or paid may be returned to the bonded premises of a distilled spirits plant but only for destruction, denaturation, redistillation, reconditioning, or rebottling.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5215_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of chapter to distilled spirits returned to a distilled spirits plant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicability of chapter to distilled spirits returned to a distilled spirits plant All provisions of this chapter applicable to distilled spirits in bond shall be applicable to distilled spirits returned to bonded premises under the provisions of this section on such return.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5215_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return of bottled distilled spirits for relabeling and reclosing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Return of bottled distilled spirits for relabeling and reclosing Under such regulations as the Secretary shall prescribe, bottled distilled spirits withdrawn from bonded premises may be returned to bonded premises for relabeling or reclosing, and the tax under section 5001 shall not again be collected on such spirits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5215_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cross reference For provisions relating to the abatement, credit, or refund of tax on distilled spirits returned to a distilled spirits plant under this section, see section 5008(c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>