<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/529A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/529A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/529A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_529A"><akn:num>529A</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified ABLE programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 529A. Qualified ABLE programs(a) General ruleA qualified ABLE program shall be exempt from taxation under this subtitle. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, such program shall be subject to the taxes imposed by section 511 (relating to imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable organizations).


(b) Qualified ABLE programFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “qualified ABLE program” means a program established and maintained by a State, or agency or instrumentality thereof—(A) under which a person may make contributions for a taxable year, for the benefit of an individual who is an eligible individual for such taxable year, to an ABLE account which is established for the purpose of meeting the qualified disability expenses of the designated beneficiary of the account,

(B) which limits a designated beneficiary to 1 ABLE account for purposes of this section, and

(C) which meets the other requirements of this section.


(2) Cash contributionsA program shall not be treated as a qualified ABLE program unless it provides that no contribution will be accepted—(A) unless it is in cash, or

(B) except in the case of contributions under subsection (c)(1)(C) or received in a qualified ABLE rollover contribution described in section 530A(d)(4)(B), if such contribution to an ABLE account would result in aggregate contributions from all contributors to the ABLE account for the taxable year exceeding the sum of—(i) the amount in effect under section 2503(b) (determined by substituting “1996” for “1997” in paragraph (2)(B) thereof) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, plus

(ii) in the case of any contribution by a designated beneficiary described in paragraph (7), the lesser of—(I) compensation (as defined by section 219(f)(1)) includible in the designated beneficiary’s gross income for the taxable year, or

(II) an amount equal to the poverty line for a one-person household, as determined for the calendar year preceding t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_529A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule A qualified ABLE program shall be exempt from taxation under this subtitle. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, such program shall be subject to the taxes imposed by section 511 (relating to imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable organizations).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_529A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified ABLE program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified ABLE program For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_529A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tax treatment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_529A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_529A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_529A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer to State Subject to any outstanding payments due for qualified disability expenses, upon the death of the designated beneficiary, all amounts remaining in the qualified ABLE account not in excess of the amount equal to the total medical assistance paid for the designated beneficiary after the establishment of the account, net of any premiums paid from the account or paid by or on behalf of the beneficiary to a Medicaid Buy-In program under any State Medicaid plan established under title XIX of the Social Security Act, shall be distributed to such State upon filing of a claim for payment by such State. For purposes of this paragraph, the State shall be a creditor of an ABLE account and not a beneficiary. Subsection (c)(3) shall not apply to a distribution under the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_529A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>