<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5368" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5368/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5368/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5368"><akn:num>5368</akn:num><akn:heading>Gauging and marking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5368. Gauging and marking(a) Gauging and markingAll wine or wine spirits shall be locked, sealed, and gauged, and shall be marked, branded, labeled, or otherwise identified, in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.


(b) MarkingWines shall be removed in such containers (including vessels, vehicles, and pipelines) bearing such marks and labels evidencing compliance with this chapter, as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.


(Added Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1381; amended Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, §§ 1905(a)(20), 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1820, 1834.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 5368, act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 666, consisted of provisions similar to those comprising this section, prior to the general revision of this chapter by Pub. L. 85–859.

Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–455 substituted “Gauging and marking” for “Gauging, marking, and stamping” in section catchline, substituted “Marking” for “Stamping” in heading for subsec. (b), and, in text of subsec. (b), substituted “marks and labels” for “marks, labels, and stamps” and struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1976 AmendmentAmendment by section 1905(a)(20) of Pub. L. 94–455 effective on first day of first month which begins more than 90 days after Oct. 4, 1976, see section 1905(d) of Pub. L. 94–455, set out as a note under section 5005 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gauging and marking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Gauging and marking All wine or wine spirits shall be locked, sealed, and gauged, and shall be marked, branded, labeled, or otherwise identified, in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5368_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Marking Wines shall be removed in such containers (including vessels, vehicles, and pipelines) bearing such marks and labels evidencing compliance with this chapter, as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>