<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5387" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5387/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5387/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5387"><akn:num>5387</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural wines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5387. Agricultural wines(a) In generalWines made from agricultural products other than the juice of fruit shall be made in accordance with good commercial practice as may be prescribed by the Secretary by regulations. Wines made in accordance with such regulations shall be classed as “standard agricultural wines”. Wines made under this section may be cellar treated under the provisions of section 5382(a) and (c).


(b) LimitationsNo wine spirits may be added to wines produced under this section, nor shall any coloring material or herbs or other flavoring material (except hops in the case of honey wine) be used in their production.


(c) Restriction on blendingWines from different agricultural commodities shall not be blended together.


(Added Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1386; amended Pub. L. 90–619, § 5, Oct. 22, 1968, 82 Stat. 1237; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 5387, act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 671, consisted of provisions similar to those comprising this section, prior to the general revision of this chapter by Pub. L. 85–859.

Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–455 struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.
1968—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 90–619 inserted reference to subsec. (a) of section 5382.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1968 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 90–619 effective on first day of first month which begins 90 days or more after Oct. 22, 1968, see section 6 of Pub. L. 90–619, set out as a note under section 5373 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Wines made from agricultural products other than the juice of fruit shall be made in accordance with good commercial practice as may be prescribed by the Secretary by regulations. Wines made in accordance with such regulations shall be classed as “standard agricultural wines”. Wines made under this section may be cellar treated under the provisions of section 5382(a) and (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations No wine spirits may be added to wines produced under this section, nor shall any coloring material or herbs or other flavoring material (except hops in the case of honey wine) be used in their production.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5387_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on blending</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Restriction on blending Wines from different agricultural commodities shall not be blended together.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>