<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5402"><akn:num>5402</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5402. Definitions(a) BreweryThe brewery shall consist of the land and buildings described in the brewer’s notice. The continuity of the brewery must be unbroken except where separated by public passageways, streets, highways, waterways, or carrier rights-of-way, or partitions; and if parts of the brewery are so separated they must abut on the dividing medium and be adjacent to each other. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, facilities under the control of the brewer for case packing, loading, or storing which are located within reasonable proximity to the brewery packaging facilities may be approved by the Secretary as a part of the brewery if the revenue will not be jeopardized thereby.


(b) BrewerFor definition of brewer, see section 5052(d).


(Added Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1389; amended Pub. L. 91–673, § 3(b), Jan. 12, 1971, 84 Stat. 2057; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834; Pub. L. 109–59, title XI, § 11125(b)(17), Aug. 10, 2005, 119 Stat. 1956.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 5402, act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 674, consisted of provisions similar to those comprising this section, prior to the general revision of this chapter by Pub. L. 85–859.

Amendments2005—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 109–59 substituted “section 5052(d)” for “section 5092”.
1976—Pub. L. 94–455 struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.
1971—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 91–673 inserted proviso to definition of “Brewery” that the continuity of the brewery must be unbroken except where separated by public passageways, streets, highways, waterways, or carrier rights-of-way, or partitions, with the exception that the Secretary approve facilities under the control of the brewer for case packing, loading, or storing, which are located within reasonable proximity to the brewery as a part of the brewery if the revenue will not be jeopardized thereby.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Brewery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Brewery The brewery shall consist of the land and buildings described in the brewer’s notice. The continuity of the brewery must be unbroken except where separated by public passageways, streets, highways, waterways, or carrier rights-of-way, or partitions; and if parts of the brewery are so separated they must abut on the dividing medium and be adjacent to each other. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, facilities under the control of the brewer for case packing, loading, or storing which are located within reasonable proximity to the brewery packaging facilities may be approved by the Secretary as a part of the brewery if the revenue will not be jeopardized thereby.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Brewer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Brewer For definition of brewer, see section 5052(d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>