<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/542" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/542/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/542/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_542"><akn:num>542</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of personal holding company</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 542. Definition of personal holding company(a) General ruleFor purposes of this subtitle, the term “personal holding company” means any corporation (other than a corporation described in subsection (c)) if—(1) Adjusted ordinary gross income requirementAt least 60 percent of its adjusted ordinary gross income (as defined in section 543(b)(2)) for the taxable year is personal holding company income (as defined in section 543(a)), and


(2) Stock ownership requirementAt any time during the last half of the taxable year more than 50 percent in value of its outstanding stock is owned, directly or indirectly, by or for not more than 5 individuals. For purposes of this paragraph, an organization described in section 401(a), 501(c)(17), or 509(a) or a portion of a trust permanently set aside or to be used exclusively for the purposes described in section 642(c) or a corresponding provision of a prior income tax law shall be considered an individual.



(b) Corporations filing consolidated returns(1) General ruleIn the case of an affiliated group of corporations filing or required to file a consolidated return under section 1501 for any taxable year, the adjusted ordinary gross income requirement of subsection (a)(1) of this section shall, except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), be applied for such year with respect to the consolidated adjusted ordinary gross income and the consolidated personal holding company income of the affiliated group. No member of such an affiliated group shall be considered to meet such adjusted ordinary gross income requirement unless the affiliated group meets such requirement.


(2) Ineligible affiliated groupParagraph (1) shall not apply to an affiliated group of corporations if—(A) any member of the affiliated group of corporations (including the common parent corporation) derived 10 percent or more of its adjusted ordinary gross income for the taxable year from sources outside the affiliated group, and

(B) 80 percent or more of the am</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule For purposes of this subtitle, the term “personal holding company” means any corporation (other than a corporation described in subsection (c)) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporations filing consolidated returns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Corporations filing consolidated returns</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions The term “personal holding company” as defined in subsection (a) does not include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_542_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for applying subsection (c)(6)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules for applying subsection (c)(6)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>