<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/55" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/55/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/55/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_55"><akn:num>55</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative minimum tax imposed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 55. Alternative minimum tax imposed(a) General ruleThere is hereby imposed (in addition to any other tax imposed by this subtitle) a tax equal to the excess (if any) of—(1) the tentative minimum tax for the taxable year, over

(2) the regular tax for the taxable year plus, in the case of an applicable corporation, the tax imposed by section 59A.


(b) Tentative minimum taxFor purposes of this part—(1) Noncorporate taxpayersIn the case of a taxpayer other than a corporation—(A) In generalThe tentative minimum tax for the taxable year is the sum of—(i) 26 percent of so much of the taxable excess as does not exceed $175,000, plus

(ii) 28 percent of so much of the taxable excess as exceeds $175,000.


The amount determined under the preceding sentence shall be reduced by the alternative minimum tax foreign tax credit for the taxable year.

(B) Taxable excessFor purposes of this subsection, the term “taxable excess” means so much of the alternative minimum taxable income for the taxable year as exceeds the exemption amount.


(C) Married individual filing separate returnIn the case of a married individual filing a separate return, subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting 50 percent of the dollar amount otherwise applicable under clause (i) and clause (ii) thereof. For purposes of the preceding sentence, marital status shall be determined under section 7703.


(D) Alternative minimum taxable incomeThe term “alternative minimum taxable income” means the taxable income of the taxpayer for the taxable year—(i) determined with the adjustments provided in section 56 and section 58, and

(ii) increased by the amount of the items of tax preference described in section 57.


 If a taxpayer is subject to the regular tax, such taxpayer shall be subject to the tax imposed by this section (and, if the regular tax is determined by reference to an amount other than taxable income, such amount shall be treated as the taxable income of such taxpayer for purposes of the preced</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_55_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule There is hereby imposed (in addition to any other tax imposed by this subtitle) a tax equal to the excess (if any) of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_55_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tentative minimum tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tentative minimum tax For purposes of this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_55_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regular tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regular tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_55_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemption amount For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>