<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5553" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5553/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5553/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5553"><akn:num>5553</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of premises and operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5553. Supervision of premises and operations(a) Assignment of internal revenue officersThe Secretary is authorized to assign to any premises established under the provisions of this chapter such number of internal revenue officers as may be deemed necessary.


(b) Functions of internal revenue officerWhen used in this chapter, the term “internal revenue officer assigned to the premises” means the internal revenue officer assigned by the Secretary to duties at premises established and operated under the provisions of this chapter.


(Added Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 201, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1395; amended Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 5553, act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 681, consisted of provisions similar to those comprising this section, prior to the general revision of this chapter by Pub. L. 85–859.
For application to vinegar plants of provisions of prior section 5553(a) relating to assignment of storekeeper-gaugers, see also section 5505(f) of this title.

Amendments1976—Subsecs. (a), (b). Pub. L. 94–455 struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5553_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of internal revenue officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assignment of internal revenue officers The Secretary is authorized to assign to any premises established under the provisions of this chapter such number of internal revenue officers as may be deemed necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5553_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of internal revenue officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions of internal revenue officer When used in this chapter, the term “internal revenue officer assigned to the premises” means the internal revenue officer assigned by the Secretary to duties at premises established and operated under the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>