<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/56" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/56/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/56/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_56"><akn:num>56</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments in computing alternative minimum taxable income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 56. Adjustments in computing alternative minimum taxable income(a) Adjustments applicable to all taxpayersIn determining the amount of the alternative minimum taxable income for any taxable year the following treatment shall apply (in lieu of the treatment applicable for purposes of computing the regular tax):(1) Depreciation(A) In general(i) Property other than certain personal propertyExcept as provided in clause (ii), the depreciation deduction allowable under section 167 with respect to any tangible property placed in service after December 31, 1986, shall be determined under the alternative system of section 168(g). In the case of property placed in service after December 31, 1998, the preceding sentence shall not apply but clause (ii) shall continue to apply.


(ii) 150-percent declining balance method for certain propertyThe method of depreciation used shall be—(I) the 150 percent declining balance method,

(II) switching to the straight line method for the 1st taxable year for which using the straight line method with respect to the adjusted basis as of the beginning of the year will yield a higher allowance.



 The preceding sentence shall not apply to any section 1250 property (as defined in section 1250(c)) (and the straight line method shall be used for such section 1250 property) or to any other property if the depreciation deduction determined under section 168 with respect to such other property for purposes of the regular tax is determined by using the straight line method.

(B) Exception for certain propertyThis paragraph shall not apply to property described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of section 168(f), or in section 168(e)(3)(C)(iv).


(C) Coordination with transitional rules(i) In generalThis paragraph shall not apply to property placed in service after December 31, 1986, to which the amendments made by section 201 of the Tax Reform Act of 1986 do not apply by reason of section 203, 204, or 251(d) of such Act.


(ii) Treatment of certa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_56_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments applicable to all taxpayers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Adjustments applicable to all taxpayers In determining the amount of the alternative minimum taxable income for any taxable year the following treatment shall apply (in lieu of the treatment applicable for purposes of computing the regular tax):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_56_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments applicable to individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjustments applicable to individuals In determining the amount of the alternative minimum taxable income of any taxpayer (other than a corporation), the following treatment shall apply (in lieu of the treatment applicable for purposes of computing the regular tax):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_56_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 115–97, title I, § 12001(b)(8)(A), Dec. 22, 2017, 131 Stat. 2093]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_56_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative tax net operating loss deduction defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Alternative tax net operating loss deduction defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_56_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified housing interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Qualified housing interest For purposes of this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>