<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/562" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/562/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/562/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_562"><akn:num>562</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules applicable in determining dividends eligible for dividends paid deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 562. Rules applicable in determining dividends eligible for dividends paid deduction(a) General ruleFor purposes of this part, the term “dividend” shall, except as otherwise provided in this section, include only dividends described in section 316 (relating to definition of dividends for purposes of corporate distributions).


(b) Distributions in liquidation(1) Except in the case of a personal holding company described in section 542—(A) in the case of amounts distributed in liquidation, the part of such distribution which is properly chargeable to earnings and profits accumulated after February 28, 1913, shall be treated as a dividend for purposes of computing the dividends paid deduction, and

(B) in the case of a complete liquidation occurring within 24 months after the adoption of a plan of liquidation, any distribution within such period pursuant to such plan shall, to the extent of the earnings and profits (computed without regard to capital losses) of the corporation for the taxable year in which such distribution is made, be treated as a dividend for purposes of computing the dividends paid deduction.


For purposes of subparagraph (A), a liquidation includes a redemption of stock to which section 302 applies. Except to the extent provided in regulations, the preceding sentence shall not apply in the case of any mere holding or investment company which is not a regulated investment company.

(2) In the case of a complete liquidation of a personal holding company, occurring within 24 months after the adoption of a plan of liquidation, the amount of any distribution within such period pursuant to such plan shall be treated as a dividend for purposes of computing the dividends paid deduction, to the extent that such amount is distributed to corporate distributees and represents such corporate distributees’ allocable share of the undistributed personal holding company income for the taxable year of such distribution computed without regard to this paragraph a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_562_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule For purposes of this part, the term “dividend” shall, except as otherwise provided in this section, include only dividends described in section 316 (relating to definition of dividends for purposes of corporate distributions).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_562_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions in liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Distributions in liquidation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_562_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferential dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preferential dividends</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_562_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions by a member of an affiliated group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Distributions by a member of an affiliated group In the case where a corporation which is a member of an affiliated group of corporations filing or required to file a consolidated return for a taxable year is required to file a separate personal holding company schedule for such taxable year, a distribution by such corporation to another member of the affiliated group shall be considered as a dividend for purposes of computing the dividends paid deduction if such distribution would constitute a dividend under the other provisions of this section to a recipient which is not a member of an affiliated group.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_562_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for real estate investment trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for real estate investment trusts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>