<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5701"><akn:num>5701</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5701. Rate of tax(a) CigarsOn cigars, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed the following taxes:(1) Small cigarsOn cigars, weighing not more than 3 pounds per thousand, $50.33 per thousand;


(2) Large cigarsOn cigars weighing more than 3 pounds per thousand, a tax equal to 52.75 percent of the price for which sold but not more than 40.26 cents per cigar.



Cigars not exempt from tax under this chapter which are removed but not intended for sale shall be taxed at the same rate as similar cigars removed for sale.

(b) CigarettesOn cigarettes, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed the following taxes:(1) Small cigarettesOn cigarettes, weighing not more than 3 pounds per thousand, $50.33 per thousand;


(2) Large cigarettesOn cigarettes, weighing more than 3 pounds per thousand, $105.69 per thousand; except that, if more than 6½ inches in length, they shall be taxable at the rate prescribed for cigarettes weighing not more than 3 pounds per thousand, counting each 2¾ inches, or fraction thereof, of the length of each as one cigarette.



(c) Cigarette papersOn cigarette papers, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed a tax of 3.15 cents for each 50 papers or fractional part thereof; except that, if cigarette papers measure more than 6½ inches in length, they shall be taxable at the rate prescribed, counting each 2¾ inches, or fraction thereof, of the length of each as one cigarette paper.


(d) Cigarette tubesOn cigarette tubes, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed a tax of 6.30 cents for each 50 tubes or fractional part thereof, except that if cigarette tubes measure more than 6½ inches in length, they shall be taxable at the rate prescribed, counting each 2¾ inches, or fraction thereof, of the length of each as one cigarette tube.


(e) Smokeless tobaccoOn smokeless tobacco, manufactured in or imported into the United S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigars</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cigars On cigars, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed the following taxes: Cigars not exempt from tax under this chapter which are removed but not intended for sale shall be taxed at the same rate as similar cigars removed for sale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigarettes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cigarettes On cigarettes, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed the following taxes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigarette papers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cigarette papers On cigarette papers, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed a tax of 3.15 cents for each 50 papers or fractional part thereof; except that, if cigarette papers measure more than 6½ inches in length, they shall be taxable at the rate prescribed, counting each 2¾ inches, or fraction thereof, of the length of each as one cigarette paper.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigarette tubes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cigarette tubes On cigarette tubes, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed a tax of 6.30 cents for each 50 tubes or fractional part thereof, except that if cigarette tubes measure more than 6½ inches in length, they shall be taxable at the rate prescribed, counting each 2¾ inches, or fraction thereof, of the length of each as one cigarette tube.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Smokeless tobacco</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Smokeless tobacco On smokeless tobacco, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed the following taxes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pipe tobacco</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Pipe tobacco On pipe tobacco, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed a tax of $2.8311 cents per pound (and a proportionate tax at the like rate on all fractional parts of a pound).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Roll-your-own tobacco</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Roll-your-own tobacco On roll-your-own tobacco, manufactured in or imported into the United States, there shall be imposed a tax of $24.78 per pound (and a proportionate tax at the like rate on all fractional parts of a pound).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imported tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Imported tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes The taxes imposed by this section on tobacco products and cigarette papers and tubes imported into the United States shall be in addition to any import duties imposed on such articles, unless such import duties are imposed in lieu of internal revenue tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>