<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5702"><akn:num>5702</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5702. Definitions
When used in this chapter—(a) Cigar“Cigar” means any roll of tobacco wrapped in leaf tobacco or in any substance containing tobacco (other than any roll of tobacco which is a cigarette within the meaning of subsection (b)(2)).


(b) Cigarette“Cigarette” means—(1) any roll of tobacco wrapped in paper or in any substance not containing tobacco, and

(2) any roll of tobacco wrapped in any substance containing tobacco which, because of its appearance, the type of tobacco used in the filler, or its packaging and labeling, is likely to be offered to, or purchased by, consumers as a cigarette described in paragraph (1).


(c) Tobacco products“Tobacco products” means cigars, cigarettes, smokeless tobacco, pipe tobacco, and roll-your-own tobacco.


(d) Manufacturer of tobacco products“Manufacturer of tobacco products” means any person who manufactures cigars, cigarettes, smokeless tobacco, pipe tobacco, or roll-your-own tobacco, except that such term shall not include—(1) a person who produces cigars, cigarettes, smokeless tobacco, pipe tobacco, or roll-your-own tobacco solely for the person’s own personal consumption or use, and

(2) a proprietor of a customs bonded manufacturing warehouse with respect to the operation of such warehouse.


Such term shall include any person who for commercial purposes makes available for consumer use (including such consumer’s personal consumption or use under paragraph (1)) a machine capable of making cigarettes, cigars, or other tobacco products. A person making such a machine available for consumer use shall be deemed the person making the removal as defined by subsection (j) with respect to any tobacco products manufactured by such machine. A person who sells a machine directly to a consumer at retail for a consumer’s personal home use is not making a machine available for commercial purposes if such machine is not used at a retail premises and is designed to produce tobacco products only in personal use quantities.
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigar</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cigar “Cigar” means any roll of tobacco wrapped in leaf tobacco or in any substance containing tobacco (other than any roll of tobacco which is a cigarette within the meaning of subsection (b)(2)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigarette</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cigarette “Cigarette” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tobacco products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tobacco products “Tobacco products” means cigars, cigarettes, smokeless tobacco, pipe tobacco, and roll-your-own tobacco.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturer of tobacco products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Manufacturer of tobacco products “Manufacturer of tobacco products” means any person who manufactures cigars, cigarettes, smokeless tobacco, pipe tobacco, or roll-your-own tobacco, except that such term shall not include— Such term shall include any person who for commercial purposes makes available for consumer use (including such consumer’s personal consumption or use under paragraph (1)) a machine capable of making cigarettes, cigars, or other tobacco products. A person making such a machine available for consumer use shall be deemed the person making the removal as defined by subsection (j) with respect to any tobacco products manufactured by such machine. A person who sells a machine directly to a consumer at retail for a consumer’s personal home use is not making a machine available for commercial purposes if such machine is not used at a retail premises and is designed to produce tobacco products only in personal use quantities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigarette paper</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cigarette paper “Cigarette paper” means paper, or any other material except tobacco, prepared for use as a cigarette wrapper.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigarette tube</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cigarette tube “Cigarette tube” means cigarette paper made into a hollow cylinder for use in making cigarettes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturer of cigarette papers and tubes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Manufacturer of cigarette papers and tubes “Manufacturer of cigarette papers and tubes” means any person who manufactures cigarette paper, or makes up cigarette paper into tubes, except for his own personal use or consumption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Export warehouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Export warehouse “Export warehouse” means a bonded internal revenue warehouse for the storage of tobacco products or cigarette papers or tubes or any processed tobacco, upon which the internal revenue tax has not been paid, for subsequent shipment to a foreign country, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, or a possession of the United States, or for consumption beyond the jurisdiction of the internal revenue laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Export warehouse proprietor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Export warehouse proprietor “Export warehouse proprietor” means any person who operates an export warehouse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5702_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal or remove</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Removal or remove “Removal” or “remove” means the removal of tobacco products or cigarette papers or tubes, or any processed tobacco, from the factory or from internal revenue bond under section 5704, as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe, or release from customs custody, and shall also include the smuggling or other unlawful importation of such articles into the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>