<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/584" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/584/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/584/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_584"><akn:num>584</akn:num><akn:heading>Common trust funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 584. Common trust funds(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this subtitle, the term “common trust fund” means a fund maintained by a bank—(1) exclusively for the collective investment and reinvestment of moneys contributed thereto by the bank in its capacity—(A) as a trustee, executor, administrator, or guardian, or

(B) as a custodian of accounts—(i) which the Secretary determines are established pursuant to a State law which is substantially similar to the Uniform Gifts to Minors Act as published by the American Law Institute, and

(ii) with respect to which the bank establishes, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that it has duties and responsibilities similar to duties and responsibilities of a trustee or guardian; and



(2) in conformity with the rules and regulations, prevailing from time to time, of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Comptroller of the Currency pertaining to the collective investment of trust funds by national banks.


For purposes of this subsection, two or more banks which are members of the same affiliated group (within the meaning of section 1504) shall be treated as one bank for the period of affiliation with respect to any fund of which any of the member banks is trustee or two or more of the member banks are cotrustees.

(b) Taxation of common trust fundsA common trust fund shall not be subject to taxation under this chapter and for purposes of this chapter shall not be considered a corporation.


(c) Income of participants in fundEach participant in the common trust fund in computing its taxable income shall include, whether or not distributed and whether or not distributable—(1) as part of its gains and losses from sales or exchanges of capital assets held for not more than 1 year, its proportionate share of the gains and losses of the common trust fund from sales or exchanges of capital assets held for not more than 1 year,

(2) as part of its gains and losses from sales or exchanges of capital assets held f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_584_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this subtitle, the term “common trust fund” means a fund maintained by a bank— For purposes of this subsection, two or more banks which are members of the same affiliated group (within the meaning of section 1504) shall be treated as one bank for the period of affiliation with respect to any fund of which any of the member banks is trustee or two or more of the member banks are cotrustees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_584_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxation of common trust funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Taxation of common trust funds A common trust fund shall not be subject to taxation under this chapter and for purposes of this chapter shall not be considered a corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_584_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income of participants in fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Income of participants in fund Each participant in the common trust fund in computing its taxable income shall include, whether or not distributed and whether or not distributable— The proportionate share of each participant in the amount of dividends received by the common trust fund and to which section 1(h)(11) applies shall be considered for purposes of such paragraph as having been received by such participant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_584_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of common trust fund income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Computation of common trust fund income The taxable income of a common trust fund shall be computed in the same manner and on the same basis as in the case of an individual, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_584_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Admission and withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Admission and withdrawal No gain or loss shall be realized by the common trust fund by the admission or withdrawal of a participant. The admission of a participant shall be treated with respect to the participant as the purchase of, or an exchange for, the participating interest. The withdrawal of any participating interest by a participant shall be treated as a sale or exchange of such interest by the participant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_584_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Different taxable years of common trust fund and participant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Different taxable years of common trust fund and participant If the taxable year of the common trust fund is different from that of a participant, the inclusions with respect to the taxable income of the common trust fund, in computing the taxable income of the participant for its taxable year, shall be based upon the taxable income of the common trust fund for any taxable year of the common trust fund ending within or with the taxable year of the participant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_584_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net operating loss deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Net operating loss deduction The benefit of the deduction for net operating losses provided by section 172 shall not be allowed to a common trust fund, but shall be allowed to the participants in the common trust fund under regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_584_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonrecognition treatment for certain transfers to regulated investment companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Nonrecognition treatment for certain transfers to regulated investment companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_584_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable year of common trust fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Taxable year of common trust fund For purposes of this subtitle, the taxable year of any common trust fund shall be the calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>