<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5852" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5852/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/5852/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5852"><akn:num>5852</akn:num><akn:heading>General transfer and making tax exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5852. General transfer and making tax exemption(a) TransferAny firearm may be transferred to the United States or any department, independent establishment, or agency thereof, without payment of the transfer tax imposed by section 5811.


(b) Making by a person other than a qualified manufacturerAny firearm may be made by, or on behalf of, the United States, or any department, independent establishment, or agency thereof, without payment of the making tax imposed by section 5821.


(c) Making by a qualified manufacturerA manufacturer qualified under this chapter to engage in such business may make the type of firearm which he is qualified to manufacture without payment of the making tax imposed by section 5821.


(d) Transfers between special (occupational) tax­payersA firearm registered to a person qualified under this chapter to engage in business as an importer, manufacturer, or dealer may be transferred by that person without payment of the transfer tax imposed by section 5811 to any other person qualified under this chapter to manufacture, import, or deal in that type of firearm.


(e) Unserviceable firearmAn unserviceable firearm may be transferred as a curio or ornament without payment of the transfer tax imposed by section 5811, under such requirements as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.


(f) Right to exemptionNo firearm may be transferred or made exempt from tax under the provisions of this section unless the transfer or making is performed pursuant to an application in such form and manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.


(Added Pub. L. 90–618, title II, § 201, Oct. 22, 1968, 82 Stat. 1233; amended Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 5852, act Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 728, related to removing or changing identification marks, prior to the general revision of this chapter by Pub. L. 90–618. See section 5861(g) of this title and sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5852_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer Any firearm may be transferred to the United States or any department, independent establishment, or agency thereof, without payment of the transfer tax imposed by section 5811.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5852_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Making by a person other than a qualified manufacturer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Making by a person other than a qualified manufacturer Any firearm may be made by, or on behalf of, the United States, or any department, independent establishment, or agency thereof, without payment of the making tax imposed by section 5821.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5852_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Making by a qualified manufacturer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Making by a qualified manufacturer A manufacturer qualified under this chapter to engage in such business may make the type of firearm which he is qualified to manufacture without payment of the making tax imposed by section 5821.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5852_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers between special (occupational) tax­payers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfers between special (occupational) tax­payers A firearm registered to a person qualified under this chapter to engage in business as an importer, manufacturer, or dealer may be transferred by that person without payment of the transfer tax imposed by section 5811 to any other person qualified under this chapter to manufacture, import, or deal in that type of firearm.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5852_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unserviceable firearm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Unserviceable firearm An unserviceable firearm may be transferred as a curio or ornament without payment of the transfer tax imposed by section 5811, under such requirements as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5852_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Right to exemption No firearm may be transferred or made exempt from tax under the provisions of this section unless the transfer or making is performed pursuant to an application in such form and manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>