<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6013" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6013/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6013/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6013"><akn:num>6013</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint returns of income tax by husband and wife</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6013. Joint returns of income tax by husband and wife(a) Joint returnsA husband and wife may make a single return jointly of income taxes under subtitle A, even though one of the spouses has neither gross income nor deductions, except as provided below:(1) no joint return shall be made if either the husband or wife at any time during the taxable year is a nonresident alien;

(2) no joint return shall be made if the husband and wife have different taxable years; except that if such taxable years begin on the same day and end on different days because of the death of either or both, then the joint return may be made with respect to the taxable year of each. The above exception shall not apply if the surviving spouse remarries before the close of his taxable year, nor if the taxable year of either spouse is a fractional part of a year under section 443(a)(1);

(3) in the case of death of one spouse or both spouses the joint return with respect to the decedent may be made only by his executor or administrator; except that in the case of the death of one spouse the joint return may be made by the surviving spouse with respect to both himself and the decedent if no return for the taxable year has been made by the decedent, no executor or administrator has been appointed, and no executor or administrator is appointed before the last day prescribed by law for filing the return of the surviving spouse. If an executor or administrator of the decedent is appointed after the making of the joint return by the surviving spouse, the executor or administrator may disaffirm such joint return by making, within 1 year after the last day prescribed by law for filing the return of the surviving spouse, a separate return for the taxable year of the decedent with respect to which the joint return was made, in which case the return made by the survivor shall constitute his separate return.


(b) Joint return after filing separate return(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6013_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint returns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Joint returns A husband and wife may make a single return jointly of income taxes under subtitle A, even though one of the spouses has neither gross income nor deductions, except as provided below:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6013_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint return after filing separate return</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Joint return after filing separate return</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6013_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of joint return after death of either spouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of joint return after death of either spouse For purposes of sections 15, 443, and 7851(a)(1)(A), where the husband and wife have different taxable years because of the death of either spouse, the joint return shall be treated as if the taxable years of both spouses ended on the date of the closing of the surviving spouse’s taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6013_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6013_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 105–206, title III, § 3201(e)(1), July 22, 1998, 112 Stat. 740]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6013_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint return where individual is in missing status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Joint return where individual is in missing status For purposes of this section and subtitle A—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6013_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to treat nonresident alien individual as resident of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Election to treat nonresident alien individual as resident of the United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6013_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint return, etc., for year in which nonresident alien becomes resident of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Joint return, etc., for year in which nonresident alien becomes resident of United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>