<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6042" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6042/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6042/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6042"><akn:num>6042</akn:num><akn:heading>Returns regarding payments of dividends and corporate earnings and profits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6042. Returns regarding payments of dividends and corporate earnings and profits(a) Requirement of reporting(1) In generalEvery person—(A) who makes payments of dividends aggregating $10 or more to any other person during any calendar year, or

(B) who receives payments of dividends as a nominee and who makes payments aggregating $10 or more during any calendar year to any other person with respect to the dividends so received,


shall make a return according to the forms or regulations prescribed by the Secretary, setting forth the aggregate amount of such payments and the name and address of the person to whom paid.

(2) Returns required by the SecretaryEvery person who makes payments of dividends aggregating less than $10 to any other person during any calendar year shall, when required by the Secretary, make a return setting forth the aggregate amount of such payments, and the name and address of the person to whom paid.



(b) Dividend defined(1) General ruleFor purposes of this section, the term “dividend” means—(A) any distribution by a corporation which is a dividend (as defined in section 316); and

(B) any payment made by a stockbroker to any person as a substitute for a dividend (as so defined).


(2) ExceptionsFor purposes of this section, the term “dividend” does not include any distribution or payment—(A) to the extent provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary—(i) by a foreign corporation, or

(ii) to a foreign corporation, a nonresident alien, or a partnership not engaged in a trade or business in the United States and composed in whole or in part of nonresident aliens, or


(B) except to the extent otherwise provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, to any person described in section 6049(b)(4).


(3) Special ruleIf the person making any payment described in subsection (a)(1)(A) or (B) is unable to determine the portion of such payment which is a dividend or is paid with respect to a dividend, he shall, for purposes of subsecti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6042_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement of reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6042_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dividend defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Dividend defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6042_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statements to be furnished to persons with respect to whom information is required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statements to be furnished to persons with respect to whom information is required Every person required to make a return under subsection (a) shall furnish to each person whose name is required to be set forth in such return a written statement showing— The written statement required under the preceding sentence shall be furnished (either in person or in a statement mailing by first-class mail which includes adequate notice that the statement is enclosed) to the person on or before January 31 of the year following the calendar year for which the return under subsection (a) was required to be made and shall be in such form as the Secretary may prescribe by regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6042_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statements to be furnished by corporations to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Statements to be furnished by corporations to Secretary Every corporation shall, when required by the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>