<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6047" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6047/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6047/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6047"><akn:num>6047</akn:num><akn:heading>Information relating to certain trusts and annuity plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6047. Information relating to certain trusts and annuity plans(a) Trustees and insurance companiesThe trustee of a trust described in section 401(a) which is exempt from tax under section 501(a) to which contributions have been paid under a plan on behalf of any owner-employee (as defined in section 401(c)(3)), and each insurance company or other person which is the issuer of a contract purchased by such a trust, or purchased under a plan described in section 403(a), contributions for which have been paid on behalf of any owner-employee, shall file such returns (in such form and at such times), keep such records, make such identification of contracts and funds (and accounts within such funds), and supply such information, as the Secretary shall by forms or regulations prescribe.


(b) Owner-employeesEvery individual on whose behalf contributions have been paid as an owner-employee (as defined in section 401(c)(3))—(1) to a trust described in section 401(a) which is exempt from tax under section 501(a), or

(2) to an insurance company or other person under a plan described in section 403(a),


shall furnish the trustee, insurance company, or other person, as the case may be, such information at such times and in such form and manner as the Secretary shall prescribe by forms or regulations.

(c) Other programsTo the extent provided by regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the provisions of this section apply with respect to any payment described in section 219 and to transactions of any trust described in section 408(a) or under an individual retirement annuity described in section 408(b).


(d) Reports by employers, plan administrators, etc.(1) In generalThe Secretary shall by forms or regulations require that—(A) the employer maintaining, or the plan administrator (within the meaning of section 414(g)) of, a plan from which designated distributions (as defined in section 3405(e)(1)) may be made, and

(B) any person issuing any contract under which designated di</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6047_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trustees and insurance companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Trustees and insurance companies The trustee of a trust described in section 401(a) which is exempt from tax under section 501(a) to which contributions have been paid under a plan on behalf of any owner-employee (as defined in section 401(c)(3)), and each insurance company or other person which is the issuer of a contract purchased by such a trust, or purchased under a plan described in section 403(a), contributions for which have been paid on behalf of any owner-employee, shall file such returns (in such form and at such times), keep such records, make such identification of contracts and funds (and accounts within such funds), and supply such information, as the Secretary shall by forms or regulations prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6047_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Owner-employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Owner-employees Every individual on whose behalf contributions have been paid as an owner-employee (as defined in section 401(c)(3))— shall furnish the trustee, insurance company, or other person, as the case may be, such information at such times and in such form and manner as the Secretary shall prescribe by forms or regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6047_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other programs To the extent provided by regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the provisions of this section apply with respect to any payment described in section 219 and to transactions of any trust described in section 408(a) or under an individual retirement annuity described in section 408(b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6047_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by employers, plan administrators, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports by employers, plan administrators, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6047_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee stock ownership plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Employee stock ownership plans The Secretary shall require— to make returns and reports regarding such plan, transaction, or loan to the Secretary and to such other persons as the Secretary may prescribe. Such returns and reports shall be made in such form, shall be made at such time, and shall contain such information as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6047_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated Roth contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Designated Roth contributions The Secretary shall require the plan administrator of each applicable retirement plan (as defined in section 402A) to make such returns and reports regarding designated Roth contributions (as defined in section 402A) to the Secretary, participants and beneficiaries of the plan, and such other persons as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6047_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information relating to life insurance contract transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Information relating to life insurance contract transactions This section shall not apply to any information which is required to be reported under section 6050Y.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6047_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>