<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6050V" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6050V/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6050V/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6050V"><akn:num>6050V</akn:num><akn:heading>Returns relating to applicable insurance contracts in which certain exempt organizations hold intere</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6050V. Returns relating to applicable insurance contracts in which certain exempt organizations hold interests(a) In generalEach applicable exempt organization which makes a reportable acquisition shall make the return described in subsection (c).


(b) Time for making returnAny applicable exempt organization required to make a return under subsection (a) shall file such return at such time as may be established by the Secretary.


(c) Form and manner of returnsA return is described in this subsection if such return—(1) is in such form as the Secretary prescribes,

(2) contains the name, address, and taxpayer identification number of the applicable exempt organization and the issuer of the applicable insurance contract, and

(3) contains such other information as the Secretary may prescribe.


(d) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) Reportable acquisitionThe term “reportable acquisition” means the acquisition by an applicable exempt organization of a direct or indirect interest in any applicable insurance contract in any case in which such acquisition is a part of a structured transaction involving a pool of such contracts.


(2) Applicable insurance contract(A) In generalThe term “applicable insurance contract” means any life insurance, annuity, or endowment contract with respect to which both an applicable exempt organization and a person other than an applicable exempt organization have directly or indirectly held an interest in the contract (whether or not at the same time).


(B) ExceptionsSuch term shall not include a life insurance, annuity, or endowment contract if—(i) all persons directly or indirectly holding any interest in the contract (other than applicable exempt organizations) have an insurable interest in the insured under the contract independent of any interest of an applicable exempt organization in the contract,

(ii) the sole interest in the contract of an applicable exempt organization or each person other than an applicable exempt or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6050V_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each applicable exempt organization which makes a reportable acquisition shall make the return described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6050V_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for making return</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Time for making return Any applicable exempt organization required to make a return under subsection (a) shall file such return at such time as may be established by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6050V_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and manner of returns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Form and manner of returns A return is described in this subsection if such return—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6050V_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6050V_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination This section shall not apply to reportable acquisitions occurring after the date which is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>