<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6051" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6051/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6051/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6051"><akn:num>6051</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipts for employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6051. Receipts for employees(a) RequirementEvery person required to deduct and withhold from an employee a tax under section 3101 or 3402, or who would have been required to deduct and withhold a tax under section 3402 (determined without regard to subsection (n)) if the employee had claimed no more than one withholding exemption, or every employer engaged in a trade or business who pays remuneration for services performed by an employee, including the cash value of such remuneration paid in any medium other than cash, shall furnish to each such employee in respect of the remuneration paid by such person to such employee during the calendar year, on or before January 31 of the succeeding year, or, if his employment is terminated before the close of such calendar year, within 30 days after the date of receipt of a written request from the employee if such 30-day period ends before January 31, a written statement showing the following:(1) the name of such person,

(2) the name of the employee (and an identifying number for the employee if wages as defined in section 3121(a) have been paid),

(3) the total amount of wages as defined in section 3401(a),

(4) the total amount deducted and withheld as tax under section 3402,

(5) the total amount of wages as defined in section 3121(a),

(6) the total amount deducted and withheld as tax under section 3101,

[(7) Repealed. Pub. L. 111–226, title II, § 219(a)(3), Aug. 10, 2010, 124 Stat. 2403]

(8) the total amount of elective deferrals (within the meaning of section 402(g)(3)) and compensation deferred under section 457, including the amount of designated Roth contributions (as defined in section 402A),

(9) the total amount incurred for dependent care assistance with respect to such employee under a dependent care assistance program described in section 129(d),

(10) in the case of an employee who is a member of the Armed Forces of the United States, such employee’s earned income as determined for purposes of section 32 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6051_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement Every person required to deduct and withhold from an employee a tax under section 3101 or 3402, or who would have been required to deduct and withhold a tax under section 3402 (determined without regard to subsection (n)) if the employee had claimed no more than one withholding exemption, or every employer engaged in a trade or business who pays remuneration for services performed by an employee, including the cash value of such remuneration paid in any medium other than cash, shall furnish to each such employee in respect of the remuneration paid by such person to such employee during the calendar year, on or before January 31 of the succeeding year, or, if his employment is terminated before the close of such calendar year, within 30 days after the date of receipt of a written request from the employee if such 30-day period ends before January 31, a written statement showing the following: In the case of compensation paid for service as a member of a uniformed service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6051_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule as to compensation of members of Armed Forces</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rule as to compensation of members of Armed Forces In the case of compensation paid for service as a member of the Armed Forces, the statement required by subsection (a) shall be furnished if any tax was withheld during the calendar year under section 3402, or if any of the compensation paid during such year is includible in gross income under chapter 1, or if during the calendar year any amount was required to be withheld as tax under section 3101. In lieu of the amount required to be shown by paragraph (3) of subsection (a), such statement shall show as wages paid during the calendar year the amount of such compensation paid during the calendar year which is not excluded from gross income under chapter 1 (whether or not such compensation constituted wages as defined in section 3401(a)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6051_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional requirements The statements required to be furnished pursuant to this section in respect of any remuneration shall be furnished at such other times, shall contain such other information, and shall be in such form as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe. The statements required under this section shall also show the proportion of the total amount withheld as tax under section 3101 which is for financing the cost of hospital insurance benefits under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6051_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statements to constitute information returns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Statements to constitute information returns A duplicate of any statement made pursuant to this section and in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary shall, when required by such regulations, be filed with the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6051_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Railroad employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Railroad employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6051_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statements required in case of sick pay paid by third parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Statements required in case of sick pay paid by third parties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6051_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable employer-sponsored coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applicable employer-sponsored coverage For purposes of subsection (a)(14)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>