<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6056" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6056/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6056/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6056"><akn:num>6056</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain employers required to report on health insurance coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6056. Certain employers required to report on health insurance coverage(a) In generalEvery applicable large employer required to meet the requirements of section 4980H with respect to its full-time employees during a calendar year shall, at such time as the Secretary may prescribe, make a return described in subsection (b).


(b) Form and manner of returnA return is described in this subsection if such return—(1) is in such form as the Secretary may prescribe, and

(2) contains—(A) the name, date, and employer identification number of the employer,

(B) a certification as to whether the employer offers to its full-time employees (and their dependents) the opportunity to enroll in minimum essential coverage under an eligible employer-sponsored plan (as defined in section 5000A(f)(2)),

(C) if the employer certifies that the employer did offer to its full-time employees (and their dependents) the opportunity to so enroll—(i) the length of any waiting period (as defined in section 2701(b)(4) of the Public Health Service Act) with respect to such coverage,

(ii) the months during the calendar year for which coverage under the plan was available,

(iii) the monthly premium for the lowest cost option in each of the enrollment categories under the plan, and

(iv) the employer share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under the plan,


(D) the number of full-time employees for each month during the calendar year,

(E) the name, address, and TIN of each full-time employee during the calendar year and the months (if any) during which such employee (and any dependents) were covered under any such health benefits plans, and

(F) such other information as the Secretary may require.



The Secretary shall have the authority to review the accuracy of the information provided under this subsection, including the applicable large employer’s share under paragraph (2)(C)(iv).

(c) Statements to be furnished to individuals with respect to whom information is reported(1) I</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6056_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Every applicable large employer required to meet the requirements of section 4980H with respect to its full-time employees during a calendar year shall, at such time as the Secretary may prescribe, make a return described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6056_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and manner of return</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form and manner of return A return is described in this subsection if such return— The Secretary shall have the authority to review the accuracy of the information provided under this subsection, including the applicable large employer’s share under paragraph (2)(C)(iv).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6056_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statements to be furnished to individuals with respect to whom information is reported</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statements to be furnished to individuals with respect to whom information is reported</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6056_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination with other requirements To the maximum extent feasible, the Secretary may provide that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6056_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage provided by governmental units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coverage provided by governmental units In the case of any applicable large employer which is a governmental unit or any agency or instrumentality thereof, the person appropriately designated for purposes of this section shall make the returns and statements required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6056_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this section, any term used in this section which is also used in section 4980H shall have the meaning given such term by section 4980H.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>