<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6059" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6059/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6059/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6059"><akn:num>6059</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic report of actuary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6059. Periodic report of actuary(a) General ruleThe actuarial report described in subsection (b) shall be filed by the plan administrator (as defined in section 414(g) of each defined benefit plan to which section 412 applies, for the first plan year for which section 412 applies to the plan and for each third plan year thereafter (or more frequently if the Secretary determines that more frequent reports are necessary).


(b) Actuarial reportThe actuarial report of a plan required by subsection (a) shall be prepared and signed by an enrolled actuary (within the meaning of section 7701(a)(35)) and shall contain—(1) a description of the funding method and actuarial assumptions used to determine costs under the plan,

(2) a certification of the contribution necessary to reduce the minimum required contribution determined under section 430, the accumulated funding deficiency under section 433, or the accumulated funding deficiency determined under section 431, to zero,

(3) a statement—(A) that to the best of his knowledge the report is complete and accurate, and

(B) that the requirements for reasonable actuarial assumptions under section 430(h)(1), 431(c)(3), or 433(c)(3), whichever are applicable, have been complied with,


(4) such other information as may be necessary to fully and fairly disclose the actuarial position of the plan, and

(5) such other information regarding the plan as the Secretary may by regulations require.


(c) Time and manner of filingThe actuarial report and statement required by this section shall be filed at the time and in the manner provided by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(d) Cross referenceFor coordination between the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Labor with respect to the report required to be filed under this section, see section 3004 of title III of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.


(Added Pub. L. 93–406, title II, § 1033(a), Sept. 2, 1974, 88 Stat. 947; amended Pub. L. 94–455, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6059_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule The actuarial report described in subsection (b) shall be filed by the plan administrator (as defined in section 414(g) of each defined benefit plan to which section 412 applies, for the first plan year for which section 412 applies to the plan and for each third plan year thereafter (or more frequently if the Secretary determines that more frequent reports are necessary).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6059_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actuarial report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Actuarial report The actuarial report of a plan required by subsection (a) shall be prepared and signed by an enrolled actuary (within the meaning of section 7701(a)(35)) and shall contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6059_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time and manner of filing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Time and manner of filing The actuarial report and statement required by this section shall be filed at the time and in the manner provided by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6059_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cross reference For coordination between the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Labor with respect to the report required to be filed under this section, see section 3004 of title III of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>