<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6103"><akn:num>6103</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality and disclosure of returns and return information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6103. Confidentiality and disclosure of returns and return information(a) General ruleReturns and return information shall be confidential, and except as authorized by this title—(1) no officer or employee of the United States,

(2) no officer or employee of any State, any local law enforcement agency receiving information under subsection (i)(1)(C) or (7)(A), any tribal or local child support enforcement agency, or any local agency administering a program listed in subsection (l)(7)(D) who has or had access to returns or return information under this section or section 6104(c), and

(3) no other person (or officer or employee thereof) who has or had access to returns or return information under subsection (c), subsection (e)(1)(D)(iii), paragraph (10), (13), (14), or (15) of subsection (k), paragraph (6), (8), (10), (12), (13) (other than subparagraphs (D)(v) and (D)(vi) thereof), (16), (19), (20), or (21) of subsection (l), paragraph (2) or (4)(B) of subsection (m), or subsection (n),


shall disclose any return or return information obtained by him in any manner in connection with his service as such an officer or an employee or otherwise or under the provisions of this section. For purposes of this subsection, the term “officer or employee” includes a former officer or employee.

(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) ReturnThe term “return” means any tax or information return, declaration of estimated tax, or claim for refund required by, or provided for or permitted under, the provisions of this title which is filed with the Secretary by, on behalf of, or with respect to any person, and any amendment or supplement thereto, including supporting schedules, attachments, or lists which are supplemental to, or part of, the return so filed.


(2) Return informationThe term “return information” means—(A) a taxpayer’s identity, the nature, source, or amount of his income, payments, receipts, deductions, exemptions, credits, assets, liabilities, net worth, t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Returns and return information shall be confidential, and except as authorized by this title— shall disclose any return or return information obtained by him in any manner in connection with his service as such an officer or an employee or otherwise or under the provisions of this section. For purposes of this subsection, the term “officer or employee” includes a former officer or employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of returns and return information to designee of taxpayer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disclosure of returns and return information to designee of taxpayer The Secretary may, subject to such requirements and conditions as he may prescribe by regulations, disclose the return of any taxpayer, or return information with respect to such taxpayer, to such person or persons as the taxpayer may designate in a request for or consent to such disclosure, or to any other person at the taxpayer’s request to the extent necessary to comply with a request for information or assistance made by the taxpayer to such other person. However, return information shall not be disclosed to such person or persons if the Secretary determines that such disclosure would seriously impair Federal tax administration. Persons designated by the taxpayer under this subsection to receive return information shall not use the information for any purpose other than the express purpose for which consent was granted and shall not disclose return information to any other person without the express permission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to State tax officials and State and local law enforcement agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disclosure to State tax officials and State and local law enforcement agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to persons having material interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disclosure to persons having material interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to Committees of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosure to Committees of Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to President and certain other persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Disclosure to President and certain other persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to certain Federal officers and employees for purposes of tax administration, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Disclosure to certain Federal officers and employees for purposes of tax administration, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to Federal officers or employees for administration of Federal laws not relating to tax administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Disclosure to Federal officers or employees for administration of Federal laws not relating to tax administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6103_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statistical use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Statistical use</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>