<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6104"><akn:num>6104</akn:num><akn:heading>Publicity of information required from certain exempt organizations and certain trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6104. Publicity of information required from certain exempt organizations and certain trusts(a) Inspection of applications for tax exemption or notice of status(1) Public inspection(A) Organizations described in section 501 or 527If an organization described in section 501(c) or (d) is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) for any taxable year or a political organization is exempt from taxation under section 527 for any taxable year, the application filed by the organization with respect to which the Secretary made his determination that such organization was entitled to exemption under section 501(a) or notice of status filed by the organization under section 527(i), together with any papers submitted in support of such application or notice, and any letter or other document issued by the Internal Revenue Service with respect to such application or notice shall be open to public inspection at the national office of the Internal Revenue Service. In the case of any application or notice filed after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, a copy of such application or notice and such letter or document shall be open to public inspection at the appropriate field office of the Internal Revenue Service (determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary). Any inspection under this subparagraph may be made at such times, and in such manner, as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe. After the application of any organization for exemption from taxation under section 501(a) has been opened to public inspection under this subparagraph, the Secretary shall, on the request of any person with respect to such organization, furnish a statement indicating the subsection and paragraph of section 501 which it has been determined describes such organization.


(B) Pension, etc., plansThe following shall be open to public inspection at such times and in such places as the Secretary may prescribe:(i) any application filed with respect to the qualification of a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection of applications for tax exemption or notice of status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Inspection of applications for tax exemption or notice of status</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection of annual returns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inspection of annual returns The information required to be furnished by sections 6033, 6034, and 6058, together with the names and addresses of such organizations and trusts, shall be made available to the public at such times and in such places as the Secretary may prescribe. Nothing in this subsection shall authorize the Secretary to disclose the name or address of any contributor to any organization or trust (other than a private foundation, as defined in section 509(a) or a political organization exempt from taxation under section 527) which is required to furnish such information. In the case of an organization described in section 501(d), this subsection shall not apply to copies referred to in section 6031(b) with respect to such organization. In the case of a trust which is required to file a return under section 6034(a), this subsection shall not apply to information regarding beneficiaries which are not organizations described in section 170(c). Any annual return which i</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication to State officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Publication to State officials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public inspection of certain annual returns, reports, applications for exemption, and notices of status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public inspection of certain annual returns, reports, applications for exemption, and notices of status</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>