<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/614" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/614/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/614/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_614"><akn:num>614</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 614. Definition of property(a) General ruleFor the purpose of computing the depletion allowance in the case of mines, wells, and other natural deposits, the term “property” means each separate interest owned by the taxpayer in each mineral deposit in each separate tract or parcel of land.


(b) Special rules as to operating mineral interests in oil and gas wells or geothermal depositsIn the case of oil and gas wells or geothermal deposits—(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this subsection—(A) all of the taxpayer’s operating mineral interests in a separate tract or parcel of land shall be combined and treated as one property, and

(B) the taxpayer may not combine an operating mineral interest in one tract or parcel of land with an operating mineral interest in another tract or parcel of land.


(2) Election to treat operating mineral interests as separate propertiesIf the taxpayer has more than one operating mineral interest in a single tract or parcel of land, he may elect to treat one or more of such operating mineral interests as separate properties. The taxpayer may not have more than one combination of operating mineral interests in a single tract or parcel of land. If the taxpayer makes the election provided in this paragraph with respect to any interest in a tract or parcel of land, each operating mineral interest which is discovered or acquired by the taxpayer in such tract or parcel of land after the taxable year for which the election is made shall be treated—(A) if there is no combination of interests in such tract or parcel, as a separate property unless the taxpayer elects to combine it with another interest, or

(B) if there is a combination of interests in such tract or parcel, as part of such combination unless the taxpayer elects to treat it as a separate property.


(3) Certain unitization or pooling arrangements(A) In generalUnder regulations prescribed by the Secretary, if one or more of the taxpayer’s operating mineral interests part</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_614_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule For the purpose of computing the depletion allowance in the case of mines, wells, and other natural deposits, the term “property” means each separate interest owned by the taxpayer in each mineral deposit in each separate tract or parcel of land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_614_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules as to operating mineral interests in oil and gas wells or geothermal deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rules as to operating mineral interests in oil and gas wells or geothermal deposits In the case of oil and gas wells or geothermal deposits—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_614_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules as to operating mineral interests in mines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules as to operating mineral interests in mines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_614_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operating mineral interests defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Operating mineral interests defined For purposes of this section, the term “operating mineral interest” includes only an interest in respect of which the costs of production of the mineral are required to be taken into account by the taxpayer for purposes of computing the taxable income limitation provided for in section 613, or would be so required if the mine, well, or other natural deposit were in the production stage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_614_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule as to nonoperating mineral interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rule as to nonoperating mineral interests</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>