<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6151" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6151/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6151/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6151"><akn:num>6151</akn:num><akn:heading>Time and place for paying tax shown on returns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6151. Time and place for paying tax shown on returns(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in this subchapter, when a return of tax is required under this title or regulations, the person required to make such return shall, without assessment or notice and demand from the Secretary, pay such tax to the internal revenue officer with whom the return is filed, and shall pay such tax at the time and place fixed for filing the return (determined without regard to any extension of time for filing the return).


(b) Exceptions(1) Income tax not computed by taxpayerIf the taxpayer elects under section 6014 not to show the tax on the return, the amount determined by the Secretary as payable shall be paid within 30 days after the mailing by the Secretary to the taxpayer of a notice stating such amount and making demand therefor.


(2) Use of government depositariesFor authority of the Secretary to require payments to Government depositaries, see section 6302(c).



(c) Date fixed for payment of taxIn any case in which a tax is required to be paid on or before a certain date, or within a certain period, any reference in this title to the date fixed for payment of such tax shall be deemed a reference to the last day fixed for such payment (determined without regard to any extension of time for paying the tax).


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 757; Pub. L. 89–713, § 1(b), Nov. 2, 1966, 80 Stat. 1108; Pub. L. 94–452, § 3(c)(2), Oct. 2, 1976, 90 Stat. 1514; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–455 struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 94–452 substituted “subchapter,” for “section,”.
1966—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 89–713 substituted the revenue officer with whom the return is filed for the principal internal revenue officer for the internal revenue district in which the return is required to be filed as the description of the person to whom the t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6151_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, when a return of tax is required under this title or regulations, the person required to make such return shall, without assessment or notice and demand from the Secretary, pay such tax to the internal revenue officer with whom the return is filed, and shall pay such tax at the time and place fixed for filing the return (determined without regard to any extension of time for filing the return).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6151_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6151_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date fixed for payment of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Date fixed for payment of tax In any case in which a tax is required to be paid on or before a certain date, or within a certain period, any reference in this title to the date fixed for payment of such tax shall be deemed a reference to the last day fixed for such payment (determined without regard to any extension of time for paying the tax).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>