<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6166" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6166/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6166/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6166"><akn:num>6166</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of time for payment of estate tax where estate consists largely of interest in closely hel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6166. Extension of time for payment of estate tax where estate consists largely of interest in closely held business(a) 5-year deferral; 10-year installment payment(1) In generalIf the value of an interest in a closely held business which is included in determining the gross estate of a decedent who was (at the date of his death) a citizen or resident of the United States exceeds 35 percent of the adjusted gross estate, the executor may elect to pay part or all of the tax imposed by section 2001 in 2 or more (but not exceeding 10) equal installments.


(2) LimitationThe maximum amount of tax which may be paid in installments under this subsection shall be an amount which bears the same ratio to the tax imposed by section 2001 (reduced by the credits against such tax) as—(A) the closely held business amount, bears to

(B) the amount of the adjusted gross estate.


(3) Date for payment of installmentsIf an election is made under paragraph (1), the first installment shall be paid on or before the date selected by the executor which is not more than 5 years after the date prescribed by section 6151(a) for payment of the tax, and each succeeding installment shall be paid on or before the date which is 1 year after the date prescribed by this paragraph for payment of the preceding installment.



(b) Definitions and special rules(1) Interest in closely held businessFor purposes of this section, the term “interest in a closely held business” means—(A) an interest as a proprietor in a trade or business carried on as a proprietorship;

(B) an interest as a partner in a partnership carrying on a trade or business, if—(i) 20 percent or more of the total capital interest in such partnership is included in determining the gross estate of the decedent, or

(ii) such partnership had 45 or fewer partners; or


(C) stock in a corporation carrying on a trade or business if—(i) 20 percent or more in value of the voting stock of such corporation is included in determining the gross e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>5-year deferral; 10-year installment payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) 5-year deferral; 10-year installment payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions and special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for interest in 2 or more closely held businesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule for interest in 2 or more closely held businesses For purposes of this section, interest in 2 or more closely held businesses, with respect to each of which there is included in determining the value of the decedent’s gross estate 20 percent or more of the total value of each such business, shall be treated as an interest in a single closely held business. For purposes of the 20-percent requirement of the preceding sentence, an interest in a closely held business which represents the surviving spouse’s interest in property held by the decedent and the surviving spouse as community property or as joint tenants, tenants by the entirety, or tenants in common shall be treated as having been included in determining the value of the decedent’s gross estate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Election Any election under subsection (a) shall be made not later than the time prescribed by section 6075(a) for filing the return of tax imposed by section 2001 (including extensions thereof), and shall be made in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulations prescribe. If an election under subsection (a) is made, the provisions of this subtitle shall apply as though the Secretary were extending the time for payment of the tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proration of deficiency to installments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Proration of deficiency to installments If an election is made under subsection (a) to pay any part of the tax imposed by section 2001 in installments and a deficiency has been assessed, the deficiency shall (subject to the limitation provided by subsection (a)(2)) be prorated to the installments payable under subsection (a). The part of the deficiency so prorated to any installment the date for payment of which has not arrived shall be collected at the same time as, and as a part of, such installment. The part of the deficiency so prorated to any installment the date for payment of which has arrived shall be paid upon notice and demand from the Secretary. This subsection shall not apply if the deficiency is due to negligence, to intentional disregard of rules and regulations, or to fraud with intent to evade tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for payment of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Time for payment of interest If the time for payment of any amount of tax has been extended under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceleration of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Acceleration of payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election in case of certain deficiencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Election in case of certain deficiencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for certain direct skips</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Special rule for certain direct skips To the extent that an interest in a closely held business is the subject of a direct skip (within the meaning of section 2612(c)) occurring at the same time as and as a result of the decedent’s death, then for purposes of this section any tax imposed by section 2601 on the transfer of such interest shall be treated as if it were additional tax imposed by section 2001.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6166_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to the application of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>