<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6213" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6213/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6213/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6213"><akn:num>6213</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions applicable to deficiencies; petition to Tax Court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6213. Restrictions applicable to deficiencies; petition to Tax Court(a) Time for filing petition and restriction on assessmentWithin 90 days, or 150 days if the notice is addressed to a person outside the United States, after the notice of deficiency authorized in section 6212 is mailed (not counting Saturday, Sunday, or a legal holiday in the District of Columbia as the last day), the taxpayer may file a petition with the Tax Court for a redetermination of the deficiency. Except as otherwise provided in section 6851, 6852, or 6861 no assessment of a deficiency in respect of any tax imposed by subtitle A, or B, chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 and no levy or proceeding in court for its collection shall be made, begun, or prosecuted until such notice has been mailed to the taxpayer, nor until the expiration of such 90-day or 150-day period, as the case may be, nor, if a petition has been filed with the Tax Court, until the decision of the Tax Court has become final. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 7421(a), the making of such assessment or the beginning of such proceeding or levy during the time such prohibition is in force may be enjoined by a proceeding in the proper court, including the Tax Court, and a refund may be ordered by such court of any amount collected within the period during which the Secretary is prohibited from collecting by levy or through a proceeding in court under the provisions of this subsection. The Tax Court shall have no jurisdiction to enjoin any action or proceeding or order any refund under this subsection unless a timely petition for a redetermination of the deficiency has been filed and then only in respect of the deficiency that is the subject of such petition. Any petition filed with the Tax Court on or before the last date specified for filing such petition by the Secretary in the notice of deficiency shall be treated as timely filed.


(b) Exceptions to restrictions on assessment(1) Assessments arising out of mathematical or cle</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6213_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for filing petition and restriction on assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Time for filing petition and restriction on assessment Within 90 days, or 150 days if the notice is addressed to a person outside the United States, after the notice of deficiency authorized in section 6212 is mailed (not counting Saturday, Sunday, or a legal holiday in the District of Columbia as the last day), the taxpayer may file a petition with the Tax Court for a redetermination of the deficiency. Except as otherwise provided in section 6851, 6852, or 6861 no assessment of a deficiency in respect of any tax imposed by subtitle A, or B, chapter 41, 42, 43, or 44 and no levy or proceeding in court for its collection shall be made, begun, or prosecuted until such notice has been mailed to the taxpayer, nor until the expiration of such 90-day or 150-day period, as the case may be, nor, if a petition has been filed with the Tax Court, until the decision of the Tax Court has become final. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 7421(a), the making of such assessment or the beginn</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6213_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions to restrictions on assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions to restrictions on assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6213_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to file petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Failure to file petition If the taxpayer does not file a petition with the Tax Court within the time prescribed in subsection (a), the deficiency, notice of which has been mailed to the taxpayer, shall be assessed, and shall be paid upon notice and demand from the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6213_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver of restrictions The taxpayer shall at any time (whether or not a notice of deficiency has been issued) have the right, by a signed notice in writing filed with the Secretary, to waive the restrictions provided in subsection (a) on the assessment and collection of the whole or any part of the deficiency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6213_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of filing period for certain excise taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Suspension of filing period for certain excise taxes The running of the time prescribed by subsection (a) for filing a petition in the Tax Court with respect to the taxes imposed by section 4941 (relating to taxes on self-dealing), 4942 (relating to taxes on failure to distribute income), 4943 (relating to taxes on excess business holdings), 4944 (relating to investments which jeopardize charitable purpose), 4945 (relating to taxes on taxable expenditures), 4951 (relating to taxes on self-dealing), or 4952 (relating to taxes on taxable expenditures), 4955 (relating to taxes on political expenditures), 4958 (relating to private excess benefit), 4971 (relating to excise taxes on failure to meet minimum funding standard), 4975 (relating to excise taxes on prohibited transactions) shall be suspended for any period during which the Secretary has extended the time allowed for making correction under section 4963(e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6213_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with title 11</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with title 11</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6213_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6213_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>