<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6231" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6231/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6231/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6231"><akn:num>6231</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of proceedings and adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6231. Notice of proceedings and adjustment(a) In generalThe Secretary shall mail to the partnership and the partnership representative—(1) notice of any administrative proceeding initiated at the partnership level with respect to an adjustment of any partnership-related item for any partnership taxable year, or any partner’s distributive share thereof,

(2) notice of any proposed partnership adjustment resulting from such proceeding, and

(3) notice of any final partnership adjustment resulting from such proceeding.


Any notice of a final partnership adjustment shall be sufficient if mailed to the last known address of the partnership representative or the partnership (even if the partnership has terminated its existence). The first sentence shall apply to any proceeding with respect to an administrative adjustment request filed by a partnership under section 6227.

(b) Timing of notices(1) Notice of proposed partnership adjustmentAny notice of a proposed partnership adjustment shall not be mailed later than the date determined under section 6235 (determined without regard to paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (a) thereof).


(2) Notice of final partnership adjustment(A) In generalExcept to the extent that the partnership elects to waive the application of this subparagraph, any notice of a final partnership adjustment shall not be mailed earlier than 270 days after the date on which the notice of the proposed partnership adjustment is mailed.


(B) Statute of limitations on adjustmentFor the period of limitations on making adjustments, see section 6235.




(c) Further notices restrictedIf the Secretary mails a notice of a final partnership adjustment to any partnership for any partnership taxable year and the partnership files a petition under section 6234 with respect to such notice, in the absence of a showing of fraud, malfeasance, or misrepresentation of a material fact, the Secretary shall not mail another such notice to such partnership with respect to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6231_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall mail to the partnership and the partnership representative— Any notice of a final partnership adjustment shall be sufficient if mailed to the last known address of the partnership representative or the partnership (even if the partnership has terminated its existence). The first sentence shall apply to any proceeding with respect to an administrative adjustment request filed by a partnership under section 6227.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6231_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of notices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Timing of notices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6231_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Further notices restricted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Further notices restricted If the Secretary mails a notice of a final partnership adjustment to any partnership for any partnership taxable year and the partnership files a petition under section 6234 with respect to such notice, in the absence of a showing of fraud, malfeasance, or misrepresentation of a material fact, the Secretary shall not mail another such notice to such partnership with respect to such taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6231_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to rescind notice with partnership consent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority to rescind notice with partnership consent The Secretary may, with the consent of the partnership, rescind any notice of a partnership adjustment mailed to such partnership. Any notice so rescinded shall not be treated as a notice of a partnership adjustment for purposes of this subchapter, and the taxpayer shall have no right to bring a proceeding under section 6234 with respect to such notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>