<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6302"><akn:num>6302</akn:num><akn:heading>Mode or time of collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6302. Mode or time of collection(a) Establishment by regulationsIf the mode or time for collecting any tax is not provided for by this title, the Secretary may establish the same by regulations.


(b) Discretionary methodWhether or not the method of collecting any tax imposed by chapter 21, 31, 32, or 33, or by section 4481 is specifically provided for by this title, any such tax may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be collected by means of returns, stamps, coupons, tickets, books, or such other reasonable devices or methods as may be necessary or helpful in securing a complete and proper collection of the tax.


(c) Use of Government depositariesThe Secretary may authorize Federal Reserve banks, and incorporated banks, trust companies, domestic building and loan associations, or credit unions which are depositaries or financial agents of the United States, to receive any tax imposed under the internal revenue laws, in such manner, at such times, and under such conditions as he may prescribe; and he shall prescribe the manner, times, and conditions under which the receipt of such tax by such banks, trust companies, domestic building and loan associations, and credit unions is to be treated as payment of such tax to the Secretary.


(d) Time for payment of manufacturers’ excise tax on recreational equipmentThe taxes imposed by subchapter D of chapter 32 of this title (relating to taxes on recreational equipment) shall be due and payable on the date for filing the return for such taxes.


(e) Time for deposit of taxes on communications services and airline tickets(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), if, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, a person is required to make deposits of any tax imposed by section 4251 or subsection (a) or (b) of section 4261 with respect to amounts considered collected by such person during any semimonthly period, such deposit shall be made not later than the 3rd day (not including Saturdays, Sundays,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment by regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment by regulations If the mode or time for collecting any tax is not provided for by this title, the Secretary may establish the same by regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretionary method</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Discretionary method Whether or not the method of collecting any tax imposed by chapter 21, 31, 32, or 33, or by section 4481 is specifically provided for by this title, any such tax may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, be collected by means of returns, stamps, coupons, tickets, books, or such other reasonable devices or methods as may be necessary or helpful in securing a complete and proper collection of the tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Government depositaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of Government depositaries The Secretary may authorize Federal Reserve banks, and incorporated banks, trust companies, domestic building and loan associations, or credit unions which are depositaries or financial agents of the United States, to receive any tax imposed under the internal revenue laws, in such manner, at such times, and under such conditions as he may prescribe; and he shall prescribe the manner, times, and conditions under which the receipt of such tax by such banks, trust companies, domestic building and loan associations, and credit unions is to be treated as payment of such tax to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for payment of manufacturers’ excise tax on recreational equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time for payment of manufacturers’ excise tax on recreational equipment The taxes imposed by subchapter D of chapter 32 of this title (relating to taxes on recreational equipment) shall be due and payable on the date for filing the return for such taxes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for deposit of taxes on communications services and airline tickets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Time for deposit of taxes on communications services and airline tickets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for deposit of certain excise taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Time for deposit of certain excise taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits of social security taxes and withheld income taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Deposits of social security taxes and withheld income taxes If, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, a person is required to make deposits of taxes imposed by chapters 21, 22, and 24 on the basis of eighth-month periods, such person shall make deposits of such taxes on the 1st banking day after any day on which such person has $100,000 or more of such taxes for deposit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of electronic fund transfer system for collection of certain taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of electronic fund transfer system for collection of certain taxes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>