<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6306"><akn:num>6306</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified tax collection contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6306. Qualified tax collection contracts(a) In generalNothing in any provision of law shall be construed to prevent the Secretary from entering into a qualified tax collection contract.


(b) Qualified tax collection contractFor purposes of this section, the term “qualified tax collection contract” means any contract which—(1) is for the services of any person (other than an officer or employee of the Treasury Department)—(A) to locate and contact any taxpayer specified by the Secretary,

(B) to request full payment from such taxpayer of an amount of Federal tax specified by the Secretary and, if such request cannot be met by the taxpayer, to offer the taxpayer an installment agreement providing for full payment of such amount during a period not to exceed 7 years, and

(C) to obtain financial information specified by the Secretary with respect to such taxpayer,


(2) prohibits each person providing such services under such contract from committing any act or omission which employees of the Internal Revenue Service are prohibited from committing in the performance of similar services,

(3) prohibits subcontractors from—(A) having contacts with taxpayers,

(B) providing quality assurance services, and

(C) composing debt collection notices, and


(4) permits subcontractors to perform other services only with the approval of the Secretary.


(c) Collection of inactive tax receivables(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall enter into one or more qualified tax collection contracts for the collection of all outstanding inactive tax receivables.


(2) Inactive tax receivablesFor purposes of this section—(A) In generalThe term “inactive tax receivable” means any tax receivable if—(i) at any time after assessment, the Internal Revenue Service removes such receivable from the active inventory for lack of resources or inability to locate the taxpayer,

(ii) more than 2 years has passed since assessment and such receivable has not been a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Nothing in any provision of law shall be construed to prevent the Secretary from entering into a qualified tax collection contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified tax collection contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified tax collection contract For purposes of this section, the term “qualified tax collection contract” means any contract which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of inactive tax receivables</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Collection of inactive tax receivables</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain tax receivables not eligible for collection under qualified tax collections contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certain tax receivables not eligible for collection under qualified tax collections contracts A tax receivable shall not be eligible for collection pursuant to a qualified tax collection contract if such receivable—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fees The Secretary may retain and use— The Secretary shall keep adequate records regarding amounts so retained and used. The amount credited as paid by any taxpayer shall be determined without regard to this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Federal liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No Federal liability The United States shall not be liable for any act or omission of any person performing services under a qualified tax collection contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Fair Debt Collection Practices Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application of Fair Debt Collection Practices Act The provisions of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act (15 U.S.C. 1692 et seq.) shall apply to any qualified tax collection contract, except to the extent superseded by section 6304, section 7602(c), or by any other provision of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Contracting priority In contracting for the services of any person under this section, the Secretary shall utilize private collection contractors and debt collection centers on the schedule required under section 3711(g) of title 31, United States Code, including the technology and communications infrastructure established therein, to the extent such private collection contractors and debt collection centers are appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxpayers in presidentially declared disaster areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Taxpayers in presidentially declared disaster areas The Secretary may prescribe procedures under which a taxpayer determined to be affected by a Federally declared disaster (as defined by section 165(i)(5)) may request—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6306_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Report to Congress Not later than 90 days after the last day of each fiscal year (beginning with the first such fiscal year ending after the date of the enactment of this subsection), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report with respect to qualified tax collection contracts under this section which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>