<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6307"><akn:num>6307</akn:num><akn:heading>Special compliance personnel program account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6307. Special compliance personnel program account(a) Establishment of a special compliance personnel program accountThe Secretary shall establish an account within the Department for carrying out a program consisting of the hiring, training, and employment of special compliance personnel, and shall transfer to such account from time to time amounts retained by the Secretary under section 6306(e)(2).


(b) RestrictionsThe program described in subsection (a) shall be subject to the following restrictions:(1) No funds shall be transferred to such account except as described in subsection (a).

(2) No other funds from any other source shall be expended for special compliance personnel employed under such program.

(3) Notwithstanding any other authority, the Secretary is prohibited from spending funds out of such account for other than program costs.


(c) ReportingNot later than March of each year, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall submit a report to the Committees on Finance and Appropriations of the Senate and the Committees on Ways and Means and Appropriations of the House of Representatives consisting of the following:(1) For the preceding fiscal year, all funds received in the account established under subsection (a), administrative and program costs for the program described in such subsection, the number of special compliance personnel hired and employed under the program, and the amount of revenue actually collected by such personnel.

(2) For the current fiscal year, all actual and estimated funds received or to be received in the account, all actual and estimated administrative and program costs, the number of all actual and estimated special compliance personnel hired and employed under the program, and the actual and estimated revenue actually collected or to be collected by such personnel.

(3) For the following fiscal year, an estimate of all funds to be received in the account, all estimated administrative and program costs, the estimated num</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of a special compliance personnel program account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of a special compliance personnel program account The Secretary shall establish an account within the Department for carrying out a program consisting of the hiring, training, and employment of special compliance personnel, and shall transfer to such account from time to time amounts retained by the Secretary under section 6306(e)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Restrictions The program described in subsection (a) shall be subject to the following restrictions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting Not later than March of each year, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall submit a report to the Committees on Finance and Appropriations of the Senate and the Committees on Ways and Means and Appropriations of the House of Representatives consisting of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>