<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6323"><akn:num>6323</akn:num><akn:heading>Validity and priority against certain persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6323. Validity and priority against certain persons(a) Purchasers, holders of security interests, mechanic’s lienors, and judgment lien creditorsThe lien imposed by section 6321 shall not be valid as against any purchaser, holder of a security interest, mechanic’s lienor, or judgment lien creditor until notice thereof which meets the requirements of subsection (f) has been filed by the Secretary.


(b) Protection for certain interests even though notice filedEven though notice of a lien imposed by section 6321 has been filed, such lien shall not be valid—(1) SecuritiesWith respect to a security (as defined in subsection (h)(4))—(A) as against a purchaser of such security who at the time of purchase did not have actual notice or knowledge of the existence of such lien; and

(B) as against a holder of a security interest in such security who, at the time such interest came into existence, did not have actual notice or knowledge of the existence of such lien.


(2) Motor vehiclesWith respect to a motor vehicle (as defined in subsection (h)(3)), as against a purchaser of such motor vehicle, if—(A) at the time of the purchase such purchaser did not have actual notice or knowledge of the existence of such lien, and

(B) before the purchaser obtains such notice or knowledge, he has acquired possession of such motor vehicle and has not thereafter relinquished possession of such motor vehicle to the seller or his agent.


(3) Personal property purchased at retailWith respect to tangible personal property purchased at retail, as against a purchaser in the ordinary course of the seller’s trade or business, unless at the time of such purchase such purchaser intends such purchase to (or knows such purchase will) hinder, evade, or defeat the collection of any tax under this title.


(4) Personal property purchased in casual saleWith respect to household goods, personal effects, or other tangible personal property described in section 6334(a) purchased (not for resale) in a casu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchasers, holders of security interests, mechanic’s lienors, and judgment lien creditors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purchasers, holders of security interests, mechanic’s lienors, and judgment lien creditors The lien imposed by section 6321 shall not be valid as against any purchaser, holder of a security interest, mechanic’s lienor, or judgment lien creditor until notice thereof which meets the requirements of subsection (f) has been filed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection for certain interests even though notice filed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Protection for certain interests even though notice filed Even though notice of a lien imposed by section 6321 has been filed, such lien shall not be valid—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection for certain commercial transactions financing agreements, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Protection for certain commercial transactions financing agreements, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>45-day period for making disbursements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) 45-day period for making disbursements Even though notice of a lien imposed by section 6321 has been filed, such lien shall not be valid with respect to a security interest which came into existence after tax lien filing by reason of disbursements made before the 46th day after the date of tax lien filing, or (if earlier) before the person making such disbursements had actual notice or knowledge of tax lien filing, but only if such security interest—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority of interest and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority of interest and expenses If the lien imposed by section 6321 is not valid as against a lien or security interest, the priority of such lien or security interest shall extend to— to the extent that, under local law, any such item has the same priority as the lien or security interest to which it relates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Place for filing notice; form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Place for filing notice; form</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refiling of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Refiling of notice For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions For purposes of this section and section 6324—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6323_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of notice in certain circumstances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Withdrawal of notice in certain circumstances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>