<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6325" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6325/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6325/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6325"><akn:num>6325</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of lien or discharge of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6325. Release of lien or discharge of property(a) Release of lienSubject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary shall issue a certificate of release of any lien imposed with respect to any internal revenue tax not later than 30 days after the day on which—(1) Liability satisfied or unenforceableThe Secretary finds that the liability for the amount assessed, together with all interest in respect thereof, has been fully satisfied or has become legally unenforceable; or


(2) Bond acceptedThere is furnished to the Secretary and accepted by him a bond that is conditioned upon the payment of the amount assessed, together with all interest in respect thereof, within the time prescribed by law (including any extension of such time), and that is in accordance with such requirements relating to terms, conditions, and form of the bond and sureties thereon, as may be specified by such regulations.



(b) Discharge of property(1) Property double the amount of the liabilitySubject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may issue a certificate of discharge of any part of the property subject to any lien imposed under this chapter if the Secretary finds that the fair market value of that part of such property remaining subject to the lien is at least double the amount of the unsatisfied liability secured by such lien and the amount of all other liens upon such property which have priority over such lien.


(2) Part payment; interest of United States valuelessSubject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may issue a certificate of discharge of any part of the property subject to the lien if—(A) there is paid over to the Secretary in partial satisfaction of the liability secured by the lien an amount determined by the Secretary, which shall not be less than the value, as determined by the Secretary, of the interest of the United States in the part to be so discharged, or

(B) the Secretary determines</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of lien</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Release of lien Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary shall issue a certificate of release of any lien imposed with respect to any internal revenue tax not later than 30 days after the day on which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Discharge of property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estate or gift tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Estate or gift tax Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may issue a certificate of discharge of any or all of the property subject to any lien imposed by section 6324 if the Secretary finds that the liability secured by such lien has been fully satisfied or provided for.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subordination of lien</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subordination of lien Subject to such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may issue a certificate of subordination of any lien imposed by this chapter upon any part of the property subject to such lien if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonattachment of lien</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nonattachment of lien If the Secretary determines that, because of confusion of names or otherwise, any person (other than the person against whom the tax was assessed) is or may be injured by the appearance that a notice of lien filed under section 6323 refers to such person, the Secretary may issue a certificate that the lien does not attach to the property of such person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of certificate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect of certificate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of certificates and notices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Filing of certificates and notices If a certificate or notice issued pursuant to this section may not be filed in the office designated by State law in which the notice of lien imposed by section 6321 is filed, such certificate or notice shall be effective if filed in the office of the clerk of the United States district court for the judicial district in which such office is situated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cross reference For provisions relating to bonds, see chapter 73 (sec. 7101 and following).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>