<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6330" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6330/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6330/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6330"><akn:num>6330</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and opportunity for hearing before levy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6330. Notice and opportunity for hearing before levy(a) Requirement of notice before levy(1) In generalNo levy may be made on any property or right to property of any person unless the Secretary has notified such person in writing of their right to a hearing under this section before such levy is made. Such notice shall be required only once for the taxable period to which the unpaid tax specified in paragraph (3)(A) relates.


(2) Time and method for noticeThe notice required under paragraph (1) shall be—(A) given in person;

(B) left at the dwelling or usual place of business of such person; or

(C) sent by certified or registered mail, return receipt requested, to such person’s last known address;


not less than 30 days before the day of the first levy with respect to the amount of the unpaid tax for the taxable period.

(3) Information included with noticeThe notice required under paragraph (1) shall include in simple and nontechnical terms—(A) the amount of unpaid tax;

(B) the right of the person to request a hearing during the 30-day period under paragraph (2); and

(C) the proposed action by the Secretary and the rights of the person with respect to such action, including a brief statement which sets forth—(i) the provisions of this title relating to levy and sale of property;

(ii) the procedures applicable to the levy and sale of property under this title;

(iii) the administrative appeals available to the taxpayer with respect to such levy and sale and the procedures relating to such appeals;

(iv) the alternatives available to taxpayers which could prevent levy on property (including installment agreements under section 6159); and

(v) the provisions of this title and procedures relating to redemption of property and release of liens on property.




(b) Right to fair hearing(1) In generalIf the person requests a hearing in writing under subsection (a)(3)(B) and states the grounds for the requested hearing, such hearing shall be held by the Internal R</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6330_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of notice before levy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement of notice before levy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6330_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to fair hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Right to fair hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6330_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters considered at hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Matters considered at hearing In the case of any hearing conducted under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6330_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeding after hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Proceeding after hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6330_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of collections and statute of limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Suspension of collections and statute of limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6330_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exceptions If— this section shall not apply, except that the taxpayer shall be given the opportunity for the hearing described in this section within a reasonable period of time after the levy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6330_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Frivolous requests for hearing, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Frivolous requests for hearing, etc. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, if the Secretary determines that any portion of a request for a hearing under this section or section 6320 meets the requirement of clause (i) or (ii) of section 6702(b)(2)(A), then the Secretary may treat such portion as if it were never submitted and such portion shall not be subject to any further administrative or judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6330_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions related to exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions related to exceptions For purposes of subsection (f)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>