<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6334" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6334/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6334/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6334"><akn:num>6334</akn:num><akn:heading>Property exempt from levy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6334. Property exempt from levy(a) EnumerationThere shall be exempt from levy—(1) Wearing apparel and school booksSuch items of wearing apparel and such school books as are necessary for the taxpayer or for members of his family;


(2) Fuel, provisions, furniture, and personal effectsSo much of the fuel, provisions, furniture, and personal effects in the taxpayer’s household, and of the arms for personal use, livestock, and poultry of the taxpayer, as does not exceed $6,250 in value;


(3) Books and tools of a trade, business, or professionSo many of the books and tools necessary for the trade, business, or profession of the taxpayer as do not exceed in the aggregate $3,125 in value.


(4) Unemployment benefitsAny amount payable to an individual with respect to his unemployment (including any portion thereof payable with respect to dependents) under an unemployment compensation law of the United States, of any State, or of the District of Columbia or of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.


(5) Undelivered mailMail, addressed to any person, which has not been delivered to the addressee.


(6) Certain annuity and pension paymentsAnnuity or pension payments under the Railroad Retirement Act, benefits under the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Act, special pension payments received by a person whose name has been entered on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor roll (38 U.S.C. 1562), and annuities based on retired or retainer pay under chapter 73 of title 10 of the United States Code.


(7) Workmen’s compensationAny amount payable to an individual as workmen’s compensation (including any portion thereof payable with respect to dependents) under a workmen’s compensation law of the United States, any State, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.


(8) Judgments for support of minor childrenIf the taxpayer is required by judgment of a court of competent jurisdiction, entered prior to the date of levy, to contribute to the support o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6334_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enumeration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enumeration There shall be exempt from levy—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6334_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appraisal The officer seizing property of the type described in subsection (a) shall appraise and set aside to the owner the amount of such property declared to be exempt. If the taxpayer objects at the time of the seizure to the valuation fixed by the officer making the seizure, the Secretary shall summon three disinterested individuals who shall make the valuation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6334_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No other property exempt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No other property exempt Notwithstanding any other law of the United States (including section 207 of the Social Security Act), no property or rights to property shall be exempt from levy other than the property specifically made exempt by subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6334_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exempt amount of wages, salary, or other income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exempt amount of wages, salary, or other income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6334_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Levy allowed on principal residences and certain business assets in certain circumstances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Levy allowed on principal residences and certain business assets in certain circumstances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6334_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Levy allowed on certain specified payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Levy allowed on certain specified payments Any payment described in subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 6331(h)(2) shall not be exempt from levy if the Secretary approves the levy thereon under section 6331(h).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6334_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inflation adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Inflation adjustment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>