<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6335" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6335/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6335/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6335"><akn:num>6335</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of seized property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6335. Sale of seized property(a) Notice of seizureAs soon as practicable after seizure of property, notice in writing shall be given by the Secretary to the owner of the property (or, in the case of personal property, the possessor thereof), or shall be left at his usual place of abode or business if he has such within the internal revenue district where the seizure is made. If the owner cannot be readily located, or has no dwelling or place of business within such district, the notice may be mailed to his last known address. Such notice shall specify the sum demanded and shall contain, in the case of personal property, an account of the property seized and, in the case of real property, a description with reasonable certainty of the property seized.


(b) Notice of saleThe Secretary shall as soon as practicable after the seizure of the property give notice to the owner, in the manner prescribed in subsection (a), and shall cause a notification to be published in some newspaper published or generally circulated within the county wherein such seizure is made, or if there be no newspaper published or generally circulated in such county, shall post such notice at the post office nearest the place where the seizure is made, and in not less than two other public places. Such notice shall specify the property to be sold, and the time, place, manner, and conditions of the sale thereof. Whenever levy is made without regard to the 10-day period provided in section 6331(a), public notice of sale of the property seized shall not be made within such 10-day period unless section 6336 (relating to sale of perishable goods) is applicable.


(c) Sale of indivisible propertyIf any property liable to levy is not divisible, so as to enable the Secretary by sale of a part thereof to raise the whole amount of the tax and expenses, the whole of such property shall be sold.


(d) Time and place of saleThe time of sale shall not be less than 10 days nor more than 40 days from the time of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6335_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of seizure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice of seizure As soon as practicable after seizure of property, notice in writing shall be given by the Secretary to the owner of the property (or, in the case of personal property, the possessor thereof), or shall be left at his usual place of abode or business if he has such within the internal revenue district where the seizure is made. If the owner cannot be readily located, or has no dwelling or place of business within such district, the notice may be mailed to his last known address. Such notice shall specify the sum demanded and shall contain, in the case of personal property, an account of the property seized and, in the case of real property, a description with reasonable certainty of the property seized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6335_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice of sale The Secretary shall as soon as practicable after the seizure of the property give notice to the owner, in the manner prescribed in subsection (a), and shall cause a notification to be published in some newspaper published or generally circulated within the county wherein such seizure is made, or if there be no newspaper published or generally circulated in such county, shall post such notice at the post office nearest the place where the seizure is made, and in not less than two other public places. Such notice shall specify the property to be sold, and the time, place, manner, and conditions of the sale thereof. Whenever levy is made without regard to the 10-day period provided in section 6331(a), public notice of sale of the property seized shall not be made within such 10-day period unless section 6336 (relating to sale of perishable goods) is applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6335_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of indivisible property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sale of indivisible property If any property liable to levy is not divisible, so as to enable the Secretary by sale of a part thereof to raise the whole amount of the tax and expenses, the whole of such property shall be sold.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6335_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time and place of sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time and place of sale The time of sale shall not be less than 10 days nor more than 40 days from the time of giving public notice under subsection (b). The place of sale shall be within the county in which the property is seized, except by special order of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6335_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner and conditions of sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Manner and conditions of sale</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6335_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to request sale of seized property within 60 days</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Right to request sale of seized property within 60 days The owner of any property seized by levy may request that the Secretary sell such property within 60 days after such request (or within such longer period as may be specified by the owner). The Secretary shall comply with such request unless the Secretary determines (and notifies the owner within such period) that such compliance would not be in the best interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6335_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of sale of seized property pending Tax Court decision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Stay of sale of seized property pending Tax Court decision For restrictions on sale of seized property pending Tax Court decision, see section 6863(b)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>