<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6338" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6338/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6338/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6338"><akn:num>6338</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate of sale; deed of real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6338. Certificate of sale; deed of real property(a) Certificate of saleIn the case of property sold as provided in section 6335, the Secretary shall give to the purchaser a certificate of sale upon payment in full of the purchase price. In the case of real property, such certificate shall set forth the real property purchased, for whose taxes the same was sold, the name of the purchaser, and the price paid therefor.


(b) Deed to real propertyIn the case of any real property sold as provided in section 6335 and not redeemed in the manner and within the time provided in section 6337, the Secretary shall execute (in accordance with the laws of the State in which such real property is situated pertaining to sales of real property under execution) to the purchaser of such real property at such sale, upon his surrender of the certificate of sale, a deed of the real property so purchased by him, reciting the facts set forth in the certificate.


(c) Real property purchased by United StatesIf real property is declared purchased by the United States at a sale pursuant to section 6335, the Secretary shall at the proper time execute a deed therefor; and without delay cause such deed to be duly recorded in the proper registry of deeds.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 787; Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 78, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1662; Pub. L. 89–719, title I, § 104(f), Nov. 2, 1966, 80 Stat. 1137; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–455 struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary” wherever appearing.
1966—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 89–719 struck out provisions requiring the endorsement of approval as to the form of the deed by the United States Attorney for the district in which the property is situated.
1958—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 85–866 struck out “district” before “attorney”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1966 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 89–719 applicable after No</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6338_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate of sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Certificate of sale In the case of property sold as provided in section 6335, the Secretary shall give to the purchaser a certificate of sale upon payment in full of the purchase price. In the case of real property, such certificate shall set forth the real property purchased, for whose taxes the same was sold, the name of the purchaser, and the price paid therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6338_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deed to real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deed to real property In the case of any real property sold as provided in section 6335 and not redeemed in the manner and within the time provided in section 6337, the Secretary shall execute (in accordance with the laws of the State in which such real property is situated pertaining to sales of real property under execution) to the purchaser of such real property at such sale, upon his surrender of the certificate of sale, a deed of the real property so purchased by him, reciting the facts set forth in the certificate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6338_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Real property purchased by United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Real property purchased by United States If real property is declared purchased by the United States at a sale pursuant to section 6335, the Secretary shall at the proper time execute a deed therefor; and without delay cause such deed to be duly recorded in the proper registry of deeds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>