<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/636" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/636/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/636/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_636"><akn:num>636</akn:num><akn:heading>Income tax treatment of mineral production payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 636. Income tax treatment of mineral production payments(a) Carved-out production paymentsA production payment carved out of mineral property shall be treated, for purposes of this subtitle, as if it were a mortgage loan on the property, and shall not qualify as an economic interest in the mineral property. In the case of a production payment carved out for exploration or development of a mineral property, the preceding sentence shall apply only if and to the extent gross income from the property (for purposes of section 613) would be realized, in the absence of the application of such sentence, by the person creating the production payment.


(b) Retained production payment on sale of mineral propertyA production payment retained on the sale of a mineral property shall be treated, for purposes of this subtitle, as if it were a purchase money mortgage loan and shall not qualify as an economic interest in the mineral property.


(c) Retained production payment on lease of mineral propertyA production payment retained in a mineral property by the lessor in a leasing transaction shall be treated, for purposes of this subtitle, insofar as the lessee (or his successors in interest) is concerned, as if it were a bonus granted by the lessee to the lessor payable in installments. The treatment of the production payment in the hands of the lessor shall be determined without regard to the provisions of this subsection.


(d) DefinitionAs used in this section, the term “mineral property” has the meaning assigned to the term “property” in section 614(a).


(e) RegulationsThe Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.


(Added Pub. L. 91–172, title V, § 503(a), Dec. 30, 1969, 83 Stat. 630; amended Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1976—Subsec. (e). Pub. L. 94–455 struck out “or his delegate” after “Secretary”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carved-out production payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Carved-out production payments A production payment carved out of mineral property shall be treated, for purposes of this subtitle, as if it were a mortgage loan on the property, and shall not qualify as an economic interest in the mineral property. In the case of a production payment carved out for exploration or development of a mineral property, the preceding sentence shall apply only if and to the extent gross income from the property (for purposes of section 613) would be realized, in the absence of the application of such sentence, by the person creating the production payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retained production payment on sale of mineral property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Retained production payment on sale of mineral property A production payment retained on the sale of a mineral property shall be treated, for purposes of this subtitle, as if it were a purchase money mortgage loan and shall not qualify as an economic interest in the mineral property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retained production payment on lease of mineral property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Retained production payment on lease of mineral property A production payment retained in a mineral property by the lessor in a leasing transaction shall be treated, for purposes of this subtitle, insofar as the lessee (or his successors in interest) is concerned, as if it were a bonus granted by the lessee to the lessor payable in installments. The treatment of the production payment in the hands of the lessor shall be determined without regard to the provisions of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definition As used in this section, the term “mineral property” has the meaning assigned to the term “property” in section 614(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_636_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>