<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6402"><akn:num>6402</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to make credits or refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6402. Authority to make credits or refunds(a) General ruleIn the case of any overpayment, the Secretary, within the applicable period of limitations, may credit the amount of such overpayment, including any interest allowed thereon, against any liability in respect of an internal revenue tax on the part of the person who made the overpayment and shall, subject to subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f), refund any balance to such person.


(b) Credits against estimated taxThe Secretary is authorized to prescribe regulations providing for the crediting against the estimated income tax for any taxable year of the amount determined by the taxpayer or the Secretary to be an overpayment of the income tax for a preceding taxable year.


(c) Offset of past-due support against overpaymentsThe amount of any overpayment to be refunded to the person making the overpayment shall be reduced by the amount of any past-due support (as defined in section 464(c) of the Social Security Act) owed by that person of which the Secretary has been notified by a State in accordance with section 464 of such Act. The Secretary shall remit the amount by which the overpayment is so reduced to the State collecting such support and notify the person making the overpayment that so much of the overpayment as was necessary to satisfy his obligation for past-due support has been paid to the State. The Secretary shall apply a reduction under this subsection first to an amount certified by the State as past due support under section 464 of the Social Security Act before any other reductions allowed by law. This subsection shall be applied to an overpayment prior to its being credited to a person’s future liability for an internal revenue tax. For purposes of this subsection, any reference to a State shall include a reference to any Indian tribe or tribal organization receiving a grant under section 455(f) of the Social Security Act.


(d) Collection of debts owed to Federal agencies(1) In generalUpon recei</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of any overpayment, the Secretary, within the applicable period of limitations, may credit the amount of such overpayment, including any interest allowed thereon, against any liability in respect of an internal revenue tax on the part of the person who made the overpayment and shall, subject to subsections (c), (d), (e), and (f), refund any balance to such person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credits against estimated tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Credits against estimated tax The Secretary is authorized to prescribe regulations providing for the crediting against the estimated income tax for any taxable year of the amount determined by the taxpayer or the Secretary to be an overpayment of the income tax for a preceding taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offset of past-due support against overpayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Offset of past-due support against overpayments The amount of any overpayment to be refunded to the person making the overpayment shall be reduced by the amount of any past-due support (as defined in section 464(c) of the Social Security Act) owed by that person of which the Secretary has been notified by a State in accordance with section 464 of such Act. The Secretary shall remit the amount by which the overpayment is so reduced to the State collecting such support and notify the person making the overpayment that so much of the overpayment as was necessary to satisfy his obligation for past-due support has been paid to the State. The Secretary shall apply a reduction under this subsection first to an amount certified by the State as past due support under section 464 of the Social Security Act before any other reductions allowed by law. This subsection shall be applied to an overpayment prior to its being credited to a person’s future liability for an internal revenue tax. For p</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of debts owed to Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Collection of debts owed to Federal agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of past-due, legally enforceable State income tax obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Collection of past-due, legally enforceable State income tax obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of unemployment compensation debts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Collection of unemployment compensation debts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of reductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Review of reductions No court of the United States shall have jurisdiction to hear any action, whether legal or equitable, brought to restrain or review a reduction authorized by subsection (c), (d), (e), or (f). No such reduction shall be subject to review by the Secretary in an administrative proceeding. No action brought against the United States to recover the amount of any such reduction shall be considered to be a suit for refund of tax. This subsection does not preclude any legal, equitable, or administrative action against the Federal agency or State to which the amount of such reduction was paid or any such action against the Commissioner of Social Security which is otherwise available with respect to recoveries of overpayments of benefits under section 204 of the Social Security Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Federal agency For purposes of this section, the term “Federal agency” means a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States, and includes a Government corporation (as such term is defined in section 103 of title 5, United States Code).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of payments to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Treatment of payments to States The Secretary may provide that, for purposes of determining interest, the payment of any amount withheld under subsection (c), (e), or (f) to a State shall be treated as a payment to the person or persons making the overpayment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cross reference For procedures relating to agency notification of the Secretary, see section 3721 of title 31, United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>