<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6417" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6417/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6417/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6417"><akn:num>6417</akn:num><akn:heading>Elective payment of applicable credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6417. Elective payment of applicable credits(a) In generalIn the case of an applicable entity making an election (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide) under this section with respect to any applicable credit determined with respect to such entity, such entity shall be treated as making a payment against the tax imposed by subtitle A (for the taxable year with respect to which such credit was determined) equal to the amount of such credit.


(b) Applicable creditThe term “applicable credit” means each of the following:(1) So much of the credit for alternative fuel vehicle refueling property allowed under section 30C which, pursuant to subsection (d)(1) of such section, is treated as a credit listed in section 38(b).

(2) So much of the renewable electricity production credit determined under section 45(a) as is attributable to qualified facilities which are originally placed in service after December 31, 2022.

(3) So much of the credit for carbon oxide sequestration determined under section 45Q(a) as is attributable to carbon capture equipment which is originally placed in service after December 31, 2022.

(4) The zero-emission nuclear power production credit determined under section 45U(a).

(5) So much of the credit for production of clean hydrogen determined under section 45V(a) as is attributable to qualified clean hydrogen production facilities which are originally placed in service after December 31, 2012.

(6) In the case of a tax-exempt entity described in clause (i), (ii), or (iv) of section 168(h)(2)(A), the credit for qualified commercial vehicles determined under section 45W by reason of subsection (d)(3) thereof.

(7) The credit for advanced manufacturing production under section 45X(a).

(8) The clean electricity production credit determined under section 45Y(a).

(9) The clean fuel production credit determined under section 45Z(a).

(10) The energy credit determined under section 48.

(11) The qualifying advanced energy proj</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6417_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of an applicable entity making an election (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide) under this section with respect to any applicable credit determined with respect to such entity, such entity shall be treated as making a payment against the tax imposed by subtitle A (for the taxable year with respect to which such credit was determined) equal to the amount of such credit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6417_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicable credit The term “applicable credit” means each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6417_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to partnerships and S corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application to partnerships and S corporations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6417_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6417_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of double benefit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Denial of double benefit In the case of an applicable entity making an election under this section with respect to an applicable credit, such credit shall be reduced to zero and shall, for any other purposes under this title, be deemed to have been allowed to such entity for such taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6417_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mirror code possessions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Mirror code possessions In the case of any possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system (as defined in section 24(k)), this section shall not be treated as part of the income tax laws of the United States for purposes of determining the income tax law of such possession unless such possession elects to have this section be so treated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6417_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis reduction and recapture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Basis reduction and recapture Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c)(2)(A), rules similar to the rules of section 50 shall apply for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6417_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including guidance to ensure that the amount of the payment or deemed payment made under this section is commensurate with the amount of the credit that would be otherwise allowable (determined without regard to section 38(c)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>