<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6418" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6418/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6418/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6418"><akn:num>6418</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6418. Transfer of certain credits(a) In generalIn the case of an eligible taxpayer which elects to transfer all (or any portion specified in the election) of an eligible credit determined with respect to such taxpayer for any taxable year to a taxpayer (referred to in this section as the “transferee taxpayer”) which is not related (within the meaning of section 267(b) or 707(b)(1)) to the eligible taxpayer, the transferee taxpayer specified in such election (and not the eligible taxpayer) shall be treated as the taxpayer for purposes of this title with respect to such credit (or such portion thereof).


(b) Treatment of payments made in connection with transferWith respect to any amount paid by a transferee taxpayer to an eligible taxpayer as consideration for a transfer described in subsection (a), such consideration—(1) shall be required to be paid in cash,

(2) shall not be includible in gross income of the eligible taxpayer, and

(3) with respect to the transferee taxpayer, shall not be deductible under this title.


(c) Application to partnerships and S corporations(1) In generalIn the case of any eligible credit determined with respect to any facility or property held directly by a partnership or S corporation, if such partnership or S corporation makes an election under subsection (a) (in such manner as the Secretary may provide) with respect to such credit—(A) any amount received as consideration for a transfer described in such subsection shall be treated as tax exempt income for purposes of sections 705 and 1366, and

(B) a partner’s distributive share of such tax exempt income shall be based on such partner’s distributive share of the otherwise eligible credit for each taxable year.


(2) Coordination with application at partner or shareholder levelIn the case of any facility or property held directly by a partnership or S corporation, no election by any partner or shareholder shall be allowed under subsection (a) with respect to any eligible credit det</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6418_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of an eligible taxpayer which elects to transfer all (or any portion specified in the election) of an eligible credit determined with respect to such taxpayer for any taxable year to a taxpayer (referred to in this section as the “transferee taxpayer”) which is not related (within the meaning of section 267(b) or 707(b)(1)) to the eligible taxpayer, the transferee taxpayer specified in such election (and not the eligible taxpayer) shall be treated as the taxpayer for purposes of this title with respect to such credit (or such portion thereof).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6418_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of payments made in connection with transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treatment of payments made in connection with transfer With respect to any amount paid by a transferee taxpayer to an eligible taxpayer as consideration for a transfer described in subsection (a), such consideration—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6418_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to partnerships and S corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application to partnerships and S corporations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6418_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable year in which credit taken into account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Taxable year in which credit taken into account In the case of any credit (or portion thereof) with respect to which an election is made under subsection (a), such credit shall be taken into account in the first taxable year of the transferee taxpayer ending with, or after, the taxable year of the eligible taxpayer with respect to which the credit was determined.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6418_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations on election</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6418_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6418_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6418_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or other guidance providing rules for determining a partner’s distributive share of the tax exempt income described in subsection (c)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>