<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6420" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6420/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6420/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6420"><akn:num>6420</akn:num><akn:heading>Gasoline used on farms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6420. Gasoline used on farms(a) GasolineExcept as provided in subsection (g), if gasoline is used on a farm for farming purposes, the Secretary shall pay (without interest) to the ultimate purchaser of such gasoline the amount determined by multiplying—(1) the number of gallons so used, by

(2) the rate of tax on gasoline under section 4081 which applied on the date he purchased such gasoline.


(b) Time for filing claims; period coveredNot more than one claim may be filed under this section by any person with respect to gasoline used during his taxable year, and no claim shall be allowed under this section with respect to gasoline used during any taxable year unless filed by such person not later than the time prescribed by law for filing a claim for credit or refund of overpayment of income tax for such taxable year. For purposes of this subsection, a person’s taxable year shall be his taxable year for purposes of subtitle A.


(c) Meaning of termsFor purposes of this section—(1) Use on a farm for farming purposesGasoline shall be treated as used on a farm for farming purposes only if used (A) in carrying on a trade or business, (B) on a farm situated in the United States, and (C) for farming purposes.


(2) FarmThe term “farm” includes stock, dairy, poultry, fruit, fur-bearing animal, and truck farms, plantations, ranches, nurseries, ranges, greenhouses or other similar structures used primarily for the raising of agricultural or horticultural commodities, and orchards.


(3) Farming purposesGasoline shall be treated as used for farming purposes only if used—(A) by the owner, tenant, or operator of a farm, in connection with cultivating the soil, or in connection with raising or harvesting any agricultural or horticultural commodity, including the raising, shearing, feeding, caring for, training, and management of livestock, bees, poultry, and fur-bearing animals and wildlife, on a farm of which he is the owner, tenant, or operator;

(B) by the owner, tenant, o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6420_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gasoline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Gasoline Except as provided in subsection (g), if gasoline is used on a farm for farming purposes, the Secretary shall pay (without interest) to the ultimate purchaser of such gasoline the amount determined by multiplying—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6420_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for filing claims; period covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Time for filing claims; period covered Not more than one claim may be filed under this section by any person with respect to gasoline used during his taxable year, and no claim shall be allowed under this section with respect to gasoline used during any taxable year unless filed by such person not later than the time prescribed by law for filing a claim for credit or refund of overpayment of income tax for such taxable year. For purposes of this subsection, a person’s taxable year shall be his taxable year for purposes of subtitle A.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6420_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meaning of terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Meaning of terms For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6420_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exempt sales; other payments or refunds available</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exempt sales; other payments or refunds available No amount shall be payable under this section with respect to any gasoline which the Secretary determines was exempt from the tax imposed by section 4081. The amount which (but for this sentence) would be payable under this section with respect to any gasoline shall be reduced by any other amount which the Secretary determines is payable under this section, or is refundable under any provision of this title, to any person with respect to such gasoline.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6420_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicable laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6420_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Secretary may by regulations prescribe the conditions, not inconsistent with the provisions of this section, under which payments may by made under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6420_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income tax credit in lieu of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Income tax credit in lieu of payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6420_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 103–66, title XIII, § 13241(f)(5), Aug. 10, 1993, 107 Stat. 512]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(h) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6420_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>