<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6428B" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6428B/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6428B/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6428B"><akn:num>6428B</akn:num><akn:heading>2021 recovery rebates to individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6428B. 2021 recovery rebates to individuals(a) In generalIn the case of an eligible individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by subtitle A for the first taxable year beginning in 2021 an amount equal to the 2021 rebate amount determined for such taxable year.


(b) 2021 rebate amountFor purposes of this section, the term “2021 rebate amount” means, with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year, the sum of—(1) $1,400 ($2,800 in the case of a joint return), plus

(2) $1,400 multiplied by the number of dependents of the taxpayer for such taxable year.


(c) Eligible individualFor purposes of this section, the term “eligible individual” means any individual other than—(1) any nonresident alien individual,

(2) any individual who is a dependent of another taxpayer for a taxable year beginning in the calendar year in which the individual’s taxable year begins, and

(3) an estate or trust.


(d) Limitation based on adjusted gross income(1) In generalThe amount of the credit allowed by subsection (a) (determined without regard to this subsection and subsection (f)) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount which bears the same ratio to such credit (as so determined) as—(A) the excess of—(i) the taxpayer’s adjusted gross income for such taxable year, over

(ii) $75,000, bears to


(B) $5,000.


(2) Special rules(A) Joint return or surviving spouseIn the case of a joint return or a surviving spouse (as defined in section 2(a)), paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting “$150,000” for “$75,000” and “$10,000” for “$5,000”.


(B) Head of householdIn the case of a head of household (as defined in section 2(b)), paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting “$112,500” for “$75,000” and “$7,500” for “$5,000”.




(e) Definitions and special rules(1) Dependent definedFor purposes of this section, the term “dependent” has the meaning given such term by section 152.


(2) Identification number requirement(A) In generalIn the case of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6428B_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of an eligible individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by subtitle A for the first taxable year beginning in 2021 an amount equal to the 2021 rebate amount determined for such taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6428B_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>2021 rebate amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) 2021 rebate amount For purposes of this section, the term “2021 rebate amount” means, with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year, the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6428B_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible individual For purposes of this section, the term “eligible individual” means any individual other than—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6428B_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation based on adjusted gross income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation based on adjusted gross income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6428B_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions and special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6428B_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with advance refunds of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with advance refunds of credit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6428B_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance refunds and credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Advance refunds and credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6428B_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6428B_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Outreach The Secretary shall carry out a robust and comprehensive outreach program to ensure that all taxpayers described in subsection (h)(1) learn of their eligibility for the advance refunds and credits under subsection (g); are advised of the opportunity to receive such advance refunds and credits as provided under subsection (h)(1); and are provided assistance in applying for such advance refunds and credits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>