<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/643" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/643/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/643/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_643"><akn:num>643</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions applicable to subparts A, B, C, and D</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 643. Definitions applicable to subparts A, B, C, and D(a) Distributable net incomeFor purposes of this part, the term “distributable net income” means, with respect to any taxable year, the taxable income of the estate or trust computed with the following modifications—(1) Deduction for distributionsNo deduction shall be taken under sections 651 and 661 (relating to additional deductions).


(2) Deduction for personal exemptionNo deduction shall be taken under section 642(b) (relating to deduction for personal exemptions).


(3) Capital gains and lossesGains from the sale or exchange of capital assets shall be excluded to the extent that such gains are allocated to corpus and are not (A) paid, credited, or required to be distributed to any beneficiary during the taxable year, or (B) paid, permanently set aside, or to be used for the purposes specified in section 642(c). Losses from the sale or exchange of capital assets shall be excluded, except to the extent such losses are taken into account in determining the amount of gains from the sale or exchange of capital assets which are paid, credited, or required to be distributed to any beneficiary during the taxable year. The exclusion under section 1202 shall not be taken into account.


(4) Extraordinary dividends and taxable stock dividendsFor purposes only of subpart B (relating to trusts which distribute current income only), there shall be excluded those items of gross income constituting extraordinary dividends or taxable stock dividends which the fiduciary, acting in good faith, does not pay or credit to any beneficiary by reason of his determination that such dividends are allocable to corpus under the terms of the governing instrument and applicable local law.


(5) Tax-exempt interestThere shall be included any tax-exempt interest to which section 103 applies, reduced by any amounts which would be deductible in respect of disbursements allocable to such interest but for the provisions of section 265 (relat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_643_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributable net income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Distributable net income For purposes of this part, the term “distributable net income” means, with respect to any taxable year, the taxable income of the estate or trust computed with the following modifications— If the estate or trust is allowed a deduction under section 642(c), the amount of the modifications specified in paragraphs (5) and (6) shall be reduced to the extent that the amount of income which is paid, permanently set aside, or to be used for the purposes specified in section 642(c) is deemed to consist of items specified in those paragraphs. For this purpose, such amount shall (in the absence of specific provisions in the governing instrument) be deemed to consist of the same proportion of each class of items of income of the estate or trust as the total of each class bears to the total of all classes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_643_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Income For purposes of this subpart and subparts B, C, and D, the term “income”, when not preceded by the words “taxable”, “distributable net”, “undistributed net”, or “gross”, means the amount of income of the estate or trust for the taxable year determined under the terms of the governing instrument and applicable local law. Items of gross income constituting extraordinary dividends or taxable stock dividends which the fiduciary, acting in good faith, determines to be allocable to corpus under the terms of the governing instrument and applicable local law shall not be considered income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_643_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Beneficiary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Beneficiary For purposes of this part, the term “beneficiary” includes heir, legatee, devisee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_643_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with back-up withholding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination with back-up withholding Except to the extent otherwise provided in regulations, this subchapter shall be applied with respect to payments subject to withholding under section 3406—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_643_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of property distributed in kind</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of property distributed in kind</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_643_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of multiple trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of multiple trusts For purposes of this subchapter, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, 2 or more trusts shall be treated as 1 trust if— For purposes of the preceding sentence, a husband and wife shall be treated as 1 person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_643_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain payments of estimated tax treated as paid by beneficiary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certain payments of estimated tax treated as paid by beneficiary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_643_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions by certain foreign trusts through nominees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Distributions by certain foreign trusts through nominees For purposes of this part, any amount paid to a United States person which is derived directly or indirectly from a foreign trust of which the payor is not the grantor shall be deemed in the year of payment to have been directly paid by the foreign trust to such United States person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_643_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans from foreign trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Loans from foreign trusts For purposes of subparts B, C, and D—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>