<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6433" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6433/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6433/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6433"><akn:num>6433</akn:num><akn:heading>Saver’s Match</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6433. Saver’s Match(a) In general(1) Allowance of matchAny eligible individual who makes qualified retirement savings contributions for the taxable year shall be allowed a matching contribution for such taxable year in an amount equal to the applicable percentage of so much of the qualified retirement savings contributions made by such eligible individual for the taxable year as does not exceed $2,000.


(2) Payment of match(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the matching contribution under this section shall be allowed as a credit which shall be payable by the Secretary as a contribution (as soon as practicable after the eligible individual has filed a tax return making a claim for such matching contribution for the taxable year) to the applicable retirement savings vehicle of the eligible individual.


(B) ExceptionIn the case of an eligible individual who elects the application of this subparagraph and with respect to whom the matching contribution determined under paragraph (1) is greater than zero but less than $100 for the taxable year, subparagraph (A) shall not apply and such matching contribution shall be treated as a credit allowed by subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1.




(b) Applicable percentageFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the applicable percentage is 50 percent.


(2) PhaseoutThe percentage under paragraph (1) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the number of percentage points which bears the same ratio to 50 percentage points as—(A) the excess of—(i) the taxpayer’s modified adjusted gross income for such taxable year, over

(ii) the applicable dollar amount, bears to


(B) the phaseout range.



If any reduction determined under this paragraph is not a whole percentage point, such reduction shall be rounded to the next lowest whole percentage point.
(3) Applicable dollar amount; phaseout range(A) Joint returns and surviving spousesExcept as provided in subparag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable percentage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicable percentage For purposes of this section— If any reduction determined under this paragraph is not a whole percentage point, such reduction shall be rounded to the next lowest whole percentage point.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible individual For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified retirement savings contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Qualified retirement savings contributions For purposes of this section— Such term shall not include any amount attributable to a payment under subsection (a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable retirement savings vehicle</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicable retirement savings vehicle</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other definitions and special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision by Secretary of information relating to contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Provision by Secretary of information relating to contributions In the case of an amount elected by an eligible individual to be contributed to an account or plan under subsection (e)(2), the Secretary shall provide general guidance applicable to the custodian of the account or the plan sponsor, as the case may be, detailing the treatment of such contribution under subsection (f)(2) and the reporting requirements with respect to such contribution under section 6058, particularly as such requirements are modified pursuant to section 102(c)(2) 11 See References in Text note below. of the SECURE 2.0 Act of 2022.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inflation adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Inflation adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>