<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/646" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/646/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/646/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_646"><akn:num>646</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of electing Alaska Native Settlement Trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 646. Tax treatment of electing Alaska Native Settlement Trusts(a) In generalIf an election under this section is in effect with respect to any Settlement Trust, the provisions of this section shall apply in determining the income tax treatment of the Settlement Trust and its beneficiaries with respect to the Settlement Trust.


(b) Taxation of income of trustExcept as provided in subsection (f)(1)(B)(ii)—(1) In generalThere is hereby imposed on the taxable income of an electing Settlement Trust, other than its net capital gain, a tax at the lowest rate specified in section 1(c).11 See References in Text note below.


(2) Capital gainIn the case of an electing Settlement Trust with a net capital gain for the taxable year, a tax is hereby imposed on such gain at the rate of tax which would apply to such gain if the taxpayer were subject to a tax on its other taxable income at only the lowest rate specified in section 1(c).



Any such tax shall be in lieu of the income tax otherwise imposed by this chapter on such income or gain.

(c) One-time election(1) In generalA Settlement Trust may elect to have the provisions of this section apply to the trust and its beneficiaries.


(2) Time and method of electionAn election under paragraph (1) shall be made by the trustee of such trust—(A) on or before the due date (including extensions) for filing the Settlement Trust’s return of tax for the first taxable year of such trust ending after the date of the enactment of this section, and

(B) by attaching to such return of tax a statement specifically providing for such election.


(3) Period election in effectExcept as provided in subsection (f), an election under this subsection—(A) shall apply to the first taxable year described in paragraph (2)(A) and all subsequent taxable years, and

(B) may not be revoked once it is made.



(d) Contributions to trust(1) Beneficiaries of electing trust not taxed on contributionsIn the case of an electing Settlement Trust, no amount shal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If an election under this section is in effect with respect to any Settlement Trust, the provisions of this section shall apply in determining the income tax treatment of the Settlement Trust and its beneficiaries with respect to the Settlement Trust.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxation of income of trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Taxation of income of trust Except as provided in subsection (f)(1)(B)(ii)— Any such tax shall be in lieu of the income tax otherwise imposed by this chapter on such income or gain.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>One-time election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) One-time election</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions to trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contributions to trust</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of distributions to beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Tax treatment of distributions to beneficiaries Amounts distributed by an electing Settlement Trust during any taxable year shall be considered as having the following characteristics in the hands of the recipient beneficiary: Amounts distributed to which paragraph (3) applies shall not be treated as a corporate distribution subject to section 311(b), and for purposes of determining the amount of a distribution for purposes of paragraph (3) and the basis to the recipients, section 643(e) and not section 301(b) or (d) shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules where transfer restrictions modified</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rules where transfer restrictions modified</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Taxable income For purposes of this title, the taxable income of an electing Settlement Trust shall be determined under section 641(b) without regard to any deduction under section 651 or 661.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special loss disallowance rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Special loss disallowance rule Any loss that would otherwise be recognized by a shareholder upon a disposition of a share of stock of a sponsoring Native Corporation shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the per share loss adjustment factor. The per share loss adjustment factor shall be the aggregate of all contributions to all electing Settlement Trusts sponsored by such Native Corporation made on or after the first day each trust is treated as an electing Settlement Trust expressed on a per share basis and determined as of the day of each such contribution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_646_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cross reference For information required with respect to electing Settlement Trusts and sponsoring Native Corporations, see section 6039H.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>