<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6501"><akn:num>6501</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on assessment and collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6501. Limitations on assessment and collection(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in this section, the amount of any tax imposed by this title shall be assessed within 3 years after the return was filed (whether or not such return was filed on or after the date prescribed) or, if the tax is payable by stamp, at any time after such tax became due and before the expiration of 3 years after the date on which any part of such tax was paid, and no proceeding in court without assessment for the collection of such tax shall be begun after the expiration of such period. For purposes of this chapter, the term “return” means the return required to be filed by the taxpayer (and does not include a return of any person from whom the taxpayer has received an item of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit).


(b) Time return deemed filed(1) Early returnFor purposes of this section, a return of tax imposed by this title, except tax imposed by chapter 3, 4, 21, or 24, filed before the last day prescribed by law or by regulations promulgated pursuant to law for the filing thereof, shall be considered as filed on such last day.


(2) Return of certain employment and withholding taxesFor purposes of this section, if a return of tax imposed by chapter 3, 4, 21, or 24 for any period ending with or within a calendar year is filed before April 15 of the succeeding calendar year, such return shall be considered filed on April 15 of such calendar year.


(3) Return executed by SecretaryNotwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (2) of section 6020(b), the execution of a return by the Secretary pursuant to the authority conferred by such section shall not start the running of the period of limitations on assessment and collection.


(4) Return of excise taxesFor purposes of this section, the filing of a return for a specified period on which an entry has been made with respect to a tax imposed under a provision of subtitle D (including a return on which an entry has been made sh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided in this section, the amount of any tax imposed by this title shall be assessed within 3 years after the return was filed (whether or not such return was filed on or after the date prescribed) or, if the tax is payable by stamp, at any time after such tax became due and before the expiration of 3 years after the date on which any part of such tax was paid, and no proceeding in court without assessment for the collection of such tax shall be begun after the expiration of such period. For purposes of this chapter, the term “return” means the return required to be filed by the taxpayer (and does not include a return of any person from whom the taxpayer has received an item of income, gain, loss, deduction, or credit).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time return deemed filed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Time return deemed filed</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for prompt assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Request for prompt assessment Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c), (e), or (f), in the case of any tax (other than the tax imposed by chapter 11 of subtitle B, relating to estate taxes) for which return is required in the case of a decedent, or by his estate during the period of administration, or by a corporation, the tax shall be assessed, and any proceeding in court without assessment for the collection of such tax shall be begun, within 18 months after written request therefor (filed after the return is made and filed in such manner and such form as may be prescribed by regulations of the Secretary) by the executor, administrator, or other fiduciary representing the estate of such decedent, or by the corporation, but not after the expiration of 3 years after the return was filed. This subsection shall not apply in the case of a corporation unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantial omission of items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Substantial omission of items Except as otherwise provided in subsection (c)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal holding company tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Personal holding company tax If a corporation which is a personal holding company for any taxable year fails to file with its return under chapter 1 for such year a schedule setting forth— the personal holding company tax for such year may be assessed, or a proceeding in court for the collection of such tax may be begun without assessment, at any time within 6 years after the return for such year was filed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain income tax returns of corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certain income tax returns of corporations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net operating loss or capital loss carrybacks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Net operating loss or capital loss carrybacks In the case of a deficiency attributable to the application to the taxpayer of a net operating loss carryback or a capital loss carryback (including deficiencies which may be assessed pursuant to the provisions of section 6213(b)(3)), such deficiency may be assessed at any time before the expiration of the period within which a deficiency for the taxable year of the net operating loss or net capital loss which results in such carryback may be assessed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign tax carrybacks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Foreign tax carrybacks In the case of a deficiency attributable to the application to the taxpayer of a carryback under section 904(c) (relating to carryback and carryover of excess foreign taxes) or under section 907(f) (relating to carryback and carryover of disallowed foreign oil and gas taxes), such deficiency may be assessed at any time before the expiration of one year after the expiration of the period within which a deficiency may be assessed for the taxable year of the excess taxes described in section 904(c) or 907(f) which result in such carryback.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6501_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain credit carrybacks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Certain credit carrybacks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>