<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6601" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6601/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6601/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6601"><akn:num>6601</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest on underpayment, nonpayment, or extensions of time for payment, of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6601. Interest on underpayment, nonpayment, or extensions of time for payment, of tax(a) General ruleIf any amount of tax imposed by this title (whether required to be shown on a return, or to be paid by stamp or by some other method) is not paid on or before the last date prescribed for payment, interest on such amount at the underpayment rate established under section 6621 shall be paid for the period from such last date to the date paid.


(b) Last date prescribed for paymentFor purposes of this section, the last date prescribed for payment of the tax shall be determined under chapter 62 with the application of the following rules:(1) Extensions of time disregardedThe last date prescribed for payment shall be determined without regard to any extension of time for payment or any installment agreement entered into under section 6159.


(2) JeopardyThe last date prescribed for payment shall be determined without regard to any notice and demand for payment issued, by reason of jeopardy (as provided in chapter 70), prior to the last date otherwise prescribed for such payment.


(3) Accumulated earnings taxIn the case of the tax imposed by section 531 for any taxable year, the last date prescribed for payment shall be deemed to be the due date (without regard to extensions) for the return of tax imposed by subtitle A for such taxable year.


(4) Last date for payment not otherwise prescribedIn the case of taxes payable by stamp and in all other cases in which the last date for payment is not otherwise prescribed, the last date for payment shall be deemed to be the date the liability for tax arises (and in no event shall be later than the date notice and demand for the tax is made by the Secretary).



(c) Suspension of interest in certain income, estate, gift, and certain excise tax casesIn the case of a deficiency as defined in section 6211 (relating to income, estate, gift, and certain excise taxes), if a waiver of restrictions under section 6213(d) on the assessme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule If any amount of tax imposed by this title (whether required to be shown on a return, or to be paid by stamp or by some other method) is not paid on or before the last date prescribed for payment, interest on such amount at the underpayment rate established under section 6621 shall be paid for the period from such last date to the date paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Last date prescribed for payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Last date prescribed for payment For purposes of this section, the last date prescribed for payment of the tax shall be determined under chapter 62 with the application of the following rules:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of interest in certain income, estate, gift, and certain excise tax cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Suspension of interest in certain income, estate, gift, and certain excise tax cases In the case of a deficiency as defined in section 6211 (relating to income, estate, gift, and certain excise taxes), if a waiver of restrictions under section 6213(d) on the assessment of such deficiency has been filed, and if notice and demand by the Secretary for payment of such deficiency is not made within 30 days after the filing of such waiver, interest shall not be imposed on such deficiency for the period beginning immediately after such 30th day and ending with the date of notice and demand and interest shall not be imposed during such period on any interest with respect to such deficiency for any prior period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income tax reduced by carryback or adjustment for certain unused deductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Income tax reduced by carryback or adjustment for certain unused deductions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicable rules Except as otherwise provided in this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Satisfaction by credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Satisfaction by credits If any portion of a tax is satisfied by credit of an overpayment, then no interest shall be imposed under this section on the portion of the tax so satisfied for any period during which, if the credit had not been made, interest would have been allowable with respect to such overpayment. The preceding sentence shall not apply to the extent that section 6621(d) applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on assessment and collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on assessment and collection Interest prescribed under this section on any tax may be assessed and collected at any time during the period within which the tax to which such interest relates may be collected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception as to estimated tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exception as to estimated tax This section shall not apply to any failure to pay any estimated tax required to be paid by section 6654 or 6655.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception as to Federal unemployment tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Exception as to Federal unemployment tax This section shall not apply to any failure to make a payment of tax imposed by section 3301 for a calendar quarter or other period within a taxable year required under authority of section 6157.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6601_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>2-percent rate on certain portion of estate tax extended under section 6166</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) 2-percent rate on certain portion of estate tax extended under section 6166</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>