<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6611"><akn:num>6611</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest on overpayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6611. Interest on overpayments(a) RateInterest shall be allowed and paid upon any overpayment in respect of any internal revenue tax at the overpayment rate established under section 6621.


(b) PeriodSuch interest shall be allowed and paid as follows:(1) CreditsIn the case of a credit, from the date of the overpayment to the due date of the amount against which the credit is taken.


(2) RefundsIn the case of a refund, from the date of the overpayment to a date (to be determined by the Secretary) preceding the date of the refund check by not more than 30 days, whether or not such refund check is accepted by the taxpayer after tender of such check to the taxpayer. The acceptance of such check shall be without prejudice to any right of the taxpayer to claim any additional overpayment and interest thereon.


(3) Late returnsNotwithstanding paragraph (1) or (2) in the case of a return of tax which is filed after the last date prescribed for filing such return (determined with regard to extensions), no interest shall be allowed or paid for any day before the date on which the return is filed.



[(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 83(c), Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1664]

(d) Advance payment of tax, payment of estimated tax, and credit for income tax withholdingThe provisions of section 6513 (except the provisions of subsection (c) thereof, applicable in determining the date of payment of tax for purposes of determining the period of limitation on credit or refund, shall be applicable in determining the date of payment for purposes of subsection (a).


(e) Disallowance of interest on certain overpayments(1) Refunds within 45 days after return is filedIf any overpayment of tax imposed by this title is refunded within 45 days after the last day prescribed for filing the return of such tax (determined without regard to any extension of time for filing the return) or, in the case of a return filed after such last date, is refunded within 45 days after the date the retur</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rate Interest shall be allowed and paid upon any overpayment in respect of any internal revenue tax at the overpayment rate established under section 6621.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Period Such interest shall be allowed and paid as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 85–866, title I, § 83(c), Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1664]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance payment of tax, payment of estimated tax, and credit for income tax withholding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Advance payment of tax, payment of estimated tax, and credit for income tax withholding The provisions of section 6513 (except the provisions of subsection (c) thereof, applicable in determining the date of payment of tax for purposes of determining the period of limitation on credit or refund, shall be applicable in determining the date of payment for purposes of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disallowance of interest on certain overpayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disallowance of interest on certain overpayments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refund of income tax caused by carryback or adjustment for certain unused deductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Refund of income tax caused by carryback or adjustment for certain unused deductions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No interest until return in processible form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No interest until return in processible form</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of administrative review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prohibition of administrative review For prohibition of administrative review, see section 6406.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>