<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/664" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/664/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/664/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_664"><akn:num>664</akn:num><akn:heading>Charitable remainder trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 664. Charitable remainder trusts(a) General ruleNotwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the provisions of this section shall, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, apply in the case of a charitable remainder annuity trust and a charitable remainder unitrust.


(b) Character of distributionsAmounts distributed by a charitable remainder annuity trust or by a charitable remainder unitrust shall be considered as having the following characteristics in the hands of a beneficiary to whom is paid the annuity described in subsection (d)(1)(A) or the payment described in subsection (d)(2)(A):(1) First, as amounts of income (other than gains, and amounts treated as gains, from the sale or other disposition of capital assets) includible in gross income to the extent of such income of the trust for the year and such undistributed income of the trust for prior years;

(2) Second, as a capital gain to the extent of the capital gain of the trust for the year and the undistributed capital gain of the trust for prior years;

(3) Third, as other income to the extent of such income of the trust for the year and such undistributed income of the trust for prior years; and

(4) Fourth, as a distribution of trust corpus.


For purposes of this section, the trust shall determine the amount of its undistributed capital gain on a cumulative net basis.

(c) Taxation of trusts(1) Income taxA charitable remainder annuity trust and a charitable remainder unitrust shall, for any taxable year, not be subject to any tax imposed by this subtitle.


(2) Excise tax(A) In generalIn the case of a charitable remainder annuity trust or a charitable remainder unitrust which has unrelated business taxable income (within the meaning of section 512, determined as if part III of subchapter F applied to such trust) for a taxable year, there is hereby imposed on such trust or unitrust an excise tax equal to the amount of such unrelated business taxable income.


(B) Certai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the provisions of this section shall, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, apply in the case of a charitable remainder annuity trust and a charitable remainder unitrust.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Character of distributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Character of distributions Amounts distributed by a charitable remainder annuity trust or by a charitable remainder unitrust shall be considered as having the following characteristics in the hands of a beneficiary to whom is paid the annuity described in subsection (d)(1)(A) or the payment described in subsection (d)(2)(A): For purposes of this section, the trust shall determine the amount of its undistributed capital gain on a cumulative net basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxation of trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Taxation of trusts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation of interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Valuation of interests For purposes of determining the amount of any charitable contribution, the remainder interest of a charitable remainder annuity trust or charitable remainder unitrust shall be computed on the basis that an amount equal to 5 percent of the net fair market value of its assets (or a greater amount, if required under the terms of the trust instrument) is to be distributed each year. In the case of the early termination of a trust which is a charitable remainder unitrust by reason of subsection (d)(3), the valuation of interests in such trust for purposes of this section shall be made under rules similar to the rules of the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain contingencies permitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certain contingencies permitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified gratuitous transfer of qualified employer securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Qualified gratuitous transfer of qualified employer securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>