<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6652" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6652/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6652/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6652"><akn:num>6652</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to file certain information returns, registration statements, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6652. Failure to file certain information returns, registration statements, etc.(a) Returns with respect to certain payments aggregating less than $10In the case of each failure to file a statement of a payment to another person required under the authority of—(1) section 6042(a)(2) (relating to payments of dividends aggregating less than $10), or

(2) section 6044(a)(2) (relating to payments of patronage dividends aggregating less than $10),


on the date prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid (upon notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing to so file the statement, $1 for each such statement not so filed, but the total amount imposed on the delinquent person for all such failures during the calendar year shall not exceed $1,000.

(b) Failure to report tipsIn the case of failure by an employee to report to his employer on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor any amount of tips required to be so reported by section 6053(a) which are wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) or which are compensation (as defined in section 3231(e)), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, there shall be paid by the employee, in addition to the tax imposed by section 3101 or section 3201 (as the case may be) with respect to the amount of tips which he so failed to report, an amount equal to 50 percent of such tax.


(c) Returns by exempt organizations and by certain trusts(1) Annual returns under section 6033(a)(1) or 6012(a)(6)(A) Penalty on organizationIn the case of—(i) a failure to file a return required under section 6033(a)(1) (relating to returns by exempt organizations) or section 6012(a)(6) (relating to returns by political organizations) on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor (determined with regard to a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Returns with respect to certain payments aggregating less than $10</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Returns with respect to certain payments aggregating less than $10 In the case of each failure to file a statement of a payment to another person required under the authority of— on the date prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid (upon notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing to so file the statement, $1 for each such statement not so filed, but the total amount imposed on the delinquent person for all such failures during the calendar year shall not exceed $1,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to report tips</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Failure to report tips In the case of failure by an employee to report to his employer on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor any amount of tips required to be so reported by section 6053(a) which are wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) or which are compensation (as defined in section 3231(e)), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not due to willful neglect, there shall be paid by the employee, in addition to the tax imposed by section 3101 or section 3201 (as the case may be) with respect to the amount of tips which he so failed to report, an amount equal to 50 percent of such tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Returns by exempt organizations and by certain trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Returns by exempt organizations and by certain trusts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual registration and other notification by pension plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual registration and other notification by pension plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required in connection with certain plans of deferred compensation, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Information required in connection with certain plans of deferred compensation, etc. In the case of failure to file a return or statement required under section 6058 (relating to information required in connection with certain plans of deferred compensation), 6047 (relating to information relating to certain trusts and annuity and bond purchase plans), or 6039D (relating to returns and records with respect to certain fringe benefit plans) on the date and in the manner prescribed therefor (determined with regard to any extension of time for filing), unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause, there shall be paid (on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax) by the person failing so to file, $250 for each day during which such failure continues, but the total amount imposed under this subsection on any person for failure to file any return shall not exceed $150,000. This subsection shall not apply to any return or statement which is an inf</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Returns required under section 6039C</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Returns required under section 6039C</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 113–295, div. A, title II, § 221(a)(39)(B), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 4043]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(g) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to give notice to recipients of certain pension, etc., distributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Failure to give notice to recipients of certain pension, etc., distributions In the case of each failure to provide notice as required by section 3405(e)(10)(B), at the time prescribed therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid, on notice and demand of the Secretary and in the same manner as tax, by the person failing to provide such notice, an amount equal to $100 for each such failure, but the total amount imposed on such person for all such failures during any calendar year shall not exceed $50,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to give written explanation to recipients of certain qualifying rollover distributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Failure to give written explanation to recipients of certain qualifying rollover distributions In the case of each failure to provide a written explanation as required by section 402(f), at the time prescribed therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid, on notice and demand of the Secretary and in the same manner as tax, by the person failing to provide such written explanation, an amount equal to $100 for each such failure, but the total amount imposed on such person for all such failures during any calendar year shall not exceed $50,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6652_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to file certification with respect to certain residential rental projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Failure to file certification with respect to certain residential rental projects In the case of each failure to provide a certification as required by section 142(d)(7) at the time prescribed therefor, unless it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect, there shall be paid, on notice and demand of the Secretary and in the same manner as tax, by the person failing to provide such certification, an amount equal to $100 for each such failure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>