<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6654" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6654/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6654/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6654"><akn:num>6654</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure by individual to pay estimated income tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6654. Failure by individual to pay estimated income tax(a) Addition to the taxExcept as otherwise provided in this section, in the case of any underpayment of estimated tax by an individual, there shall be added to the tax under chapter 1, the tax under chapter 2, and the tax under chapter 2A for the taxable year an amount determined by applying—(1) the underpayment rate established under section 6621,

(2) to the amount of the underpayment,

(3) for the period of the underpayment.


(b) Amount of underpayment; period of underpaymentFor purposes of subsection (a)—(1) AmountThe amount of the underpayment shall be the excess of—(A) the required installment, over

(B) the amount (if any) of the installment paid on or before the due date for the installment.


(2) Period of underpaymentThe period of the underpayment shall run from the due date for the installment to whichever of the following dates is the earlier—(A) the 15th day of the 4th month following the close of the taxable year, or

(B) with respect to any portion of the underpayment, the date on which such portion is paid.


(3) Order of crediting paymentsFor purposes of paragraph (2)(B), a payment of estimated tax shall be credited against unpaid required installments in the order in which such installments are required to be paid.



(c) Number of required installments; due datesFor purposes of this section—(1) Payable in 4 installmentsThere shall be 4 required installments for each taxable year.


(2) Time for payment of installments






  In the case of the following   required installments:The due date is:


  1stApril 15
  2ndJune 15
  3rdSeptember 15
  4thJanuary 15 of the following taxable year.





(d) Amount of required installmentsFor purposes of this section—(1) Amount(A) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the amount of any required installment shall be 25 percent of the required annual payment.


(B) Required annual paymentFor purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “required annual</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Addition to the tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Addition to the tax Except as otherwise provided in this section, in the case of any underpayment of estimated tax by an individual, there shall be added to the tax under chapter 1, the tax under chapter 2, and the tax under chapter 2A for the taxable year an amount determined by applying—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of underpayment; period of underpayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of underpayment; period of underpayment For purposes of subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number of required installments; due dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Number of required installments; due dates For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of required installments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of required installments For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax computed after application of credits against tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Tax computed after application of credits against tax For purposes of this section, the term “tax” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of section in case of tax withheld on wages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application of section in case of tax withheld on wages</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule where return filed on or before January 31</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rule where return filed on or before January 31 If, on or before January 31 of the following taxable year, the taxpayer files a return for the taxable year and pays in full the amount computed on the return as payable, then no addition to tax shall be imposed under subsection (a) with respect to any underpayment of the 4th required installment for the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for farmers and fishermen</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Special rules for farmers and fishermen For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6654_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for nonresident aliens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Special rules for nonresident aliens In the case of a nonresident alien described in section 6072(c):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>