<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6664" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6664/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6664/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6664"><akn:num>6664</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6664. Definitions and special rules(a) UnderpaymentFor purposes of this part, the term “underpayment” means the amount by which any tax imposed by this title exceeds the excess of—(1) the sum of—(A) the amount shown as the tax by the taxpayer on his return, plus

(B) amounts not so shown previously assessed (or collected without assessment), over


(2) the amount of rebates made.


For purposes of paragraph (2), the term “rebate” means so much of an abatement, credit, refund, or other repayment, as was made on the ground that the tax imposed was less than the excess of the amount specified in paragraph (1) over the rebates previously made. A rule similar to the rule of section 6211(b)(4) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.

(b) Penalties applicable only where return filedThe penalties provided in this part shall apply only in cases where a return of tax is filed (other than a return prepared by the Secretary under the authority of section 6020(b)).


(c) Reasonable cause exception for underpayments(1) In generalNo penalty shall be imposed under section 6662 or 6663 with respect to any portion of an underpayment if it is shown that there was a reasonable cause for such portion and that the taxpayer acted in good faith with respect to such portion.


(2) ExceptionParagraph (1) shall not apply to any portion of an underpayment which is attributable to one or more transactions described in section 6662(b)(6) or to any disallowance of a deduction described in section 6662(b)(10).


(3) Special rule for certain valuation overstatementsIn the case of any underpayment attributable to a substantial or gross valuation overstatement under chapter 1 with respect to charitable deduction property, paragraph (1) shall not apply. The preceding sentence shall not apply to a substantial valuation overstatement under chapter 1 if—(A) the claimed value of the property was based on a qualified appraisal made by a qualified appraiser, and

(B) in addition to obtaining such app</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6664_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Underpayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Underpayment For purposes of this part, the term “underpayment” means the amount by which any tax imposed by this title exceeds the excess of— For purposes of paragraph (2), the term “rebate” means so much of an abatement, credit, refund, or other repayment, as was made on the ground that the tax imposed was less than the excess of the amount specified in paragraph (1) over the rebates previously made. A rule similar to the rule of section 6211(b)(4) shall apply for purposes of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6664_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties applicable only where return filed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalties applicable only where return filed The penalties provided in this part shall apply only in cases where a return of tax is filed (other than a return prepared by the Secretary under the authority of section 6020(b)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6664_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable cause exception for underpayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reasonable cause exception for underpayments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6664_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable cause exception for reportable transaction understatements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reasonable cause exception for reportable transaction understatements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>