<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6694" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6694/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6694/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6694"><akn:num>6694</akn:num><akn:heading>Understatement of taxpayer’s liability by tax return preparer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6694. Understatement of taxpayer’s liability by tax return preparer(a) Understatement due to unreasonable positions(1) In generalIf a tax return preparer—(A) prepares any return or claim of refund with respect to which any part of an understatement of liability is due to a position described in paragraph (2), and

(B) knew (or reasonably should have known) of the position,


such tax return preparer shall pay a penalty with respect to each such return or claim in an amount equal to the greater of $1,000 or 50 percent of the income derived (or to be derived) by the tax return preparer with respect to the return or claim.

(2) Unreasonable position(A) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this paragraph, a position is described in this paragraph unless there is or was substantial authority for the position.


(B) Disclosed positionsIf the position was disclosed as provided in section 6662(d)(2)(B)(ii)(I) and is not a position to which subparagraph (C) applies, the position is described in this paragraph unless there is a reasonable basis for the position.


(C) Tax shelters and reportable transactionsIf the position is with respect to a tax shelter (as defined in section 6662(d)(2)(C)(ii)) or a reportable transaction to which section 6662A applies, the position is described in this paragraph unless it is reasonable to believe that the position would more likely than not be sustained on its merits.



(3) Reasonable cause exceptionNo penalty shall be imposed under this subsection if it is shown that there is reasonable cause for the understatement and the tax return preparer acted in good faith.



(b) Understatement due to willful or reckless conduct(1) In generalAny tax return preparer who prepares any return or claim for refund with respect to which any part of an understatement of liability is due to a conduct described in paragraph (2) shall pay a penalty with respect to each such return or claim in an amount equal to the greater of—(A) $5,000, or

(B) 75 pe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6694_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Understatement due to unreasonable positions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Understatement due to unreasonable positions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6694_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Understatement due to willful or reckless conduct</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Understatement due to willful or reckless conduct</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6694_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of period of collection where preparer pays 15 percent of penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Extension of period of collection where preparer pays 15 percent of penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6694_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Abatement of penalty where taxpayer’s liability not understated</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Abatement of penalty where taxpayer’s liability not understated If at any time there is a final administrative determination or a final judicial decision that there was no understatement of liability in the case of any return or claim for refund with respect to which a penalty under subsection (a) or (b) has been assessed, such assessment shall be abated, and if any portion of such penalty has been paid the amount so paid shall be refunded to the person who made such payment as an overpayment of tax without regard to any period of limitations which, but for this subsection, would apply to the making of such refund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6694_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Understatement of liability defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Understatement of liability defined For purposes of this section, the term “understatement of liability” means any understatement of the net amount payable with respect to any tax imposed by this title or any overstatement of the net amount creditable or refundable with respect to any such tax. Except as otherwise provided in subsection (d), the determination of whether or not there is an understatement of liability shall be made without regard to any administrative or judicial action involving the taxpayer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6694_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cross reference For definition of tax return preparer, see section 7701(a)(36).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>