<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6696" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6696/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6696/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6696"><akn:num>6696</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules applicable with respect to sections 6694, 6695, 6695A, and 6695B</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6696. Rules applicable with respect to sections 6694, 6695, 6695A, and 6695B(a) Penalties to be additional to any other penaltiesThe penalties provided by sections 6694, 6695, 6695A, and 6695B shall be in addition to any other penalties provided by law.


(b) Deficiency procedures not to applySubchapter B of chapter 63 (relating to deficiency procedures for income, estate, gift, and certain excise taxes) shall not apply with respect to the assessment or collection of the penalties provided by sections 6694, 6695, 6695A, and 6695B.


(c) Procedure for claiming refundAny claim for credit or refund of any penalty paid under section 6694, 6695, 6695A, or 6695B shall be filed in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(d) Periods of limitation(1) AssessmentThe amount of any penalty under section 6694(a), 6695, or 6695A shall be assessed within 3 years (or, in the case of any penalty under section 6695B, 6 years) after the return or claim for refund with respect to which the penalty is assessed was filed, and no proceeding in court without assessment for the collection of such tax shall be begun after the expiration of such period. In the case of any penalty under section 6694(b), the penalty may be assessed, or a proceeding in court for the collection of the penalty may be begun without assessment, at any time.


(2) Claim for refundExcept as provided in section 6694(d), any claim for refund of an overpayment of any penalty assessed under section 6694, 6695, or 6695A shall be filed within 3 years (or, in the case of any claim for refund of an overpayment of any penalty assessed under section 6695B, 6 years) from the time the penalty was paid.



(e) DefinitionsFor purposes of sections 6694, 6695, 6695A, and 6695B—(1) ReturnThe term “return” means any return of any tax imposed by this title, any administrative adjustment request under section 6227, and any partnership adjustment tracking report under section 6226(b)(4)(A).


(2) Claim for refundThe te</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6696_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties to be additional to any other penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Penalties to be additional to any other penalties The penalties provided by sections 6694, 6695, 6695A, and 6695B shall be in addition to any other penalties provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6696_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deficiency procedures not to apply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deficiency procedures not to apply Subchapter B of chapter 63 (relating to deficiency procedures for income, estate, gift, and certain excise taxes) shall not apply with respect to the assessment or collection of the penalties provided by sections 6694, 6695, 6695A, and 6695B.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6696_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for claiming refund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Procedure for claiming refund Any claim for credit or refund of any penalty paid under section 6694, 6695, 6695A, or 6695B shall be filed in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6696_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periods of limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Periods of limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6696_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of sections 6694, 6695, 6695A, and 6695B—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>