<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6704"><akn:num>6704</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to keep records necessary to meet reporting requirements under section 6047(d)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6704. Failure to keep records necessary to meet reporting requirements under section 6047(d)(a) Liability for penaltyAny person who—(1) has a duty to report or may have a duty to report any information under section 6047(d), and

(2) fails to keep such records as may be required by regulations prescribed under section 6047(d) for the purpose of providing the necessary data base for either current reporting or future reporting,


shall pay a penalty for each calendar year for which there is any failure to keep such records.

(b) Amount of penalty(1) In generalThe penalty of any person for any calendar year shall be $50, multiplied by the number of individuals with respect to whom such failure occurs in such year.


(2) Maximum amountThe penalty under this section of any person for any calendar year shall not exceed $50,000.



(c) Exceptions(1) Reasonable causeNo penalty shall be imposed by this section on any person for any failure which is shown to be due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect.


(2) Inability to correct previous failureNo penalty shall be imposed by this section on any failure by a person if such failure is attributable to a prior failure which has been penalized under this section and with respect to which the person has made all reasonable efforts to correct the failure.


(3) Pre-1983 failuresNo penalty shall be imposed by this section on any person for any failure which is attributable to a failure occurring before January 1, 1983, if the person has made all reasonable efforts to correct such pre-1983 failure.



(Added Pub. L. 97–248, title III, § 334(c)(1), Sept. 3, 1982, 96 Stat. 627; amended Pub. L. 99–514, title XVIII, § 1848(e)(1), Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2857.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1986—Pub. L. 99–514 substituted “section 6047(d)” for “section 6047(e)” in section catchline and in subsec. (a).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1986 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 99–514 effective, except as otherw</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liability for penalty Any person who— shall pay a penalty for each calendar year for which there is any failure to keep such records.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>