<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6724" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6724/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6724/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6724"><akn:num>6724</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver; definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6724. Waiver; definitions and special rules(a) Reasonable cause waiverNo penalty shall be imposed under this part with respect to any failure if it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect.


(b) Payment of penaltyAny penalty imposed by this part shall be paid on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax.


(c) Special rule for failure to meet magnetic media requirementsNo penalty shall be imposed under section 6721 solely by reason of any failure to comply with the requirements of the regulations prescribed under section 6011(e)(2), except to the extent that such a failure occurs with respect to more than the applicable number (determined under section 6011(e)(5) with respect to the calendar year to which such returns relate) of information returns or with respect to a return described in section 6011(e)(4).


(d) DefinitionsFor purposes of this part—(1) Information returnThe term “information return” means—(A) any statement of the amount of payments to another person required by—(i) section 6041(a) or (b) (relating to certain information at source),

(ii) section 6042(a)(1) (relating to payments of dividends),

(iii) section 6044(a)(1) (relating to payments of patronage dividends),

(iv) section 6049(a) (relating to payments of interest),

(v) section 6050A(a) (relating to reporting requirements of certain fishing boat operators),

(vi) section 6050N(a) (relating to payments of royalties),

(vii) section 6051(d) (relating to information returns with respect to income tax withheld),

(viii) section 6050R (relating to returns relating to certain purchases of fish), or

(ix) section 110(d) (relating to qualified lessee construction allowances for short-term leases),


(B) any return required by—(i) section 6041A(a) or (b) (relating to returns of direct sellers),

(ii) section 6043A(a) (relating to returns relating to taxable mergers and acquisitions),

(iii) section 6045(a) or (d) (relating to returns o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable cause waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reasonable cause waiver No penalty shall be imposed under this part with respect to any failure if it is shown that such failure is due to reasonable cause and not to willful neglect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment of penalty Any penalty imposed by this part shall be paid on notice and demand by the Secretary and in the same manner as tax.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for failure to meet magnetic media requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule for failure to meet magnetic media requirements No penalty shall be imposed under section 6721 solely by reason of any failure to comply with the requirements of the regulations prescribed under section 6011(e)(2), except to the extent that such a failure occurs with respect to more than the applicable number (determined under section 6011(e)(5) with respect to the calendar year to which such returns relate) of information returns or with respect to a return described in section 6011(e)(4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for certain partnership returns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rule for certain partnership returns If any partnership return under section 6031(a) is required under section 6011(e) to be filed on magnetic media or in other machine-readable form, for purposes of this part, each schedule required to be included with such return with respect to each partner shall be treated as a separate information return.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for returns of educational institutions related to higher education tuition and related expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rule for returns of educational institutions related to higher education tuition and related expenses No penalty shall be imposed under section 6721 or 6722 solely by reason of failing to provide the TIN of an individual on a return or statement required by section 6050S(a)(1) if the eligible educational institution required to make such return contemporaneously makes a true and accurate certification under penalty of perjury (and in such form and manner as may be prescribed by the Secretary) that it has complied with standards promulgated by the Secretary for obtaining such individual’s TIN.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for reporting certain additional taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rule for reporting certain additional taxes No penalty shall be imposed under section 6721 or 6722 if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>