<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/673" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/673/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/673/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_673"><akn:num>673</akn:num><akn:heading>Reversionary interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 673. Reversionary interests(a) General ruleThe grantor shall be treated as the owner of any portion of a trust in which he has a reversionary interest in either the corpus or the income therefrom, if, as of the inception of that portion of the trust, the value of such interest exceeds 5 percent of the value of such portion.


(b) Reversionary interest taking effect at death of minor lineal descendant beneficiaryIn the case of any beneficiary who—(1) is a lineal descendant of the grantor, and

(2) holds all of the present interests in any portion of a trust,


the grantor shall not be treated under subsection (a) as the owner of such portion solely by reason of a reversionary interest in such portion which takes effect upon the death of such beneficiary before such beneficiary attains age 21.

(c) Special rule for determining value of reversionary interestFor purposes of subsection (a), the value of the grantor’s reversionary interest shall be determined by assuming the maximum exercise of discretion in favor of the grantor.


(d) Postponement of date specified for reacquisitionAny postponement of the date specified for the reacquisition of possession or enjoyment of the reversionary interest shall be treated as a new transfer in trust commencing with the date on which the postponement is effective and terminating with the date prescribed by the postponement. However, income for any period shall not be included in the income of the grantor by reason of the preceding sentence if such income would not be so includible in the absence of such postponement.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 227; Pub. L. 91–172, title II, § 201(c), Dec. 30, 1969, 83 Stat. 560; Pub. L. 99–514, title XIV, § 1402(a), Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2711; Pub. L. 100–647, title I, § 1014(b), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3559.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1988—Subsecs. (c), (d). Pub. L. 100–647 added subsecs. (c) and (d).
1986—Pub. L. 99–514 amended section generally, substituting “the value of such i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_673_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule The grantor shall be treated as the owner of any portion of a trust in which he has a reversionary interest in either the corpus or the income therefrom, if, as of the inception of that portion of the trust, the value of such interest exceeds 5 percent of the value of such portion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_673_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reversionary interest taking effect at death of minor lineal descendant beneficiary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reversionary interest taking effect at death of minor lineal descendant beneficiary In the case of any beneficiary who— the grantor shall not be treated under subsection (a) as the owner of such portion solely by reason of a reversionary interest in such portion which takes effect upon the death of such beneficiary before such beneficiary attains age 21.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_673_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for determining value of reversionary interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule for determining value of reversionary interest For purposes of subsection (a), the value of the grantor’s reversionary interest shall be determined by assuming the maximum exercise of discretion in favor of the grantor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_673_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Postponement of date specified for reacquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Postponement of date specified for reacquisition Any postponement of the date specified for the reacquisition of possession or enjoyment of the reversionary interest shall be treated as a new transfer in trust commencing with the date on which the postponement is effective and terminating with the date prescribed by the postponement. However, income for any period shall not be included in the income of the grantor by reason of the preceding sentence if such income would not be so includible in the absence of such postponement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>