<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6851" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6851/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/6851/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6851"><akn:num>6851</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination assessments of income tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6851. Termination assessments of income tax(a) Authority for making(1) In generalIf the Secretary finds that a taxpayer designs quickly to depart from the United States or to remove his property therefrom, or to conceal himself or his property therein, or to do any other act (including in the case of a corporation distributing all or a part of its assets in liquidation or otherwise) tending to prejudice or to render wholly or partially ineffectual proceedings to collect the income tax for the current or the immediately preceding taxable year unless such proceeding be brought without delay, the Secretary shall immediately make a determination of tax for the current taxable year or for the preceding taxable year, or both, as the case may be, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, such tax shall become immediately due and payable. The Secretary shall immediately assess the amount of the tax so determined (together with all interest, additional amounts, and additions to the tax provided by law) for the current taxable year or such preceding taxable year, or both, as the case may be, and shall cause notice of such determination and assessment to be given the taxpayer, together with a demand for immediate payment of such tax.


(2) Computation of taxIn the case of a current taxable year, the Secretary shall determine the tax for the period beginning on the first day of such current taxable year and ending on the date of the determination under paragraph (1) as though such period were a taxable year of the taxpayer, and shall take into account any prior determination made under this subsection with respect to such current taxable year.


(3) Treatment of amounts collectedAny amounts collected as a result of any assessments under this subsection shall, to the extent thereof, be treated as a payment of tax for such taxable year.


(4) This section inapplicable where section 6861 appliesThis section shall not authorize any assessment of tax for the preceding taxabl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6851_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for making</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority for making</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6851_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of deficiency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice of deficiency If an assessment of tax is made under the authority of subsection (a), the Secretary shall mail a notice under section 6212(a) for the taxpayer’s full taxable year (determined without regard to any action taken under subsection (a)) with respect to which such assessment was made within 60 days after the later of (i) the due date of the taxpayer’s return for such taxable year (determined with regard to any extensions), or (ii) the date such taxpayer files such return. Such deficiency may be in an amount greater or less than the amount assessed under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6851_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Citizens In the case of a citizen of the United States or of a possession of the United States about to depart from the United States, the Secretary may, at his discretion, waive any or all of the requirements placed on the taxpayer by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6851_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Departure of alien</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Departure of alien Subject to such exceptions as may, by regulations, be prescribed by the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6851_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sections 6861(f) and (g) to apply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sections 6861(f) and (g) to apply The provisions of section 6861(f) (relating to collection of unpaid amounts) and 6861(g) (relating to abatement if jeopardy does not exist) shall apply with respect to any assessment made under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6851_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>