<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/72" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/72/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/72/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_72"><akn:num>72</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuities; certain proceeds of endowment and life insurance contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 72. Annuities; certain proceeds of endowment and life insurance contracts(a) General rules for annuities(1) Income inclusionExcept as otherwise provided in this chapter, gross income includes any amount received as an annuity (whether for a period certain or during one or more lives) under an annuity, endowment, or life insurance contract.


(2) Partial annuitizationIf any amount is received as an annuity for a period of 10 years or more or during one or more lives under any portion of an annuity, endowment, or life insurance contract—(A) such portion shall be treated as a separate contract for purposes of this section,

(B) for purposes of applying subsections (b), (c), and (e), the investment in the contract shall be allocated pro rata between each portion of the contract from which amounts are received as an annuity and the portion of the contract from which amounts are not received as an annuity, and

(C) a separate annuity starting date under subsection (c)(4) shall be determined with respect to each portion of the contract from which amounts are received as an annuity.



(b) Exclusion ratio(1) In generalGross income does not include that part of any amount received as an annuity under an annuity, endowment, or life insurance contract which bears the same ratio to such amount as the investment in the contract (as of the annuity starting date) bears to the expected return under the contract (as of such date).


(2) Exclusion limited to investmentThe portion of any amount received as an annuity which is excluded from gross income under paragraph (1) shall not exceed the unrecovered investment in the contract immediately before the receipt of such amount.


(3) Deduction where annuity payments cease before entire investment recovered(A) In generalIf—(i) after the annuity starting date, payments as an annuity under the contract cease by reason of the death of an annuitant, and

(ii) as of the date of such cessation, there is unrecovered investment in the contrac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rules for annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rules for annuities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion ratio</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exclusion ratio</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for qualified employer retirement plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules for qualified employer retirement plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts not received as annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amounts not received as annuities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for computing employees’ contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rules for computing employees’ contributions In computing, for purposes of subsection (c)(1)(A), the aggregate amount of premiums or other consideration paid for the contract, and for purposes of subsection (e)(6), the aggregate premiums or other consideration paid, amounts contributed by the employer shall be included, but only to the extent that— Paragraph (2) shall not apply to amounts which were contributed by the employer after December 31, 1962, and which would not have been includible in the gross income of the employee by reason of the application of section 911 if such amounts had been paid directly to the employee at the time of contribution. The preceding sentence shall not apply to amounts which were contributed by the employer, as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, to provide pension or annuity credits, to the extent such credits are attributable to services performed before January 1, 1963, and are provided pursuant to pension or annuity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules for transferee where transfer was for value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rules for transferee where transfer was for value Where any contract (or any interest therein) is transferred (by assignment or otherwise) for a valuable consideration, to the extent that the contract (or interest therein) does not, in the hands of the transferee, have a basis which is determined by reference to the basis in the hands of the transferor, then— For purposes of this subsection, the term “transferee” includes a beneficiary of, or the estate of, the transferee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Option to receive annuity in lieu of lump sum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Option to receive annuity in lieu of lump sum If— then, for purposes of this subtitle, no part of such lump sum shall be considered as includible in gross income at the time such lump sum first became payable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1951(b)(1)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1836]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_72_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Interest Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, if any amount is held under an agreement to pay interest thereon, the interest payments shall be included in gross income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>