<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/724" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/724/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/724/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_724"><akn:num>724</akn:num><akn:heading>Character of gain or loss on contributed unrealized receivables, inventory items, and capital loss p</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 724. Character of gain or loss on contributed unrealized receivables, inventory items, and capital loss property(a) Contributions of unrealized receivablesIn the case of any property which—(1) was contributed to the partnership by a partner, and

(2) was an unrealized receivable in the hands of such partner immediately before such contribution,


any gain or loss recognized by the partnership on the disposition of such property shall be treated as ordinary income or ordinary loss, as the case may be.

(b) Contributions of inventory itemsIn the case of any property which—(1) was contributed to the partnership by a partner, and

(2) was an inventory item in the hands of such partner immediately before such contribution,


any gain or loss recognized by the partnership on the disposition of such property during the 5-year period beginning on the date of such contribution shall be treated as ordinary income or ordinary loss, as the case may be.

(c) Contributions of capital loss propertyIn the case of any property which—(1) was contributed by a partner to the partnership, and

(2) was a capital asset in the hands of such partner immediately before such contribution,


any loss recognized by the partnership on the disposition of such property during the 5-year period beginning on the date of such contribution shall be treated as a loss from the sale of a capital asset to the extent that, immediately before such contribution, the adjusted basis of such property in the hands of the partner exceeded the fair market value of such property.

(d) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) Unrealized receivableThe term “unrealized receivable” has the meaning given such term by section 751(c) (determined by treating any reference to the partnership as referring to the partner).


(2) Inventory itemThe term “inventory item” has the meaning given such term by section 751(d) (determined by treating any reference to the partnership as referring to the partner and by applying sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_724_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions of unrealized receivables</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contributions of unrealized receivables In the case of any property which— any gain or loss recognized by the partnership on the disposition of such property shall be treated as ordinary income or ordinary loss, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_724_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions of inventory items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contributions of inventory items In the case of any property which— any gain or loss recognized by the partnership on the disposition of such property during the 5-year period beginning on the date of such contribution shall be treated as ordinary income or ordinary loss, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_724_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions of capital loss property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contributions of capital loss property In the case of any property which— any loss recognized by the partnership on the disposition of such property during the 5-year period beginning on the date of such contribution shall be treated as a loss from the sale of a capital asset to the extent that, immediately before such contribution, the adjusted basis of such property in the hands of the partner exceeded the fair market value of such property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_724_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>