<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7273" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7273/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7273/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7273"><akn:num>7273</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for offenses relating to special taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7273. Penalties for offenses relating to special taxes
Any person who shall fail to place and keep stamps denoting the payment of the special tax as provided in section 6806 shall be liable to a penalty (not less than $10) equal to the special tax for which his business rendered him liable, unless such failure is shown to be due to reasonable cause. If such failure to comply with section 6806 is through willful neglect or refusal, then the penalty shall be double the amount above prescribed.
(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 866; Pub. L. 90–618, title II, § 205, Oct. 22, 1968, 82 Stat. 1235.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1968—Pub. L. 90–618 redesignated former subsec. (a) as existing provisions, struck out heading “General rule”, all references to subsecs. (a) or (b) of section 6806 of this title, provision that nothing in this subsec. affects the liability of any person doing any act, etc., upon which a special tax is imposed for such special tax, and struck out subsec. (b) setting forth penalties for the failure to comply with the provisions of section 6806(c) of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1968 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 90–618 effective Oct. 22, 1968, see section 207 of Pub. L. 90–618, set out as an Effective Date note under section 5801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>