<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/732" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/732/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/732/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_732"><akn:num>732</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis of distributed property other than money</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 732. Basis of distributed property other than money(a) Distributions other than in liquidation of a partner’s interest(1) General ruleThe basis of property (other than money) distributed by a partnership to a partner other than in liquidation of the partner’s interest shall, except as provided in paragraph (2), be its adjusted basis to the partnership immediately before such distribution.


(2) LimitationThe basis to the distributee partner of property to which paragraph (1) is applicable shall not exceed the adjusted basis of such partner’s interest in the partnership reduced by any money distributed in the same transaction.



(b) Distributions in liquidationThe basis of property (other than money) distributed by a partnership to a partner in liquidation of the partner’s interest shall be an amount equal to the adjusted basis of such partner’s interest in the partnership reduced by any money distributed in the same transaction.


(c) Allocation of basis(1) In generalThe basis of distributed properties to which subsection (a)(2) or (b) is applicable shall be allocated—(A)(i) first to any unrealized receivables (as defined in section 751(c)) and inventory items (as defined in section 751(d)) in an amount equal to the adjusted basis of each such property to the partnership, and

(ii) if the basis to be allocated is less than the sum of the adjusted bases of such properties to the partnership, then, to the extent any decrease is required in order to have the adjusted bases of such properties equal the basis to be allocated, in the manner provided in paragraph (3), and


(B) to the extent of any basis remaining after the allocation under subparagraph (A), to other distributed properties—(i) first by assigning to each such other property such other property’s adjusted basis to the partnership, and

(ii) then, to the extent any increase or decrease in basis is required in order to have the adjusted bases of such other distributed properties equal such remaining basis, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions other than in liquidation of a partner’s interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Distributions other than in liquidation of a partner’s interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions in liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Distributions in liquidation The basis of property (other than money) distributed by a partnership to a partner in liquidation of the partner’s interest shall be an amount equal to the adjusted basis of such partner’s interest in the partnership reduced by any money distributed in the same transaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocation of basis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special partnership basis to transferee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special partnership basis to transferee For purposes of subsections (a), (b), and (c), a partner who acquired all or a part of his interest by a transfer with respect to which the election provided in section 754 is not in effect, and to whom a distribution of property (other than money) is made with respect to the transferred interest within 2 years after such transfer, may elect, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, to treat as the adjusted partnership basis of such property the adjusted basis such property would have if the adjustment provided in section 743(b) were in effect with respect to the partnership property. The Secretary may by regulations require the application of this subsection in the case of a distribution to a transferee partner, whether or not made within 2 years after the transfer, if at the time of the transfer the fair market value of the partnership property (other than money) exceeded 110 percent of its adjusted basis to the partnership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exception This section shall not apply to the extent that a distribution is treated as a sale or exchange of property under section 751(b) (relating to unrealized receivables and inventory items).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corresponding adjustment to basis of assets of a distributed corporation controlled by a corporate partner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Corresponding adjustment to basis of assets of a distributed corporation controlled by a corporate partner</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>