<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7324" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7324/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7324/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7324"><akn:num>7324</akn:num><akn:heading>Special disposition of perishable goods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7324. Special disposition of perishable goods
When any property which is seized under the provisions of section 7301 or section 7302 is liable to perish or become greatly reduced in price or value by keeping, or when it cannot be kept without great expense—(1) Application for examinationThe owner thereof, or the United States marshal of the district, may apply to the Secretary to examine it; and


(2) AppraisalIf, in the opinion of the Secretary, it shall be necessary that such property should be sold to prevent such waste or expense, the Secretary shall appraise the same; and thereupon


(3) Return to owner under bondThe owner shall have such property returned to him upon giving bond in an amount equal to such appraised value to abide the final order, decree, or judgment of the court having cognizance of the case, and to pay the amount of said appraised value to the Secretary, the United States marshal, or otherwise, as may be ordered and directed by the court, which bond shall be filed by the Secretary with the United States attorney for the district in which the proceedings in rem authorized in section 7323 may be commenced.


(4) Sale in absence of bond(A) Order to sellIf such owner shall neglect or refuse to give such bond, the Secretary shall issue to any Treasury officer or employee or to the United States marshal an order to sell the same.


(B) Manner of saleSuch Treasury officer or employee or the marshal shall as soon as practicable make public sale of such property in accordance with such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary.


(C) Disposition of proceedsThe proceeds of the sale, after deducting the reasonable costs of the seizure and sale, shall be paid to the court to abide its final order, decree, or judgment.



(5) Form of bond and suretiesFor provisions relating to form and sureties on bonds, see section 7101.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 870; Pub. L. 85–859, title II, § 204(9), Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1429; Pub. L. 85–866, t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7324_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Application for examination The owner thereof, or the United States marshal of the district, may apply to the Secretary to examine it; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7324_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appraisal If, in the opinion of the Secretary, it shall be necessary that such property should be sold to prevent such waste or expense, the Secretary shall appraise the same; and thereupon</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7324_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return to owner under bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Return to owner under bond The owner shall have such property returned to him upon giving bond in an amount equal to such appraised value to abide the final order, decree, or judgment of the court having cognizance of the case, and to pay the amount of said appraised value to the Secretary, the United States marshal, or otherwise, as may be ordered and directed by the court, which bond shall be filed by the Secretary with the United States attorney for the district in which the proceedings in rem authorized in section 7323 may be commenced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7324_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale in absence of bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Sale in absence of bond</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7324_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of bond and sureties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Form of bond and sureties For provisions relating to form and sureties on bonds, see section 7101.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>