<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7341" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7341/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7341/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7341"><akn:num>7341</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for sales to evade tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7341. Penalty for sales to evade tax(a) Nonenforceability of contractWhenever any person who is liable to pay any tax imposed by this title upon, for, or in respect of, any property sells or causes or allows the same to be sold before such tax is paid, with intent to avoid such tax, or in fraud of the internal revenue laws, any debt contracted in such sale, and any security given therefor, unless the same shall have been bona fide transferred to an innocent holder, shall be void, and the collection thereof shall not be enforced in any court.


(b) Forfeiture of sum paid on contractIf such property has been paid for, in whole or in part, the sum so paid shall be deemed forfeited.


(c) MoietyAny person who shall sue for the sum so paid (in an action of debt) shall recover from the seller the amount so paid, one-half to his own use and the other half to the use of the United States.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 872.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7341_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonenforceability of contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nonenforceability of contract Whenever any person who is liable to pay any tax imposed by this title upon, for, or in respect of, any property sells or causes or allows the same to be sold before such tax is paid, with intent to avoid such tax, or in fraud of the internal revenue laws, any debt contracted in such sale, and any security given therefor, unless the same shall have been bona fide transferred to an innocent holder, shall be void, and the collection thereof shall not be enforced in any court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7341_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeiture of sum paid on contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Forfeiture of sum paid on contract If such property has been paid for, in whole or in part, the sum so paid shall be deemed forfeited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7341_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Moiety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Moiety Any person who shall sue for the sum so paid (in an action of debt) shall recover from the seller the amount so paid, one-half to his own use and the other half to the use of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>