<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7345" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7345/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7345/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7345"><akn:num>7345</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation or denial of passport in case of certain tax delinquencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7345. Revocation or denial of passport in case of certain tax delinquencies(a) In generalIf the Secretary receives certification by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue that an individual has a seriously delinquent tax debt, the Secretary shall transmit such certification to the Secretary of State for action with respect to denial, revocation, or limitation of a passport pursuant to section 32101 of the FAST Act.


(b) Seriously delinquent tax debt(1) In generalFor purposes of this section, the term “seriously delinquent tax debt” means an unpaid, legally enforceable Federal tax liability of an individual—(A) which has been assessed,

(B) which is greater than $50,000, and

(C) with respect to which—(i) a notice of lien has been filed pursuant to section 6323 and the administrative rights under section 6320 with respect to such filing have been exhausted or have lapsed, or

(ii) a levy is made pursuant to section 6331.



(2) ExceptionsSuch term shall not include—(A) a debt that is being paid in a timely manner pursuant to an agreement to which the individual is party under section 6159 or 7122, and

(B) a debt with respect to which collection is suspended with respect to the individual—(i) because a due process hearing under section 6330 is requested or pending, or

(ii) because an election under subsection (b) or (c) of section 6015 is made or relief under subsection (f) of such section is requested.




(c) Reversal of certification(1) In generalIn the case of an individual with respect to whom the Commissioner makes a certification under subsection (a), the Commissioner shall notify the Secretary (and the Secretary shall subsequently notify the Secretary of State) if such certification is found to be erroneous or if the debt with respect to such certification is fully satisfied or ceases to be a seriously delinquent tax debt by reason of subsection (b)(2).


(2) Timing of notice(A) Full satisfaction of debtIn the case of a debt that has been fully satisfied or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7345_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If the Secretary receives certification by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue that an individual has a seriously delinquent tax debt, the Secretary shall transmit such certification to the Secretary of State for action with respect to denial, revocation, or limitation of a passport pursuant to section 32101 of the FAST Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7345_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seriously delinquent tax debt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Seriously delinquent tax debt</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7345_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reversal of certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reversal of certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7345_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contemporaneous notice to individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contemporaneous notice to individual The Commissioner shall contemporaneously notify an individual of any certification under subsection (a), or any reversal of certification under subsection (c), with respect to such individual. Such notice shall include a description in simple and nontechnical terms of the right to bring a civil action under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7345_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Judicial review of certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7345_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment for inflation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Adjustment for inflation In the case of a calendar year beginning after 2016, the dollar amount in subsection (b)(1)(B) shall be increased by an amount equal to— If any amount as adjusted under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of $1,000, such amount shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $1,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7345_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Delegation of certification A certification under subsection (a) or reversal of certification under subsection (c) may only be delegated by the Commissioner of Internal Revenue to the Deputy Commissioner for Services and Enforcement, or the Commissioner of an operating division, of the Internal Revenue Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>