<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7409" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7409/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7409/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7409"><akn:num>7409</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to enjoin flagrant political expenditures of section 501(c)(3) organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7409. Action to enjoin flagrant political expenditures of section 501(c)(3) organizations(a) Authority to seek injunction(1) In generalIf the requirements of paragraph (2) are met, a civil action in the name of the United States may be commenced at the request of the Secretary to enjoin any section 501(c)(3) organization from further making political expenditures and for such other relief as may be appropriate to ensure that the assets of such organization are preserved for charitable or other purposes specified in section 501(c)(3). Any action under this section shall be brought in the district court of the United States for the district in which such organization has its principal place of business or for any district in which it has made political expenditures. The court may exercise its jurisdiction over such action (as provided in section 7402(a)) separate and apart from any other action brought by the United States against such organization.


(2) RequirementsAn action may be brought under subsection (a) only if—(A) the Internal Revenue Service has notified the organization of its intention to seek an injunction under this section if the making of political expenditures does not immediately cease, and

(B) the Commissioner of Internal Revenue has personally determined that—(i) such organization has flagrantly participated in, or intervened in (including the publication or distribution of statements), any political campaign on behalf of (or in opposition to) any candidate for public office, and

(ii) injunctive relief is appropriate to prevent future political expenditures.




(b) Adjudication and decreeIn any action under subsection (a), if the court finds on the basis of clear and convincing evidence that—(1) such organization has flagrantly participated in, or intervened in (including the publication or distribution of statements), any political campaign on behalf of (or in opposition to) any candidate for public office, and

(2) injunctive relief is appr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7409_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to seek injunction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to seek injunction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7409_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjudication and decree</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjudication and decree In any action under subsection (a), if the court finds on the basis of clear and convincing evidence that— the court may enjoin such organization from making political expenditures and may grant such other relief as may be appropriate to ensure that the assets of such organization are preserved for charitable or other purposes specified in section 501(c)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7409_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section, the terms “section 501(c)(3) organization” and “political expenditures” have the respective meanings given to such terms by section 4955.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>