<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7426" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7426/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7426/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7426"><akn:num>7426</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions by persons other than taxpayers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7426. Civil actions by persons other than taxpayers(a) Actions permitted(1) Wrongful levyIf a levy has been made on property or property has been sold pursuant to a levy, any person (other than the person against whom is assessed the tax out of which such levy arose) who claims an interest in or lien on such property and that such property was wrongfully levied upon may bring a civil action against the United States in a district court of the United States. Such action may be brought without regard to whether such property has been surrendered to or sold by the Secretary.


(2) Surplus proceedsIf property has been sold pursuant to a levy, any person (other than the person against whom is assessed the tax out of which such levy arose) who claims an interest in or lien on such property junior to that of the United States and to be legally entitled to the surplus proceeds of such sale may bring a civil action against the United States in a district court of the United States.


(3) Substituted sale proceedsIf property has been sold pursuant to an agreement described in section 6325(b)(3) (relating to substitution of proceeds of sale), any person who claims to be legally entitled to all or any part of the amount held as a fund pursuant to such agreement may bring a civil action against the United States in a district court of the United States.


(4) Substitution of valueIf a certificate of discharge is issued to any person under section 6325(b)(4) with respect to any property, such person may, within 120 days after the day on which such certificate is issued, bring a civil action against the United States in a district court of the United States for a determination of whether the value of the interest of the United States (if any) in such property is less than the value determined by the Secretary. No other action may be brought by such person for such a determination.



(b) AdjudicationThe district court shall have jurisdiction to grant only such of the following f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions permitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Actions permitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjudication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjudication The district court shall have jurisdiction to grant only such of the following forms of relief as may be appropriate in the circumstances:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Validity of assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Validity of assessment For purposes of an adjudication under this section, the assessment of tax upon which the interest or lien of the United States is based shall be conclusively presumed to be valid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on rights of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on rights of action No action may be maintained against any officer or employee of the United States (or former officer or employee) or his personal representative with respect to any acts for which an action could be maintained under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substitution of United States as party</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Substitution of United States as party If an action, which could be brought against the United States under this section, is improperly brought against any officer or employee of the United States (or former officer or employee) or his personal representative, the court shall order, upon such terms as are just, that the pleadings be amended to substitute the United States as a party for such officer or employee as of the time such action was commenced upon proper service of process on the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision inapplicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Provision inapplicable The provisions of section 7422(a) (relating to prohibition of suit prior to filing claim for refund) shall not apply to actions under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Interest Interest shall be allowed at the overpayment rate established under section 6621—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of damages permitted in certain cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Recovery of damages permitted in certain cases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Cross reference For period of limitation, see section 6532(c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>