<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/743" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/743/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/743/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_743"><akn:num>743</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules where section 754 election or substantial built-in loss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 743. Special rules where section 754 election or substantial built-in loss(a) General ruleThe basis of partnership property shall not be adjusted as the result of a transfer of an interest in a partnership by sale or exchange or on the death of a partner unless the election provided by section 754 (relating to optional adjustment to basis of partnership property) is in effect with respect to such partnership or unless the partnership has a substantial built-in loss immediately after such transfer.


(b) Adjustment to basis of partnership propertyIn the case of a transfer of an interest in a partnership by sale or exchange or upon the death of a partner, a partnership with respect to which the election provided in section 754 is in effect or which has a substantial built-in loss immediately after such transfer shall—(1) increase the adjusted basis of the partnership property by the excess of the basis to the transferee partner of his interest in the partnership over his proportionate share of the adjusted basis of the partnership property, or

(2) decrease the adjusted basis of the partnership property by the excess of the transferee partner’s proportionate share of the adjusted basis of the partnership property over the basis of his interest in the partnership.


Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, such increase or decrease shall constitute an adjustment to the basis of partnership property with respect to the transferee partner only. A partner’s proportionate share of the adjusted basis of partnership property shall be determined in accordance with his interest in partnership capital and, in the case of property contributed to the partnership by a partner, section 704(c) (relating to contributed property) shall apply in determining such share. In the case of an adjustment under this subsection to the basis of partnership property subject to depletion, any depletion allowable shall be determined separately for the transferee partner with respect to his </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_743_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule The basis of partnership property shall not be adjusted as the result of a transfer of an interest in a partnership by sale or exchange or on the death of a partner unless the election provided by section 754 (relating to optional adjustment to basis of partnership property) is in effect with respect to such partnership or unless the partnership has a substantial built-in loss immediately after such transfer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_743_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment to basis of partnership property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjustment to basis of partnership property In the case of a transfer of an interest in a partnership by sale or exchange or upon the death of a partner, a partnership with respect to which the election provided in section 754 is in effect or which has a substantial built-in loss immediately after such transfer shall— Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, such increase or decrease shall constitute an adjustment to the basis of partnership property with respect to the transferee partner only. A partner’s proportionate share of the adjusted basis of partnership property shall be determined in accordance with his interest in partnership capital and, in the case of property contributed to the partnership by a partner, section 704(c) (relating to contributed property) shall apply in determining such share. In the case of an adjustment under this subsection to the basis of partnership property subject to depletion, any depletion allowable shall be determined separately for the t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_743_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocation of basis The allocation of basis among partnership properties where subsection (b) is applicable shall be made in accordance with the rules provided in section 755.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_743_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantial built-in loss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Substantial built-in loss</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_743_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative rules for electing investment partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Alternative rules for electing investment partnerships</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_743_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for securitization partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exception for securitization partnerships</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>