<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7430" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7430/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7430/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7430"><akn:num>7430</akn:num><akn:heading>Awarding of costs and certain fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7430. Awarding of costs and certain fees(a) In generalIn any administrative or court proceeding which is brought by or against the United States in connection with the determination, collection, or refund of any tax, interest, or penalty under this title, the prevailing party may be awarded a judgment or a settlement for—(1) reasonable administrative costs incurred in connection with such administrative proceeding within the Internal Revenue Service, and

(2) reasonable litigation costs incurred in connection with such court proceeding.


(b) Limitations(1) Requirement that administrative remedies be exhaustedA judgment for reasonable litigation costs shall not be awarded under subsection (a) in any court proceeding unless the court determines that the prevailing party has exhausted the administrative remedies available to such party within the Internal Revenue Service. Any failure to agree to an extension of the time for the assessment of any tax shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining whether the prevailing party meets the requirements of the preceding sentence.


(2) Only costs allocable to the United StatesAn award under subsection (a) shall be made only for reasonable litigation and administrative costs which are allocable to the United States and not to any other party.


(3) Costs denied where party prevailing protracts proceedingsNo award for reasonable litigation and administrative costs may be made under subsection (a) with respect to any portion of the administrative or court proceeding during which the prevailing party has unreasonably protracted such proceeding.


(4) Period for applying to IRS for administrative costsAn award may be made under subsection (a) by the Internal Revenue Service for reasonable administrative costs only if the prevailing party files an application with the Internal Revenue Service for such costs before the 91st day after the date on which the final decision of the Internal Revenue Service as to the deter</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7430_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In any administrative or court proceeding which is brought by or against the United States in connection with the determination, collection, or refund of any tax, interest, or penalty under this title, the prevailing party may be awarded a judgment or a settlement for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7430_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7430_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7430_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for payment of costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules for payment of costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7430_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiple actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Multiple actions For purposes of this section, in the case of— such actions or cases shall be treated as 1 court proceeding regardless of whether such joinder or consolidation actually occurs, unless the court in which such action is brought determines, in its discretion, that it would be inappropriate to treat such actions or cases as joined or consolidated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7430_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of appeal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Right of appeal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7430_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified offer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Qualified offer For purposes of subsection (c)(4)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>