<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7436" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7436/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7436/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7436"><akn:num>7436</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings for determination of employment status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7436. Proceedings for determination of employment status(a) Creation of remedyIf, in connection with an audit of any person, there is an actual controversy involving a determination by the Secretary as part of an examination that—(1) one or more individuals performing services for such person are employees of such person for purposes of subtitle C, or

(2) such person is not entitled to the treatment under subsection (a) of section 530 of the Revenue Act of 1978 with respect to such an individual,


upon the filing of an appropriate pleading, the Tax Court may determine whether such a determination by the Secretary is correct and the proper amount of employment tax under such determination. Any such redetermination by the Tax Court shall have the force and effect of a decision of the Tax Court and shall be reviewable as such.

(b) Limitations(1) PetitionerA pleading may be filed under this section only by the person for whom the services are performed.


(2) Time for filing actionIf the Secretary sends by certified or registered mail notice to the petitioner of a determination by the Secretary described in subsection (a), no proceeding may be initiated under this section with respect to such determination unless the pleading is filed before the 91st day after the date of such mailing.


(3) No adverse inference from treatment while action is pendingIf, during the pendency of any proceeding brought under this section, the petitioner changes his treatment for employment tax purposes of any individual whose employment status as an employee is involved in such proceeding (or of any individual holding a substantially similar position) to treatment as an employee, such change shall not be taken into account in the Tax Court’s determination under this section.



(c) Small case procedures(1) In generalAt the option of the petitioner, concurred in by the Tax Court or a division thereof before the hearing of the case, proceedings under this section may (notwithstanding the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7436_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation of remedy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation of remedy If, in connection with an audit of any person, there is an actual controversy involving a determination by the Secretary as part of an examination that— upon the filing of an appropriate pleading, the Tax Court may determine whether such a determination by the Secretary is correct and the proper amount of employment tax under such determination. Any such redetermination by the Tax Court shall have the force and effect of a decision of the Tax Court and shall be reviewable as such.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7436_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7436_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small case procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Small case procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7436_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7436_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Employment tax The term “employment tax” means any tax imposed by subtitle C.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>