<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7443" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7443/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7443/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7443"><akn:num>7443</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7443. Membership(a) NumberThe Tax Court shall be composed of 19 members.


(b) AppointmentJudges of the Tax Court shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, solely on the grounds of fitness to perform the duties of the office.


(c) Salary(1) Each judge shall receive salary at the same rate and in the same installments as judges of the district courts of the United States.

(2) For rate of salary and frequency of installment see section 135, title 28, United States Code, and section 5505, title 5, United States Code.


(d) Expenses for travel and subsistenceJudges of the Tax Court shall receive necessary traveling expenses, and expenses actually incurred for subsistence while traveling on duty and away from their designated stations, subject to the same limitations in amount as are now or may hereafter be applicable to the United States Court of International Trade.


(e) Term of officeThe term of office of any judge of the Tax Court shall expire 15 years after he takes office.


(f) Removal from officeJudges of the Tax Court may be removed by the President, after notice and opportunity for public hearing, for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office, but for no other cause.


(g) Disbarment of removed judgesA judge of the Tax Court removed from office in accordance with subsection (f) shall not be permitted at any time to practice before the Tax Court.


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 879; Mar. 2, 1955, ch. 9, § 1(h), 69 Stat. 10; Pub. L. 88–426, title IV, § 403(i), Aug. 14, 1964, 78 Stat. 434; Pub. L. 91–172, title IX, §§ 952, 953, Dec. 30, 1969, 83 Stat. 730; Pub. L. 96–417, title VI, § 601(10), Oct. 10, 1980, 94 Stat. 1744; Pub. L. 96–439, § 1(a), (b), Oct. 13, 1980, 94 Stat. 1878.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1980—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 96–439, § 1(a), increased number of judges from 16 to 19.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 96–439, § 1(b), struck out age limitation that no one could be appointed a member of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7443_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Number The Tax Court shall be composed of 19 members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7443_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment Judges of the Tax Court shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, solely on the grounds of fitness to perform the duties of the office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7443_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Salary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Salary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7443_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses for travel and subsistence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expenses for travel and subsistence Judges of the Tax Court shall receive necessary traveling expenses, and expenses actually incurred for subsistence while traveling on duty and away from their designated stations, subject to the same limitations in amount as are now or may hereafter be applicable to the United States Court of International Trade.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7443_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Term of office The term of office of any judge of the Tax Court shall expire 15 years after he takes office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7443_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal from office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Removal from office Judges of the Tax Court may be removed by the President, after notice and opportunity for public hearing, for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office, but for no other cause.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7443_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbarment of removed judges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Disbarment of removed judges A judge of the Tax Court removed from office in accordance with subsection (f) shall not be permitted at any time to practice before the Tax Court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>