<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7447A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7447A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7447A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7447A"><akn:num>7447A</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement for special trial judges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7447A. Retirement for special trial judges(a) In general(1) RetirementAny special trial judge appointed pursuant to section 7443A may retire from service as a special trial judge if the individual meets the age and service requirements set forth in the following table:






If the special trial judge has attained age:And the years of service as a special trial judge are at least:


6515
6614
6713
6812
6911
7010.





(2) Length of serviceIn making any determination of length of service as a special trial judge there shall be included all periods (whether or not consecutive) during which an individual served as a special trial judge



(b) Retirement upon disabilityAny special trial judge appointed pursuant to section 7443A who becomes permanently disabled from performing such individual’s duties shall retire from service as a special trial judge.


(c) Recalling of retired special trial judgesAny individual who has retired pursuant to subsection (a) may be called upon by the chief judge to perform such judicial duties with the Tax Court as may be requested of such individual for a period or periods specified by the chief judge, except that in the case of any such individual—(1) the aggregate of such periods in any 1 calendar year shall not (without the consent of such individual) exceed 90 calendar days, and

(2) such individual shall be relieved of performing such duties during any period in which illness or disability precludes the performance of such duties.


Any act, or failure to act, by an individual performing judicial duties pursuant to this subsection shall have the same force and effect as if it were the act (or failure to act) of a special trial judge. Any individual who is performing judicial duties pursuant to this subsection shall be paid the same compensation (in lieu of retired pay) and allowances for travel and other expenses as a special trial judge.

(d) Retired pay(1) In generalAny individual who retires pursuant to subsection (a) and elects </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7447A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7447A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement upon disability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Retirement upon disability Any special trial judge appointed pursuant to section 7443A who becomes permanently disabled from performing such individual’s duties shall retire from service as a special trial judge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7447A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recalling of retired special trial judges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recalling of retired special trial judges Any individual who has retired pursuant to subsection (a) may be called upon by the chief judge to perform such judicial duties with the Tax Court as may be requested of such individual for a period or periods specified by the chief judge, except that in the case of any such individual— Any act, or failure to act, by an individual performing judicial duties pursuant to this subsection shall have the same force and effect as if it were the act (or failure to act) of a special trial judge. Any individual who is performing judicial duties pursuant to this subsection shall be paid the same compensation (in lieu of retired pay) and allowances for travel and other expenses as a special trial judge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7447A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retired pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Retired pay</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7447A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to Receive Retired Pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Election to Receive Retired Pay Any special trial judge may elect to receive retired pay under subsection (d). Such an election— The chief judge shall transmit to the Office of Personnel Management a copy of each notice filed with the chief judge under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7447A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other rules made applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other rules made applicable The rules of subsections (f), (g), (h)(2), (i), and (j), and the first sentence of subsection (h)(1), of section 7447 shall apply to a special trial judge in the same manner as a judge of the Tax Court. For purposes of the preceding sentence, any reference to the President in such subsections shall be applied as if it were a reference to the chief judge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>