<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7526" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7526/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7526/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7526"><akn:num>7526</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-income taxpayer clinics</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7526. Low-income taxpayer clinics(a) In generalThe Secretary may, subject to the availability of appropriated funds, make grants to provide matching funds for the development, expansion, or continuation of qualified low-income taxpayer clinics.


(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) Qualified low-income taxpayer clinic(A) In generalThe term “qualified low-income taxpayer clinic” means a clinic that—(i) does not charge more than a nominal fee for its services (except for reimbursement of actual costs incurred); and

(ii)(I) represents low-income taxpayers in controversies with the Internal Revenue Service; or

(II) operates programs to inform individuals for whom English is a second language about their rights and responsibilities under this title.



(B) Representation of low-income taxpayersA clinic meets the requirements of subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) if—(i) at least 90 percent of the taxpayers represented by the clinic have incomes which do not exceed 250 percent of the poverty level, as determined in accordance with criteria established by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget; and

(ii) the amount in controversy for any taxable year generally does not exceed the amount specified in section 7463.



(2) ClinicThe term “clinic” includes—(A) a clinical program at an accredited law, business, or accounting school in which students represent low-income taxpayers in controversies arising under this title; and

(B) an organization described in section 501(c) and exempt from tax under section 501(a) which satisfies the requirements of paragraph (1) through representation of taxpayers or referral of taxpayers to qualified representatives.


(3) Qualified representativeThe term “qualified representative” means any individual (whether or not an attorney) who is authorized to practice before the Internal Revenue Service or the applicable court.



(c) Special rules and limitations(1) Aggregate limitationUnless otherwise provided by specific appropria</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7526_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may, subject to the availability of appropriated funds, make grants to provide matching funds for the development, expansion, or continuation of qualified low-income taxpayer clinics.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7526_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7526_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules and limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules and limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>