<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7527" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7527/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7527/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7527"><akn:num>7527</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance payment of credit for health insurance costs of eligible individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7527. Advance payment of credit for health insurance costs of eligible individuals(a) General ruleNot later than the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Trade Adjustment Assistance Reauthorization Act of 2015, the Secretary shall establish a program for making payments on behalf of certified individuals to providers of qualified health insurance (as defined in section 35(e)) for such individuals.


(b) Limitation on advance payments during any taxable yearThe Secretary may make payments under subsection (a) only to the extent that the total amount of such payments made on behalf of any individual during the taxable year does not exceed 72.5 percent of the amount paid by the taxpayer for coverage of the taxpayer and qualifying family members under qualified health insurance for eligible coverage months beginning in the taxable year.


(c) Certified individualFor purposes of this section, the term “certified individual” means any individual for whom a qualified health insurance costs credit eligibility certificate is in effect.


(d) Qualified health insurance costs eligibility certificate(1) In generalFor purposes of this section, the term “qualified health insurance costs eligibility certificate” means any written statement that an individual is an eligible individual (as defined in section 35(c)) if such statement provides such information as the Secretary may require for purposes of this section and—(A) in the case of an eligible TAA recipient (as defined in section 35(c)(2)) or an eligible alternative TAA recipient (as defined in section 35(c)(3)), is certified by the Secretary of Labor (or by any other person or entity designated by the Secretary), or

(B) in the case of an eligible PBGC pension recipient (as defined in section 35(c)(4)), is certified by the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (or by any other person or entity designated by the Secretary).


(2) Inclusion of certain informationIn the case of any statement described in p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7527_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Not later than the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Trade Adjustment Assistance Reauthorization Act of 2015, the Secretary shall establish a program for making payments on behalf of certified individuals to providers of qualified health insurance (as defined in section 35(e)) for such individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7527_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on advance payments during any taxable year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on advance payments during any taxable year The Secretary may make payments under subsection (a) only to the extent that the total amount of such payments made on behalf of any individual during the taxable year does not exceed 72.5 percent of the amount paid by the taxpayer for coverage of the taxpayer and qualifying family members under qualified health insurance for eligible coverage months beginning in the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7527_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certified individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certified individual For purposes of this section, the term “certified individual” means any individual for whom a qualified health insurance costs credit eligibility certificate is in effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7527_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified health insurance costs eligibility certificate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Qualified health insurance costs eligibility certificate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7527_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment for premiums due prior to commencement of advance payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment for premiums due prior to commencement of advance payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>