<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7602"><akn:num>7602</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of books and witnesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7602. Examination of books and witnesses(a) Authority to summon, etc.For the purpose of ascertaining the correctness of any return, making a return where none has been made, determining the liability of any person for any internal revenue tax or the liability at law or in equity of any transferee or fiduciary of any person in respect of any internal revenue tax, or collecting any such liability, the Secretary is authorized—(1) To examine any books, papers, records, or other data which may be relevant or material to such inquiry;

(2) To summon the person liable for tax or required to perform the act, or any officer or employee of such person, or any person having possession, custody, or care of books of account containing entries relating to the business of the person liable for tax or required to perform the act, or any other person the Secretary may deem proper, to appear before the Secretary at a time and place named in the summons and to produce such books, papers, records, or other data, and to give such testimony, under oath, as may be relevant or material to such inquiry; and

(3) To take such testimony of the person concerned, under oath, as may be relevant or material to such inquiry.


(b) Purpose may include inquiry into offenseThe purposes for which the Secretary may take any action described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) include the purpose of inquiring into any offense connected with the administration or enforcement of the internal revenue laws.


(c) Notice of contact of third parties(1) General noticeAn officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service may not contact any person other than the taxpayer with respect to the determination or collection of the tax liability of such taxpayer unless such contact occurs during a period (not greater than 1 year) which is specified in a notice which—(A) informs the taxpayer that contacts with persons other than the taxpayer are intended to be made during such period, and

(B) except as </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to summon, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to summon, etc. For the purpose of ascertaining the correctness of any return, making a return where none has been made, determining the liability of any person for any internal revenue tax or the liability at law or in equity of any transferee or fiduciary of any person in respect of any internal revenue tax, or collecting any such liability, the Secretary is authorized—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose may include inquiry into offense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose may include inquiry into offense The purposes for which the Secretary may take any action described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) include the purpose of inquiring into any offense connected with the administration or enforcement of the internal revenue laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of contact of third parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice of contact of third parties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No administrative summons when there is Justice Department referral</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No administrative summons when there is Justice Department referral</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on examination on unreported income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on examination on unreported income The Secretary shall not use financial status or economic reality examination techniques to determine the existence of unreported income of any taxpayer unless the Secretary has a reasonable indication that there is a likelihood of such unreported income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on access of persons other than Internal Revenue Service officers and employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on access of persons other than Internal Revenue Service officers and employees The Secretary shall not, under the authority of section 6103(n), provide any books, papers, records, or other data obtained pursuant to this section to any person authorized under section 6103(n), except when such person requires such information for the sole purpose of providing expert evaluation and assistance to the Internal Revenue Service. No person other than an officer or employee of the Internal Revenue Service or the Office of Chief Counsel may, on behalf of the Secretary, question a witness under oath whose testimony was obtained pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>