<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/761" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/761/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/761/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_761"><akn:num>761</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 761. Terms defined(a) PartnershipFor purposes of this subtitle, the term “partnership” includes a syndicate, group, pool, joint venture, or other unincorporated organization through or by means of which any business, financial operation, or venture is carried on, and which is not, within the meaning of this title, a corporation or a trust or estate. Under regulations the Secretary may, at the election of all the members of an unincorporated organization, exclude such organization from the application of all or part of this subchapter, if it is availed of—(1) for investment purposes only and not for the active conduct of a business,

(2) for the joint production, extraction, or use of property, but not for the purpose of selling services or property produced or extracted, or

(3) by dealers in securities for a short period for the purpose of underwriting, selling, or distributing a particular issue of securities,


if the income of the members of the organization may be adequately determined without the computation of partnership taxable income.

(b) PartnerFor purposes of this subtitle, the term “partner” means a member of a partnership. In the case of a capital interest in a partnership in which capital is a material income-producing factor, whether a person is a partner with respect to such interest shall be determined without regard to whether such interest was derived by gift from any other person.


(c) Partnership agreementFor purposes of this subchapter, a partnership agreement includes any modifications of the partnership agreement made prior to, or at, the time prescribed by law for the filing of the partnership return for the taxable year (not including extensions) which are agreed to by all the partners, or which are adopted in such other manner as may be provided by the partnership agreement.


(d) Liquidation of a partner’s interestFor purposes of this subchapter, the term “liquidation of a partner’s interest” means the termination of a partner’s enti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Partnership For purposes of this subtitle, the term “partnership” includes a syndicate, group, pool, joint venture, or other unincorporated organization through or by means of which any business, financial operation, or venture is carried on, and which is not, within the meaning of this title, a corporation or a trust or estate. Under regulations the Secretary may, at the election of all the members of an unincorporated organization, exclude such organization from the application of all or part of this subchapter, if it is availed of— if the income of the members of the organization may be adequately determined without the computation of partnership taxable income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Partner For purposes of this subtitle, the term “partner” means a member of a partnership. In the case of a capital interest in a partnership in which capital is a material income-producing factor, whether a person is a partner with respect to such interest shall be determined without regard to whether such interest was derived by gift from any other person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnership agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Partnership agreement For purposes of this subchapter, a partnership agreement includes any modifications of the partnership agreement made prior to, or at, the time prescribed by law for the filing of the partnership return for the taxable year (not including extensions) which are agreed to by all the partners, or which are adopted in such other manner as may be provided by the partnership agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation of a partner’s interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Liquidation of a partner’s interest For purposes of this subchapter, the term “liquidation of a partner’s interest” means the termination of a partner’s entire interest in a partnership by means of a distribution, or a series of distributions, to the partner by the partnership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions of partnership interests treated as exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Distributions of partnership interests treated as exchanges Except as otherwise provided in regulations, for purposes of— any distribution of an interest in a partnership (not otherwise treated as an exchange) shall be treated as an exchange.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified joint venture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Qualified joint venture</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_761_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cross reference For rules in the case of the sale, exchange, liquidation, or reduction of a partner’s interest, see sections 704(b) and 706(c)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>