<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7651" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7651/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7651/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7651"><akn:num>7651</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and collection of taxes in possessions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7651. Administration and collection of taxes in possessions
Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, and except as otherwise provided in section 28(a) of the Revised Organic Act of the Virgin Islands and section 30 of the Organic Act of Guam (relating to the covering of the proceeds of certain taxes into the treasuries of the Virgin Islands and Guam, respectively)—(1) Applicability of administrative provisionsAll provisions of the laws of the United States applicable to the assessment and collection of any tax imposed by this title or of any other liability arising under this title (including penalties) shall, in respect of such tax or liability, extend to and be applicable in any possession of the United States in the same manner and to the same extent as if such possession were a State, and as if the term “United States” when used in a geographical sense included such possession.


(2) Tax imposed in possessionIn the case of any tax which is imposed by this title in any possession of the United States—(A) Internal revenue collectionsSuch tax shall be collected under the direction of the Secretary, and shall be paid into the Treasury of the United States as internal revenue collections; and


(B) Applicable lawsAll provisions of the laws of the United States applicable to the administration, collection, and enforcement of such tax (including penalties) shall, in respect of such tax, extend to and be applicable in such possession of the United States in the same manner and to the same extent as if such possession were a State, and as if the term “United States” when used in a geographical sense included such possession.



(3) Other laws relating to possessionsThis section shall apply notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to any possession of the United States.


(4) Virgin Islands(A) For purposes of this section, the reference in section 28(a) of the Revised Organic Act of the Virgin Islands to “any tax specified in section 3811 of the Inter</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Applicability of administrative provisions All provisions of the laws of the United States applicable to the assessment and collection of any tax imposed by this title or of any other liability arising under this title (including penalties) shall, in respect of such tax or liability, extend to and be applicable in any possession of the United States in the same manner and to the same extent as if such possession were a State, and as if the term “United States” when used in a geographical sense included such possession.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax imposed in possession</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Tax imposed in possession In the case of any tax which is imposed by this title in any possession of the United States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other laws relating to possessions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Other laws relating to possessions This section shall apply notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to any possession of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7651_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Virgin Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Virgin Islands</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>