<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7652" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7652/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7652/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7652"><akn:num>7652</akn:num><akn:heading>Shipments to the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7652. Shipments to the United States(a) Puerto Rico(1) Rate of taxExcept as provided in section 5314, articles of merchandise of Puerto Rican manufacture coming into the United States and withdrawn for consumption or sale shall be subject to a tax equal to the internal revenue tax imposed in the United States upon the like articles of merchandise of domestic manufacture.


(2) Payment of taxThe Secretary shall by regulations prescribe the mode and time for payment and collection of the tax described in paragraph (1), including any discretionary method described in section 6302(b) and (c). Such regulations shall authorize the payment of such tax before shipment from Puerto Rico, and the provisions of section 7651(2)(B) shall be applicable to the payment and collection of such tax in Puerto Rico.


(3) Deposit of internal revenue collectionsAll taxes collected under the internal revenue laws of the United States on articles produced in Puerto Rico and transported to the United States (less the estimated amount necessary for payment of refunds and drawbacks), or consumed in the island, shall be covered into the treasury of Puerto Rico.



(b) Virgin Islands(1) Taxes imposed in the United StatesExcept as provided in section 5314, there shall be imposed in the United States, upon articles coming into the United States from the Virgin Islands, a tax equal to the internal revenue tax imposed in the United States upon like articles of domestic manufacture.


(2) Exemption from tax imposed in the Virgin IslandsSuch articles shipped from such islands to the United States shall be exempt from the payment of any tax imposed by the internal revenue laws of such islands.


(3) Disposition of internal revenue collectionsThe Secretary shall determine the amount of all taxes imposed by, and collected under the internal revenue laws of the United States on articles produced in the Virgin Islands and transported to the United States. The amount so determined less 1 percent and less </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7652_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Puerto Rico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Puerto Rico</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7652_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Virgin Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Virgin Islands</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7652_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Articles containing distilled spirits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Articles containing distilled spirits For purposes of subsections (a)(3) and (b)(3), any article containing distilled spirits shall in no event be treated as produced in Puerto Rico or the Virgin Islands unless at least 92 percent of the alcoholic content in such article is attributable to rum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7652_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Articles other than articles containing distilled spirits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Articles other than articles containing distilled spirits For purposes of subsections (a)(3) and (b)(3)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7652_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shipments of rum to the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Shipments of rum to the United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7652_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on cover over of tax on distilled spirits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on cover over of tax on distilled spirits For purposes of this section, with respect to taxes imposed under section 5001 or this section on distilled spirits, the amount covered into the treasuries of Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands shall not exceed the lesser of the rate of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7652_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drawback for medicinal alcohol, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Drawback for medicinal alcohol, etc. In the case of medicines, medicinal preparations, food products, flavors, flavoring extracts, or perfume containing distilled spirits, which are unfit for beverage purposes and which are brought into the United States from Puerto Rico or the Virgin Islands—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7652_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of cover over of tax must be derived from this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Manner of cover over of tax must be derived from this title No amount shall be covered into the treasury of Puerto Rico or the Virgin Islands with respect to taxes for which cover over is provided under this section unless made in the manner specified in this section without regard to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7652_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of taxes collected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Determination of taxes collected For purposes of subsections (a)(3), (b)(3), and (e)(1), refunds under section 5001(c)(4) shall not be taken into account as a refund, and the amount of taxes imposed by and collected under section 5001(a)(1) shall be determined without regard to section 5001(c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>