<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7701"><akn:num>7701</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7701. Definitions(a) When used in this title, where not otherwise distinctly expressed or manifestly incompatible with the intent thereof—(1) PersonThe term “person” shall be construed to mean an+d include an individual, a trust, estate, partnership, association, company or corporation.


(2) Partnership and partnerThe term “partnership” includes a syndicate, group, pool, joint venture, or other unincorporated organization, through or by means of which any business, financial operation, or venture is carried on, and which is not, within the meaning of this title, a trust or estate or a corporation; and the term “partner” includes a member in such a syndicate, group, pool, joint venture, or organization.


(3) CorporationThe term “corporation” includes associations, joint-stock companies, and insurance companies.


(4) DomesticThe term “domestic” when applied to a corporation or partnership means created or organized in the United States or under the law of the United States or of any State unless, in the case of a partnership, the Secretary provides otherwise by regulations.


(5) ForeignThe term “foreign” when applied to a corporation or partnership means a corporation or partnership which is not domestic.


(6) FiduciaryThe term “fiduciary” means a guardian, trustee, executor, administrator, receiver, conservator, or any person acting in any fiduciary capacity for any person.


(7) StockThe term “stock” includes shares in an association, joint-stock company, or insurance company.


(8) ShareholderThe term “shareholder” includes a member in an association, joint-stock company, or insurance company.


(9) United StatesThe term “United States” when used in a geographical sense includes only the States and the District of Columbia.


(10) StateThe term “State” shall be construed to include the District of Columbia, where such construction is necessary to carry out provisions of this title.


(11) Secretary of the Treasury and Secretary(A) Secretary of the TreasuryTh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) When used in this title, where not otherwise distinctly expressed or manifestly incompatible with the intent thereof—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of resident alien and nonresident alien</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definition of resident alien and nonresident alien</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Includes and including</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Includes and including The terms “includes” and “including” when used in a definition contained in this title shall not be deemed to exclude other things otherwise within the meaning of the term defined.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commonwealth of Puerto Rico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Commonwealth of Puerto Rico Where not otherwise distinctly expressed or manifestly incompatible with the intent thereof, references in this title to possessions of the United States shall be treated as also referring to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain contracts for providing services, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of certain contracts for providing services, etc. For purposes of chapter 1—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of related persons or pass-thru entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of related persons or pass-thru entities The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to prevent the avoidance of those provisions of this title which deal with— through the use of related persons, pass-thru entities, or other intermediaries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification of fair market value in the case of nonrecourse indebtedness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Clarification of fair market value in the case of nonrecourse indebtedness For purposes of subtitle A, in determining the amount of gain or loss (or deemed gain or loss) with respect to any property, the fair market value of such property shall be treated as being not less than the amount of any nonrecourse indebtedness to which such property is subject.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motor vehicle operating leases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Motor vehicle operating leases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable mortgage pools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Taxable mortgage pools</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7701_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of Federal Thrift Savings Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Tax treatment of Federal Thrift Savings Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>