<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7704"><akn:num>7704</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain publicly traded partnerships treated as corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7704. Certain publicly traded partnerships treated as corporations(a) General ruleFor purposes of this title, except as provided in subsection (c), a publicly traded partnership shall be treated as a corporation.


(b) Publicly traded partnershipFor purposes of this section, the term “publicly traded partnership” means any partnership if—(1) interests in such partnership are traded on an established securities market, or

(2) interests in such partnership are readily tradable on a secondary market (or the substantial equivalent thereof).


(c) Exception for partnerships with passive-type income(1) In generalSubsection (a) shall not apply to any publicly traded partnership for any taxable year if such partnership met the gross income requirements of paragraph (2) for such taxable year and each preceding taxable year beginning after December 31, 1987, during which the partnership (or any predecessor) was in existence. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a partnership shall not be treated as being in existence during any period before the 1st taxable year in which such partnership (or a predecessor) was a publicly traded partnership.


(2) Gross income requirementsA partnership meets the gross income requirements of this paragraph for any taxable year if 90 percent or more of the gross income of such partnership for such taxable year consists of qualifying income.


(3) Exception not to apply to certain partnerships which could qualify as regulated investment companiesThis subsection shall not apply to any partnership which would be described in section 851(a) if such partnership were a domestic corporation. To the extent provided in regulations, the preceding sentence shall not apply to any partnership a principal activity of which is the buying and selling of commodities (not described in section 1221(a)(1)), or options, futures, or forwards with respect to commodities.



(d) Qualifying incomeFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule For purposes of this title, except as provided in subsection (c), a publicly traded partnership shall be treated as a corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publicly traded partnership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Publicly traded partnership For purposes of this section, the term “publicly traded partnership” means any partnership if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for partnerships with passive-type income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception for partnerships with passive-type income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Qualifying income For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7704_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inadvertent terminations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Inadvertent terminations If— then, notwithstanding such failure, such entity shall be treated as continuing to meet such gross income requirements for such period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7704_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of becoming corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect of becoming corporation As of the 1st day that a partnership is treated as a corporation under this section, for purposes of this title, such partnership shall be treated as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7704_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for electing 1987 partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exception for electing 1987 partnerships</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>