<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7803"><akn:num>7803</akn:num><akn:heading>Commissioner of Internal Revenue; other officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7803. Commissioner of Internal Revenue; other officials(a) Commissioner of Internal Revenue(1) Appointment(A) In generalThere shall be in the Department of the Treasury a Commissioner of Internal Revenue who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Such appointment shall be made from individuals who, among other qualifications, have a demonstrated ability in management.


(B) TermThe term of the Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall be a 5-year term, beginning with a term to commence on November 13, 1997. Each subsequent term shall begin on the day after the date on which the previous term expires.


(C) VacancyAny individual appointed as Commissioner of Internal Revenue during a term as defined in subparagraph (B) shall be appointed for the remainder of that term.


(D) RemovalThe Commissioner may be removed at the will of the President.


(E) ReappointmentThe Commissioner may be appointed to serve more than one term.



(2) DutiesThe Commissioner shall have such duties and powers as the Secretary may prescribe, including the power to—(A) administer, manage, conduct, direct, and supervise the execution and application of the internal revenue laws or related statutes and tax conventions to which the United States is a party; and

(B) recommend to the President a candidate for appointment as Chief Counsel for the Internal Revenue Service when a vacancy occurs, and recommend to the President the removal of such Chief Counsel.


If the Secretary determines not to delegate a power specified in subparagraph (A) or (B), such determination may not take effect until 30 days after the Secretary notifies the Committees on Ways and Means, Government Reform and Oversight, and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Finance, Governmental Affairs, and Appropriations of the Senate.

(3) Execution of duties in accord with taxpayer rightsIn discharging his duties, the Commissioner shall ensure that employe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commissioner of Internal Revenue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Commissioner of Internal Revenue</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Counsel for the Internal Revenue Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Chief Counsel for the Internal Revenue Service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of the Taxpayer Advocate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Office of the Taxpayer Advocate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional duties of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional duties of the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7803_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent Office of Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Independent Office of Appeals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7803_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Internal Revenue Service Chief Information Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Internal Revenue Service Chief Information Officer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>