<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7805" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7805/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7805/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7805"><akn:num>7805</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7805. Rules and regulations(a) AuthorizationExcept where such authority is expressly given by this title to any person other than an officer or employee of the Treasury Department, the Secretary shall prescribe all needful rules and regulations for the enforcement of this title, including all rules and regulations as may be necessary by reason of any alteration of law in relation to internal revenue.


(b) Retroactivity of regulations(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this subsection, no temporary, proposed, or final regulation relating to the internal revenue laws shall apply to any taxable period ending before the earliest of the following dates:(A) The date on which such regulation is filed with the Federal Register.

(B) In the case of any final regulation, the date on which any proposed or temporary regulation to which such final regulation relates was filed with the Federal Register.

(C) The date on which any notice substantially describing the expected contents of any temporary, proposed, or final regulation is issued to the public.


(2) Exception for promptly issued regulationsParagraph (1) shall not apply to regulations filed or issued within 18 months of the date of the enactment of the statutory provision to which the regulation relates.


(3) Prevention of abuseThe Secretary may provide that any regulation may take effect or apply retroactively to prevent abuse.


(4) Correction of procedural defectsThe Secretary may provide that any regulation may apply retroactively to correct a procedural defect in the issuance of any prior regulation.


(5) Internal regulationsThe limitation of paragraph (1) shall not apply to any regulation relating to internal Treasury Department policies, practices, or procedures.


(6) Congressional authorizationThe limitation of paragraph (1) may be superseded by a legislative grant from Congress authorizing the Secretary to prescribe the effective date with respect to any regulation.


(7) Election to apply retro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7805_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization Except where such authority is expressly given by this title to any person other than an officer or employee of the Treasury Department, the Secretary shall prescribe all needful rules and regulations for the enforcement of this title, including all rules and regulations as may be necessary by reason of any alteration of law in relation to internal revenue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7805_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retroactivity of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Retroactivity of regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7805_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation and distribution of regulations, forms, stamps, and other matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preparation and distribution of regulations, forms, stamps, and other matters The Secretary shall prepare and distribute all the instructions, regulations, directions, forms, blanks, stamps, and other matters pertaining to the assessment and collection of internal revenue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7805_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of making elections prescribed by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Manner of making elections prescribed by Secretary Except to the extent otherwise provided by this title, any election under this title shall be made at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7805_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Temporary regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7805_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of impact of regulations on small business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Review of impact of regulations on small business</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>