<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7851" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7851/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7851/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7851"><akn:num>7851</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of revenue laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7851. Applicability of revenue laws(a) General rulesExcept as otherwise provided in any section of this title—(1) Subtitle A(A) Chapters 1, 2, and 6 of this title shall apply only with respect to taxable years beginning after December 31, 1953, and ending after the date of enactment of this title, and with respect to such taxable years, chapters 1 (except sections 143 and 144) and 2, and section 3801, of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 are hereby repealed.

(B) Chapter 3 of this title shall apply with respect to payments and transfers occurring after December 31, 1954, and as to such payments and transfers sections 143 and 144 and chapter 7 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 are hereby repealed.

(C) Any provision of subtitle A of this title the applicability of which is stated in terms of a specific date (occurring after December 31, 1953), or in terms of taxable years ending after a specific date (occurring after December 31, 1953), shall apply to taxable years ending after such specific date. Each such provision shall, in the case of a taxable year subject to the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, be deemed to be included in the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, but shall be applicable only to taxable years ending after such specific date. The provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 superseded by provisions of subtitle A of this title the applicability of which is stated in terms of a specific date (occurring after December 31, 1953) shall be deemed to be included in subtitle A of this title, but shall be applicable only to the period prior to the taking effect of the corresponding provision of subtitle A.

(D) Effective with respect to taxable years ending after March 31, 1954, and subject to tax under chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939—(i) Sections 13(b)(3), 26(b)(2)(C), 26(h) (1)(C) (including the comma and the word “and” immediately preceding such section), 26(i)(3), 108(k), 207(a)(1)(C), 207(a)(3)(C), and the last sentence of section 362(b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7851_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rules Except as otherwise provided in any section of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7851_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of repeal of Internal Revenue Code of 1939</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effect of repeal of Internal Revenue Code of 1939</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7851_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crimes and forfeitures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Crimes and forfeitures All offenses committed, and all penalties or forfeitures incurred, under any provision of law hereby repealed, may be prosecuted and punished in the same manner and with the same effect as if this title had not been enacted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7851_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periods of limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Periods of limitation All periods of limitation, whether applicable to civil causes and proceedings, or to the prosecution of offenses, or for the recovery of penalties or forfeitures, hereby repealed shall not be affected thereby, but all suits, proceedings, or prosecutions, whether civil or criminal, for causes arising, or acts done or committed, prior to said repeal, may be commenced and prosecuted within the same time as if this title had not been enacted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7851_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reference to other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reference to other provisions For the purpose of applying the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 or the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to any period, any reference in either such code to another provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 or the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which is not then applicable to such period shall be deemed a reference to the corresponding provision of the other code which is then applicable to such period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>