<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7872" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7872/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/7872/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7872"><akn:num>7872</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of loans with below-market interest rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7872. Treatment of loans with below-market interest rates(a) Treatment of gift loans and demand loans(1) In generalFor purposes of this title, in the case of any below-market loan to which this section applies and which is a gift loan or a demand loan, the forgone interest shall be treated as—(A) transferred from the lender to the borrower, and

(B) retransferred by the borrower to the lender as interest.


(2) Time when transfers madeExcept as otherwise provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary, any forgone interest attributable to periods during any calendar year shall be treated as transferred (and retransferred) under paragraph (1) on the last day of such calendar year.



(b) Treatment of other below-market loans(1) In generalFor purposes of this title, in the case of any below-market loan to which this section applies and to which subsection (a)(1) does not apply, the lender shall be treated as having transferred on the date the loan was made (or, if later, on the first day on which this section applies to such loan), and the borrower shall be treated as having received on such date, cash in an amount equal to the excess of—(A) the amount loaned, over

(B) the present value of all payments which are required to be made under the terms of the loan.


(2) Obligation treated as having original issue discountFor purposes of this title—(A) In generalAny below-market loan to which paragraph (1) applies shall be treated as having original issue discount in an amount equal to the excess described in paragraph (1).


(B) Amount in addition to other original issue discountAny original issue discount which a loan is treated as having by reason of subparagraph (A) shall be in addition to any other original issue discount on such loan (determined without regard to subparagraph (A)).




(c) Below-market loans to which section applies(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this subsection and subsection (g), this section shall apply to—(A) GiftsAny below-m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7872_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of gift loans and demand loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Treatment of gift loans and demand loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7872_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of other below-market loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treatment of other below-market loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7872_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Below-market loans to which section applies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Below-market loans to which section applies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7872_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for gift loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules for gift loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7872_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions of below-market loan and forgone interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions of below-market loan and forgone interest For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7872_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7872_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for certain loans to qualified continuing care facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exception for certain loans to qualified continuing care facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7872_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for loans to qualified continuing care facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exception for loans to qualified continuing care facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7872_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>