<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/808" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/808/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/808/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_808"><akn:num>808</akn:num><akn:heading>Policyholder dividends deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 808. Policyholder dividends deduction(a) Policyholder dividend definedFor purposes of this part, the term “policyholder dividend” means any dividend or similar distribution to policyholders in their capacity as such.


(b) Certain amounts includedFor purposes of this part, the term “policyholder dividend” includes—(1) any amount paid or credited (including as an increase in benefits) where the amount is not fixed in the contract but depends on the experience of the company or the discretion of the management,

(2) excess interest,

(3) premium adjustments, and

(4) experience-rated refunds.


(c) Amount of deductionThe deduction for policyholder dividends for any taxable year shall be an amount equal to the policyholder dividends paid or accrued during the taxable year.


(d) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) Excess interestThe term “excess interest” means any amount in the nature of interest—(A) paid or credited to a policyholder in his capacity as such, and

(B) in excess of interest determined at the prevailing State assumed rate for such contract.


(2) Premium adjustmentThe term “premium adjustment” means any reduction in the premium under an insurance or annuity contract which (but for the reduction) would have been required to be paid under the contract.


(3) Experience-rated refundThe term “experience-rated refund” means any refund or credit based on the experience of the contract or group involved.



(e) Treatment of policyholder dividendsFor purposes of this part, any policyholder dividend which—(1) increases the cash surrender value of the contract or other benefits payable under the contract, or

(2) reduces the premium otherwise required to be paid,


shall be treated as paid to the policyholder and returned by the policyholder to the company as a premium.

(f) Coordination of 1984 fresh-start adjustment with acceleration of policyholder dividends deduction through change in business practice(1) In generalThe amount determined under paragr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_808_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policyholder dividend defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Policyholder dividend defined For purposes of this part, the term “policyholder dividend” means any dividend or similar distribution to policyholders in their capacity as such.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_808_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain amounts included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certain amounts included For purposes of this part, the term “policyholder dividend” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_808_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amount of deduction The deduction for policyholder dividends for any taxable year shall be an amount equal to the policyholder dividends paid or accrued during the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_808_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_808_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of policyholder dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of policyholder dividends For purposes of this part, any policyholder dividend which— shall be treated as paid to the policyholder and returned by the policyholder to the company as a premium.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_808_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of 1984 fresh-start adjustment with acceleration of policyholder dividends deduction through change in business practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination of 1984 fresh-start adjustment with acceleration of policyholder dividends deduction through change in business practice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_808_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevailing State assumed interest rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prevailing State assumed interest rate For purposes of this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>