<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/814" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/814/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/814/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_814"><akn:num>814</akn:num><akn:heading>Contiguous country branches of domestic life insurance companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 814. Contiguous country branches of domestic life insurance companies(a) Exclusion of itemsIn the case of a domestic mutual insurance company which—(1) is a life insurance company,

(2) has a contiguous country life insurance branch, and

(3) makes the election provided by subsection (g) with respect to such branch,


there shall be excluded from each item involved in the determination of life insurance company taxable income the items separately accounted for in accordance with subsection (c).

(b) Contiguous country life insurance branchFor purposes of this section, the term contiguous country life insurance branch means a branch which—(1) issues insurance contracts insuring risks in connection with the lives or health of residents of a country which is contiguous to the United States,

(2) has its principal place of business in such contiguous country, and

(3) would constitute a mutual life insurance company if such branch were a separate domestic insurance company.


For purposes of this section, the term “insurance contract” means any life, health, accident, or annuity contract or reinsurance contract or any contract relating thereto.

(c) Separate accounting requiredAny taxpayer which makes the election provided by subsection (g) shall establish and maintain a separate account for the various income, exclusion, deduction, asset, reserve, liability, and surplus items properly attributable to the contracts described in subsection (b). Such separate accounting shall be made—(1) in accordance with the method regularly employed by such company, if such method clearly reflects income derived from, and the other items attributable to, the contracts described in subsection (b), and

(2) in all other cases, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(d) Recognition of gain on assets in branch accountIf the aggregate fair market value of all the invested assets and tangible property which are separately accounted for by the domestic life insurance </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_814_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Exclusion of items In the case of a domestic mutual insurance company which— there shall be excluded from each item involved in the determination of life insurance company taxable income the items separately accounted for in accordance with subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_814_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contiguous country life insurance branch</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contiguous country life insurance branch For purposes of this section, the term contiguous country life insurance branch means a branch which— For purposes of this section, the term “insurance contract” means any life, health, accident, or annuity contract or reinsurance contract or any contract relating thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_814_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate accounting required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Separate accounting required Any taxpayer which makes the election provided by subsection (g) shall establish and maintain a separate account for the various income, exclusion, deduction, asset, reserve, liability, and surplus items properly attributable to the contracts described in subsection (b). Such separate accounting shall be made—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_814_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition of gain on assets in branch account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recognition of gain on assets in branch account If the aggregate fair market value of all the invested assets and tangible property which are separately accounted for by the domestic life insurance company in the branch account established pursuant to subsection (c) exceeds the aggregate adjusted basis of such assets for purposes of determining gain, then the domestic life insurance company shall be treated as having sold all such assets on the first day of the first taxable year for which the election is in effect at their fair market value on such first day. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the net gain shall be recognized to the domestic life insurance company on the deemed sale described in the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_814_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions between contiguous country branch and domestic life insurance company</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transactions between contiguous country branch and domestic life insurance company</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_814_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_814_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Election A taxpayer may make the election provided by this subsection with respect to any contiguous country for any taxable year. An election made under this subsection for any taxable year shall remain in effect for all subsequent taxable years, except that it may be revoked with the consent of the Secretary. The election provided by this subsection shall be made not later than the time prescribed by law for filing the return for the taxable year (including extensions thereof) with respect to which such election is made, and such election and any approved revocation thereof shall be made in the manner provided by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_814_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for domestic stock life insurance companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rule for domestic stock life insurance companies At the election of a domestic stock life insurance company which has a contiguous country life insurance branch described in subsection (b) (without regard to the mutual requirement in subsection (b)(3)), the assets of such branch may be transferred to a foreign corporation organized under the laws of the contiguous country without the application of section 367. Subsection (a) shall apply to the stock of such foreign corporation as if such domestic company were a mutual company and as if the stock were an item described in subsection (c). Subsection (e)(2) shall apply to amounts transferred or credited to such domestic company as if such domestic company and such foreign corporation constituted one domestic mutual life insurance company. The insurance contracts which may be transferred pursuant to this subsection shall include only those which are similar to the types of insurance contracts issued by a mutual life insurance </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>