<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/818" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/818/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/818/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_818"><akn:num>818</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 818. Other definitions and special rules(a) Pension plan contractsFor purposes of this part, the term “pension plan contract” means any contract—(1) entered into with trusts which (as of the time the contracts were entered into) were deemed to be trusts described in section 401(a) and exempt from tax under section 501(a) (or trusts exempt from tax under section 165 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 or the corresponding provisions of prior revenue laws);

(2) entered into under plans which (as of the time the contracts were entered into) were deemed to be plans described in section 403(a), or plans meeting the requirements of paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) of section 165(a) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939;

(3) provided for employees of the life insurance company under a plan which, for the taxable year, meets the requirements of paragraphs (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (8), (11), (12), (13), (14), (15), (16), (17), (19), (20), (22), (26), and (27) of section 401(a);

(4) purchased to provide retirement annuities for its employees by an organization which (as of the time the contracts were purchased) was an organization described in section 501(c)(3) which was exempt from tax under section 501(a) (or was an organization exempt from tax under section 101(6) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939 or the corresponding provisions of prior revenue laws), or purchased to provide retirement annuities for employees described in section 403(b)(1)(A)(ii) by an employer which is a State, a political subdivision of a State, or an agency or instrumentality of any one or more of the foregoing;

(5) entered into with trusts which (at the time the contracts were entered into) were individual retirement accounts described in section 408(a) or under contracts entered into with individual retirement annuities described in section 408(b); or

(6) purchased by—(A) a governmental plan (within the meaning of section 414(d)) or an eligible deferred compensation plan (within the meanin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_818_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pension plan contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pension plan contracts For purposes of this part, the term “pension plan contract” means any contract—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_818_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of capital gains and losses, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treatment of capital gains and losses, etc. In the case of a life insurance company—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_818_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gain on property held on December 31, 1958 and certain substituted property acquired after 1958</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Gain on property held on</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_818_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance or annuity contract includes contracts supplementary thereto</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Insurance or annuity contract includes contracts supplementary thereto For purposes of this part, the term “insurance or annuity contract” includes any contract supplementary thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_818_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for consolidated returns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for consolidated returns</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_818_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of certain items for purposes of foreign tax credit, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Allocation of certain items for purposes of foreign tax credit, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_818_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified accelerated death benefit riders treated as life insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Qualified accelerated death benefit riders treated as life insurance For purposes of this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>