<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/831" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/831/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/831/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_831"><akn:num>831</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax on insurance companies other than life insurance companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 831. Tax on insurance companies other than life insurance companies(a) General ruleTaxes computed as provided in section 11 shall be imposed for each taxable year on the taxable income of every insurance company other than a life insurance company.


(b) Alternative tax for certain small companies(1) In generalIn lieu of the tax otherwise applicable under subsection (a), there is hereby imposed for each taxable year on the income of every insurance company to which this subsection applies a tax computed by multiplying the taxable investment income of such company for such taxable year by the rates provided in section 11(b).


(2) Companies to which this subsection applies(A) In generalThis subsection shall apply to every insurance company other than life if—(i) the net written premiums (or, if greater, direct written premiums) for the taxable year do not exceed $2,200,000,

(ii) such company meets the diversification requirements of subparagraph (B), and

(iii) such company elects the application of this subsection for such taxable year.


The election under clause (iii) shall apply to the taxable year for which made and for all subsequent taxable years for which the requirements of clauses (i) and (ii) are met. Such an election, once made, may be revoked only with the consent of the Secretary.

(B) Diversification requirements(i) In generalAn insurance company meets the requirements of this subparagraph if—(I) no more than 20 percent of the net written premiums (or, if greater, direct written premiums) of such company for the taxable year is attributable to any one policyholder, or

(II) such insurance company does not meet the requirement of subclause (I) and no person who holds (directly or indirectly) an interest in such insurance company is a specified holder who holds (directly or indirectly) aggregate interests in such insurance company which constitute a percentage of the entire interests in such insurance company which is more than a de minimis percentage</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Taxes computed as provided in section 11 shall be imposed for each taxable year on the taxable income of every insurance company other than a life insurance company.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative tax for certain small companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alternative tax for certain small companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance company defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Insurance company defined For purposes of this section, the term “insurance company” has the meaning given to such term by section 816(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting Every insurance company for which an election is in effect under subsection (b) for any taxable year shall furnish to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe such information for such taxable year as the Secretary shall require with respect to the requirements of subsection (b)(2)(A)(ii).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>