<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/832" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/832/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/832/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_832"><akn:num>832</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance company taxable income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 832. Insurance company taxable income(a) Definition of taxable incomeIn the case of an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831, the term “taxable income” means the gross income as defined in subsection (b)(1) less the deductions allowed by subsection (c).


(b) DefinitionsIn the case of an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831—(1) Gross incomeThe term “gross income” means the sum of—(A) the combined gross amount earned during the taxable year, from investment income and from underwriting income as provided in this subsection, computed on the basis of the underwriting and investment exhibit of the annual statement approved by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners,

(B) gain during the taxable year from the sale or other disposition of property,

(C) all other items constituting gross income under subchapter B, except that, in the case of a mutual fire insurance company exclusively issuing perpetual policies, the amount of single deposit premiums paid to such company shall not be included in gross income,

(D) in the case of a mutual fire or flood insurance company whose principal business is the issuance of policies—(i) for which the premium deposits are the same (regardless of the length of the term for which the policies are written), and

(ii) under which the unabsorbed portion of such premium deposits not required for losses, expenses, or establishment of reserves is returned or credited to the policyholder on cancellation or expiration of the policy,


an amount equal to 2 percent of the premiums earned on insurance contracts during the taxable year with respect to such policies after deduction of premium deposits returned or credited during the same taxable year, and

(E) in the case of a company which writes mortgage guaranty insurance, the amount required by subsection (e)(5) to be subtracted from the mortgage guaranty account.


(2) Investment incomeThe term “investment income” means the gross amount </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_832_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of taxable income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of taxable income In the case of an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831, the term “taxable income” means the gross income as defined in subsection (b)(1) less the deductions allowed by subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_832_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In the case of an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_832_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductions allowed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deductions allowed In computing the taxable income of an insurance company subject to the tax imposed by section 831, there shall be allowed as deductions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_832_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Double deductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Double deductions Nothing in this section shall permit the same item to be deducted more than once.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_832_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special deduction and income account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special deduction and income account In the case of a company which writes mortgage guaranty insurance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_832_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interinsurers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Interinsurers In the case of a mutual insurance company which is an interinsurer or reciprocal underwriter— For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “savings credited to subscriber accounts” means such portion of the surplus as is credited to the individual accounts of subscribers before the 16th day of the 3rd month following the close of the taxable year, but only if the company would be obligated to pay such amount promptly to such subscriber if he terminated his contract at the close of the company’s taxable year. For purposes of determining his taxable income, the subscriber shall treat any such savings credited to his account as a dividend paid or declared.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_832_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dividends within group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Dividends within group In the case of an insurance company subject to tax under section 831(a) filing or required to file a consolidated return under section 1501 with respect to any affiliated group for any taxable year, any determination under this part with respect to any dividend paid by one member of such group to another member of such group shall be made as if such group were not filing a consolidated return.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>