<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/848" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/848/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/848/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_848"><akn:num>848</akn:num><akn:heading>Capitalization of certain policy acquisition expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 848. Capitalization of certain policy acquisition expenses(a) General ruleIn the case of an insurance company—(1) specified policy acquisition expenses for any taxable year shall be capitalized, and

(2) such expenses shall be allowed as a deduction ratably over the 180-month period beginning with the first month in the second half of such taxable year.


(b) 5-year amortization for first $5,000,000 of specified policy acquisition expenses(1) In generalParagraph (2) of subsection (a) shall be applied with respect to so much of the specified policy acquisition expenses of an insurance company for any taxable year as does not exceed $5,000,000 by substituting “60-month” for “180-month”.


(2) Phase-outIf the specified policy acquisition expenses of an insurance company exceed $10,000,000 for any taxable year, the $5,000,000 amount under paragraph (1) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount of such excess.


(3) Special rule for members of controlled groupIn the case of any controlled group—(A) all insurance companies which are members of such group shall be treated as 1 company for purposes of this subsection, and

(B) the amount to which paragraph (1) applies shall be allocated among such companies in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe.


For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “controlled group” means any controlled group of corporations as defined in section 1563(a); except that subsections (a)(4) and (b)(2)(D) of section 1563 shall not apply, and subsection (b)(2)(C) of section 1563 shall not apply to the extent it excludes a foreign corporation to which section 842 applies.

(4) Exception for acquisition expenses attributable to certain reinsurance contractsParagraph (1) shall not apply to any specified policy acquisition expenses for any taxable year which are attributable to premiums or other consideration under any reinsurance contract.



(c) Specified policy acquisition expensesFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe ter</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_848_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of an insurance company—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_848_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>5-year amortization for first $5,000,000 of specified policy acquisition expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) 5-year amortization for first $5,000,000 of specified policy acquisition expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_848_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specified policy acquisition expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Specified policy acquisition expenses For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_848_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Net premiums For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_848_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classification of contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Classification of contracts For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_848_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule where negative net premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rule where negative net premiums</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_848_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain ceding commissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Treatment of certain ceding commissions Nothing in any provision of law (other than this section or section 197) shall require the capitalization of any ceding commission incurred on or after September 30, 1990, under any contract which reinsures a specified insurance contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_848_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial authority to adjust capitalization amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Secretarial authority to adjust capitalization amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>