<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/853" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/853/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/853/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_853"><akn:num>853</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign tax credit allowed to shareholders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 853. Foreign tax credit allowed to shareholders(a) General ruleA regulated investment company—(1) more than 50 percent of the value (as defined in section 851(c)(4)) of whose total assets at the close of the taxable year consists of stock or securities in foreign corporations, and

(2) which meets the requirements of section 852(a) for the taxable year,


may, for such taxable year, elect the application of this section with respect to income, war profits, and excess profits taxes described in section 901(b)(1), which are paid by the investment company during such taxable year to foreign countries and possessions of the United States.

(b) Effect of electionIf the election provided in subsection (a) is effective for a taxable year—(1) the regulated investment company—(A) shall not, with respect to such taxable year, be allowed a deduction under section 164(a) or a credit under section 901 for taxes to which subsection (a) is applicable, and

(B) shall be allowed as an addition to the dividends paid deduction for such taxable year the amount of such taxes;


(2) each shareholder of such investment company shall—(A) include in gross income and treat as paid by him his proportionate share of such taxes, and

(B) treat as gross income from sources within the respective foreign countries and possessions of the United States, for purposes of applying subpart A of part III of subchapter N, the sum of his proportionate share of such taxes and the portion of any dividend paid by such investment company which represents income derived from sources within foreign countries or possessions of the United States.



(c) Statements to shareholdersThe amounts to be treated by the shareholder, for purposes of subsection (b)(2), as his proportionate share of—(1) taxes paid to any foreign country or possession of the United States, and

(2) gross income derived from sources within any foreign country or possession of the United States,


shall not exceed the amounts so reported by th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule A regulated investment company— may, for such taxable year, elect the application of this section with respect to income, war profits, and excess profits taxes described in section 901(b)(1), which are paid by the investment company during such taxable year to foreign countries and possessions of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effect of election If the election provided in subsection (a) is effective for a taxable year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statements to shareholders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statements to shareholders The amounts to be treated by the shareholder, for purposes of subsection (b)(2), as his proportionate share of— shall not exceed the amounts so reported by the company in a written statement furnished to such shareholder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of making election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Manner of making election The election provided in subsection (a) shall be made in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe by regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain taxes not allowed as a credit under section 901</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of certain taxes not allowed as a credit under section 901 This section shall not apply to any tax with respect to which the regulated investment company is not allowed a credit under section 901 by reason of subsection (k) or (l) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cross references</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>