<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/853A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/853A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/853A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_853A"><akn:num>853A</akn:num><akn:heading>Credits from tax credit bonds allowed to shareholders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 853A. Credits from tax credit bonds allowed to shareholders(a) General ruleA regulated investment company—(1) which holds (directly or indirectly) one or more tax credit bonds on one or more applicable dates during the taxable year, and

(2) which meets the requirements of section 852(a) for the taxable year (determined after the application of this section),


may elect the application of this section with respect to some or all of the credits allowable (determined without regard to this section and sections 54(c), 54A(c)(1), 54AA(c)(1), and 1397E(c)) 11 See References in Text note below. to the investment company during such taxable year with respect to such bonds.

(b) Effect of electionIf the election provided in subsection (a) is in effect with respect to any credits for any taxable year—(1) the regulated investment company—(A) shall not be allowed such credits,

(B) shall include in gross income (as interest) for such taxable year the amount which would have been so included with respect to such credits had the application of this section not been elected,

(C) shall include in earnings and profits the amount so included in gross income, and

(D) shall be treated as making one or more distributions of money with respect to its stock equal to the amount of such credits on the date or dates (on or after the applicable date for any such credit) during such taxable year (or following the close of the taxable year pursuant to section 855) selected by the company, and


(2) each shareholder of such investment company shall—(A) be treated as receiving such shareholder’s proportionate share of any distribution of money which is treated as made by such investment company under paragraph (1)(D), and

(B) be allowed credits against the tax imposed by this chapter equal to the amount of such distribution, subject to the provisions of this title applicable to the credit involved.



(c) Statements 22 See 2010 Amendment note below. to shareholdersThe amount treated as a d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule A regulated investment company— may elect the application of this section with respect to some or all of the credits allowable (determined without regard to this section and sections 54(c), 54A(c)(1), 54AA(c)(1), and 1397E(c)) 11 See References in Text note below. to the investment company during such taxable year with respect to such bonds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effect of election If the election provided in subsection (a) is in effect with respect to any credits for any taxable year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statements 22 See 2010 Amendment note below. to shareholders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statements The amount treated as a distribution of money received by a shareholder under subsection (b)(2)(A) (and as credits allowed to such shareholder under subsection (b)(2)(B)) shall not exceed the amount so reported by the regulated investment company in a written statement furnished to such shareholder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of making election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Manner of making election The election provided in subsection (a) shall be made in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions and special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_853A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations, etc. The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including methods for determining a shareholder’s proportionate share of credits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>