<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/860" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/860/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/860/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_860"><akn:num>860</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction for deficiency dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 860. Deduction for deficiency dividends(a) General ruleIf a determination with respect to any qualified investment entity results in any adjustment for any taxable year, a deduction shall be allowed to such entity for the amount of deficiency dividends for purposes of determining the deduction for dividends paid (for purposes of section 852 or 857, whichever applies) for such year.


(b) Qualified investment entity definedFor purposes of this section, the term “qualified investment entity” means—(1) a regulated investment company, and

(2) a real estate investment trust.


(c) Rules for application of section(1) Interest and additions to tax determined with respect to the amount of deficiency dividend deduction allowedFor purposes of determining interest, additions to tax, and additional amounts—(A) the tax imposed by this chapter (after taking into account the deduction allowed by subsection (a)) on the qualified investment entity for the taxable year with respect to which the determination is made shall be deemed to be increased by an amount equal to the deduction allowed by subsection (a) with respect to such taxable year,

(B) the last date prescribed for payment of such increase in tax shall be deemed to have been the last date prescribed for the payment of tax (determined in the manner provided by section 6601(b)) for the taxable year with respect to which the determination is made, and

(C) such increase in tax shall be deemed to be paid as of the date the claim for the deficiency dividend deduction is filed.


(2) Credit or refundIf the allowance of a deficiency dividend deduction results in an overpayment of tax for any taxable year, credit or refund with respect to such overpayment shall be made as if on the date of the determination 2 years remained before the expiration of the period of limitations on the filing of claim for refund for the taxable year to which the overpayment relates.



(d) AdjustmentFor purposes of this section—(1) Adjustment in the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule If a determination with respect to any qualified investment entity results in any adjustment for any taxable year, a deduction shall be allowed to such entity for the amount of deficiency dividends for purposes of determining the deduction for dividends paid (for purposes of section 852 or 857, whichever applies) for such year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified investment entity defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified investment entity defined For purposes of this section, the term “qualified investment entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules for application of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rules for application of section</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adjustment For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Determination For purposes of this section, the term “determination” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deficiency dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Deficiency dividends</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claim required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Claim required No deficiency dividend deduction shall be allowed under subsection (a) unless (under regulations prescribed by the Secretary) claim therefore is filed within 120 days after the date of the determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of statute of limitations and stay of collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Suspension of statute of limitations and stay of collection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction denied in case of fraud</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Deduction denied in case of fraud No deficiency dividend deduction shall be allowed under subsection (a) if the determination contains a finding that any part of any deficiency attributable to an adjustment with respect to the taxable year is due to fraud with intent to evade tax or to willful failure to file an income tax return within the time prescribed by law or prescribed by the Secretary in pursuance of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>