<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/860E" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/860E/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/860E/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_860E"><akn:num>860E</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of income in excess of daily accruals on residual interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 860E. Treatment of income in excess of daily accruals on residual interests(a) Excess inclusions may not be offset by net operating losses(1) In generalThe taxable income of any holder of a residual interest in a REMIC for any taxable year shall in no event be less than the excess inclusion for such taxable year.


(2) Special rule for affiliated groupsAll members of an affiliated group filing a consolidated return shall be treated as 1 taxpayer for purposes of this subsection.


(3) Coordination with section 172Any excess inclusion for any taxable year shall not be taken into account—(A) in determining under section 172 the amount of any net operating loss for such taxable year, and

(B) in determining taxable income for such taxable year for purposes of subsection (a)(2)(B)(ii)(I) and the second sentence of subsection (b)(2) of section 172.


(4) Coordination with minimum taxFor purposes of part VI of subchapter A of this chapter—(A) the reference in section 55(b)(1)(D) to taxable income shall be treated as a reference to taxable income determined without regard to this subsection,

(B) the alternative minimum taxable income of any holder of a residual interest in a REMIC for any taxable year shall in no event be less than the excess inclusion for such taxable year, and

(C) any excess inclusion shall be disregarded for purposes of computing the alternative tax net operating loss deduction.



(b) Organizations subject to unrelated business taxIf the holder of any residual interest in a REMIC is an organization subject to the tax imposed by section 511, the excess inclusion of such holder for any taxable year shall be treated as unrelated business taxable income of such holder for purposes of section 511.


(c) Excess inclusionFor purposes of this section—(1) In generalThe term “excess inclusion” means, with respect to any residual interest in a REMIC for any calendar quarter, the excess (if any) of—(A) the amount taken into account with respect to such interest</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860E_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess inclusions may not be offset by net operating losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Excess inclusions may not be offset by net operating losses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860E_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organizations subject to unrelated business tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Organizations subject to unrelated business tax If the holder of any residual interest in a REMIC is an organization subject to the tax imposed by section 511, the excess inclusion of such holder for any taxable year shall be treated as unrelated business taxable income of such holder for purposes of section 511.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860E_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess inclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Excess inclusion For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860E_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of residual interests held by real estate investment trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of residual interests held by real estate investment trusts If a residual interest in a REMIC is held by a real estate investment trust, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary— Rules similar to the rules of the preceding sentence shall apply also in the case of regulated investment companies, common trust funds, and organizations to which part I of subchapter T applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860E_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax on transfers of residual interests to certain organizations, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Tax on transfers of residual interests to certain organizations, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860E_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of variable insurance contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of variable insurance contracts Except as provided in regulations, with respect to any variable contract (as defined in section 817), there shall be no adjustment in the reserve to the extent of any excess inclusion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>