<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/860G" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/860G/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/860G/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_860G"><akn:num>860G</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 860G. Other definitions and special rules(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this part—(1) Regular interestThe term “regular interest” means any interest in a REMIC which is issued on the startup day with fixed terms and which is designated as a regular interest if—(A) such interest unconditionally entitles the holder to receive a specified principal amount (or other similar amount), and

(B) interest payments (or other similar amount), if any, with respect to such interest at or before maturity—(i) are payable based on a fixed rate (or to the extent provided in regulations, at a variable rate), or

(ii) consist of a specified portion of the interest payments on qualified mortgages and such portion does not vary during the period such interest is outstanding.



The interest shall not fail to meet the requirements of subparagraph (A) merely because the timing (but not the amount) of the principal payments (or other similar amounts) may be contingent on the extent of prepayments on qualified mortgages and the amount of income from permitted investments. An interest shall not fail to qualify as a regular interest solely because the specified principal amount of the regular interest (or the amount of interest accrued on the regular interest) can be reduced as a result of the nonoccurrence of 1 or more contingent payments with respect to any reverse mortgage loan held by the REMIC if, on the startup day for the REMIC, the sponsor reasonably believes that all principal and interest due under the regular interest will be paid at or prior to the liquidation of the REMIC.

(2) Residual interestThe term “residual interest” means an interest in a REMIC which is issued on the startup day, which is not a regular interest, and which is designated as a residual interest.


(3) Qualified mortgageThe term “qualified mortgage” means—(A) any obligation (including any participation or certificate of beneficial ownership therein) which is principally secured by an interest in real propert</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860G_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860G_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of nonresident aliens and foreign corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treatment of nonresident aliens and foreign corporations If the holder of a residual interest in a REMIC is a nonresident alien individual or a foreign corporation, for purposes of sections 871(a), 881, 1441, and 1442— The Secretary may by regulations provide that such amounts shall be taken into account earlier than as provided in paragraph (1) where necessary or appropriate to prevent the avoidance of tax imposed by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860G_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax on income from foreclosure property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tax on income from foreclosure property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860G_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax on contributions after startup date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tax on contributions after startup date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_860G_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this part, including regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>