<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/861" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/861/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/861/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_861"><akn:num>861</akn:num><akn:heading>Income from sources within the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 861. Income from sources within the United States(a) Gross income from sources within United StatesThe following items of gross income shall be treated as income from sources within the United States:(1) InterestInterest from the United States or the District of Columbia, and interest on bonds, notes, or other interest-bearing obligations of noncorporate residents or domestic corporations not including—(A) interest—(i) on deposits with a foreign branch of a domestic corporation or a domestic partnership if such branch is engaged in the commercial banking business, and

(ii) on amounts satisfying the requirements of subparagraph (B) of section 871(i)(3) which are paid by a foreign branch of a domestic corporation or a domestic partnership, and


(B) in the case of a foreign partnership, which is predominantly engaged in the active conduct of a trade or business outside the United States, any interest not paid by a trade or business engaged in by the partnership in the United States and not allocable to income which is effectively connected (or treated as effectively connected) with the conduct of a trade or business in the United States.


(2) DividendsThe amount received as dividends—(A) from a domestic corporation, or

(B) from a foreign corporation unless less than 25 percent of the gross income from all sources of such foreign corporation for the 3-year period ending with the close of its taxable year preceding the declaration of such dividends (or for such part of such period as the corporation has been in existence) was effectively connected (or treated as effectively connected other than income described in section 884(d)(2)) with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States; but only in an amount which bears the same ratio to such dividends as the gross income of the corporation for such period which was effectively connected (or treated as effectively connected other than income described in section 884(d)(2)) with the conduct of a trade or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_861_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gross income from sources within United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Gross income from sources within United States The following items of gross income shall be treated as income from sources within the United States:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_861_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxable income from sources within United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Taxable income from sources within United States From the items of gross income specified in subsection (a) as being income from sources within the United States there shall be deducted the expenses, losses, and other deductions properly apportioned or allocated thereto and a ratable part of any expenses, losses, or other deductions which cannot definitely be allocated to some item or class of gross income. The remainder, if any, shall be included in full as taxable income from sources within the United States. In the case of an individual who does not itemize deductions, an amount equal to the standard deduction shall be considered a deduction which cannot definitely be allocated to some item or class of gross income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_861_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for application of subsection (a)(2)(B)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule for application of subsection (a)(2)(B) For purposes of subsection (a)(2)(B), if the foreign corporation has no gross income from any source for the 3-year period (or part thereof) specified, the requirements of such subsection shall be applied with respect to the taxable year of such corporation in which the payment of the dividend is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_861_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income from certain railroad rolling stock treated as income from sources within the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Income from certain railroad rolling stock treated as income from sources within the United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_861_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cross reference For treatment of interest paid by the branch of a foreign corporation, see section 884(f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>