<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/865" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/865/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/865/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_865"><akn:num>865</akn:num><akn:heading>Source rules for personal property sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 865. Source rules for personal property sales(a) General ruleExcept as otherwise provided in this section, income from the sale of personal property—(1) by a United States resident shall be sourced in the United States, or

(2) by a nonresident shall be sourced outside the United States.


(b) Exception for inventory propertyIn the case of income derived from the sale of inventory property—(1) this section shall not apply, and

(2) such income shall be sourced under the rules of sections 861(a)(6), 862(a)(6), and 863.


Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, any income from the sale of any unprocessed timber which is a softwood and was cut from an area in the United States shall be sourced in the United States and the rules of sections 862(a)(6) and 863(b) shall not apply to any such income. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “unprocessed timber” means any log, cant, or similar form of timber.

(c) Exception for depreciable personal property(1) In generalGain (not in excess of the depreciation adjustments) from the sale of depreciable personal property shall be allocated between sources in the United States and sources outside the United States—(A) by treating the same proportion of such gain as sourced in the United States as the United States depreciation adjustments with respect to such property bear to the total depreciation adjustments, and

(B) by treating the remaining portion of such gain as sourced outside the United States.


(2) Gain in excess of depreciationGain (in excess of the depreciation adjustments) from the sale of depreciable personal property shall be sourced as if such property were inventory property.


(3) United States depreciation adjustmentsFor purposes of this subsection—(A) In generalThe term “United States depreciation adjustments” means the portion of the depreciation adjustments to the adjusted basis of the property which are attributable to the depreciation deductions allowable in computing taxable income from source</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Except as otherwise provided in this section, income from the sale of personal property—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for inventory property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception for inventory property In the case of income derived from the sale of inventory property— Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, any income from the sale of any unprocessed timber which is a softwood and was cut from an area in the United States shall be sourced in the United States and the rules of sections 862(a)(6) and 863(b) shall not apply to any such income. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “unprocessed timber” means any log, cant, or similar form of timber.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for depreciable personal property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception for depreciable personal property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for intangibles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exception for intangibles</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for sales through offices or fixed places of business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules for sales through offices or fixed places of business</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stock of affiliates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Stock of affiliates If— any gain from such sale shall be sourced outside the United States. For purposes of paragraphs (2) and (3), the United States resident may elect to treat an affiliate and all other corporations which are wholly owned (directly or indirectly) by the affiliate as one corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States resident; nonresident</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) United States resident; nonresident For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of gains from sale of certain stock or intangibles and from certain liquidations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Treatment of gains from sale of certain stock or intangibles and from certain liquidations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Other definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_865_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purpose of this section, including regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>