<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/871" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/871/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/871/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_871"><akn:num>871</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax on nonresident alien individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 871. Tax on nonresident alien individuals(a) Income not connected with United States business—30 percent tax(1) Income other than capital gainsExcept as provided in subsection (h), there is hereby imposed for each taxable year a tax of 30 percent of the amount received from sources within the United States by a nonresident alien individual as—(A) interest (other than original issue discount as defined in section 1273), dividends, rents, salaries, wages, premiums, annuities, compensations, remunerations, emoluments, and other fixed or determinable annual or periodical gains, profits, and income,

(B) gains described in subsection (b) or (c) of section 631,

(C) in the case of—(i) a sale or exchange of an original issue discount obligation, the amount of the original issue discount accruing while such obligation was held by the nonresident alien individual (to the extent such discount was not theretofore taken into account under clause (ii)), and

(ii) a payment on an original issue discount obligation, an amount equal to the original issue discount accruing while such obligation was held by the nonresident alien individual (except that such original issue discount shall be taken into account under this clause only to the extent such discount was not theretofore taken into account under this clause and only to the extent that the tax thereon does not exceed the payment less the tax imposed by subparagraph (A) thereon), and


(D) gains from the sale or exchange after October 4, 1966, of patents, copyrights, secret processes and formulas, good will, trademarks, trade brands, franchises, and other like property, or of any interest in any such property, to the extent such gains are from payments which are contingent on the productivity, use, or disposition of the property or interest sold or exchanged,


but only to the extent the amount so received is not effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.

(2) Capital gains of alien</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income not connected with United States business—30 percent tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Income not connected with United States business—30 percent tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income connected with United States business—graduated rate of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Income connected with United States business—graduated rate of tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participants in certain exchange or training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Participants in certain exchange or training programs For purposes of this section, a nonresident alien individual who (without regard to this subsection) is not engaged in trade or business within the United States and who is temporarily present in the United States as a nonimmigrant under subparagraph (F), (J), (M), or (Q) of section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(F), (J), (M), or (Q)), shall be treated as a nonresident alien individual engaged in trade or business within the United States, and any income described in the second sentence of section 1441(b) which is received by such individual shall, to the extent derived from sources within the United States, be treated as effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to treat real property income as income connected with United States business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Election to treat real property income as income connected with United States business</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 99–514, title XII, § 1211(b)(5), Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2536]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain annuities received under qualified plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certain annuities received under qualified plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for original issue discount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rules for original issue discount For purposes of this section and section 881—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repeal of tax on interest of nonresident alien individuals received from certain portfolio debt investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Repeal of tax on interest of nonresident alien individuals received from certain portfolio debt investments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax not to apply to certain interest and dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Tax not to apply to certain interest and dividends</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_871_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for certain gambling winnings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exemption for certain gambling winnings No tax shall be imposed under paragraph (1)(A) of subsection (a) on the proceeds from a wager placed in any of the following games: blackjack, baccarat, craps, roulette, or big-6 wheel. The preceding sentence shall not apply in any case where the Secretary determines by regulation that the collection of the tax is administratively feasible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>