<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/873" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/873/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/873/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_873"><akn:num>873</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 873. Deductions(a) General ruleIn the case of a nonresident alien individual, the deductions shall be allowed only for purposes of section 871(b) and (except as provided by subsection (b)) only if and to the extent that they are connected with income which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States; and the proper apportionment and allocation of the deductions for this purpose shall be determined as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(b) ExceptionsThe following deductions shall be allowed whether or not they are connected with income which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States:(1) LossesThe deduction allowed by section 165 for casualty or theft losses described in paragraph (2) or (3) of section 165(c), but only if the loss is of property located within the United States.


(2) Charitable contributionsThe deduction for charitable contributions and gifts allowed by section 170.


(3) Personal exemptionThe deduction for personal exemptions allowed by section 151, except that only one exemption shall be allowed under section 151 unless the taxpayer is a resident of a contiguous country or is a national of the United States.



(c) Cross referenceFor rule that certain foreign taxes are not to be taken into account in determining deduction or credit, see section 906(b)(1).


(Aug. 16, 1954, ch. 736, 68A Stat. 280; Pub. L. 89–809, title I, § 103(c)(1), Nov. 13, 1966, 80 Stat. 1550; Pub. L. 92–580, § 1(b), Oct. 27, 1972, 86 Stat. 1276; Pub. L. 94–455, title XIX, § 1906(b)(13)(A), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1834; Pub. L. 95–30, title I, § 101(d)(11), May 23, 1977, 91 Stat. 134; Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title VII, § 711(c)(2)(A)(iv), July 18, 1984, 98 Stat. 945; Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title IV, § 4004(b)(3), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–911.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Subsec. (b)(1). Pub. L. 105–277 amended heading and text of par. (1) generally. Prior</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_873_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of a nonresident alien individual, the deductions shall be allowed only for purposes of section 871(b) and (except as provided by subsection (b)) only if and to the extent that they are connected with income which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States; and the proper apportionment and allocation of the deductions for this purpose shall be determined as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_873_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions The following deductions shall be allowed whether or not they are connected with income which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_873_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cross reference For rule that certain foreign taxes are not to be taken into account in determining deduction or credit, see section 906(b)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>