<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/877" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/877/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/877/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_877"><akn:num>877</akn:num><akn:heading>Expatriation to avoid tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 877. Expatriation to avoid tax(a) Treatment of expatriates(1) In generalEvery nonresident alien individual to whom this section applies and who, within the 10-year period immediately preceding the close of the taxable year, lost United States citizenship shall be taxable for such taxable year in the manner provided in subsection (b) if the tax imposed pursuant to such subsection (after any reduction in such tax under the last sentence of such subsection) exceeds the tax which, without regard to this section, is imposed pursuant to section 871.


(2) Individuals subject to this sectionThis section shall apply to any individual if—(A) the average annual net income tax (as defined in section 38(c)(1)) of such individual for the period of 5 taxable years ending before the date of the loss of United States citizenship is greater than $124,000,

(B) the net worth of the individual as of such date is $2,000,000 or more, or

(C) such individual fails to certify under penalty of perjury that he has met the requirements of this title for the 5 preceding taxable years or fails to submit such evidence of such compliance as the Secretary may require.


In the case of the loss of United States citizenship in any calendar year after 2004, such $124,000 amount shall be increased by an amount equal to such dollar amount multiplied by the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting “2003” for “1992” in subparagraph (B) thereof. Any increase under the preceding sentence shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $1,000.


(b) Alternative taxA nonresident alien individual described in subsection (a) shall be taxable for the taxable year as provided in section 1 or 55, except that—(1) the gross income shall include only the gross income described in section 872(a) (as modified by subsection (d) of this section), and

(2) the deductions shall be allowed if and to the extent that they are connected with the gross income included und</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of expatriates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Treatment of expatriates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alternative tax A nonresident alien individual described in subsection (a) shall be taxable for the taxable year as provided in section 1 or 55, except that— For purposes of paragraph (2), the deductions allowed by section 873(b) shall be allowed; and the deduction (for losses not connected with the trade or business if incurred in transactions entered into for profit) allowed by section 165(c)(2) shall be allowed, but only if the profit, if such transaction had resulted in a profit, would be included in gross income under this section. The tax imposed solely by reason of this section shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount of any income, war profits, and excess profits taxes (within the meaning of section 903) paid to any foreign country or possession of the United States on any income of the taxpayer on which tax is imposed solely by reason of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for source, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules for source, etc. For purposes of subsection (b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comparable treatment of lawful permanent residents who cease to be taxed as residents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Comparable treatment of lawful permanent residents who cease to be taxed as residents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Burden of proof</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Burden of proof If the Secretary establishes that it is reasonable to believe that an individual’s loss of United States citizenship would, but for this section, result in a substantial reduction for the taxable year in the taxes on his probable income for such year, the burden of proving for such taxable year that such loss of citizenship did not have for one of its principal purposes the avoidance of taxes under this subtitle or subtitle B shall be on such individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physical presence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Physical presence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Termination This section shall not apply to any individual whose expatriation date (as defined in section 877A(g)(3)) is on or after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>