<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/877A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/877A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/877A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_877A"><akn:num>877A</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax responsibilities of expatriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 877A. Tax responsibilities of expatriation(a) General rulesFor purposes of this subtitle—(1) Mark to marketAll property of a covered expatriate shall be treated as sold on the day before the expatriation date for its fair market value.


(2) Recognition of gain or lossIn the case of any sale under paragraph (1)—(A) notwithstanding any other provision of this title, any gain arising from such sale shall be taken into account for the taxable year of the sale, and

(B) any loss arising from such sale shall be taken into account for the taxable year of the sale to the extent otherwise provided by this title, except that section 1091 shall not apply to any such loss.


Proper adjustment shall be made in the amount of any gain or loss subsequently realized for gain or loss taken into account under the preceding sentence, determined without regard to paragraph (3).

(3) Exclusion for certain gain(A) In generalThe amount which would (but for this paragraph) be includible in the gross income of any individual by reason of paragraph (1) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by $600,000.


(B) Adjustment for inflation(i) In generalIn the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2008, the dollar amount in subparagraph (A) shall be increased by an amount equal to—(I) such dollar amount, multiplied by

(II) the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, by substituting “calendar year 2007” for “calendar year 2016” in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.


(ii) RoundingIf any amount as adjusted under clause (i) is not a multiple of $1,000, such amount shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $1,000.





(b) Election to defer tax(1) In generalIf the taxpayer elects the application of this subsection with respect to any property treated as sold by reason of subsection (a), the time for payment of the additional tax attributable to such property shall be extended until the due date of the return</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rules For purposes of this subtitle—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to defer tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Election to defer tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for certain property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception for certain property Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of deferred compensation items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of deferred compensation items</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of specified tax deferred accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of specified tax deferred accounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for nongrantor trusts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rules for nongrantor trusts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules relating to expatriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions and special rules relating to expatriation For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877A_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Other rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877A_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>