<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/879" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/879/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/879/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_879"><akn:num>879</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax treatment of certain community income in the case of nonresident alien individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 879. Tax treatment of certain community income in the case of nonresident alien individuals(a) General ruleIn the case of a married couple 1 or both of whom are nonresident alien individuals and who have community income for the taxable year, such community income shall be treated as follows:(1) Earned income (within the meaning of section 911(d)(2)), other than trade or business income and a partner’s distributive share of partnership income, shall be treated as the income of the spouse who rendered the personal services,

(2) Trade or business income, and a partner’s distributive share of partnership income, shall be treated as provided in section 1402(a)(5),

(3) Community income not described in paragraph (1) or (2) which is derived from the separate property (as determined under the applicable community property law) of one spouse shall be treated as the income of such spouse, and

(4) All other such community income shall be treated as provided in the applicable community property law.


(b) Exception where election under section 6013(g) is in effectSubsection (a) shall not apply for any taxable year for which an election under subsection (g) or (h) of section 6013 (relating to election to treat nonresident alien individual as resident of the United States) is in effect.


(c) Definitions and special rulesFor purposes of this section—(1) Community incomeThe term “community income” means income which, under applicable community property laws, is treated as community income.


(2) Community property lawsThe term “community property laws” means the community property laws of a State, a foreign country, or a possession of the United States.


(3) Determination of marital statusThe determination of marital status shall be made under section 7703(a).



(Added Pub. L. 94–455, title X, § 1012(b)(1), Oct. 4, 1976, 90 Stat. 1613; amended Pub. L. 97–34, title I, § 111(b)(4), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 194; Pub. L. 98–369, div. A, title I, § 139(a), (b)(1), July 18, 1984,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_879_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule In the case of a married couple 1 or both of whom are nonresident alien individuals and who have community income for the taxable year, such community income shall be treated as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_879_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception where election under section 6013(g) is in effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception where election under section 6013(g) is in effect Subsection (a) shall not apply for any taxable year for which an election under subsection (g) or (h) of section 6013 (relating to election to treat nonresident alien individual as resident of the United States) is in effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_879_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>