<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/882" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/882/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/882/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_882"><akn:num>882</akn:num><akn:heading>Tax on income of foreign corporations connected with United States business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 882. Tax on income of foreign corporations connected with United States business(a) Imposition of tax(1) In generalA foreign corporation engaged in trade or business within the United States during the taxable year shall be taxable as provided in section 11, 55, or 59A,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. on its taxable income which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.


(2) Determination of taxable incomeIn determining taxable income for purposes of paragraph (1), gross income includes only gross income which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.


(3) [Cross reference 22 Par. (3) heading editorially supplied.]For special tax treatment of gain or loss from the disposition by a foreign corporation of a United States real property interest, see section 897.



(b) Gross incomeIn the case of a foreign corporation, except where the context clearly indicates otherwise, gross income includes only—(1) gross income which is derived from sources within the United States and which is not effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States, and

(2) gross income which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.


(c) Allowance of deductions and credits(1) Allocation of deductions(A) General ruleIn the case of a foreign corporation, the deductions shall be allowed only for purposes of subsection (a) and (except as provided by subparagraph (B)) only if and to the extent that they are connected with income which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States; and the proper apportionment and allocation of the deductions for this purpose shall be determined as provided in regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(B) Charitable contributionsThe deduction for charitable contributions and gifts provided by section 170 shall be allo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_882_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Imposition of tax</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_882_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gross income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Gross income In the case of a foreign corporation, except where the context clearly indicates otherwise, gross income includes only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_882_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of deductions and credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allowance of deductions and credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_882_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to treat real property income as income connected with United States business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Election to treat real property income as income connected with United States business</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_882_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest on United States obligations received by banks organized in possessions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interest on United States obligations received by banks organized in possessions In the case of a corporation created or organized in, or under the law of, a possession of the United States which is carrying on the banking business in a possession of the United States, interest on obligations of the United States which is not portfolio interest (as defined in section 881(c)(2)) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_882_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Returns of tax by agent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Returns of tax by agent If any foreign corporation has no office or place of business in the United States but has an agent in the United States, the return required under section 6012 shall be made by the agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>