<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/894" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/894/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/894/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_894"><akn:num>894</akn:num><akn:heading>Income affected by treaty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 894. Income affected by treaty(a) Treaty provisions(1) In generalThe provisions of this title shall be applied to any taxpayer with due regard to any treaty obligation of the United States which applies to such taxpayer.


(2) Cross referenceFor relationship between treaties and this title, see section 7852(d).



(b) Permanent establishment in United StatesFor purposes of applying any exemption from, or reduction of, any tax provided by any treaty to which the United States is a party with respect to income which is not effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States, a nonresident alien individual or a foreign corporation shall be deemed not to have a permanent establishment in the United States at any time during the taxable year. This subsection shall not apply in respect of the tax computed under section 877(b).


(c) Denial of treaty benefits for certain payments through hybrid entities(1) Application to certain paymentsA foreign person shall not be entitled under any income tax treaty of the United States with a foreign country to any reduced rate of any withholding tax imposed by this title on an item of income derived through an entity which is treated as a partnership (or is otherwise treated as fiscally transparent) for purposes of this title if—(A) such item is not treated for purposes of the taxation laws of such foreign country as an item of income of such person,

(B) the treaty does not contain a provision addressing the applicability of the treaty in the case of an item of income derived through a partnership, and

(C) the foreign country does not impose tax on a distribution of such item of income from such entity to such person.


(2) RegulationsThe Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to determine the extent to which a taxpayer to which paragraph (1) does not apply shall not be entitled to benefits under any income tax treaty of the United States with respect to any</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_894_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treaty provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Treaty provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_894_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent establishment in United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Permanent establishment in United States For purposes of applying any exemption from, or reduction of, any tax provided by any treaty to which the United States is a party with respect to income which is not effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States, a nonresident alien individual or a foreign corporation shall be deemed not to have a permanent establishment in the United States at any time during the taxable year. This subsection shall not apply in respect of the tax computed under section 877(b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_894_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of treaty benefits for certain payments through hybrid entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Denial of treaty benefits for certain payments through hybrid entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>