<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9008" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9008/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9008/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9008"><akn:num>9008</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments for presidential nominating conventions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9008. Payments for presidential nominating conventions(a) Establishment of accountsThe Secretary shall maintain in the fund, in addition to any account which he maintains under section 9006(a), a separate account for the national committee of each major party and minor party. The Secretary shall deposit in each such account an amount equal to the amount which each such committee may receive under subsection (b). Such deposits shall be drawn from amounts designated by individuals under section 6096 and shall be made before any transfer is made to any account for any eligible candidate under section 9006(a).


(b) Entitlement to payments from the fund(1) Major partiesSubject to the provisions of this section, the national committee of a major party shall be entitled to payments under paragraph (3), with respect to any presidential nominating convention, in amounts which, in the aggregate, shall not exceed $4,000,000.


(2) Minor partiesSubject to the provisions of this section, the national committee of a minor party shall be entitled to payments under paragraph (3), with respect to any presidential nominating convention, in amounts which, in the aggregate, shall not exceed an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount the national committee of a major party is entitled to receive under paragraph (1) as the number of popular votes received by the candidate for President of the minor party, as such candidate, in the preceding presidential election bears to the average number of popular votes received by the candidates for President of the United States of the major parties in the preceding presidential election.


(3) PaymentsUpon receipt of certification from the Commission under subsection (g), the Secretary shall make payments from the appropriate account maintained under subsection (a) to the national committee of a major party or minor party which elects to receive its entitlement under this subsection. Such payments shall be available for use by such commi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9008_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of accounts The Secretary shall maintain in the fund, in addition to any account which he maintains under section 9006(a), a separate account for the national committee of each major party and minor party. The Secretary shall deposit in each such account an amount equal to the amount which each such committee may receive under subsection (b). Such deposits shall be drawn from amounts designated by individuals under section 6096 and shall be made before any transfer is made to any account for any eligible candidate under section 9006(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9008_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement to payments from the fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Entitlement to payments from the fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9008_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds No part of any payment made under subsection (b) shall be used to defray the expenses of any candidate or delegate who is participating in any presidential nominating convention. Such payments shall be used only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9008_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation of expenditures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9008_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability of payments The national committee of a major party or minor party may receive payments under subsection (b)(3) beginning on July 1 of the calendar year immediately preceding the calendar year in which a presidential nominating convention of the political party involved is held.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9008_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to the fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer to the fund If, after the close of a presidential nominating convention and after the national committee of the political party involved has been paid the amount which it is entitled to receive under this section, there are moneys remaining in the account of such national committee, the Secretary shall transfer the moneys so remaining to the fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9008_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certification by Commission Any major party or minor party may file a statement with the Commission in such form and manner and at such times as it may require, designating the national committee of such party. Such statement shall include the information required by section 303(b) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, together with such additional information as the Commission may require. Upon receipt of a statement filed under the preceding sentences, the Commission promptly shall verify such statement according to such procedures and criteria as it may establish and shall certify to the Secretary for payment in full to any such committee of amounts to which such committee may be entitled under subsection (b). Such certifications shall be subject to an examination and audit which the Commission shall conduct no later than December 31, of the calendar year in which the presidential nominating convention involved is held.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9008_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Repayments The Commission shall have the same authority to require repayments from the national committee of a major party or a minor party as it has with respect to repayments from any eligible candidate under section 9007(b). The provisions of section 9007(c) and section 9007(d) shall apply with respect to any repayment required by the Commission under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9008_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of payments for conventions; use of amounts for pediatric research initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination of payments for conventions; use of amounts for pediatric research initiative Effective on the date of the enactment of the Gabriella Miller Kids First Research Act—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>