<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_901"><akn:num>901</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxes of foreign countries and of possessions of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 901. Taxes of foreign countries and of possessions of United States(a) Allowance of creditIf the taxpayer chooses to have the benefits of this subpart, the tax imposed by this chapter shall, subject to the limitation of section 904, be credited with the amounts provided in the applicable paragraph of subsection (b) plus, in the case of a corporation, the taxes deemed to have been paid under section 960. Such choice for any taxable year may be made or changed at any time before the expiration of the period prescribed for making a claim for credit or refund of the tax imposed by this chapter for such taxable year. The credit shall not be allowed against any tax treated as a tax not imposed by this chapter under section 26(b).


(b) Amount allowedSubject to the limitation of section 904, the following amounts shall be allowed as the credit under subsection (a):(1) Citizens and domestic corporationsIn the case of a citizen of the United States and of a domestic corporation, the amount of any income, war profits, and excess profits taxes paid or accrued during the taxable year to any foreign country or to any possession of the United States; and


(2) Resident of the United States or Puerto RicoIn the case of a resident of the United States and in the case of an individual who is a bona fide resident of Puerto Rico during the entire taxable year, the amount of any such taxes paid or accrued during the taxable year to any possession of the United States; and


(3) Alien resident of the United States or Puerto RicoIn the case of an alien resident of the United States and in the case of an alien individual who is a bona fide resident of Puerto Rico during the entire taxable year, the amount of any such taxes paid or accrued during the taxable year to any foreign country; and


(4) Nonresident alien individuals and foreign corporationsIn the case of any nonresident alien individual not described in section 876 and in the case of any foreign corporation, the amount determin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allowance of credit If the taxpayer chooses to have the benefits of this subpart, the tax imposed by this chapter shall, subject to the limitation of section 904, be credited with the amounts provided in the applicable paragraph of subsection (b) plus, in the case of a corporation, the taxes deemed to have been paid under section 960. Such choice for any taxable year may be made or changed at any time before the expiration of the period prescribed for making a claim for credit or refund of the tax imposed by this chapter for such taxable year. The credit shall not be allowed against any tax treated as a tax not imposed by this chapter under section 26(b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount allowed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount allowed Subject to the limitation of section 904, the following amounts shall be allowed as the credit under subsection (a):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Similar credit required for certain alien residents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Similar credit required for certain alien residents Whenever the President finds that— the President shall proclaim that, for taxable years beginning while the proclamation remains in effect, the credit under subsection (b)(3) shall be allowed to citizens or subjects of such foreign country only if such foreign country, in imposing income, war profits, and excess profits taxes, allows to citizens of the United States residing in such foreign country such a similar credit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of dividends from a DISC or former DISC</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of dividends from a DISC or former DISC For purposes of this subpart, dividends from a DISC or former DISC (as defined in section 992(a)) shall be treated as dividends from a foreign corporation to the extent such dividends are treated under part I as income from sources without the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign taxes on mineral income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Foreign taxes on mineral income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain payments for oil or gas not considered as taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certain payments for oil or gas not considered as taxes Notwithstanding subsection (b) and section 960, the amount of any income, or profits, and excess profits taxes paid or accrued during the taxable year to any foreign country in connection with the purchase and sale of oil or gas extracted in such country is not to be considered as tax for purposes of section 275(a) and this section if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain taxes paid with respect to distributions from possessions corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certain taxes paid with respect to distributions from possessions corporations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 110–172, § 11(g)(9), Dec. 29, 2007, 121 Stat. 2490]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(h) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxes used to provide subsidies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Taxes used to provide subsidies Any income, war profits, or excess profits tax shall not be treated as a tax for purposes of this title to the extent—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of foreign tax credit, etc., with respect to certain foreign countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Denial of foreign tax credit, etc., with respect to certain foreign countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>