<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_907"><akn:num>907</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules in case of foreign oil and gas income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 907. Special rules in case of foreign oil and gas income(a) Reduction in amount allowed as foreign tax under section 901In applying section 901, the amount of any foreign oil and gas taxes paid or accrued (or deemed to have been paid) during the taxable year which would (but for this subsection) be taken into account for purposes of section 901 shall be reduced by the amount (if any) by which the amount of such taxes exceeds the product of—(1) the amount of the combined foreign oil and gas income for the taxable year,

(2) multiplied by—(A) in the case of a corporation, the percentage which is equal to the highest rate of tax specified under section 11(b), or

(B) in the case of an individual, a fraction the numerator of which is the tax against which the credit under section 901(a) is taken and the denominator of which is the taxpayer’s entire taxable income.



(b) Combined foreign oil and gas income; foreign oil and gas taxesFor purposes of this section—(1) Combined foreign oil and gas incomeThe term “combined foreign oil and gas income” means, with respect to any taxable year, the sum of—(A) foreign oil and gas extraction income, and

(B) foreign oil related income.


(2) Foreign oil and gas taxesThe term “foreign oil and gas taxes” means, with respect to any taxable year, the sum of—(A) oil and gas extraction taxes, and

(B) any income, war profits, and excess profits taxes paid or accrued (or deemed to have been paid or accrued under section 960) during the taxable year with respect to foreign oil related income (determined without regard to subsection (c)(4)) or loss which would be taken into account for purposes of section 901 without regard to this section.



(c) Foreign income definitions and special rulesFor purposes of this section—(1) Foreign oil and gas extraction incomeThe term “foreign oil and gas extraction income” means the taxable income derived from sources without the United States and its possessions from—(A) the extraction (by the taxpayer </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction in amount allowed as foreign tax under section 901</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reduction in amount allowed as foreign tax under section 901 In applying section 901, the amount of any foreign oil and gas taxes paid or accrued (or deemed to have been paid) during the taxable year which would (but for this subsection) be taken into account for purposes of section 901 shall be reduced by the amount (if any) by which the amount of such taxes exceeds the product of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Combined foreign oil and gas income; foreign oil and gas taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Combined foreign oil and gas income; foreign oil and gas taxes For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign income definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Foreign income definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disregard of certain posted prices, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disregard of certain posted prices, etc. For purposes of this chapter, in determining the amount of taxable income in the case of foreign oil and gas extraction income, if the oil or gas is disposed of, or is acquired other than from the government of a foreign country, at a posted price (or other pricing arrangement) which differs from the fair market value for such oil or gas, such fair market value shall be used in lieu of such posted price (or other pricing arrangement).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 101–508, title XI, § 11801(a)(32), Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1388–521]</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_907_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryback and carryover of disallowed credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Carryback and carryover of disallowed credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>