<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/934" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/934/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/934/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_934"><akn:num>934</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on reduction in income tax liability incurred to the Virgin Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 934. Limitation on reduction in income tax liability incurred to the Virgin Islands(a) General ruleTax liability incurred to the Virgin Islands pursuant to this subtitle, as made applicable in the Virgin Islands by the Act entitled “An Act making appropriations for the naval service for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1922, and for other purposes”, approved July 12, 1921 (48 U.S.C. 1397), or pursuant to section 28(a) of the Revised Organic Act of the Virgin Islands, approved July 22, 1954 (48 U.S.C. 1642), shall not be reduced or remitted in any way, directly or indirectly, whether by grant, subsidy, or other similar payment, by any law enacted in the Virgin Islands, except to the extent provided in subsection (b).


(b) Reductions permitted with respect to certain income(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to so much of the tax liability referred to in subsection (a) as is attributable to income derived from sources within the Virgin Islands or income effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the Virgin Islands.


(2) Exception for liability paid by citizens or residents of the United StatesParagraph (1) shall not apply to any liability payable to the Virgin Islands under section 932(b).


(3) Special rule for non-United States income of certain foreign corporations(A) In generalIn the case of a qualified foreign corporation, subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to so much of the tax liability referred to in subsection (a) as is attributable to income which is derived from sources outside the United States and which is not effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business within the United States.


(B) Qualified foreign corporationFor purposes of subparagraph (A), the term “qualified foreign corporation” means any foreign corporation if less than 10 percent of—(i) the total voting power of the stock of such corporation, and

(ii) the total value of the stock o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_934_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Tax liability incurred to the Virgin Islands pursuant to this subtitle, as made applicable in the Virgin Islands by the Act entitled “An Act making appropriations for the naval service for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1922, and for other purposes”, approved July 12, 1921 (48 U.S.C. 1397), or pursuant to section 28(a) of the Revised Organic Act of the Virgin Islands, approved July 22, 1954 (48 U.S.C. 1642), shall not be reduced or remitted in any way, directly or indirectly, whether by grant, subsidy, or other similar payment, by any law enacted in the Virgin Islands, except to the extent provided in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_934_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reductions permitted with respect to certain income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reductions permitted with respect to certain income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>