<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9501"><akn:num>9501</akn:num><akn:heading>Black Lung Disability Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9501. Black Lung Disability Trust Fund(a) Creation of Trust Fund(1) In generalThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Black Lung Disability Trust Fund”, consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or credited to the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund.


(2) TrusteesThe trustees of the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund shall be the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services.



(b) Transfer of certain taxes; other receipts(1) Transfer to Black Lung Disability Trust Fund of amounts equivalent to certain taxesThere are hereby appropriated to the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the taxes received in the Treasury under section 4121 or subchapter B of chapter 42.


(2) Certain repaid amounts, etc.The following amounts shall be credited to the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund:(A) Amounts repaid or recovered under subsection (b) of section 424 of the Black Lung Benefits Act (including interest thereon).

(B) Amounts paid as fines or penalties, or interest thereon, under section 423, 431, or 432 of the Black Lung Benefits Act.

(C) Amounts paid into the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund by a trust described in section 501(c)(21).



(c) Repayable advances(1) AuthorizationThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund, as repayable advances, such sums as may from time to time be necessary to make the expenditures described in subsection (d).


(2) Repayment with interestRepayable advances made to the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund shall be repaid, and interest on such advances shall be paid, to the general fund of the Treasury when the Secretary of the Treasury determines that moneys are available in the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund for such purposes.


(3) Rate of interestInterest on advances made pursuant to this subsection shall be at a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury (as of the close of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation of Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation of Trust Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain taxes; other receipts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of certain taxes; other receipts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayable advances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repayable advances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures from Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expenditures from Trust Fund Amounts in the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund shall be available, as provided by appropriation Acts, for— For purposes of the preceding sentence, any reference to section 402(i), 422, or 435 1 of the Black Lung Benefits Act shall be treated as a reference to such section as in effect immediately after the enactment of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>