<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9503"><akn:num>9503</akn:num><akn:heading>Highway Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9503. Highway Trust Fund(a) Creation of Trust FundThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Highway Trust Fund”, consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or credited to the Highway Trust Fund as provided in this section or section 9602(b).


(b) Transfer to Highway Trust Fund of amounts equivalent to certain taxes and penalties(1) Certain taxesThere are hereby appropriated to the Highway Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the taxes received in the Treasury before October 1, 2028, under the following provisions—(A) section 4041 (relating to taxes on diesel fuels and special motor fuels),

(B) section 4051 (relating to retail tax on heavy trucks and trailers),

(C) section 4071 (relating to tax on tires),

(D) section 4081 (relating to tax on gasoline, diesel fuel, and kerosene), and

(E) section 4481 (relating to tax on use of certain vehicles).


For purposes of this paragraph, taxes received under sections 4041 and 4081 shall be determined without reduction for credits under section 6426 and taxes received under section 4081 shall be determined without regard to tax receipts attributable to the rate specified in section 4081(a)(2)(C).

(2) Liabilities incurred before October 1, 2028There are hereby appropriated to the Highway Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the taxes which are received in the Treasury after September 30, 2028, and before July 1, 2029, and which are attributable to liability for tax incurred before October 1, 2028, under the provisions described in paragraph (1).


[(3) Repealed. Pub. L. 109–59, title XI, § 11161(c)(2)(C), Aug. 10, 2005, 119 Stat. 1972]

(4) Certain taxes not transferred to Highway Trust FundFor purposes of paragraphs (1) and (2), there shall not be taken into account the taxes imposed by—(A) section 4041(d),

(B) section 4081 to the extent attributable to the rate specified in section 4081(a)(2)(B),

(C) section 4041 or 4081 to the extent attributable to fuel used in a trai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation of Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation of Trust Fund There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Highway Trust Fund”, consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated or credited to the Highway Trust Fund as provided in this section or section 9602(b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to Highway Trust Fund of amounts equivalent to certain taxes and penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer to Highway Trust Fund of amounts equivalent to certain taxes and penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures from Highway Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expenditures from Highway Trust Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9503_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments of apportionments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adjustments of apportionments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9503_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Mass Transit Account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Establishment of Mass Transit Account</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9503_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Trust Fund balances after September 30, 1998</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Determination of Trust Fund balances after</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>