<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9505" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9505/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9505/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9505"><akn:num>9505</akn:num><akn:heading>Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9505. Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund(a) Creation of Trust FundThere is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund”, consisting of such amounts as may be—(1) appropriated to the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund as provided in this section,

(2) transferred to the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund by the Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation pursuant to section 13(a) of the Act of May 13, 1954, or

(3) credited to the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund as provided in section 9602(b).


(b) Transfer to Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund of amounts equivalent to certain taxesThere are hereby appropriated to the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the taxes received in the Treasury under section 4461 (relating to harbor maintenance tax).


(c) Expenditures from Harbor Maintenance Trust FundAmounts in the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund shall be available, as provided by appropriation Acts, for making expenditures—(1) to carry out section 210 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986,

(2) for payments of rebates of tolls or charges pursuant to section 13(b) of the Act of May 13, 1954 (as in effect on April 1, 1987), and

(3) for the payment of all expenses of administration incurred by the Department of the Treasury, the Army Corps of Engineers, and the Department of Commerce related to the administration of subchapter A of chapter 36 (relating to harbor maintenance tax), but not in excess of $5,000,000 for any fiscal year.


(Added Pub. L. 99–662, title XIV, § 1403(a), Nov. 17, 1986, 100 Stat. 4269; amended Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 683(a), Dec. 8, 1993, 107 Stat. 2218; Pub. L. 104–303, title VI, § 601, Oct. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 3792; Pub. L. 113–121, title II, § 2102(c), June 10, 2014, 128 Stat. 1278; Pub. L. 116–260, div. AA, title V, § 512(c)(3), Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2756.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 13 of the Act of May 13, 1954, referred to in sub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9505_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation of Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation of Trust Fund There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund”, consisting of such amounts as may be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9505_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund of amounts equivalent to certain taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer to Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund of amounts equivalent to certain taxes There are hereby appropriated to the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the taxes received in the Treasury under section 4461 (relating to harbor maintenance tax).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9505_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures from Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expenditures from Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund Amounts in the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund shall be available, as provided by appropriation Acts, for making expenditures—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>