<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/951" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/951/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/951/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_951"><akn:num>951</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts included in gross income of United States shareholders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 951. Amounts included in gross income of United States shareholders(a) Amounts included(1) In generalIf a foreign corporation is a controlled foreign corporation at any time during a taxable year of the foreign corporation (in this subsection referred to as the “CFC year”)—(A) each United States shareholder which owns (within the meaning of section 958(a)) stock in such corporation on any day during the CFC year shall include in gross income such shareholder’s pro rata share (determined under paragraph (2)) of the corporation’s subpart F income for the CFC year, and

(B) each United States shareholder which owns (within the meaning of section 958(a)) stock in such corporation on the last day, in the CFC year, on which such corporation is a controlled foreign corporation shall include in gross income the amount determined under section 956 with respect to such shareholder for the CFC year (but only to the extent not excluded from gross income under section 959(a)(2)).


(2) Pro rata share of subpart F incomeA United States shareholder’s pro rata share of a controlled foreign corporation’s subpart F income for a CFC year shall be the portion of such income which is attributable to—(A) the stock of such corporation owned (within the meaning of section 958(a)) by such shareholder, and

(B) any period of the CFC year during which—(i) such shareholder owned (within the meaning of section 958(a)) such stock,

(ii) such shareholder was a United States shareholder of such corporation, and

(iii) such corporation was a controlled foreign corporation.



(3) Taxable year of inclusionAny amount required to be included in gross income by a United States shareholder under paragraph (1) with respect to a CFC year shall be included in gross income for the shareholder’s taxable year which includes the last day on which the shareholder owns (within the meaning of section 958(a)) stock in the controlled foreign corporation during such CFC year.


(4) Regulatory authorityThe Secretar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts included</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amounts included</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States shareholder defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) United States shareholder defined For purposes of this title, the term “United States shareholder” means, with respect to any foreign corporation, a United States person (as defined in section 957(c)) who owns (within the meaning of section 958(a)), or is considered as owning by applying the rules of ownership of section 958(b), 10 percent or more of the total combined voting power of all classes of stock entitled to vote of such foreign corporation, or 10 percent or more of the total value of shares of all classes of stock of such foreign corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with passive foreign investment company provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination with passive foreign investment company provisions If, but for this subsection, an amount would be included in the gross income of a United States shareholder for any taxable year both under subsection (a)(1)(A)(i) and under section 1293 (relating to current taxation of income from certain passive foreign investment companies), such amount shall be included in the gross income of such shareholder only under subsection (a)(1)(A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>