<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/964" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/964/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/964/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_964"><akn:num>964</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 964. Miscellaneous provisions(a) Earnings and profitsExcept as provided in section 312(k)(4), for purposes of this subpart, the earnings and profits of any foreign corporation, and the deficit in earnings and profits of any foreign corporation, for any taxable year shall be determined according to rules substantially similar to those applicable to domestic corporations, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. In determining such earnings and profits, or the deficit in such earnings and profits, the amount of any illegal bribe, kickback, or other payment (within the meaning of section 162(c)) shall not be taken into account to decrease such earnings and profits or to increase such deficit. The payments referred to in the preceding sentence are payments which would be unlawful under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 if the payor were a United States person.


(b) Blocked foreign incomeUnder regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no part of the earnings and profits of a controlled foreign corporation for any taxable year shall be included in earnings and profits for purposes of sections 952 and 956, if it is established to the satisfaction of the Secretary that such part could not have been distributed by the controlled foreign corporation to United States shareholders who own (within the meaning of section 958(a)) stock of such controlled foreign corporation because of currency or other restrictions or limitations imposed under the laws of any foreign country.


(c) Records and accounts of United States shareholders(1) Records and accounts to be maintainedThe Secretary may by regulations require each person who is, or has been, a United States shareholder of a controlled foreign corporation to maintain such records and accounts as may be prescribed by such regulations as necessary to carry out the provisions of this subpart and subpart G.


(2) Two or more persons required to maintain or furnish the same records and accounts with respect to the same</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_964_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Earnings and profits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Earnings and profits Except as provided in section 312(k)(4), for purposes of this subpart, the earnings and profits of any foreign corporation, and the deficit in earnings and profits of any foreign corporation, for any taxable year shall be determined according to rules substantially similar to those applicable to domestic corporations, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. In determining such earnings and profits, or the deficit in such earnings and profits, the amount of any illegal bribe, kickback, or other payment (within the meaning of section 162(c)) shall not be taken into account to decrease such earnings and profits or to increase such deficit. The payments referred to in the preceding sentence are payments which would be unlawful under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act of 1977 if the payor were a United States person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_964_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Blocked foreign income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Blocked foreign income Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, no part of the earnings and profits of a controlled foreign corporation for any taxable year shall be included in earnings and profits for purposes of sections 952 and 956, if it is established to the satisfaction of the Secretary that such part could not have been distributed by the controlled foreign corporation to United States shareholders who own (within the meaning of section 958(a)) stock of such controlled foreign corporation because of currency or other restrictions or limitations imposed under the laws of any foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_964_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and accounts of United States shareholders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Records and accounts of United States shareholders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_964_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain branches</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of certain branches</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_964_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gain on certain stock sales by controlled foreign corporations treated as dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Gain on certain stock sales by controlled foreign corporations treated as dividends</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>