<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9703" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9703/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9703/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9703"><akn:num>9703</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9703. Plan benefits(a) In generalEach eligible beneficiary of the Combined Fund shall receive—(1) health benefits described in subsection (b), and

(2) in the case of an eligible beneficiary described in subsection (f)(1), death benefits coverage described in subsection (c).


(b) Health benefits(1) In generalThe trustees of the Combined Fund shall provide health care benefits to each eligible beneficiary by enrolling the beneficiary in a health care services plan which undertakes to provide such benefits on a prepaid risk basis. The trustees shall utilize all available plan resources to ensure that, consistent with paragraph (2), coverage under the managed care system shall to the maximum extent feasible be substantially the same as (and subject to the same limitations of) coverage provided under the 1950 UMWA Benefit Plan and the 1974 UMWA Benefit Plan as of January 1, 1992.


(2) Plan payment rates(A) In generalThe trustees of the Combined Fund shall negotiate payment rates with the health care services plans described in paragraph (1) for each plan year which are in amounts which—(i) vary as necessary to ensure that beneficiaries in different geographic areas have access to a uniform level of health benefits; and

(ii) result in aggregate payments for such plan year from the Combined Fund which do not exceed the total premium payments required to be paid to the Combined Fund under section 9704(a) for the plan year, adjusted as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C).


(B) ReductionsThe amount determined under subparagraph (A)(ii) for any plan year shall be reduced—(i) by the aggregate death benefit premiums determined under section 9704(c) for the plan year, and

(ii) by the amount reserved for plan administration under subsection (d).


(C) IncreasesThe amount determined under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be increased—(i) by any reduction in the total premium payments required to be paid under section 9704(a) by reason of transfers described in section 9705,

(i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9703_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each eligible beneficiary of the Combined Fund shall receive—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9703_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Health benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9703_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Death benefits coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Death benefits coverage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9703_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserves for administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reserves for administration The trustees of the Combined Fund may reserve for each plan year, for use in payment of the administrative costs of the Combined Fund, an amount not to exceed 5 percent of the premiums to be paid to the Combined Fund under section 9704(a) during the plan year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9703_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on enrollment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on enrollment The Combined Fund shall not enroll any individual who is not receiving benefits under the 1950 UMWA Benefit Plan or the 1974 UMWA Benefit Plan as of July 20, 1992.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9703_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible beneficiary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligible beneficiary For purposes of this subchapter, the term “eligible beneficiary” means an individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>