<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9721" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9721/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/9721/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9721"><akn:num>9721</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9721. Civil enforcement
The provisions of section 4301 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 shall apply, in the same manner as any claim arising out of an obligation to pay withdrawal liability under subtitle E of title IV of such Act, to any claim—(1) arising out of an obligation to pay any amount required to be paid by this chapter; or

(2) arising out of an obligation to pay any amount required by section 402(h)(5)(B)(ii) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1232(h)(5)(B)(ii)).

(Added Pub. L. 102–486, title XIX, § 19143(a), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3055; amended Pub. L. 109–432, div. C, title II, § 213(b)(2), Dec. 20, 2006, 120 Stat. 3027.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 93–406, Sept. 2, 1974, 88 Stat. 829. Subtitle E of title IV of the Act is classified generally to subtitle E (§ 1381 et seq.) of subchapter III of chapter 18 of Title 29, Labor. Section 4301 of the Act is classified to section 1451 of Title 29. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1001 of Title 29 and Tables.

Amendments2006—Pub. L. 109–432 reenacted section catchline without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The provisions of section 4301 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 shall apply to any claim arising out of an obligation to pay any amount required to be paid by this chapter in the same manner as any claim arising out of an obligation to pay withdrawal liability under subtitle E of title IV of such Act. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a signatory operator and related persons shall be treated in the same manner as employers.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9721_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) arising out of an obligation to pay any amount required to be paid by this chapter; or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9721_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) arising out of an obligation to pay any amount required by section 402(h)(5)(B)(ii) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1232(h)(5)(B)(ii)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>