<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/982" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/982/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/982/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_982"><akn:num>982</akn:num><akn:heading>Admissibility of documentation maintained in foreign countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 982. Admissibility of documentation maintained in foreign countries(a) General ruleIf the taxpayer fails to substantially comply with any formal document request arising out of the examination of the tax treatment of any item (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “examined item”) before the 90th day after the date of the mailing of such request on motion by the Secretary, any court having jurisdiction of a civil proceeding in which the tax treatment of the examined item is an issue shall prohibit the introduction by the taxpayer of any foreign-based documentation covered by such request.


(b) Reasonable cause exception(1) In generalSubsection (a) shall not apply with respect to any documentation if the taxpayer establishes that the failure to provide the documentation as requested by the Secretary is due to reasonable cause.


(2) Foreign nondisclosure law not reasonable causeFor purposes of paragraph (1), the fact that a foreign jurisdiction would impose a civil or criminal penalty on the taxpayer (or any other person) for disclosing the requested documentation is not reasonable cause.



(c) Formal document requestFor purposes of this section—(1) Formal document requestThe term “formal document request” means any request (made after the normal request procedures have failed to produce the requested documentation) for the production of foreign-based documentation which is mailed by registered or certified mail to the taxpayer at his last known address and which sets forth—(A) the time and place for the production of the documentation,

(B) a statement of the reason the documentation previously produced (if any) is not sufficient,

(C) a description of the documentation being sought, and

(D) the consequences to the taxpayer of the failure to produce the documentation described in subparagraph (C).


(2) Proceeding to quash(A) In generalNotwithstanding any other law or rule of law, any person to whom a formal document request is mailed shall have the ri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_982_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule If the taxpayer fails to substantially comply with any formal document request arising out of the examination of the tax treatment of any item (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “examined item”) before the 90th day after the date of the mailing of such request on motion by the Secretary, any court having jurisdiction of a civil proceeding in which the tax treatment of the examined item is an issue shall prohibit the introduction by the taxpayer of any foreign-based documentation covered by such request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_982_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable cause exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reasonable cause exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_982_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formal document request</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Formal document request For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_982_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions and special rules For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_982_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of statute of limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Suspension of statute of limitations If any person takes any action as provided in subsection (c)(2), the running of any period of limitations under section 6501 (relating to the assessment and collection of tax) or under section 6531 (relating to criminal prosecutions) with respect to such person shall be suspended for the period during which the proceeding under such subsection, and appeals therein, are pending.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>