<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/988" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/988/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/988/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_988"><akn:num>988</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain foreign currency transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 988. Treatment of certain foreign currency transactions(a) General ruleNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter—(1) Treatment as ordinary income or loss(A) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this section, any foreign currency gain or loss attributable to a section 988 transaction shall be computed separately and treated as ordinary income or loss (as the case may be).


(B) Special rule for forward contracts, etc.Except as provided in regulations, a taxpayer may elect to treat any foreign currency gain or loss attributable to a forward contract, a futures contract, or option described in subsection (c)(1)(B)(iii) which is a capital asset in the hands of the taxpayer and which is not a part of a straddle (within the meaning of section 1092(c), without regard to paragraph (4) thereof) as capital gain or loss (as the case may be) if the taxpayer makes such election and identifies such transaction before the close of the day on which such transaction is entered into (or such earlier time as the Secretary may prescribe).



(2) Gain or loss treated as interest for certain purposesTo the extent provided in regulations, any amount treated as ordinary income or loss under paragraph (1) shall be treated as interest income or expense (as the case may be).


(3) Source(A) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in regulations, in the case of any amount treated as ordinary income or loss under paragraph (1) (without regard to paragraph (1)(B)), the source of such amount shall be determined by reference to the residence of the taxpayer or the qualified business unit of the taxpayer on whose books the asset, liability, or item of income or expense is properly reflected.


(B) ResidenceFor purposes of this subpart—(i) In generalThe residence of any person shall be—(I) in the case of an individual, the country in which such individual’s tax home (as defined in section 911(d)(3)) is located,

(II) in the case of any corporation, partnership, trust, or estate which</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_988_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_988_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign currency gain or loss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Foreign currency gain or loss For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_988_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_988_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of 988 hedging transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of 988 hedging transactions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_988_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application to individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>