<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/999" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/999/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/26/999/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_999"><akn:num>999</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by taxpayers; determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 999. Reports by taxpayers; determinations(a) International boycott reports by taxpayers(1) Report requiredIf any person, or a member of a controlled group (within the meaning of section 993(a)(3)) which includes that person, has operations in, or related to—(A) a country (or with the government, a company, or a national of a country) which is on the list maintained by the Secretary under paragraph (3), or

(B) any other country (or with the government, a company, or a national of that country) in which such person or such member had operations during the taxable year if such person (or, if such person is a foreign corporation, any United States shareholder of that corporation) knows or has reason to know that participation in or co-operation with an international boycott is required as a condition of doing business within such country or with such government, company, or national,


that person or shareholder (within the meaning of section 951(b)) shall report such operations to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary prescribes, except that in the case of a foreign corporation such report shall be required only of a United States shareholder (within the meaning of such section) of such corporation.

(2) Participation and cooperation; request thereforA taxpayer shall report whether he, a foreign corporation of which he is a United States shareholder, or any member of a controlled group which includes the taxpayer or such foreign corporation has participated in or cooperated with an international boycott at any time during the taxable year, or has been requested to participate in or cooperate with such a boycott, and, if so, the nature of any operation in connection with which there was participation in or cooperation with such boycott (or there was a request to participate or cooperate).


(3) List to be maintainedThe Secretary shall maintain and publish not less frequently than quarterly a current list of countries which require or may requ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_999_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>International boycott reports by taxpayers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) International boycott reports by taxpayers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_999_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in or cooperation with an international boycott</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Participation in or cooperation with an international boycott</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_999_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>International boycott factor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) International boycott factor</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_999_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination with respect to particular operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Determination with respect to particular operations Upon a request made by the taxpayer, the Secretary shall issue a determination with respect to whether a particular operation of a person, or of a member of a controlled group which includes that person, constitutes participation in or cooperation with an international boycott. The Secretary may issue such a determination in advance of such operation in cases which are of such a nature that an advance determination is possible and appropriate under the circumstances. If the request is made before the operation is commenced, or before the end of a taxable year in which the operation is carried out, the Secretary may decline to issue such a determination before close of the taxable year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_999_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation or cooperation by related persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Participation or cooperation by related persons If a person controls (within the meaning of section 304(c)) a corporation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_999_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Willful failure to report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Willful failure to report Any person (within the meaning of section 6671(b)) required to report under this section who willfully fails to make such report shall, in addition to other penalties provided by law, be fined not more than $25,000, imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>