<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/35/3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/35/3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/35/3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3"><akn:num>3</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers and employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3. Officers and employees(a) Under Secretary and Director.—(1) In general.—The powers and duties of the United States Patent and Trademark Office shall be vested in an Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the United States Patent and Trademark Office (in this title referred to as the “Director”), who shall be a citizen of the United States and who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Director shall be a person who has a professional background and experience in patent or trademark law.

(2) Duties.—(A) In general.—The Director shall be responsible for providing policy direction and management supervision for the Office and for the issuance of patents and the registration of trademarks. The Director shall perform these duties in a fair, impartial, and equitable manner.

(B) Consulting with the public advisory committees.—The Director shall consult with the Patent Public Advisory Committee established in section 5 on a regular basis on matters relating to the patent operations of the Office, shall consult with the Trademark Public Advisory Committee established in section 5 on a regular basis on matters relating to the trademark operations of the Office, and shall consult with the respective Public Advisory Committee before submitting budgetary proposals to the Office of Management and Budget or changing or proposing to change patent or trademark user fees or patent or trademark regulations which are subject to the requirement to provide notice and opportunity for public comment under section 553 of title 5, as the case may be.


(3) Oath.—The Director shall, before taking office, take an oath to discharge faithfully the duties of the Office.

(4) Removal.—The Director may be removed from office by the President. The President shall provide notification of any such removal to both Houses of Congress.


(b) Officers and Employees of the Office.—(1) Deputy under secretary and deputy</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Under Secretary and Director.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers and Employees of the Office.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued Applicability of Title 5.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Officers and employees of the Office shall be subject to the provisions of title 5, relating to Federal employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of Existing Labor Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Office shall adopt all labor agreements which are in effect, as of the day before the effective date of the Patent and Trademark Office Efficiency Act, with respect to such Office (as then in effect).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryover of Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Any transfer under this paragraph shall be effective as of the same effective date as referred to in paragraph (1), and shall be made without a break in service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>