<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/35/41" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/35/41/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/35/41/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41"><akn:num>41</akn:num><akn:heading>Patent fees; patent and trademark search systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41. Patent fees; patent and trademark search systems(a) General Fees.—The Director shall charge the following fees:(1) Filing and basic national fees.—(A) On filing each application for an original patent, except for design, plant, or provisional applications, $330.

(B) On filing each application for an original design patent, $220.

(C) On filing each application for an original plant patent, $220.

(D) On filing each provisional application for an original patent, $220.

(E) On filing each application for the reissue of a patent, $330.

(F) The basic national fee for each international application filed under the treaty defined in section 351(a) entering the national stage under section 371, $330.

(G) In addition, excluding any sequence listing or computer program listing filed in an electronic medium as prescribed by the Director, for any application the specification and drawings of which exceed 100 sheets of paper (or equivalent as prescribed by the Director if filed in an electronic medium), $270 for each additional 50 sheets of paper (or equivalent as prescribed by the Director if filed in an electronic medium) or fraction thereof.


(2) Excess claims fees.—(A) In general.—In addition to the fee specified in paragraph (1)—(i) on filing or on presentation at any other time, $220 for each claim in independent form in excess of 3;

(ii) on filing or on presentation at any other time, $52 for each claim (whether dependent or independent) in excess of 20; and

(iii) for each application containing a multiple dependent claim, $390.


(B) Multiple dependent claims.—For the purpose of computing fees under subparagraph (A), a multiple dependent claim referred to in section 112 or any claim depending therefrom shall be considered as separate dependent claims in accordance with the number of claims to which reference is made.

(C) Refunds; errors in payment.—The Director may by regulation provide for a refund of any part of the fee specified in subparagraph (A) for </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Director shall charge the following fees:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delays in Payment of Maintenance Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Patent Search and Other Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of Fees; Copies Regarding Notice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Director may waive the payment of any fee for any service or material related to patents in connection with an occasional or incidental request made by a department or agency of the Government, or any officer thereof. The Director may provide any applicant issued a notice under section 132 with a copy of the specifications and drawings for all patents referred to in that notice without charge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The fees established in subsections (a) and (b) of this section may be adjusted by the Director on October 1, 1992, and every year thereafter, to reflect any fluctuations occurring during the previous 12 months in the Consumer Price Index, as determined by the Secretary of Labor. Changes of less than 1 per centum may be ignored.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(g) Repealed. Pub. L. 112–29, § 11(e)(3), Sept. 16, 2011, 125 Stat. 323.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for Small Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic Patent and Trademark Data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for False Assertions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In addition to any other penalty available under law, an entity that is found to have falsely asserted entitlement to a fee reduction under this section shall, unless the entity shows that the assertion was made in good faith, be subject to a fine, to be determined by the Director, the amount of which shall be not less than 3 times the amount that the entity failed to pay as a result of the false assertion, whether the Director discovers the false assertion before or after the date on which a patent has been issued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>