<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/11113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/11113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/11113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11113"><akn:num>11113</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of abandoned seafarers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11113. Treatment of abandoned seafarers(a) Abandoned Seafarers Fund.—(1) Establishment.—There is established in the Treasury a separate account to be known as the Abandoned Seafarers Fund.

(2) Authorized uses.—Amounts in the Fund may be appropriated to the Secretary for use—(A) to pay necessary support of a seafarer—(i) who—(I) was paroled into the United States under section 212(d)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1182(d)(5)), or for whom the Secretary has requested parole under such section; and

(II) is involved in an investigation, reporting, documentation, or adjudication of any matter that is related to the administration or enforcement of law by the Coast Guard; or


(ii) who—(I) is physically present in the United States;

(II) the Secretary determines was abandoned in the United States; and

(III) has not applied for asylum under the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.); and



(B) to reimburse a vessel owner or operator for the costs of necessary support of a seafarer who has been paroled into the United States to facilitate an investigation, reporting, documentation, or adjudication of any matter that is related to the administration or enforcement of law by the Coast Guard, if—(i) the vessel owner or operator is not convicted of a criminal offense related to such matter; or

(ii) the Secretary determines that reimbursement is appropriate.



(3) Crediting of amounts to fund.—(A) In general.—Except as provided in subparagraph (B), there shall be credited to the Fund the following:(i) Penalties deposited in the Fund under section 9 of the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships (33 U.S.C. 1908).

(ii) Amounts reimbursed or recovered under subsection (c).


(B) Limitation.—Amounts may be credited to the Fund under subparagraph (A) only if the unobligated balance of the Fund is less than $5,000,000.


(4) Report required.—Except as provided in paragraph (5), on the date on which the President submits each budget for a fis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Abandoned Seafarers Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nothing in this section shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement; Recovery.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>