<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12105"><akn:num>12105</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of documentation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12105. Issuance of documentation(a) In General.—Except as provided in section 12152 of this title, the Secretary, on receipt of a proper application, shall issue a certificate of documentation or a temporary certificate of documentation for a vessel satisfying the requirements of section 12103 of this title. The certificate shall contain each endorsement under subchapter II of this chapter for which the owner applies and the vessel is eligible.

(b) Temporary Certificates for Recreational Vessels.—The Secretary may delegate, subject to the supervision and control of the Secretary and under terms prescribed by regulation, to private entities determined and certified by the Secretary to be qualified, the authority to issue a temporary certificate of documentation for a recreational vessel eligible under section 12103 of this title. A temporary certificate issued under this subsection is valid for not more than 30 days.

(c) Information To Be Included in Certificate.—A certificate of documentation shall—(1) identify and describe the vessel;

(2) identify the owner of the vessel; and

(3) contain additional information prescribed by the Secretary.


(d) Procedures To Ensure Integrity and Accuracy.—The Secretary shall prescribe procedures to ensure the integrity of, and the accuracy of information contained in, certificates of documentation.

(e) Effective Period.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), a certificate of documentation issued under this part is valid for a 1-year period and may be renewed for additional 1-year periods.

(2) Recreational vessels.—(A) In general.—The owner or operator of a recreational vessel may choose a period of effectiveness of between 1 and 5 years for a certificate of documentation for a recreational vessel or the renewal thereof.

(B) Fees.—(i) Requirement.—The Secretary shall assess and collect a fee—(I) for the issuance of a certificate of documentation for a recreational vessel that is equivalent to the fee </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in section 12152 of this title, the Secretary, on receipt of a proper application, shall issue a certificate of documentation or a temporary certificate of documentation for a vessel satisfying the requirements of section 12103 of this title. The certificate shall contain each endorsement under subchapter II of this chapter for which the owner applies and the vessel is eligible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary Certificates for Recreational Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may delegate, subject to the supervision and control of the Secretary and under terms prescribed by regulation, to private entities determined and certified by the Secretary to be qualified, the authority to issue a temporary certificate of documentation for a recreational vessel eligible under section 12103 of this title. A temporary certificate issued under this subsection is valid for not more than 30 days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information To Be Included in Certificate.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A certificate of documentation shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12105_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures To Ensure Integrity and Accuracy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall prescribe procedures to ensure the integrity of, and the accuracy of information contained in, certificates of documentation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12105_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Period.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>