<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12113"><akn:num>12113</akn:num><akn:heading>Fishery endorsement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12113. Fishery endorsement(a) Requirements.—A fishery endorsement may be issued for a vessel that—(1) satisfies the requirements of section 12103 of this title and, if owned by an entity, the entity satisfies the ownership requirements in subsection (c);

(2) was built in the United States;

(3) if rebuilt, was rebuilt in the United States;

(4) was not forfeited to the United States Government after July 1, 2001, for a breach of the laws of the United States; and

(5) otherwise qualifies under the laws of the United States to engage in the fisheries.


(b) Authorized Activity.—(1) In general.—Subject to the laws of the United States regulating the fisheries, a vessel for which a fishery endorsement is issued may engage in the fisheries.

(2) Use by prohibited persons.—A fishery endorsement is invalid immediately if the vessel for which it is issued is used as a fishing vessel while it is chartered or leased to an individual who is not a citizen of the United States or to an entity that is not eligible to own a vessel with a fishery endorsement.


(c) Ownership Requirements for Entities.—(1) In general.—A vessel owned by an entity is eligible for a fishery endorsement only if at least 75 percent of the interest in the entity, at each tier of ownership and in the aggregate, is owned and controlled by citizens of the United States.

(2) Determining 75 percent interest.—In determining whether at least 75 percent of the interest in the entity is owned and controlled by citizens of the United States under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall apply section 50501(d) of this title, except that for this purpose the terms “control” or “controlled”—(A) include the right to—(i) direct the business of the entity;

(ii) limit the actions of or replace the chief executive officer, a majority of the board of directors, any general partner, or any person serving in a management capacity of the entity; or

(iii) direct the transfer, operation, or manning of a vessel with a fishery en</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A fishery endorsement may be issued for a vessel that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Activity.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ownership Requirements for Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements Based on Length, Tonnage, or Horsepower.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels Measuring 100 Feet or Greater.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels Measuring Less Than 100 Feet.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall establish reasonable and necessary requirements to demonstrate compliance with subsections (c) and (d), with respect to vessels measuring less than 100 feet in registered length, and shall seek to minimize the administrative burden on individuals who own and operate those vessels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels Purchased Through Fishing Capacity Reduction Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A vessel purchased by the Secretary of Commerce through a fishing capacity reduction program under the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.) or section 308 22 See References in Text note below. of the Interjurisdictional Fisheries Act of 1986 (16 U.S.C. 4107) is not eligible for a fishery endorsement, and any fishery endorsement issued for that vessel is invalid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation of Endorsements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary shall revoke the fishery endorsement of any vessel subject to subsection (c) or (d) whose owner does not comply with those provisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations to implement subsections (c) and (d) and sections 12151(c) and 31322(b) of this title shall prohibit impermissible transfers of ownership or control, specify any transactions that require prior approval of an implementing agency, identify transactions that do not require prior agency approval, and to the extent practicable, minimize disruptions to the commercial fishing industry, to the traditional financing arrangements of that industry, and to the opportunity to form fishery cooperatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>