<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12119" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12119/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12119/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12119"><akn:num>12119</akn:num><akn:heading>Owners engaged primarily in leasing or financing transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12119. Owners engaged primarily in leasing or financing transactions(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Affiliate.—The term “affiliate” means, with respect to any person, any other person that is—(i) directly or indirectly controlled by, under common control with, or controlling that person; or

(ii) named as being part of the same consolidated group in any report or other document submitted to the United States Securities and Exchange Commission or the Internal Revenue Service.


(2) Cargo.—The term “cargo” does not include cargo to which title is held for non-commercial reasons and primarily for the purpose of evading the requirements of subsection (c)(3).

(3) Oil.—The term “oil” has the meaning given that term in section 2101(26) of this title.

(4) Passive investment.—The term “passive investment” means an investment in which neither the investor nor any affiliate of the investor is involved in, or has the power to be involved in, the formulation, determination, or direction of any activity or function concerning the management, use, or operation of the asset that is the subject of the investment.

(5) Qualified proprietary cargo.—The term “qualified proprietary cargo” means—(A) oil, petroleum products, petrochemicals, or liquefied natural gas cargo that is beneficially owned by the person that submits to the Secretary an application or annual certification under subsection (c)(3), or by an affiliate of that person, immediately before, during, or immediately after the cargo is carried in coastwise trade on a vessel owned by that person;

(B) oil, petroleum products, petrochemicals, or liquefied natural gas cargo not beneficially owned by the person that submits to the Secretary an application or an annual certification under subsection (c)(3), or by an affiliate of that person, but which is carried in coastwise trade by a vessel owned by that person and which is part of an arrangement in which vessels owned by that person and at least one other person are op</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12119_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12119_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A coastwise endorsement may be issued for a vessel if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12119_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ownership Certification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12119_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of Demise Charter.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The demise charter and any amendments to the charter shall be filed with the certification required by subsection (b)(3) or within 10 days after filing an amendment to the charter. The charter and amendments shall be made available to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12119_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation of Endorsement After Termination of Charter.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) When a charter required by subsection (b)(3) is terminated for default by the charterer, the Secretary may continue the coastwise endorsement for not more than 6 months on terms and conditions the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12119_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deemed Owned by Citizens.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A vessel satisfying the requirements of this section is deemed to be owned only by citizens of the United States under sections 12103 and 50501 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>