<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12139" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12139/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/12139/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12139"><akn:num>12139</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12139. Reports(a) In General.—To ensure compliance with this chapter and laws governing the qualifications of vessels to engage in the coastwise trade and the fisheries, the Secretary may require owners, masters, charterers, and mortgagees of documented vessels to submit reports in any reasonable form and manner the Secretary may prescribe.

(b) Vessels Rebuilt Outside United States.—(1) In general.—Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, if a vessel exceeding the tonnage specified in paragraph (2) and documented or last documented under the laws of the United States is rebuilt outside the United States, the owner or master shall submit a report of the rebuilding to the Secretary.

(2) Tonnage.—The tonnage referred to in paragraph (1) is—(A) 500 gross tons as measured under section 14502 of this title; or

(B) an alternate tonnage as measured under section 14302 of this title as prescribed by the Secretary under section 14104 of this title.


(3) Timing of submission.—If the rebuilding is completed in the United States, the report shall be submitted when the rebuilding is completed. If the rebuilding is completed outside the United States, the report shall be submitted when the vessel first arrives at a port in the customs territory of the United States.


(Pub. L. 109–304, § 5, Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1507; Pub. L. 109–241, title III, § 308, July 11, 2006, 120 Stat. 528; Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3525(a)(2), (b), Jan. 28, 2008, 122 Stat. 600, 601.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


12139(a)46:12120.
12139(b)46 App.:883a (1st sentence).July 14, 1956, ch. 600, § 2 (1st sentence), 70 Stat. 544; Pub. L. 86–583, § 2, July 5, 1960, 74 Stat. 321; Pub. L. 104–324, title VII, § 707, Oct. 19, 1996, 110 Stat. 3934.


In subsection (b)(1), the word “Secretary” is substituted for “Secretary of the Treasury”, thereby incorporating the definition of “Secretary” in section 2101 of title 46.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12139_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To ensure compliance with this chapter and laws governing the qualifications of vessels to engage in the coastwise trade and the fisheries, the Secretary may require owners, masters, charterers, and mortgagees of documented vessels to submit reports in any reasonable form and manner the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12139_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels Rebuilt Outside United States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>