<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/15103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/15103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/15103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15103"><akn:num>15103</akn:num><akn:heading>National Merchant Marine Personnel Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15103. National Merchant Marine Personnel Advisory Committee(a) Establishment.—There is established a National Merchant Marine Personnel Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Committee”).

(b) Function.—The Committee shall advise the Secretary on matters relating to personnel in the United States merchant marine, including the training, qualifications, certification, documentation, and fitness of mariners.

(c) Membership.—(1) In general.—The Committee shall consist of 19 members appointed by the Secretary in accordance with this section and section 15109 of this chapter.

(2) Expertise.—Each member of the Committee shall have particular expertise, knowledge, and experience in matters relating to the function of the Committee.

(3) Representation.—Members of the Committee shall be appointed as follows:(A) 9 members shall represent mariners and, of the 9—(i) each shall—(I) be a citizen of the United States; and

(II) hold an active license or certificate issued under chapter 71 of this title or a merchant mariner document issued under chapter 73 of this title;


(ii) 3 shall be deck officers who represent merchant marine deck officers and, of the 3—(I) 2 shall be licensed for oceans any gross tons;

(II) 1 shall be licensed for inland river route with a limited or unlimited tonnage;

(III) 2 shall have a master’s license or a master of towing vessels license;

(IV) 1 shall have significant tanker experience; and

(V) to the extent practicable—(aa) 1 shall represent labor; and

(bb) 1 shall represent management;



(iii) 3 shall be engineering officers who represent merchant marine engineering officers and, of the 3—(I) 2 shall be licensed as chief engineer any horsepower;

(II) 1 shall be licensed as either a limited chief engineer or a designated duty engineer; and

(III) to the extent practicable—(aa) 1 shall represent labor; and

(bb) 1 shall represent management;



(iv) 2 shall be unlicensed seamen who represent merchant marine unlicensed sea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established a National Merchant Marine Personnel Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Committee”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Function.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Committee shall advise the Secretary on matters relating to personnel in the United States merchant marine, including the training, qualifications, certification, documentation, and fitness of mariners.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>