<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/2116" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/2116/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/2116/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2116"><akn:num>2116</akn:num><akn:heading>Marine safety strategy, goals, and performance assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2116. Marine safety strategy, goals, and performance assessments(a) Long-Term Strategy and Goals.—In conjunction with existing federally required strategic planning efforts, the Secretary shall develop a long-term strategy for improving vessel safety and the safety of individuals on vessels. The 5-year strategy shall include the issuance of a plan and schedule for achieving the following goals:(1) Reducing the number and rates of marine casualties.

(2) Improving the consistency and effectiveness of vessel and operator enforcement and compliance programs.

(3) Identifying and targeting enforcement efforts at high-risk vessels and operators.

(4) Improving research efforts to enhance and promote vessel and operator safety and performance.


(b) 5-Year Strategy and Plan.—(1) Measurable goals.—The 5-year strategy and plan shall include specific numeric or measurable goals designed to achieve the goals set forth in subsection (a). The purposes of the numeric or measurable goals are the following:(A) To increase the number of safety examinations on all high-risk vessels.

(B) To eliminate the backlog of marine safety-related rulemakings.

(C) To improve the quality and effectiveness of marine safety information databases by ensuring that all Coast Guard personnel accurately and effectively report all safety, casualty, and injury information.

(D) To provide for a sufficient number of Coast Guard marine safety personnel, and provide adequate facilities and equipment to carry out the functions referred to in section 93(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 14.


(2) Resource needs.—The 5-year strategy and plan shall include estimates of—(A) the funds and staff resources needed to accomplish each activity included in the strategy and plan; and

(B) the staff skills and training needed for timely and effective accomplishment of each goal.



(c) Submission With the President’s Budget.—Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of the Elijah E. Cummi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2116_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Long-Term Strategy and Goals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In conjunction with existing federally required strategic planning efforts, the Secretary shall develop a long-term strategy for improving vessel safety and the safety of individuals on vessels. The 5-year strategy shall include the issuance of a plan and schedule for achieving the following goals:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2116_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>5-Year Strategy and Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) 5</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2116_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission With the President’s Budget.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of the Elijah E. Cummings Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2020, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress the strategy and plan not later than 60 days following the transmission of the President’s budget submission under section 1105 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2116_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Achievement of Goals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>