<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/30701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/30701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/30701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30701"><akn:num>30701</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30701. Definition
In this chapter, the term “carrier” means the owner, manager, charterer, agent, or master of a vessel.
(Pub. L. 109–304, § 6(c), Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1516.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


30701(no source).


This chapter codifies the Act of February 13, 1893 (ch. 105, 27 Stat. 445) (commonly known as the Harter Act). Changes are made to simplify, clarify, and modernize the language and style, but the intent is that these changes should not result in changes in substance.
A definition of “carrier” is added based on language appearing in various provisions of the Harter Act. The definition avoids the need to repeat in various sections of this chapter the list of persons to whom the requirements and restrictions of this chapter apply, and it ensures that the list of persons is consistent in the chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Carriage of Goods by Sea ActAct Apr. 16, 1936, ch. 229, 49 Stat. 1207, as amended by Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(146), Aug. 6, 1981, 95 Stat. 166, provided:
“That every bill of lading or similar document of title which is evidence of a contract for the carriage of goods by sea to or from ports of the United States, in foreign trade, shall have effect subject to the provisions of this Act.
“TITLE I
“Section 1. When used in this Act—
“(a) The term ‘carrier’ includes the owner or the charterer who enters into a contract of carriage with a shipper.
“(b) The term ‘contract of carriage’ applies only to contracts of carriage covered by a bill of lading or any similar document of title, insofar as such document relates to the carriage of goods by sea, including any bill of lading or any similar document as aforesaid issued under or pursuant to a charter party from the moment at which such bill of lading or similar document of title regulates the relations between a carrier and a holder of the same.
“(c) The term ‘goods’ includes goods, wares, merchan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>