<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/31322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/31322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/31322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_31322"><akn:num>31322</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferred mortgages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 31322. Preferred mortgages(a) A preferred mortgage is a mortgage, whenever made, that—(1) includes the whole of the vessel;

(2) is filed in substantial compliance with section 31321 of this title;

(3)(A) covers a documented vessel; or

(B) covers a vessel for which an application for documentation is filed that is in substantial compliance with the requirements of chapter 121 of this title and the regulations prescribed under that chapter; and


(4) with respect to a vessel with a fishery endorsement that is 100 feet or greater in registered length, has as the mortgagee—(A) a person eligible to own a vessel with a fishery endorsement under section 12113(c) of this title;

(B) a State or federally chartered financial institution that is insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;

(C) a farm credit lender established under title 12, chapter 23 of the United States Code;

(D) a commercial fishing and agriculture bank established pursuant to State law;

(E) a commercial lender organized under the laws of the United States or of a State and eligible to own a vessel for purposes of documentation under section 12103 of this title; or

(F) a mortgage trustee under subsection (f) of this section.



(b) Any indebtedness secured by a preferred mortgage that is filed or recorded under this chapter, or that is subject to a mortgage, security agreement, or instruments granting a security interest that is deemed to be a preferred mortgage under subsection (d) of this section, may have any rate of interest to which the parties agree.

(c)(1) If a preferred mortgage includes more than one vessel or property that is not a vessel, the mortgage may provide for the separate discharge of each vessel and all property not a vessel by the payment of a part of the mortgage indebtedness.

(2) If a vessel covered by a preferred mortgage that includes more than one vessel or property that is not a vessel is to be sold on the order of a district court in a civil action in rem, an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A preferred mortgage is a mortgage, whenever made, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any indebtedness secured by a preferred mortgage that is filed or recorded under this chapter, or that is subject to a mortgage, security agreement, or instruments granting a security interest that is deemed to be a preferred mortgage under subsection (d) of this section, may have any rate of interest to which the parties agree.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31322_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31322_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If a vessel is already covered by a preferred mortgage when an application for titling or documentation is filed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31322_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31322_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For purposes of this section a “commercial lender” means an entity primarily engaged in the business of lending and other financing transactions with a loan portfolio in excess of $100,000,000, of which not more than 50 per centum in dollar amount consists of loans to borrowers in the commercial fishing industry, as certified to the Secretary by such lender.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31322_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) For purposes of this section a “lender syndicate” means an arrangement established for the combined extension of credit of not less than $20,000,000 made up of four or more entities that each have a beneficial interest, held through an agent, under a trust arrangement established pursuant to subsection (f), no one of which may exercise powers thereunder without the concurrence of at least one other unaffiliated beneficiary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>