<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/40502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/40502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/40502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40502"><akn:num>40502</akn:num><akn:heading>Service contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40502. Service contracts(a) In General.—An individual ocean common carrier or an agreement between or among ocean common carriers may enter into a service contract with one or more shippers subject to the requirements of this part.

(b) Filing Requirements.—(1) In general.—Each service contract entered into under this section by an individual ocean common carrier or an agreement shall be filed confidentially with the Federal Maritime Commission.

(2) Exceptions.—Paragraph (1) does not apply to contracts regarding bulk cargo, forest products, recycled metal scrap, new assembled motor vehicles, waste paper, or paper waste.


(c) Essential Terms.—Each service contract shall include—(1) the origin and destination port ranges;

(2) the origin and destination geographic areas in the case of through intermodal movements;

(3) the commodities involved;

(4) the minimum volume or portion;

(5) the line-haul rate;

(6) the duration;

(7) service commitments;

(8) the liquidated damages for nonperformance, if any; and

(9) any other essential terms that the Federal Maritime Commission determines necessary or appropriate through a rulemaking process.


(d) Publication of Certain Terms.—When a service contract is filed confidentially with the Commission, a concise statement of the essential terms specified in paragraphs (1), (3), (4), and (6) of subsection (c) shall be published and made available to the general public in tariff format.

(e) Disclosure of Certain Terms.—(1) Definitions.—In this subsection, the terms “dock area” and “within the port area” have the same meaning and scope as in the applicable collective bargaining agreement between the requesting labor organization and the carrier.

(2) Disclosure.—An ocean common carrier that is a party to or is otherwise subject to a collective bargaining agreement with a labor organization shall, in response to a written request by the labor organization, state whether it is responsible for the following work at a dock area or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An individual ocean common carrier or an agreement between or among ocean common carriers may enter into a service contract with one or more shippers subject to the requirements of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40502_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Essential Terms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each service contract shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40502_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of Certain Terms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) When a service contract is filed confidentially with the Commission, a concise statement of the essential terms specified in paragraphs (1), (3), (4), and (6) of subsection (c) shall be published and made available to the general public in tariff format.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40502_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of Certain Terms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40502_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedy for Breach.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Unless the parties agree otherwise, the exclusive remedy for a breach of a service contract is an action in an appropriate court. The contract dispute resolution forum may not be controlled by or in any way affiliated with a controlled carrier or by the government that owns or controls the carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>