<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/40701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/40701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/40701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40701"><akn:num>40701</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40701. Rates(a) In General.—A controlled carrier may not—(1) maintain a rate or charge in a tariff or service contract, or charge or assess a rate, that is below a just and reasonable level; or

(2) establish, maintain, or enforce in a tariff or service contract a classification, rule, or regulation that results, or is likely to result, in the carriage or handling of cargo at a rate or charge that is below a just and reasonable level.


(b) Commission Prohibition.—The Federal Maritime Commission, at any time after notice and opportunity for a hearing, may prohibit the publication or use of a rate, charge, classification, rule, or regulation that a controlled carrier has failed to demonstrate is just and reasonable.

(c) Burden of Proof.—In a proceeding under this section, the burden of proof is on the controlled carrier to demonstrate that its rate, charge, classification, rule, or regulation is just and reasonable.

(d) Voidness.—A rate, charge, classification, rule, or regulation that has been suspended or prohibited by the Commission is void and its use is unlawful.

(Pub. L. 109–304, § 7, Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1535.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


4070146 App.:1708(a).Pub. L. 98–237, § 9(a), Mar. 20, 1984, 98 Stat. 76; Pub. L. 102–100, § 5(a), Aug. 17, 1991, 105 Stat. 492; Pub. L. 105–258, title I, § 108(1)–(4), Oct. 14, 1998, 112 Stat. 1908.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A controlled carrier may not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission Prohibition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Federal Maritime Commission, at any time after notice and opportunity for a hearing, may prohibit the publication or use of a rate, charge, classification, rule, or regulation that a controlled carrier has failed to demonstrate is just and reasonable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Burden of Proof.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In a proceeding under this section, the burden of proof is on the controlled carrier to demonstrate that its rate, charge, classification, rule, or regulation is just and reasonable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40701_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voidness.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A rate, charge, classification, rule, or regulation that has been suspended or prohibited by the Commission is void and its use is unlawful.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>