<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/41306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/41306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/41306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41306"><akn:num>41306</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctive relief sought by complainants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41306. Injunctive relief sought by complainants(a) In General.—After filing a complaint with the Federal Maritime Commission under section 41301 of this title, the complainant may bring a civil action in a district court of the United States to enjoin conduct in violation of this part.

(b) Venue.—The action must be brought in the judicial district in which—(1) the Commission has brought a civil action against the defendant under section 41307(a) of this title; or

(2) the defendant resides or transacts business, if the Commission has not brought such an action.


(c) Remedies by Court.—After notice to the defendant, and a showing that the standards for granting injunctive relief by courts of equity are met, the court may grant a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction for a period not to exceed 10 days after the Commission has issued an order disposing of the complaint.

(d) Attorney Fees.—A defendant prevailing in a civil action under this section shall be allowed reasonable attorney fees to be assessed and collected as part of the costs of the action.

(Pub. L. 109–304, § 7, Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1546.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


4130646 App.:1710(h)(2).Pub. L. 98–237, § 11(h)(2), Mar. 20, 1984, 98 Stat. 81.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) After filing a complaint with the Federal Maritime Commission under section 41301 of this title, the complainant may bring a civil action in a district court of the United States to enjoin conduct in violation of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venue.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The action must be brought in the judicial district in which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies by Court.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) After notice to the defendant, and a showing that the standards for granting injunctive relief by courts of equity are met, the court may grant a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction for a period not to exceed 10 days after the Commission has issued an order disposing of the complaint.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41306_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A defendant prevailing in a civil action under this section shall be allowed reasonable attorney fees to be assessed and collected as part of the costs of the action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>