<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/42503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/42503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/42503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_42503"><akn:num>42503</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 42503. Administration(a) Meetings.—The Committee shall, not less than once each year, meet at the call of the Commission or a majority of the members of the Committee.

(b) Employee Status.—A member of the Committee shall not be considered an employee of the Federal Government by reason of service on such Committee, except for the purposes of the following:(1) Chapter 81 of title 5.

(2) Chapter 171 of title 28 and any other Federal law relating to tort liability.


(c) Volunteer Services and Compensation.—(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a member of the Committee may serve on such committee on a voluntary basis without pay.

(2) No member of the Committee shall receive compensation for service on the Committee.


(d) Status of Members.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), with respect to a member of the Committee whom the Commission appoints to represent an entity or group—(A) the member is authorized to represent the interests of the applicable entity or group; and

(B) requirements under Federal law that would interfere with such representation and that apply to a special Government employee (as defined in section 202(a) of title 18), including requirements relating to employee conduct, political activities, ethics, conflicts of interest, and corruption, do not apply to the member.


(2) Exception.—Notwithstanding subsection (b), a member of the Committee shall be treated as a special Government employee for purposes of the committee service of the member if the member, without regard to service on the Committee, is a special Government employee.


(e) Service on Committee.—(1) Solicitation of nominations.—Before appointing an individual as a member of the Committee, the Commission shall publish a timely notice in the Federal Register soliciting nominations for membership on such Committee.

(2) Appointments.—(A) In general.—After considering nominations received pursuant to a notice published under paragraph (1), the Commission m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Committee shall, not less than once each year, meet at the call of the Commission or a majority of the members of the Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee Status.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A member of the Committee shall not be considered an employee of the Federal Government by reason of service on such Committee, except for the purposes of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Volunteer Services and Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service on Committee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Commission shall furnish to the Committee any staff and services considered by the Commission to be necessary for the conduct of the Committee’s functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair; Vice Chair.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subcommittees and Working Groups.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation, Advice, Reports, and Recommendations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42503_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Observers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Commission may designate a representative to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>