<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/4312" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/4312/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/4312/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4312"><akn:num>4312</akn:num><akn:heading>Engine cut-off switches</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4312. Engine cut-off switches(a) Installation Requirement.—A manufacturer, distributor, or dealer that installs propulsion machinery and associated starting controls on a covered recreational vessel shall equip such vessel with an engine cut-off switch and engine cut-off switch link that meet American Boat and Yacht Council Standard A–33, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Frank LoBiondo Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2018 (Public Law 115–282).

(b) Use Requirement.—(1) In general.—An individual operating a covered recreational vessel shall use an engine cut-off switch link while operating on plane or above displacement speed.

(2) Exceptions.—The requirement under paragraph (1) shall not apply if—(A) the main helm of the covered vessel is installed within an enclosed cabin; or

(B) the vessel does not have an engine cut-off switch and is not required to have one under subsection (a).



(c) Education on Cut-off Switches.—The Commandant of the Coast Guard, through the National Boating Safety Advisory Committee established under section 15105, may initiate a boating safety program on the use and benefits of cut-off switches for recreational vessels.

(d) Availability of Standard for Inspection.—(1) In general.—Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commandant shall transmit American Boat and Yacht Council Standard A–33, as in effect on the date of enactment of the Frank LoBiondo Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2018 (Public Law 115–282), to—(A) the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives;

(B) the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and

(C) the Coast Guard Office of Design and Engineering Standards; and

(D) the National Archives and Records Administration.


(2) Availability.—The standard submitted under paragraph (1) shall be kept on file and available for public inspection at such Coast Guard office and the National Archives and Records Admi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4312_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Installation Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A manufacturer, distributor, or dealer that installs propulsion machinery and associated starting controls on a covered recreational vessel shall equip such vessel with an engine cut-off switch and engine cut-off switch link that meet American Boat and Yacht Council Standard A–33, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the Frank LoBiondo Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2018 (Public Law 115–282).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4312_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4312_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education on Cut-off Switches.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Commandant of the Coast Guard, through the National Boating Safety Advisory Committee established under section 15105, may initiate a boating safety program on the use and benefits of cut-off switches for recreational vessels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4312_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Standard for Inspection.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4312_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>