<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/4503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/4503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/4503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4503"><akn:num>4503</akn:num><akn:heading>Fishing, fish tender, and fish processing vessel certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4503. Fishing, fish tender, and fish processing vessel certification(a) A vessel to which this subsection applies may not be operated unless the vessel—(1) meets all survey and classification requirements prescribed by the American Bureau of Shipping or another similarly qualified organization approved by the Secretary; and

(2) has on board a certificate issued by the American Bureau of Shipping or that other organization evidencing compliance with this subsection.


(b) Subsection (a) applies to a fish processing vessel to which this chapter applies that—(1) is built after July 27, 1990; or

(2) undergoes a major conversion completed after that date.


(c)(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), subsection (a) applies to a vessel to which section 4502(b) of this title applies that is at least 50 feet overall in length and is built after July 1, 2013.

(2) Subsection (a) does not apply to a fishing vessel or fish tender vessel to which section 4502(b) of this title applies, if the vessel—(A) is at least 50 feet overall in length, and not more than 180 feet overall in length as listed on the vessel’s certificate of documentation or certificate of number; and

(B)(i) is built after the date of the enactment of the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2016; and

(ii) complies with—(I) the requirements described in subsection (d); or

(II) the alternative requirements established by the Secretary under subsection (e).





(d) The requirements referred to in subsection (c)(2)(B)(ii)(I) are the following:(1) The vessel is designed by an individual licensed by a State as a naval architect or marine engineer, and the design incorporates standards equivalent to those prescribed by a classification society to which the Secretary has delegated authority under section 3316 or another qualified organization approved by the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph.

(2) Construction of the vessel is overseen and certified as being in accordance with its design by a marine surveyo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A vessel to which this subsection applies may not be operated unless the vessel—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subsection (a) applies to a fish processing vessel to which this chapter applies that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The requirements referred to in subsection (c)(2)(B)(ii)(I) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>