<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/50308" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/50308/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/50308/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50308"><akn:num>50308</akn:num><akn:heading>Maritime transportation system emergency relief program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50308. Maritime transportation system emergency relief program(a) General Authority.—The Maritime Administrator may make grants to, and enter into contracts and agreement with, eligible State and Tribal entities and eligible entities for—(1) the costs of capital projects to protect, repair, reconstruct, or replace equipment and facilities of the United States maritime transportation system that the Maritime Administrator determines is in danger of suffering serious physical damage, or has suffered serious physical damage, as a result of an emergency; and

(2) eligible operating costs of United States maritime transportation equipment and facilities in an area directly affected by an emergency during—(A) the one-year period beginning on the date of a declaration of an emergency referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (j)(4); and

(B) an additional one-year period beginning one year after the date of an emergency referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (j)(4), if the Maritime Administrator, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, determines there is a compelling need arising out of the emergency for which the declaration is made.



(b) Allocation.—(1) In general.—The Maritime Administrator shall determine an appropriate method for the equitable allocation and distribution of funds under this section to eligible State and Tribal entities and eligible entities.

(2) Priority.—To the extent practicable, in allocating and distributing funds under this section, the Maritime Administrator shall give priority to applications submitted by eligible State or Tribal entities.


(c) Applications.—An applicant for assistance under this section shall submit an application for such assistance to the Maritime Administrator at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Maritime Administrator may require.

(d) Coordination of Emergency Funds.—(1) Use of funds.—Funds appropriate</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Maritime Administrator may make grants to, and enter into contracts and agreement with, eligible State and Tribal entities and eligible entities for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An applicant for assistance under this section shall submit an application for such assistance to the Maritime Administrator at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Maritime Administrator may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of Emergency Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A grant awarded under this section that is made to address an emergency referred to in subsection (j)(4)(B) shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share of Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Federal share payable of the costs for which a grant is made under this section shall be 100 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Of the amounts available to carry out this section, not more than two percent may be used for administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quality Assurance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Maritime Administrator shall institute adequate policies, procedures, and internal controls to prevent waste, fraud, abuse, and program mismanagement for the distribution of funds under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) On an annual basis, the Maritime Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report on the financial assistance provided under this section during the year covered by the report. Each such report shall include, for such year, a description of such assistance provided and of how such assistance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50308_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>