<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/50309" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/50309/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/50309/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50309"><akn:num>50309</akn:num><akn:heading>Securing logistics information data of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50309. Securing logistics information data of the United States(a) In General.—(1) Prohibition.—A covered entity shall not use a covered logistics platform.

(2) Eligibility.—A covered entity that is found to use a covered logistics platform shall not be eligible to receive any Federal grant funding as long as the covered entity uses a covered logistics platform.


(b) Guidance.—The Secretary of Transportation shall—(1) notify covered entities of the prohibition in subsection (a) as soon as practicable, including notice of funding opportunities for grant programs; and

(2) publish on a website of the Department of Transportation, and update regularly, a list of covered logistics platforms subject to the prohibition in subsection (a).


(c) Consultation.—In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with—(1) the Secretary of Defense;

(2) the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating;

(3) the Secretary of State; and

(4) the Secretary of Commerce.


(d) Waiver.—The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, may waive the provisions of this section for a specific contract if the Secretary of Transportation—(1) makes a determination that such waiver is vital to the national security of the United States; and

(2) submits to Congress a report justifying the use of such waiver and the importance of such waiver to the national security of the United States.


(e) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Covered logistics platform.—The term “covered logistics platform” means a data exchange platform that utilizes or provides, in part or whole—(A) the national transportation logistics public information platform (commonly referred to as “LOGINK”) provided by the People’s Republic of China, or departments, ministries, centers, agencies, or instrumentalities of the Government of the People’s Republic of China;

(B) any national transportation logistics information platform provided by or sponsored by the People’s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50309_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50309_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Transportation shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50309_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50309_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, may waive the provisions of this section for a specific contract if the Secretary of Transportation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50309_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>