<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/50307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/50307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/50307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50307"><akn:num>50307</akn:num><akn:heading>Maritime environmental and technical assistance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50307. Maritime environmental and technical assistance program(a) Emerging Marine Technologies and Practices.—(1) In general.—The Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Maritime Administrator, shall engage in or support the study, research, development, assessment, and deployment of emerging marine technologies and practices related to the maritime transportation system through eligible entities.

(2) Components.—Under this subsection, the Secretary of Transportation shall identify, study, evaluate, test, demonstrate, improve, or support efforts related to, emerging marine technologies and practices to improve—(A) environmental performance to meet United States Federal and international standards and guidelines, including—(i) reducing air emissions, water emissions, or other ship discharges;

(ii) increasing fuel economy or the use of alternative fuels and alternative energy (including the use of shore power); or

(iii) controlling aquatic invasive species; or

(iv) reducing incidental vessel-generated underwater noise, such as noise from propeller cavitation or hydrodynamic flow; and


(B) the efficiency and safety of domestic maritime industries.


(3) Coordination.—Coordination with other Federal agencies or with State, local, or Tribal governments, as appropriate, under paragraph (2)(B) may include—(A) activities that are associated with the development or approval of validation and testing regimes; and

(B) certification or validation of emerging technologies or practices that demonstrate significant environmental or other benefits to domestic maritime industries.


(4) Assistance.—The Secretary of Transportation may accept gifts, or enter into cooperative agreements, contracts, or other agreements with eligible entities to carry out the activities authorized under this subsection.

(5) Grants.—Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Maritime Administrator, may establish and carry out a competitive grant program to award grants to eligible</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emerging Marine Technologies and Practices.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The results of activities conducted under this section shall be used to inform—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities carried out under a grant or cooperative agreement made under this section may be conducted on public vessels under the control of the Maritime Administration, upon approval of the Maritime Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Entity Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Center for Maritime Innovation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>