<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_51307"><akn:num>51307</akn:num><akn:heading>Places of training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 51307. Places of training(a) In General.—The Secretary of Transportation may provide for the training of cadets at the United States Merchant Marine Academy—(1) on vessels owned, subsidized by, or contracted with the United States Government;

(2) on other documented vessels, with the permission of the owner;

(3) in shipyards or plants and with industrial or educational organizations; and

(4) on any other vessel considered by the Secretary to be necessary or appropriate or in the national interest.


(b) Sea Year Cadets on Certain Vessels.—(1) Requirements.—The Secretary shall require an operator of a vessel participating in the Maritime Security Program under chapter 531 of this title, the Cable Security Fleet under chapter 532 of this title, or the Tanker Security Fleet under chapter 534 of this title to—(A) carry on each Maritime Security Program vessel, Cable Security Fleet vessel, or Tanker Security Fleet vessel 2 United States Merchant Marine Academy cadets, if available, on each voyage; and

(B) implement and adhere to policies, programs, criteria, and requirements established pursuant to section 51322 of this title.


(2) Failure to implement or adhere to requirements.—Failure to implement or adhere to the policies, programs, criteria, and requirements referred to in paragraph (1) may, as determined by the Maritime Administrator, constitute a violation of an operating agreement entered into under chapter 531, 532, or 534 of this title and the Maritime Administrator may—(A) require the operator to take corrective actions; or

(B) withhold payment due to the operator until the violation, as determined by the Maritime Administrator, has been remedied.


(3) Withheld payments.—Any payment withheld pursuant to paragraph (2)(B) may be paid, upon a determination by the Maritime Administrator that the operator is in compliance with the policies, programs, criteria, and requirements referred to in paragraph (1).


(c) Military Sealift Command Vessels.—(1) In gene</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation may provide for the training of cadets at the United States Merchant Marine Academy—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sea Year Cadets on Certain Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military Sealift Command Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of Operator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section, the term “operator” includes a government operator and a non-government operator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings Clause.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nothing in this section may be construed as affecting—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>