<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_51302"><akn:num>51302</akn:num><akn:heading>Nomination and competitive appointment of cadets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 51302. Nomination and competitive appointment of cadets(a) Requirements.—An individual may be nominated for a competitive appointment as a cadet at the United States Merchant Marine Academy only if the individual—(1) is a citizen or national of the United States; and

(2) meets the minimum requirements that the Secretary of Transportation shall establish.


(b) Nominators.—Nominations for competitive appointments for the positions allocated under subsection (c) may be made as follows:(1) A Senator may nominate residents of the State represented by that Senator.

(2) A Member of the House of Representatives may nominate residents of the State in which the congressional district represented by that Member is located.

(3) A Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, or American Samoa may nominate residents of the jurisdiction represented by that Delegate.

(4) The Resident Commissioner to the United States from Puerto Rico may nominate residents of Puerto Rico.

(5) The Panama Canal Commission may nominate—(A) residents, or sons or daughters of residents, of an area or installation in Panama and made available to the United States under the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977, the agreements relating to and implementing that Treaty, signed September 7, 1977, and the Agreement Between the United States of America and the Republic of Panama Concerning Air Traffic Control and Related Services, concluded January 8, 1979; and

(B) sons or daughters of personnel of the United States Government and the Panama Canal Commission residing in Panama.



(c) Allocation of Positions.—Positions for competitive appointments shall be allocated each year as follows:(1) Positions shall be allocated for residents of each State nominated by the Members of Congress from that State in proportion to the representation in Congress from that State.

(2) Four positions shall be allocated for residents of the District</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An individual may be nominated for a competitive appointment as a cadet at the United States Merchant Marine Academy only if the individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nominators.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nominations for competitive appointments for the positions allocated under subsection (c) may be made as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of Positions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Positions for competitive appointments shall be allocated each year as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive System for Appointment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Notification in Advance of Appointments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) When a nominee of a Senator, Representative, or Delegate is selected for appointment as a cadet, the Senator, Representative, or Delegate shall be notified at least 48 hours before the official notification or announcement of the appointment is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>