<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51312" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51312/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51312/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_51312"><akn:num>51312</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Visitors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 51312. Board of Visitors(a) In General.—There shall be a Board of Visitors to the United States Merchant Marine Academy (referred to in this section as the “Board” and the “Academy”, respectively) to provide independent advice and recommendations on matters relating to the United States Merchant Marine Academy.

(b) Membership.—(1) In general.—The Board shall be composed of—(A) 2 Senators appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate in consultation with the ranking member of such Committee;

(B) 3 Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives in consultation with the ranking member of such Committee;

(C) 1 Senator appointed by the Vice President, who shall be a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;

(D) 2 Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Minority Leader, at least 1 of whom shall be a member of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;

(E) 5 individuals appointed by the President; and

(F) as ex officio members—(i) the Commander of the Military Sealift Command;

(ii) the Deputy Commandant for Operations of the Coast Guard;

(iii) the chairman of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;

(iv) the chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;

(v) the chairman of the Advisory Board to the Academy established under section 51313; and

(vi) the Member of the House of Representatives for the congressional district in which the Academy is located, as a nonvoting member, unless such Member of the House of Representatives is appointed as a voting member of the Board under subparagraph (B) or (D).



(2) Presidential appointees.—Of the individuals appointed by the President under paragraph (1)(E)—(A) at least 2 shall be graduates of the Academy;
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There shall be a Board of Visitors to the United States Merchant Marine Academy (referred to in this section as the “Board” and the “Academy”, respectively) to provide independent advice and recommendations on matters relating to the United States Merchant Marine Academy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Visiting the Academy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Board shall inquire into the state of morale and discipline, the curriculum, instruction, physical equipment, fiscal affairs, and academic methods of the Academy, and other matters relating to the Academy that the Board decides to consider.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Transportation Support.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Transportation shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Each of the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives may designate staff members of such Committee to serve, without additional reimbursement (except as provided in subsection (i)), as staff for the Board. Such staff may attend meetings and may visit the Academy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) While serving away from his or her home or regular place of business, a member of the Board or a staff member designated under subsection (h) shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized under section 5703 of title 5, United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51312_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>