<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_51322"><akn:num>51322</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of cadets from sexual assault onboard vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 51322. Protection of cadets from sexual assault onboard vessels(a) Safety Criteria.—The Maritime Administrator, after consulting with the Commandant of the Coast Guard, shall establish—(1) criteria, to which an owner or operator of a vessel engaged in commercial service shall adhere prior to carrying a cadet performing their Sea Year service from the United States Merchant Marine Academy, that addresses prevention of, and response to, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and

(2) a process for collecting pertinent information from such owners or operators and verifying their compliance with the criteria.

(3) Training.—(A) In general.—As part of training that shall be provided not less than semiannually to all midshipmen of the Academy, pursuant to section 51318, the Maritime Administrator shall develop and implement comprehensive in-person sexual assault risk-reduction and response training that, to the extent practicable, conforms to best practices in the sexual assault prevention and response field and includes appropriate scenario-based training.

(B) Development and consultation with experts.—In developing the sexual assault risk-reduction and response training under subparagraph (A), the Maritime Administrator shall consult with and incorporate, as appropriate, the recommendations and views of experts in the sexual assault field.



(b) Minimum Standards.—At a minimum, the criteria established under subsection (a) shall require the vessel owners or operators to have policies that address—(1) communication between a cadet and an individual ashore who is trained in responding to incidents of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking;

(2) the safety and security of cadet staterooms while a cadet is onboard the vessel;

(3) requirements for crew to report complaints or incidents of sexual assault, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, and stalking consiste</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safety Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Maritime Administrator, after consulting with the Commandant of the Coast Guard, shall establish—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) At a minimum, the criteria established under subsection (a) shall require the vessel owners or operators to have policies that address—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-certification by Owners or Operators.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Maritime Administrator shall require the owner or operator of any commercial vessel that is carrying a cadet from the United States Merchant Marine Academy to annually certify that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51322_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information, Training, and Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Maritime Administrator shall ensure that a cadet participating in Sea Year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51322_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Checks of Commercial Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51322_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of Sexual Assault Training Records.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Maritime Administrator shall require the owner or operator of a commercial vessel, and the seafarer union for a commercial vessel, to maintain records of sexual assault training for any person required to have such training.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51322_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sea Year Survey.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51322_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncommercial Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51322_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of Best Practices.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Maritime Administrator shall share with State maritime academies best practices for, and lessons learned with respect to, the prevention of, and response to, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>