<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51509" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51509/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/51509/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_51509"><akn:num>51509</akn:num><akn:heading>Student incentive payment agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 51509. Student incentive payment agreements(a) General Authority.—If a State maritime academy has an agreement with the Secretary of Transportation under section 51505 of this title, the Secretary may make an agreement with a student at the academy who is a citizen of the United States to make student incentive payments to the individual. An agreement with a student may not be effective for more than 4 academic years. The Secretary shall allocate payments under this section among the various State maritime academies in an equitable manner.

(b) Payments.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), payments under an agreement under this section shall be equal to $16,000 each academic year and be paid in such installments as the Secretary shall determine while the individual is attending the academy, as prescribed by the Secretary.

(2) Exception.—The Secretary may modify the payments made to an individual under paragraph (1), but the total amount of payments to that individual may not exceed $64,000.

(3) Authorized uses.—The payments shall be used for uniforms, tuition, books, and subsistence.


(c) Enlisted Reserve Status.—An agreement under this section shall require the student to accept enlisted reserve status in the Navy Reserve (including the Strategic Sealift Officer Program, Navy Reserve) or the Coast Guard Reserve before receiving any payments under the agreement.

(d) Agreement Requirements.—An agreement under this section shall require the student to—(1) complete the course of instruction at the academy the individual is attending;

(2) obtain a merchant mariner license, without limitation as to tonnage or horsepower, from the Coast Guard as an officer in the merchant marine of the United States, accompanied by the appropriate national and international endorsements and certification required by the Coast Guard for service aboard vessels on domestic and international voyages, without limitation, within three months of completion of the course o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51509_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) If a State maritime academy has an agreement with the Secretary of Transportation under section 51505 of this title, the Secretary may make an agreement with a student at the academy who is a citizen of the United States to make student incentive payments to the individual. An agreement with a student may not be effective for more than 4 academic years. The Secretary shall allocate payments under this section among the various State maritime academies in an equitable manner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51509_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51509_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enlisted Reserve Status.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An agreement under this section shall require the student to accept enlisted reserve status in the Navy Reserve (including the Strategic Sealift Officer Program, Navy Reserve) or the Coast Guard Reserve before receiving any payments under the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51509_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An agreement under this section shall require the student to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51509_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure To Complete Course of Instruction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51509_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure To Carry Out Other Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51509_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions To Recover Cost.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) To aid in the recovery of the cost of education provided by the Government under a commitment agreement under this section, the Secretary of Transportation may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51509_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51509_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Age Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary may make an agreement under this section only with a qualified student who will meet the age requirement for enlistment or commission in the Navy Reserve at the time of graduation from the academy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>