<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_53102"><akn:num>53102</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Maritime Security Fleet</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 53102. Establishment of Maritime Security Fleet(a) In General.—The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall establish a fleet of active, commercially viable, militarily useful, privately owned vessels to meet national defense and other security requirements and maintain a United States presence in international commercial shipping. The Fleet shall consist of privately owned, United States-documented vessels for which there are in effect operating agreements under this chapter, and shall be known as the Maritime Security Fleet.

(b) Vessel Eligibility.—A vessel is eligible to be included in the Fleet if—(1) the vessel meets the requirements of paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (c);

(2) the vessel is operated (or in the case of a vessel to be constructed, will be operated) in providing transportation in foreign commerce;

(3) the vessel is self-propelled and—(A) is a tank vessel that is 10 years of age or less on the date the vessel is included in the Fleet; or

(B) is any other type of vessel that is 15 years of age or less on the date the vessel is included in the Fleet;


(4) the vessel—(A) is suitable for use by the United States for national defense or military purposes in time of war or national emergency, as determined by the Secretary of Defense; and

(B) is commercially viable, as determined by the Secretary; and


(5) the vessel—(A) is a United States-documented vessel; or

(B) is not a United States-documented vessel, but—(i) the owner of the vessel has demonstrated an intent to have the vessel documented under chapter 121 of this title if it is included in the Fleet; and

(ii) at the time an operating agreement for the vessel is entered into under this chapter, the vessel is eligible for documentation under chapter 121 of this title.




(c) Requirements Regarding Citizenship of Owners, Charterers, and Operators.—(1) Vessel owned and operated by section 50501 citizens.—A vessel meets the requirements </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall establish a fleet of active, commercially viable, militarily useful, privately owned vessels to meet national defense and other security requirements and maintain a United States presence in international commercial shipping. The Fleet shall consist of privately owned, United States-documented vessels for which there are in effect operating agreements under this chapter, and shall be known as the Maritime Security Fleet.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessel Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A vessel is eligible to be included in the Fleet if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements Regarding Citizenship of Owners, Charterers, and Operators.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request by Secretary of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Defense shall request the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue any waiver under section 501 of this title that is necessary for purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53102_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessel Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53102_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Waive Age Restriction for Eligibility of a Vessel To Be Included in Fleet.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense, in conjunction with the Secretary of Transportation, may waive the application of an age restriction under subsection (b)(3) if the Secretaries jointly determine that the waiver—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53102_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Extend Maximum Service Age for Vessel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Defense, in conjunction with the Secretary of Transportation, may, for a particular participating fleet vessel, treat the ages specified in section 53101(5)(A)(ii) and section 53106(c)(3) as increased by up to 5 years if the Secretaries jointly determine that it is in the national interest to do so.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>