<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_53402"><akn:num>53402</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Tanker Security Fleet</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 53402. Establishment of the Tanker Security Fleet(a) In General.—The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall establish a fleet of active, commercially viable, militarily useful, privately owned product tank vessels to meet national defense and other security requirements and maintain a United States presence in international commercial shipping. The fleet shall consist of privately owned vessels of the United States for which there are in effect operating agreements under this chapter, and shall be known as the “Tanker Security Fleet” (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Fleet”).

(b) Vessel Eligibility.—A vessel is eligible to be included in the Fleet if the vessel—(1) meets the requirements under paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (c);

(2) is operated (or in the case of a vessel to be constructed, will be operated) in providing transportation in United States foreign commerce;

(3) is self-propelled;

(4) is not more than 10 years of age on the date the vessel is first included in the Fleet;

(5) is determined by the Secretary of Defense to be suitable for use by the United States for national defense or military purposes in time of war or national emergency;

(6) is commercially viable, as determined by the Secretary of Transportation; and

(7) is—(A) a vessel of the United States; or

(B) not a vessel of the United States, but—(i) the owner of the vessel has demonstrated an intent to have the vessel documented under chapter 121 of this title if it is included in the Fleet; and

(ii) at the time an operating agreement is entered into under this chapter, the vessel is eligible for documentation under chapter 121 of this title.




(c) Requirements Regarding Citizenship of Owners, Charterers, and Operators.—(1) Vessels owned and operated by section 50501 citizens.—A vessel meets the requirements of this paragraph if, during the period of an operating agreement under this chapter that applies to the v</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall establish a fleet of active, commercially viable, militarily useful, privately owned product tank vessels to meet national defense and other security requirements and maintain a United States presence in international commercial shipping. The fleet shall consist of privately owned vessels of the United States for which there are in effect operating agreements under this chapter, and shall be known as the “Tanker Security Fleet” (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Fleet”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessel Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A vessel is eligible to be included in the Fleet if the vessel—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements Regarding Citizenship of Owners, Charterers, and Operators.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request by Secretary of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Defense shall request that the Secretary of Homeland Security issue any waiver under section 501 of this title that the Secretary of Defense determines is necessary for purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessel Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>