<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53517" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53517/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53517/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_53517"><akn:num>53517</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 53517. Reports(a) In General.—Within 120 days after the close of each calendar year, the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of Commerce each shall provide the Secretary of the Treasury a written report on the capital construction funds under the particular Secretary’s jurisdiction for the calendar year.

(b) Contents.—The report shall state the name and taxpayer identification number of each person—(1) establishing a capital construction fund during the calendar year;

(2) maintaining a capital construction fund on the last day of the calendar year;

(3) terminating a capital construction fund during the calendar year;

(4) making a deposit to or withdrawal from a capital construction fund during the calendar year, and the amount of the deposit or withdrawal; or

(5) having been determined during the calendar year to have failed to fulfill a substantial obligation under a capital construction fund agreement to which the person is a party.


(Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c), Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1600.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


5351746 App.:1177(m).June 29, 1936, ch. 858, title VI, § 607(m), as added Pub. L. 99–514, § 261(d), Oct. 22, 1986, 100 Stat. 2214.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53517_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Within 120 days after the close of each calendar year, the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of Commerce each shall provide the Secretary of the Treasury a written report on the capital construction funds under the particular Secretary’s jurisdiction for the calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53517_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The report shall state the name and taxpayer identification number of each person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>