<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_53701"><akn:num>53701</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 53701. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Actual cost.—The term “actual cost” means the sum of—(A) all amounts paid by or for the account of the obligor as of the date on which a determination is made under section 53715(d)(1) of this title; and

(B) all amounts that the Secretary or Administrator reasonably estimates the obligor will become obligated to pay from time to time thereafter, for the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of the vessel, including guarantee fees that will become payable under section 53714 of this title in connection with all obligations issued for construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of the vessel or equipment to be delivered, and all obligations issued for the delivered vessel or equipment.


(2) Administrator.—The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Maritime Administration.

(3) Construction, reconstruction, and reconditioning.—The terms “construction”, “reconstruction”, and “reconditioning” include designing, inspecting, outfitting, and equipping.

(4) Depreciated actual cost.—The term “depreciated actual cost” of a vessel means—(A) if the vessel was not reconstructed or reconditioned, the actual cost of the vessel depreciated on a straight line basis over the useful life of the vessel as determined by the Secretary or Administrator, not to exceed 25 years from the date of delivery by the builder; or

(B) if the vessel was reconstructed or reconditioned, the sum of—(i) the actual cost of the vessel depreciated on a straight line basis from the date of delivery by the builder to the date of the reconstruction or reconditioning, using the original useful life of the vessel, and from the date of the reconstruction or reconditioning, using a useful life of the vessel determined by the Secretary or Administrator; and

(ii) any amount paid or obligated to be paid for the reconstruction or reconditioning, depreciated on a straight line basis using a useful life of the vessel determined by the Secretary or A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actual cost.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “actual cost” means the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Maritime Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction, reconstruction, and reconditioning.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The terms “construction”, “reconstruction”, and “reconditioning” include designing, inspecting, outfitting, and equipping.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Depreciated actual cost.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “depreciated actual cost” of a vessel means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fishery facility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fishing vessel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “fishing vessel” has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1802), and any reference in this chapter to a vessel designed principally for commercial use in the fishing trade or industry is deemed to be a reference to a fishing vessel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Historical uses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “historical uses” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “mortgage” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “obligation” means an instrument of indebtedness issued for a purpose described in section 53706 of this title, except—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53701_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “obligee” means the holder of an obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>