<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53712" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53712/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53712/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_53712"><akn:num>53712</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring financial condition and operations of obligor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 53712. Monitoring financial condition and operations of obligor(a) In General.—The Secretary or Administrator shall monitor the financial condition and operations of the obligor on a regular basis during the term of the guarantee. The Secretary or Administrator shall document the results of the monitoring on an annual or quarterly basis depending on the condition of the obligor. If the Secretary or Administrator determines that the financial condition of the obligor warrants additional protections to the Secretary or Administrator, the Secretary or Administrator shall take appropriate action under subsection (b). If the Secretary or Administrator determines that the financial condition of the obligor jeopardizes its continued ability to perform its responsibilities in connection with the guarantee of an obligation by the Secretary or Administrator, the Secretary or Administrator shall make an immediate determination whether default should take place and whether further measures described in subsection (b) should be taken to protect the interests of the Secretary or Administrator while ensuring that program objectives are met.

(b) Contract Provisions To Protect Secretary or Administrator.—The Secretary or Administrator shall include provisions in a loan agreement with an obligor that provides additional authority to the Secretary or Administrator to take action to limit potential losses in connection with a defaulted loan or a loan that is in jeopardy due to the deteriorating financial condition of the obligor. If the Secretary or Administrator has waived a requirement under section 53707(d) of this title, the loan agreement shall include requirements for additional payments, collateral, or equity contributions to meet the waived requirement upon the occurrence of verifiable conditions indicating that the obligor’s financial condition enables the obligor to meet the waived requirement.

(Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c), Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1612; Pub. L. 109–163, div. </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53712_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary or Administrator shall monitor the financial condition and operations of the obligor on a regular basis during the term of the guarantee. The Secretary or Administrator shall document the results of the monitoring on an annual or quarterly basis depending on the condition of the obligor. If the Secretary or Administrator determines that the financial condition of the obligor warrants additional protections to the Secretary or Administrator, the Secretary or Administrator shall take appropriate action under subsection (b). If the Secretary or Administrator determines that the financial condition of the obligor jeopardizes its continued ability to perform its responsibilities in connection with the guarantee of an obligation by the Secretary or Administrator, the Secretary or Administrator shall make an immediate determination whether default should take place and whether further measures described in subsection (b) should be taken to protect the interests of the Secret</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53712_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract Provisions To Protect Secretary or Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary or Administrator shall include provisions in a loan agreement with an obligor that provides additional authority to the Secretary or Administrator to take action to limit potential losses in connection with a defaulted loan or a loan that is in jeopardy due to the deteriorating financial condition of the obligor. If the Secretary or Administrator has waived a requirement under section 53707(d) of this title, the loan agreement shall include requirements for additional payments, collateral, or equity contributions to meet the waived requirement upon the occurrence of verifiable conditions indicating that the obligor’s financial condition enables the obligor to meet the waived requirement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>