<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53731" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53731/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/53731/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_53731"><akn:num>53731</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial demonstration ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 53731. Commercial demonstration ocean thermal energy conversion facilities and plantships(a) In General.—Under subchapter I of this chapter, the Administrator may guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee the payment of the principal of and interest on an obligation that aids in financing (including reimbursement of an obligor for expenditures previously made for) the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a commercial demonstration ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship. This section may be used to guarantee obligations for a total of not more than 5 separate facilities and plantships or a demonstrated 400 megawatt capacity, whichever comes first.

(b) Applicability of Other Provisions.—Except as otherwise provided in this section, a guarantee or commitment to guarantee under this section is subject to all the provisions applicable to a guarantee or commitment to guarantee under subchapter I of this chapter.

(c) Economic Soundness.—The required determination of economic soundness under section 53708 of this title applies to a guarantee or commitment to guarantee for that portion of a facility or plantship not to be supported with appropriated Federal funds.

(d) Reasonableness of Risk.—A guarantee or commitment to guarantee may not be made under this section unless the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator, certifies to the Administrator that, for the facility or plantship for which the guarantee or commitment to guarantee is sought, there is sufficient guarantee of performance and payment to lower the risk to the United States Government to a reasonable level. In deciding whether to issue such a certification, the Secretary of Energy shall consider—(1) the successful demonstration of the technology to be used in the facility at a scale sufficient to establish the likelihood of technical and economic viability in the proposed market; and

(2) the need of the United States to develop new and renewable sources of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53731_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under subchapter I of this chapter, the Administrator may guarantee or make a commitment to guarantee the payment of the principal of and interest on an obligation that aids in financing (including reimbursement of an obligor for expenditures previously made for) the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a commercial demonstration ocean thermal energy conversion facility or plantship. This section may be used to guarantee obligations for a total of not more than 5 separate facilities and plantships or a demonstrated 400 megawatt capacity, whichever comes first.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53731_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Other Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as otherwise provided in this section, a guarantee or commitment to guarantee under this section is subject to all the provisions applicable to a guarantee or commitment to guarantee under subchapter I of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53731_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic Soundness.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The required determination of economic soundness under section 53708 of this title applies to a guarantee or commitment to guarantee for that portion of a facility or plantship not to be supported with appropriated Federal funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53731_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonableness of Risk.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A guarantee or commitment to guarantee may not be made under this section unless the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator, certifies to the Administrator that, for the facility or plantship for which the guarantee or commitment to guarantee is sought, there is sufficient guarantee of performance and payment to lower the risk to the United States Government to a reasonable level. In deciding whether to issue such a certification, the Secretary of Energy shall consider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53731_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of Obligation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The total principal amount of an obligation guaranteed under this section may not exceed 87.5 percent of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53731_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>OTEC Demonstration Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53731_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance and Payment of Obligations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Section 53723 of this title applies to the OTEC Demonstration Fund. However, obligations issued by the Administrator under that section related to the OTEC Demonstration Fund shall be payable only from proceeds realized by the OTEC Demonstration Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_53731_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxation of Interest.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Interest on an obligation guaranteed under this section shall be included in gross income under chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (26 U.S.C. ch. 1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>