<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/55108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/55108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/55108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_55108"><akn:num>55108</akn:num><akn:heading>Platform jackets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 55108. Platform jackets(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Coastwise qualified vessel.—The term “coastwise qualified vessel” means a vessel that has been issued a certificate of documentation with a coastwise endorsement under chapter 121 of this title.

(2) Platform jacket.—The term “platform jacket” refers to a single physical component and includes any type of offshore exploration, development, or production structure or component thereof, including—(A) platform jackets;

(B) tension leg or SPAR platform superstructures (including the deck, drilling rig and support utilities, and supporting structure);

(C) hull (including vertical legs and connecting pontoons or vertical cylinder);

(D) tower and base sections of a platform jacket;

(E) jacket structures; and

(F) deck modules (known as “topsides”).



(b) Authorized Transportation.—Section 55102 of this title does not apply to the transportation of a platform jacket in or on a non-coastwise qualified launch barge between two points in the United States, at one of which there is an installation or other device within the meaning of section 4(a) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (43 U.S.C. 1333(a)), if—(1) the launch barge was built before December 31, 2000, and has a launch capacity of at least 12,000 long tons; and

(2) the Secretary of Transportation makes a determination, in accordance with procedures established under subsection (c), that a suitable coastwise qualified vessel is not available for use in the transportation and, if needed, launch or installation of a platform jacket.


(c) Procedures To Maximize Use of Coastwise Qualified Vessels.—The Secretary of Transportation shall adopt procedures implementing this section that are reasonably designed to provide timely information so as to maximize the use of coastwise qualified vessels. The procedures shall, among other things, establish that for purposes of this section, a coastwise qualified vessel shall be deemed to be not available only if—(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_55108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_55108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Section 55102 of this title does not apply to the transportation of a platform jacket in or on a non-coastwise qualified launch barge between two points in the United States, at one of which there is an installation or other device within the meaning of section 4(a) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (43 U.S.C. 1333(a)), if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_55108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures To Maximize Use of Coastwise Qualified Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Transportation shall adopt procedures implementing this section that are reasonably designed to provide timely information so as to maximize the use of coastwise qualified vessels. The procedures shall, among other things, establish that for purposes of this section, a coastwise qualified vessel shall be deemed to be not available only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>