<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/57502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/57502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/57502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_57502"><akn:num>57502</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction, reconditioning, and remodeling of vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 57502. Construction, reconditioning, and remodeling of vessels(a) In General.—The Secretary of Transportation may have new vessels constructed, and have old vessels reconditioned or remodeled, as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the objectives of this subtitle.

(b) Place of Work.—Construction, reconditioning, and remodeling of vessels under subsection (a) shall take place in shipyards in the continental United States (including Alaska and Hawaii). However, if satisfactory contracts cannot be obtained from private shipbuilders, the Secretary may have the work done in navy yards.

(c) Applicability of Construction-Differential Subsidy Provisions.—Contracts for the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a vessel by a private shipbuilder under this chapter are subject to the provisions of title V of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, applicable to a contract with a private shipbuilder for the construction of a vessel under title V of that Act.

(Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c), Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1664.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


57502(a), (b)46 App.:1192.June 29, 1936, ch. 858, title VII, § 702, 49 Stat. 2008; Pub. L. 85–191, Aug. 28, 1957, 71 Stat. 471; Pub. L. 86–624, § 35(c), July 12, 1960, 74 Stat. 421; Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(104), Aug. 6, 1981, 95 Stat. 162.
57502(c)46 App.:1193(b).June 29, 1936, ch. 858, title VII, § 703(b), 49 Stat. 2008.


In subsection (b), the words “for such new construction or reconstruction, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter” are omitted as unnecessary.

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Merchant Marine Act, 1936, referred to in subsec. (c), is act June 29, 1936, ch. 858, 49 Stat. 1985. Title V of the Act enacted provisions set out as notes under section 53101 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1936 Amendment note set out under section 101 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation may have new vessels constructed, and have old vessels reconditioned or remodeled, as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the objectives of this subtitle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Place of Work.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Construction, reconditioning, and remodeling of vessels under subsection (a) shall take place in shipyards in the continental United States (including Alaska and Hawaii). However, if satisfactory contracts cannot be obtained from private shipbuilders, the Secretary may have the work done in navy yards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_57502_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Construction-Differential Subsidy Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contracts for the construction, reconstruction, or reconditioning of a vessel by a private shipbuilder under this chapter are subject to the provisions of title V of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, applicable to a contract with a private shipbuilder for the construction of a vessel under title V of that Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>