<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/57513" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/57513/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/57513/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_57513"><akn:num>57513</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum bid</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 57513. Minimum bid
The Secretary of Transportation shall reject any bid for the charter under this subchapter of a vessel constructed under this subtitle or the Merchant Marine Act, 1936, if the charter hire offered is lower than the minimum charter hire would be if the vessel were chartered under section 57531 of this title.
(Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c), Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1666.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


5751346 App.:1196(b) (last sentence).June 29, 1936, ch. 858, title VII, § 706(b) (last sentence), as added Aug. 4, 1939, ch. 417, § 11(b), 53 Stat. 1186; Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(108), Aug. 6, 1981, 95 Stat. 163.



Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Merchant Marine Act, 1936, referred to in text, is act June 29, 1936, ch. 858, 49 Stat. 1985, which was classified principally to chapter 27 (§ 1101 et seq.) of the former Appendix to this title. The Act, with the exception of title V, most of title VI, and sections 301, 801, 802, 809(a), and 909 thereof, was repealed and restated, mainly in this subtitle, by Pub. L. 109–304, §§ 8, 19, Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1555, 1710. Title V and sections 301 and 909 of the Act are set out as notes under section 53101 of this title. Those portions of title VI not repealed by Pub. L. 109–304 and sections 802 and 809(a) of the Act were repealed by Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 313(a), Feb. 8, 2016, 130 Stat. 58. Section 801 of the Act was transferred to section 57522 of this title by Pub. L. 114–120, title III, § 313(c)(1)(A), Feb. 8, 2016, 130 Stat. 58. For complete classification of the Act to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of sections of the former Appendix to Title 46, see Disposition Table preceding section 101 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>