<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/58109" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/58109/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/58109/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_58109"><akn:num>58109</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 58109. Penalties(a) Individuals.—An individual convicted of violating section 58101(d), 58103, or 58105 of this title shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for at least one year but not more than 5 years, or both.

(b) Organizations.—An organization convicted of committing an act prohibited by this subtitle shall be fined under title 18.

(c) Ineligibility To Receive Benefits.—An individual or organization convicted of violating a section referred to in subsection (a) is ineligible, at the discretion of the Secretary of Transportation, to receive any benefit under the construction-differential subsidy or operating-differential subsidy programs, or a charter under chapter 575 of this title, for 5 years after the conviction.

(Pub. L. 109–304, § 8(c), Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1673.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


5810946 App.:1228 (1st, 2d pars.).June 29, 1936, ch. 858, title VIII, § 806(b), (c), 49 Stat. 2014; Pub. L. 97–31, § 12(125), Aug. 6, 1981, 95 Stat. 164.


In subsection (a), the word “individual” is substituted for “natural person” for consistency in the revised title. The words “convicted of violating section 58101(d), 58103, or 58105 of this title” are substituted for “found guilty of any act or acts declared in this chapter to constitute a misdemeanor” because the sections referred to restate the provisions which declare certain acts to be misdemeanors and because the restatement of those provisions does not use the word “misdemeanor”. The words “in any district court of the United States” are omitted as unnecessary. The words “shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for at least one year but not more than five years, or both” are substituted for “shall be punished by a fine of not more than $10,000, or by imprisonment for not less than one year or more than five years, or by both fine and imprisonment” because of chapter 227 of title 18. See 18 U.S.C. 3559 (which classifies o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58109_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An individual convicted of violating section 58101(d), 58103, or 58105 of this title shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned for at least one year but not more than 5 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58109_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organizations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An organization convicted of committing an act prohibited by this subtitle shall be fined under title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_58109_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility To Receive Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An individual or organization convicted of violating a section referred to in subsection (a) is ineligible, at the discretion of the Secretary of Transportation, to receive any benefit under the construction-differential subsidy or operating-differential subsidy programs, or a charter under chapter 575 of this title, for 5 years after the conviction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>