<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/60502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/60502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/60502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60502"><akn:num>60502</akn:num><akn:heading>Discriminating duty on goods imported in foreign vessels or from contiguous countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60502. Discriminating duty on goods imported in foreign vessels or from contiguous countries(a) Imposition of Duty.—A discriminating duty of 10 percent ad valorem (in addition to other duties imposed by law) is imposed on goods—(1) imported in a vessel not of the United States unless the vessel—(A) is entitled by law or treaty to enter the ports of the United States on payment of the same duties as are payable on goods imported in a vessel of the United States; or

(B)(i) is owned only by citizens of the United States; and

(ii) after entering a port of the United States, becomes documented as a vessel of the United States before leaving that port; or



(2) produced or manufactured in a foreign country not contiguous to the United States and imported from a country contiguous to the United States, unless imported in the usual course of strictly retail trade.


(b) Seizure and Forfeiture.—If goods are imported without payment of the duty required by this section, the goods and the vessel in which they are imported may be seized by, and forfeited to, the United States Government.

(Pub. L. 109–304, § 9(b), Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1680.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


60502(a)19:128.Oct. 3, 1913, ch. 16, § IV(J)(1), 38 Stat. 196; Mar. 15, 1915, ch. 171, § 1, 38 Stat. 1193; Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 689(a)(1), Dec. 8, 1993, 107 Stat. 2222.
 46 App.:146.
60502(b)19:130 (last sentence related to 19:128).Oct. 3, 1913, ch. 16, § IV(J)(2), 38 Stat. 196.


In this section, the word “goods” is substituted for “goods, wares, or merchandise” to eliminate unnecessary words.
In subsection (a)(1), subparagraphs (A) and (B) are substituted for “but this discriminating duty shall not apply to goods, wares, or merchandise which shall be imported in vessels not of the United States entitled at the time of such importation by treaty or convention or Act of Congress to be entered in the ports of the United Sta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of Duty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A discriminating duty of 10 percent ad valorem (in addition to other duties imposed by law) is imposed on goods—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seizure and Forfeiture.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If goods are imported without payment of the duty required by this section, the goods and the vessel in which they are imported may be seized by, and forfeited to, the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>