<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70003" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70003/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70003/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70003"><akn:num>70003</akn:num><akn:heading>Port access routes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70003. Port access routes(a) Authority To Designate.—Except as provided in subsection (b) and subject to the requirements of subsection (c), in order to provide safe access routes for the movement of vessel traffic proceeding to or from ports or places subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, the Secretary shall designate necessary fairways and traffic separation schemes for vessels operating in the territorial sea of the United States and in high seas approaches, outside the territorial sea, to such ports or places. Such a designation shall recognize, within the designated area, the paramount right of navigation over all other uses.

(b) Limitation.—(1) In general.—No designation may be made by the Secretary under this section if—(A) the Secretary determines such a designation, as implemented, would deprive any person of the effective exercise of a right granted by a lease or permit executed or issued under other applicable provisions of law; and

(B) such right has become vested before the time of publication of the notice required by paragraph (1) of subsection (c).


(2) Consultation required.—The Secretary shall make the determination under paragraph (1)(A) after consultation with the head of the agency responsible for executing the lease or issuing the permit.


(c) Consideration of Other Uses.—Before making a designation under subsection (a), and in accordance with the requirements of section 70004, the Secretary shall—(1) undertake a study of the potential traffic density and the need for safe access routes for vessels in any area for which fairways or traffic separation schemes are proposed or that may otherwise be considered and publish notice of such undertaking in the Federal Register;

(2) in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Army, and the Governors of affected States, as their responsibilities may require, take into account all other uses of the area under</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70003_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Designate.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (b) and subject to the requirements of subsection (c), in order to provide safe access routes for the movement of vessel traffic proceeding to or from ports or places subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, the Secretary shall designate necessary fairways and traffic separation schemes for vessels operating in the territorial sea of the United States and in high seas approaches, outside the territorial sea, to such ports or places. Such a designation shall recognize, within the designated area, the paramount right of navigation over all other uses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70003_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70003_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of Other Uses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Before making a designation under subsection (a), and in accordance with the requirements of section 70004, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70003_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In carrying out the Secretary’s responsibilities under subsection (c), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70003_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of Designation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In connection with a designation made under this section, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>