<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70013" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70013/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70013/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70013"><akn:num>70013</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to notify Coast Guard of release of objects into the navigable waters of the United Stat</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70013. Requirement to notify Coast Guard of release of objects into the navigable waters of the United States(a) Requirement.—As soon as a person has knowledge of any release from a vessel or facility into the navigable waters of the United States of any object that creates an obstruction prohibited under section 10 of the Act of March 3, 1899, popularly known as the Rivers and Harbors Appropriations Act of 1899 (33 U.S.C. 403), such person shall notify the Secretary and the Secretary of the Army of such release.

(b) Restriction on Use of Notification.—Any notification provided by an individual in accordance with subsection (a) may not be used against such individual in any criminal case, except a prosecution for perjury or for giving a false statement.

(Added Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4259.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 10 of the Act of March 3, 1899, popularly known as the Rivers and Harbors Appropriations Act of 1899, referred to in subsec. (a), means section 10 of act Mar. 3, 1899, ch. 425, 30 Stat. 1151, known as the Rivers and Harbors Appropriation Act of 1899, which is classified to section 403 of Title 33, Navigation and Navigable Waters.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70013_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) As soon as a person has knowledge of any release from a vessel or facility into the navigable waters of the United States of any object that creates an obstruction prohibited under section 10 of the Act of March 3, 1899, popularly known as the Rivers and Harbors Appropriations Act of 1899 (33 U.S.C. 403), such person shall notify the Secretary and the Secretary of the Army of such release.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70013_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on Use of Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any notification provided by an individual in accordance with subsection (a) may not be used against such individual in any criminal case, except a prosecution for perjury or for giving a false statement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>