<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70022" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70022/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70022/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70022"><akn:num>70022</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on entry and operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70022. Prohibition on entry and operation(a) Prohibition.—(1) In general.—Except as otherwise provided in this section, no vessel described in subsection (b) may enter or operate in the navigable waters of the United States or transfer cargo in any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States.

(2) Limitations on application.—(A) In general.—The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to—(i) a vessel described in subsection (b)(1), if the Secretary of State determines that—(I) the vessel is owned or operated by or on behalf of a country the government of which the Secretary of State determines is closely cooperating with the United States with respect to implementing the applicable United Nations Security Council resolutions (as such term is defined in section 3 of the North Korea Sanctions and Policy Enhancement Act of 2016); or

(II) it is in the national security interest not to apply the prohibition to such vessel; or


(ii) a vessel described in subsection (b)(2), if the Secretary of State determines that the vessel is no longer registered as described in that subsection.


(B) Notice.—Not later than 15 days after making a determination under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate written notice of the determination and the basis upon which the determination was made.

(C) Publication.—The Secretary of State shall publish a notice in the Federal Register of each determination made under subparagraph (A).



(b) Vessels Described.—A vessel referred to in subsection (a) is a foreign vessel for which a notice of arrival is required to be filed under section 70001(a)(5), and that—(1) is on the most recent list of vessels published in Federal 11 So in original. Probably should be prece</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70022_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70022_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels Described.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A vessel referred to in subsection (a) is a foreign vessel for which a notice of arrival is required to be filed under section 70001(a)(5), and that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70022_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and Publication.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70022_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Governments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70022_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Upon receiving a notice of arrival under section 70001(a)(5) from a vessel described in subsection (b), the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall notify the master of such vessel that the vessel may not enter or operate in the navigable waters of the United States or transfer cargo in any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States, unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70022_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisional Entry or Cargo Transfer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may allow provisional entry of, or transfer of cargo from, a vessel, if such entry or transfer is necessary for the safety of the vessel or persons aboard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70022_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of Innocent Passage and Right of Transit Passage.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) This section shall not be construed as authority to restrict the right of innocent passage or the right of transit passage as recognized under international law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>