<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70034" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70034/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70034/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70034"><akn:num>70034</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70034. Regulations(a) In General.—In accordance with section 553 of title 5, the Secretary shall issue, and may from time to time amend or repeal, regulations necessary to implement subchapters I through III and this subchapter.

(b) Consultation.—In the exercise of the regulatory authority under subchapters I through III and this subchapter, the Secretary shall consult with, and receive and consider the views of all interested persons, including—(1) interested Federal departments and agencies;

(2) officials of State and local governments;

(3) representatives of the maritime community;

(4) representatives of port and harbor authorities or associations;

(5) representatives of environmental groups;

(6) any other interested persons who are knowledgeable or experienced in dealing with problems involving vessel safety, port and waterways safety, and protection of the marine environment; and

(7) advisory committees consisting of all interested segments of the public when the establishment of such committees is considered necessary because the issues involved are highly complex or controversial.


(Added Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 401(a), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4261; amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXV [LXXXV], § 8507(a)(7), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4753.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2021—Pub. L. 116–283 substituted “I through III” for “A through C” in subsecs. (a) and (b).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Safety of Special ActivitiesPub. L. 116–283, div. G, title LVXXXIII [LXXXIII], § 8343, Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4710, provided that:
“(a) In General.—The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall conduct a 2-year pilot program to establish and implement a process to—“(1) establish safety zones to address special activities in the exclusive economic zone;

“(2) account for the number of safety zones established for special activities;

“(3) differentiate whether an applicant who requests a safety zone for such activ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70034_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In accordance with section 553 of title 5, the Secretary shall issue, and may from time to time amend or repeal, regulations necessary to implement subchapters I through III and this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70034_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In the exercise of the regulatory authority under subchapters I through III and this subchapter, the Secretary shall consult with, and receive and consider the views of all interested persons, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>