<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70118" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70118/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70118/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70118"><akn:num>70118</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by State and local officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70118. Enforcement by State and local officers(a) In General.—Any State or local government law enforcement officer who has authority to enforce State criminal laws may make an arrest for violation of a security zone regulation prescribed under section 1 11 See References in Text note below. of title II of the Act of June 15, 1917 (chapter 30; 50 U.S.C. 191) or security or safety zone regulation under section 7(b) 1 of the Ports and Waterways Safety Act (33 U.S.C. 1226(b)) or a safety zone regulation prescribed under section 10(d) of the Deepwater Port Act of 1974 (33 U.S.C. 1509(d)) by a Coast Guard official authorized by law to prescribe such regulations, if—(1) such violation is a felony; and

(2) the officer has reasonable grounds to believe that the person to be arrested has committed or is committing such violation.


(b) Other Powers not Affected.—The provisions of this section are in addition to any power conferred by law to such officers. This section shall not be construed as a limitation of any power conferred by law to such officers, or any other officer of the United States or any State. This section does not grant to such officers any powers not authorized by the law of the State in which those officers are employed.

(Added Pub. L. 108–293, title VIII, § 801(a), Aug. 9, 2004, 118 Stat. 1078, § 70119; renumbered § 70118, Pub. L. 109–241, title IX, § 901(l)(1), July 11, 2006, 120 Stat. 565; Pub. L. 109–304, § 15(33)(A), Oct. 6, 2006, 120 Stat. 1705; Pub. L. 110–181, div. C, title XXXV, § 3529(c)(1), Jan. 28, 2008, 122 Stat. 603.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 1 of title II of the Act of June 15, 1917, referred to in subsec. (a), which was classified to section 191 of Title 50, War and National Defense, was redesignated and transferred to section 70051 of this title by Pub. L. 115–282, title IV, § 407(b)(1), (5), Dec. 4, 2018, 132 Stat. 4267.
Section 7(b) of the Ports and Waterways Safety Act, referred to in subsec. (a), which was classif</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70118_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any State or local government law enforcement officer who has authority to enforce State criminal laws may make an arrest for violation of a security zone regulation prescribed under section 1 11 See References in Text note below. of title II of the Act of June 15, 1917 (chapter 30; 50 U.S.C. 191) or security or safety zone regulation under section 7(b) 1 of the Ports and Waterways Safety Act (33 U.S.C. 1226(b)) or a safety zone regulation prescribed under section 10(d) of the Deepwater Port Act of 1974 (33 U.S.C. 1509(d)) by a Coast Guard official authorized by law to prescribe such regulations, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70118_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Powers not Affected.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The provisions of this section are in addition to any power conferred by law to such officers. This section shall not be construed as a limitation of any power conferred by law to such officers, or any other officer of the United States or any State. This section does not grant to such officers any powers not authorized by the law of the State in which those officers are employed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>