<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70113"><akn:num>70113</akn:num><akn:heading>Maritime intelligence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70113. Maritime intelligence(a) In General.—The Secretary shall implement a system to collect, integrate, and analyze information concerning vessels operating on or bound for waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, including information related to crew, passengers, cargo, and intermodal shipments. The system may include a vessel risk profiling component that assigns incoming vessels a terrorism risk rating.

(b) Consultation.—In developing the information system under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the Transportation Security Oversight Board and other departments and agencies, as appropriate.

(c) Information Integration.—To deter a transportation security incident, the Secretary may collect information from public and private entities to the extent that the information is not provided by other Federal departments and agencies.

(Added Pub. L. 107–295, title I, § 102(a), Nov. 25, 2002, 116 Stat. 2082; amended Pub. L. 108–293, title VIII, § 803(a), Aug. 9, 2004, 118 Stat. 1080.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2004—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 108–293 inserted at end “The system may include a vessel risk profiling component that assigns incoming vessels a terrorism risk rating.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall implement a system to collect, integrate, and analyze information concerning vessels operating on or bound for waters subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, including information related to crew, passengers, cargo, and intermodal shipments. The system may include a vessel risk profiling component that assigns incoming vessels a terrorism risk rating.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In developing the information system under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the Transportation Security Oversight Board and other departments and agencies, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Integration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To deter a transportation security incident, the Secretary may collect information from public and private entities to the extent that the information is not provided by other Federal departments and agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>