<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70132" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70132/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/70132/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70132"><akn:num>70132</akn:num><akn:heading>Credentialing standards, training, and certification for State and local support for the enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70132. Credentialing standards, training, and certification for State and local support for the enforcement of security zones for the transportation of especially hazardous cargo(a) Standard.—The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall establish, by regulation, national standards for training and credentialing of public safety personnel—(1) to enforce a security zone; or

(2) to assist in the enforcement of a security zone.


(b) Training.—(1) The Commandant of the Coast Guard—(A) shall develop and publish a training curriculum for—(i) public safety personnel to enforce a security zone;

(ii) public safety personnel to enforce or assist in the enforcement of a security zone; and

(iii) personnel who are employed or retained by a facility or vessel owner to assist in the enforcement of a security zone; and


(B) may—(i) test and deliver such training, the curriculum for which is developed pursuant to subparagraph (A);

(ii) enter into an agreement under which a public entity (including a Federal agency) or private entity may test and deliver such training, the curriculum for which has been developed pursuant to subparagraph (A); and

(iii) may accept a program, conducted by a public entity (including a Federal agency) or private entity, through which such training is delivered the curriculum for which is developed pursuant to subparagraph (A).



(2) Any Federal agency that provides such training, and any public or private entity that receives moneys, pursuant to section 70107(b)(8) of this title, to provide such training, shall provide such training—(A) to public safety personnel who enforce or assist in the enforcement of a security zone; and

(B) on an availability basis to—(i) public safety personnel who assist in the enforcement of a security zone; and

(ii) personnel who are employed or retained by a facility or vessel owner or operator to assist in the enforcement of a security zone.



(3) If a Federal agency provides the training, the head of such agency may, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70132_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall establish, by regulation, national standards for training and credentialing of public safety personnel—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70132_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70132_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification; Training Partners.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In developing and delivering training under the training program, the Secretary, in coordination with the Maritime Administrator of the Department of Transportation, and consistent with section 109 of the Maritime Transportation Security Act of 2002 (46 U.S.C. 70101 note), shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70132_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Safety Personnel Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For the purposes of this section, the term “public safety personnel” includes any Federal, State (or political subdivision thereof), territorial, or Tribal law enforcement officer, firefighter, or emergency response provider.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>