<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/7101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/7101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/7101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7101"><akn:num>7101</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuing and classifying licenses and certificates of registry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7101. Issuing and classifying licenses and certificates of registry(a) Licenses and certificates of registry are established for individuals who are required to hold licenses or certificates under this subtitle.

(b) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the Secretary—(1) issues the licenses and certificates of registry; and

(2) may classify the licenses and certificates of registry as provided in subsections (c) and (f) of this section, based on—(A) the tonnage, means of propulsion, and horsepower of machine-propelled vessels;

(B) the waters on which vessels are to be operated; or

(C) other reasonable standards.



(c) The Secretary may issue licenses in the following classes to applicants found qualified as to age, character, habits of life, experience, professional qualifications, and physical fitness:(1) masters, mates, and engineers.

(2) pilots.

(3) operators.

(4) radio officers.


(d) In classifying individuals under subsection (c)(1) of this section, the Secretary shall establish, when possible, suitable career patterns and service and other qualifying requirements appropriate to the particular service or industry in which the individuals are engaged.

(e) An individual may be issued a license under subsection (c)(2) of this section only if the applicant—(1) is at least 21 years of age;

(2) is of sound health and has no physical limitations that would hinder or prevent the performance of a pilot’s duties;

(3) has a thorough physical examination each year while holding the license, except that this requirement does not apply to an individual who will serve as a pilot only on a vessel of less than 1,600 gross tons as measured under section 14502 of this title, or an alternate tonnage measured under section 14302 of this title as prescribed by the Secretary under section 14104 of this title;

(4) demonstrates, to the satisfaction of the Secretary, that the applicant has the requisite general knowledge and skill to hold the license;

(5) demons</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Licenses and certificates of registry are established for individuals who are required to hold licenses or certificates under this subtitle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may issue licenses in the following classes to applicants found qualified as to age, character, habits of life, experience, professional qualifications, and physical fitness:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In classifying individuals under subsection (c)(1) of this section, the Secretary shall establish, when possible, suitable career patterns and service and other qualifying requirements appropriate to the particular service or industry in which the individuals are engaged.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) An individual may be issued a license under subsection (c)(2) of this section only if the applicant—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary may issue certificates of registry in the following classes to applicants found qualified as to character, knowledge, skill, and experience:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary may not issue a license or certificate of registry under this section unless an individual applying for the license or certificate makes available to the Secretary, under section 206(b)(7) of the National Driver Register Act of 1982 (23 U.S.C. 401 note), any information contained in the National Driver Register related to an offense described in section 205(a)(3)(A) or (B) of that Act committed by the individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary may review the criminal record of an individual who applies for a license or certificate of registry under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary shall require the testing of an individual who applies for issuance or renewal of a license or certificate of registry under this chapter for use of a dangerous drug in violation of law or Federal regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7101_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretary may issue a license under this section in a class under subsection (c) to an applicant that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>