<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/8103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/8103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/8103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8103"><akn:num>8103</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizenship and Navy Reserve requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8103. Citizenship and Navy Reserve requirements(a) Except as otherwise provided in this title, only a citizen of the United States may serve as master, chief engineer, radio officer, or officer in charge of a deck watch or engineering watch on a documented vessel.

(b)(1) Except as otherwise provided in this section, on a documented vessel—(A) each unlicensed seaman must be—(i) a citizen of the United States;

(ii) an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence; or

(iii) a foreign national who is enrolled in the United States Merchant Marine Academy; and


(B) not more than 25 percent of the total number of unlicensed seamen on the vessel may be aliens lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence.


(2) Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply to—(A) a yacht;

(B) a fishing vessel fishing exclusively for highly migratory species (as that term is defined in section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (16 U.S.C. 1802)); and

(C) a fishing vessel fishing outside of the exclusive economic zone.


(3) The Secretary may waive a citizenship requirement under this section, other than a requirement that applies to the master of a documented vessel, with respect to—(A) an offshore supply vessel or other similarly engaged vessel of less than 1,600 gross tons as measured under section 14502 of this title, or an alternate tonnage measured under section 14302 of this title as prescribed by the Secretary under section 14104 of this title that operates from a foreign port;

(B) a mobile offshore drilling unit or other vessel engaged in support of exploration, exploitation, or production of offshore mineral energy resources operating beyond the water above the outer Continental Shelf (as that term is defined in section 2(a) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (43 U.S.C. 1331(a)); and

(C) any other vessel if the Secretary determines, after an investigation, that qualified seamen who are citizens </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as otherwise provided in this title, only a citizen of the United States may serve as master, chief engineer, radio officer, or officer in charge of a deck watch or engineering watch on a documented vessel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) On each departure of a vessel (except a passenger vessel) for which a construction differential subsidy has been granted, all of the seamen of the vessel must be citizens of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If a documented vessel is deprived for any reason of the services of an individual (except the master and the radio officer) when on a foreign voyage and a vacancy consequently occurs, until the vessel’s return to a port at which in the most expeditious manner a replacement who is a citizen of the United States can be obtained, an individual not a citizen of the United States may serve in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A person employing an individual in violation of this section or a regulation prescribed under this section is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of $500 for each individual so employed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A deck or engineer officer employed on a vessel on which an operating differential subsidy is paid, or employed on a vessel (except a vessel of the Coast Guard or Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation) owned or operated by the Department of Transportation or by a corporation organized or controlled by the Department, if eligible, shall be a member of the Navy Reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The President may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Riding Gang Member.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) This section does not apply to an individual who is a riding gang member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>