<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/9307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/9307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/46/9307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9307"><akn:num>9307</akn:num><akn:heading>Great Lakes Pilotage Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9307. Great Lakes Pilotage Advisory Committee(a) The Secretary shall establish a Great Lakes Pilotage Advisory Committee. The Committee—(1) may review proposed Great Lakes pilotage regulations and policies and make recommendations to the Secretary that the Committee considers appropriate;

(2) may advise, consult with, report to, and make recommendations to the Secretary on matters relating to Great Lakes pilotage;

(3) may make available to the Congress recommendations that the Committee makes to the Secretary; and

(4) shall meet at the call of—(A) the Secretary, who shall call such a meeting at least once during each calendar year; or

(B) a majority of the Committee.



(b)(1) The Committee shall consist of 8 members appointed by the Secretary in accordance with this subsection, each of whom has at least 5 years practical experience in maritime operations. The term of each member is for a period of not more than 5 years, specified by the Secretary. Before filling a position on the Committee, the Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting nominations for membership on the Committee.

(2) The membership of the Committee shall include—(A) the President of each of the 3 Great Lakes pilotage districts, or the President’s representative;

(B) one member chosen from among nominations made by vessel operators that contract for Great Lakes pilotage services;

(C) one member chosen from among nominations made by Great Lakes port authorities and marine terminals;

(D) one member chosen from among nominations made by shippers whose cargoes are transported through Great Lakes ports;

(E) one member chosen from among nominations made by Great Lakes maritime labor organizations; and

(F) a member who—(i) must have been recommended to the Secretary by a unanimous vote of the other members of the Committee, and

(ii) may be appointed without regard to requirement in paragraph (1) that each member have 5 years of practical experience in maritime operati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall establish a Great Lakes Pilotage Advisory Committee. The Committee—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9307_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>