<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1106"><akn:num>1106</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures and audit of trust fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1106. Expenditures and audit of trust fund(a) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to pay to the Center from the interest and earnings of the fund, and moneys credited to the fund pursuant to section 1108(a) of this title, such sums as the Board determines are necessary and appropriate to enable the Center to carry out the provisions of this chapter.


(b) Audit by GAOThe activities of the Center under this chapter may be audited by the Government Accountability Office under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. Representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, records, reports, and files and all other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by the Center, pertaining to such activities and necessary to facilitate the audit.


(Pub. L. 100–458, title I, § 117, Oct. 1, 1988, 102 Stat. 2175; Pub. L. 101–520, title III, § 313(b), Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 2282; Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b), July 7, 2004, 118 Stat. 814.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2004—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 108–271 substituted “Government Accountability Office” for “General Accounting Office” in two places.
1990—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 101–520 amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to pay to the Center from the interest and earnings of the fund such sums as the Board determines are necessary and appropriate to enable the Center to carry out the provisions of this chapter.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to pay to the Center from the interest and earnings of the fund, and moneys credited to the fund pursuant to section 1108(a) of this title, such sums as the Board determines are necessary and appropriate to enable the Center to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit by GAO</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Audit by GAO The activities of the Center under this chapter may be audited by the Government Accountability Office under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. Representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, records, reports, and files and all other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by the Center, pertaining to such activities and necessary to facilitate the audit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>