<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1151" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1151/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1151/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1151"><akn:num>1151</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Office for International Leadership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1151. Congressional Office for International Leadership(a) Establishment(1) In generalThere is established in the legislative branch of the Government an office to be known as the “Congressional Office for International Leadership” (the “Office”).


(2) Board of TrusteesThe Office shall be subject to the supervision and direction of a Board of Trustees (the “Board”) which shall be composed of 11 members as follows:(A) Two Members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, one of whom shall be designated by the Majority Leader of the House of Representatives and one of whom shall be designated by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives.

(B) Two Senators appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate, one of whom shall be designated by the Majority Leader of the Senate and one of whom shall be designated by the Minority Leader of the Senate.

(C) The Librarian of Congress.

(D) Four private individuals with interests in improving relations between the United States and eligible foreign states, designated by the Librarian of Congress.

(E) The chair of the Subcommittee on Legislative Branch of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the chair of the Subcommittee on Legislative Branch of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.


Each member appointed under this paragraph shall serve for a term of 3 years. Any vacancy shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment and the individual so appointed shall serve for the remainder of the term. Members of the Board shall serve without pay, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties.


(b) Purpose and authority of the Office(1) PurposeThe purpose of the Office is to establish, in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (2), a program to enable emerging political and civic leaders of eligible foreign states at all le</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and authority of the Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose and authority of the Office</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Executive Director On behalf of the Board, the Librarian of Congress shall appoint an Executive Director who shall be the chief executive officer of the Office and who shall carry out the functions of the Office subject to the supervision and direction of the Board of Trustees. The Executive Director of the Office shall be compensated at the annual rate specified by the Board, but in no event shall such rate exceed level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administrative provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transfer of funds Any amounts appropriated for use in the program established under section 3011 of the 1999 Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act (Public Law 106–31; 113 Stat. 93) shall be transferred to the Fund and shall remain available without fiscal year limitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effective dates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1151_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. No subsec. (i) has been enacted. Eligible foreign state defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section, the term “eligible foreign state” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>