<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1314" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1314/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1314/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1314"><akn:num>1314</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights and protections under Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1314. Rights and protections under Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988(a) Polygraph practices prohibited(1) In generalNo employing office, irrespective of whether a covered employee works in that employing office, may require a covered employee to take a lie detector test where such a test would be prohibited if required by an employer under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 3 of the Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (29 U.S.C. 2002(1), (2), or (3)). In addition, the waiver provisions of section 6(d) of such Act (29 U.S.C. 2005(d)) shall apply to covered employees.


(2) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the term “covered employee” shall include employees of the Government Accountability Office and the term “employing office” shall include the Government Accountability Office.


(3) Capitol PoliceNothing in this section shall preclude the Capitol Police from using lie detector tests in accordance with regulations under subsection (c).



(b) RemedyThe remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under section 6(c)(1) of the Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (29 U.S.C. 2005(c)(1)).


(c) Regulations to implement section(1) In generalThe Board shall, pursuant to section 1384 of this title, issue regulations to implement this section.


(2) Agency regulationsThe regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Labor to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsections (a) and (b) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.



(d) Effective date(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective 1 year after January 23, 1995.


(2) Government Accountability Office and Lib</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1314_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Polygraph practices prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Polygraph practices prohibited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1314_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Remedy The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under section 6(c)(1) of the Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (29 U.S.C. 2005(c)(1)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1314_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations to implement section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations to implement section</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1314_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>