<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1315" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1315/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1315/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1315"><akn:num>1315</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights and protections under Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1315. Rights and protections under Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act(a) Worker adjustment and retraining notification rights(1) In generalNo employing office shall be closed or a mass layoff ordered within the meaning of section 3 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (29 U.S.C. 2102) until the end of a 60-day period after the employing office serves written notice of such prospective closing or layoff to representatives of covered employees or, if there are no representatives, to covered employees.


(2) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the term “covered employee” shall include employees of the Government Accountability Office and the term “employing office” shall include the Government Accountability Office.



(b) RemedyThe remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under paragraphs (1), (2), and (4) of section 5(a) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (29 U.S.C. 2104(a)(1), (2), and (4)).


(c) Regulations to implement section(1) In generalThe Board shall, pursuant to section 1384 of this title, issue regulations to implement this section.


(2) Agency regulationsThe regulations issued under paragraph (1) shall be the same as substantive regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Labor to implement the statutory provisions referred to in subsection (a) except insofar as the Board may determine, for good cause shown and stated together with the regulation, that a modification of such regulations would be more effective for the implementation of the rights and protections under this section.



(d) Effective date(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), subsections (a) and (b) shall be effective 1 year after January 23, 1995.


(2) Government Accountability Office and Library of CongressThis section shall be effective with respect to the Government Accountability Office and the Library of Congress 1 year after transmission to the Congres</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Worker adjustment and retraining notification rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Worker adjustment and retraining notification rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Remedy The remedy for a violation of subsection (a) shall be such remedy as would be appropriate if awarded under paragraphs (1), (2), and (4) of section 5(a) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (29 U.S.C. 2104(a)(1), (2), and (4)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations to implement section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations to implement section</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>