<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/136a–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/136a–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/136a–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_136a_2"><akn:num>136a–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Librarian of Congress and Deputy Librarian of Congress; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 136a–2. Librarian of Congress and Deputy Librarian of Congress; compensation
Notwithstanding any other provision of law—(1) the Librarian of Congress shall be compensated at an annual rate of pay which is equal to the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of title 5; and

(2) the Deputy Librarian of Congress shall be compensated at the greater of the rate of pay in effect for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5 or the maximum annual rate of basic pay payable under section 5376 of such title for positions at agencies with a performance appraisal system certified under section 5307(d) of such title.

(Pub. L. 98–63, title I, § 904, July 30, 1983, 97 Stat. 336; Pub. L. 106–57, title II, § 209(a), Sept. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 424; Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XIV, § 1404(a)(1), Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 3207.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2019—Par. (2). Pub. L. 116–94 amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “the Deputy Librarian of Congress shall be compensated at an annual rate of pay which is equal to the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5.”
1999—Pub. L. 106–57 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows:
“(a) Subject to subsection (b) of this section and notwithstanding any other provision of law—
“(1) the compensation of the Librarian of Congress shall be at an annual rate which is equal to the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5, and
“(2) the compensation of the Deputy Librarian of Congress shall be at an annual rate which is equal to the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5.
“(b) The limitations contained in section 306 of S. 2939, Ninety-seventh Congress, as made applicable by sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_2_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) the Librarian of Congress shall be compensated at an annual rate of pay which is equal to the annual rate of basic pay payable for positions at level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of title 5; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_2_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) the Deputy Librarian of Congress shall be compensated at the greater of the rate of pay in effect for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5 or the maximum annual rate of basic pay payable under section 5376 of such title for positions at agencies with a performance appraisal system certified under section 5307(d) of such title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>