<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1402"><akn:num>1402</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiation of procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1402. Initiation of procedures(a) Claim(1) Filing of claimTo commence a proceeding under this subchapter, a covered employee alleging a violation of law made applicable under part A of subchapter II shall file a claim with the Office. The Office shall not accept a claim which is filed after the deadline applicable under subsection (d).


(2) Contents of claimThe claim filed under this section shall be made in writing under oath or affirmation, shall describe the facts that form the basis of the claim and the violation that is being alleged, shall identify the employing office alleged to have committed the violation or in which the violation is alleged to have occurred, and shall be in such form as the Office requires.


(3) No effect on ability of covered employee to seek information from office or pursue reliefNothing in paragraph (2), or subsection (b) or (c), may be construed to limit the ability of a covered employee—(A) to contact the Office or any other appropriate office prior to filing a claim under this section to seek information regarding the employee’s rights under this chapter and the procedures available under this chapter;

(B) in the case of a covered employee of an employing office of the House of Representatives or Senate, to refer information regarding an alleged violation of part A of subchapter II to the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives or the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate (as the case may be); or

(C) to file a civil action in accordance with section 1401(b) of this title.



(b) Initial processing of claim(1) Intake and recording; notification to employing officeUpon the filing of a claim by a covered employee under subsection (a), the Office shall take such steps as may be necessary for the initial intake and recording of the claim, including providing each party with all relevant information with respect to the rights of the party under this chapter, and shall transmit immediately a copy of the claim to the he</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claim</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Claim</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial processing of claim</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Initial processing of claim</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of secure electronic reporting and tracking system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of secure electronic reporting and tracking system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deadline A covered employee may not file a claim under this section with respect to an allegation of a violation of law after the expiration of the 180-day period which begins on the date of the alleged violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>