<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1407" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1407/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1407/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1407"><akn:num>1407</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of Board decisions and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1407. Judicial review of Board decisions and enforcement(a) Jurisdiction(1) Judicial reviewThe United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall have jurisdiction over any proceeding commenced by a petition of—(A) a party aggrieved by a final decision of the Board under section 1406(e) of this title in cases arising under part A of subchapter II,

(B) a charging individual or a respondent before the Board who files a petition under section 1331(d)(4) of this title,

(C) the General Counsel or a respondent before the Board who files a petition under section 1341(c)(5) of this title, or

(D) the General Counsel or a respondent before the Board who files a petition under section 1351(c)(3) of this title.


The court of appeals shall have exclusive jurisdiction to set aside, suspend (in whole or in part), to determine the validity of, or otherwise review the decision of the Board.

(2) EnforcementThe United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall have jurisdiction over any petition of the General Counsel, filed in the name of the Office and at the direction of the Board, to enforce a final decision under section 1405(g) or 1406(e) of this title with respect to a violation of part A, B, C, or D of subchapter II.



(b) Procedures(1) Respondents(A) In any proceeding commenced by a petition filed under subsection (a)(1)(A) or (B), or filed by a party other than the General Counsel under subsection (a)(1)(C) or (D), the Office shall be named respondent and any party before the Board may be named respondent by filing a notice of election with the court within 30 days after service of the petition.

(B) In any proceeding commenced by a petition filed by the General Counsel under subsection (a)(1)(C) or (D), the prevailing party in the final decision entered under section 1406(e) of this title shall be named respondent, and any other party before the Board may be named respondent by filing a notice of election with the court within 30 days after serv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Law applicable Chapter 158 of title 28 shall apply to judicial review under paragraph (1) of subsection (a), except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard of review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Standard of review To the extent necessary for decision in a proceeding commenced under subsection (a)(1) and when presented, the court shall decide all relevant questions of law and interpret constitutional and statutory provisions. The court shall set aside a final decision of the Board if it is determined that the decision was—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Record</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Record In making determinations under subsection (d), the court shall review the whole record, or those parts of it cited by a party, and due account shall be taken of the rule of prejudicial error.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>