<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1415" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1415/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1415/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1415"><akn:num>1415</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1415. Payments(a) Awards and settlementsExcept as provided in subsection (c), only funds which are appropriated to an account of the Office in the Treasury of the United States for the payment of awards and settlements may be used for the payment of awards and settlements under this chapter. There are appropriated for such account such sums as may be necessary to pay such awards and settlements. Funds in the account are not available for awards and settlements involving the Government Accountability Office or the Government Publishing Office.


(b) ComplianceExcept as provided in subsection (c), there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for administrative, personnel, and similar expenses of employing offices which are needed to comply with this chapter.


(c) OSHA, accommodation, and access requirementsFunds to correct violations of section 1311(a)(3), 1331, or 1341 of this title may be paid only from funds appropriated to the employing office or entity responsible for correcting such violations. There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for such funds.


(d) Reimbursement by Members of Congress of amounts paid as settlements and awards(1) Reimbursement required for certain violations(A) In generalSubject to subparagraphs (B) and (D), if a payment is made from the account described in subsection (a) for an award or settlement in connection with a claim alleging a violation described in subparagraph (C) committed personally by an individual who, at the time of committing the violation, was a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or a Senator, the individual shall reimburse the account for the amount of the award or settlement for the claim involved.


(B) ConditionsIn the case of an award made pursuant to a decision of a hearing officer under section 1405 of this title, or a court in a civil action, subparagraph (A) shall apply only if the hearin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards and settlements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Awards and settlements Except as provided in subsection (c), only funds which are appropriated to an account of the Office in the Treasury of the United States for the payment of awards and settlements may be used for the payment of awards and settlements under this chapter. There are appropriated for such account such sums as may be necessary to pay such awards and settlements. Funds in the account are not available for awards and settlements involving the Government Accountability Office or the Government Publishing Office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compliance Except as provided in subsection (c), there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for administrative, personnel, and similar expenses of employing offices which are needed to comply with this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>OSHA, accommodation, and access requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) OSHA, accommodation, and access requirements Funds to correct violations of section 1311(a)(3), 1331, or 1341 of this title may be paid only from funds appropriated to the employing office or entity responsible for correcting such violations. There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for such funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement by Members of Congress of amounts paid as settlements and awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reimbursement by Members of Congress of amounts paid as settlements and awards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement by employing offices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reimbursement by employing offices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>