<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1416" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1416/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1416/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1416"><akn:num>1416</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1416. Confidentiality(a) MediationAll information discussed or disclosed in the course of any mediation shall be strictly confidential, and the Executive Director shall notify each person participating in the mediation of the confidentiality requirement and of the sanctions applicable to any person who violates the confidentiality requirement.


(b) Hearings and deliberationsExcept as provided in subsections (c), (d), and (e), all proceedings and deliberations of hearing officers and the Board, including any related records, shall be confidential. This subsection shall not apply to proceedings under section 1341 of this title, but shall apply to the deliberations of hearing officers and the Board under that section. The Executive Director shall notify each person participating in a proceeding or deliberation to which this subsection applies of the requirements of this subsection and of the sanctions applicable to any person who violates the requirements of this subsection.


(c) Release of records for judicial actionThe records of hearing officers and the Board may be made public if required for the purpose of judicial review under section 1407 of this title.


(d) Automatic referral to Congressional Ethics Committee of dispositions of claims involving Members of Congress and senior staff(1) ReferralUpon the final disposition under this subchapter (as described in paragraph (6)) of a claim alleging a violation described in section 1415(d)(1)(C) of this title committed personally by a Member of the House of Representatives (including a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress) or a Senator, or by a senior staff of the House of Representatives or Senate, the Executive Director shall refer the claim to—(A) the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives, in the case of a Member or senior staff of the House; or

(B) the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate, in the case of a Senator or senior staff of the Senate.


(2) Access to records and informa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mediation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Mediation All information discussed or disclosed in the course of any mediation shall be strictly confidential, and the Executive Director shall notify each person participating in the mediation of the confidentiality requirement and of the sanctions applicable to any person who violates the confidentiality requirement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings and deliberations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hearings and deliberations Except as provided in subsections (c), (d), and (e), all proceedings and deliberations of hearing officers and the Board, including any related records, shall be confidential. This subsection shall not apply to proceedings under section 1341 of this title, but shall apply to the deliberations of hearing officers and the Board under that section. The Executive Director shall notify each person participating in a proceeding or deliberation to which this subsection applies of the requirements of this subsection and of the sanctions applicable to any person who violates the requirements of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of records for judicial action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Release of records for judicial action The records of hearing officers and the Board may be made public if required for the purpose of judicial review under section 1407 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Automatic referral to Congressional Ethics Committee of dispositions of claims involving Members of Congress and senior staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Automatic referral to Congressional Ethics Committee of dispositions of claims involving Members of Congress and senior staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final decisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Final decisions A final decision entered under section 1405(g) or 1406(e) of this title shall be made public if it is in favor of the complaining covered employee, or in favor of the charging party under section 1331 of this title, or if the decision reverses a decision of a hearing officer which had been in favor of the covered employee or charging party. The Board may make public any other decision at its discretion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Claims Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit a covered employee from disclosing the factual allegations underlying the covered employee’s claim, or to prohibit an employing office from disclosing the factual allegations underlying the employing office’s defense to the claim, in the course of any proceeding under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>