<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1553" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1553/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1553/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1553"><akn:num>1553</akn:num><akn:heading>Special authorities of Advisory Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1553. Special authorities of Advisory Commission(a) Experts and consultantsFor purposes of carrying out this subchapter, the Advisory Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services of experts or consultants under section 3109(b) of title 5.


(b) Detail of staff of Federal agenciesUpon request of the Executive Director of the Advisory Commission, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Advisory Commission to assist it in carrying out this subchapter.


(c) Administrative support servicesUpon the request of the Advisory Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Advisory Commission, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Advisory Commission to carry out its duties under this subchapter.


(d) Contract authorityThe Advisory Commission may, subject to appropriations, contract with and compensate government and private persons (including agencies) for property and services used to carry out its duties under this subchapter.


(Pub. L. 104–4, title III, § 303, Mar. 22, 1995, 109 Stat. 69.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1553_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Experts and consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Experts and consultants For purposes of carrying out this subchapter, the Advisory Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services of experts or consultants under section 3109(b) of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1553_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail of staff of Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Detail of staff of Federal agencies Upon request of the Executive Director of the Advisory Commission, the head of any Federal department or agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that department or agency to the Advisory Commission to assist it in carrying out this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1553_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative support services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative support services Upon the request of the Advisory Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Advisory Commission, on a reimbursable basis, the administrative support services necessary for the Advisory Commission to carry out its duties under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1553_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contract authority The Advisory Commission may, subject to appropriations, contract with and compensate government and private persons (including agencies) for property and services used to carry out its duties under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>