<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/162b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/162b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/162b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_162b"><akn:num>162b</akn:num><akn:heading>Little Scholars Child Development Center; employee compensation and personnel matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 162b. Little Scholars Child Development Center; employee compensation and personnel matters(a) Election of coverage; creditable service; qualification for survivor annuities and disability benefits; contributions to thrift savings plan; certification concerning creditable service(1) This subsection shall apply to any individual who—(A) is employed by the Library of Congress Child Development Center (known as the “Little Scholars Child Development Center”, in this section referred to as the “Center”) established under section 205(g)(1) of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1991; and

(B) makes an election to be covered by this subsection with the Librarian of Congress, not later than the later of—(i) 60 days after December 21, 2000; or

(ii) 60 days after the date the individual begins such employment.



(2)(A) Any individual described under paragraph (1) may be credited, under section 8411 of title 5 for service as an employee of the Center before December 21, 2000, if such employee makes a payment of the deposit under section 8411(f)(2) of such title without application of section 8411(b)(3) of such title.

(B) An individual described under paragraph (1) shall be credited under section 8411 of title 5 for any service as an employee of the Center on or after December 21, 2000, if such employee has such amounts deducted and withheld from his pay as determined by the Office of Personnel Management which would be deducted and withheld from the basic pay of an employee under section 8422 of title 5.


(3) Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, any service performed by an individual described under paragraph (1) as an employee of the Center is deemed to be civilian service creditable under section 8411 of title 5 for purposes of qualifying for survivor annuities and disability benefits under subchapters IV and V of chapter 84 of such title, if such individual makes payment of an amount, determined by the Office of Personnel Management, which w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_162b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of coverage; creditable service; qualification for survivor annuities and disability benefits; contributions to thrift savings plan; certification concerning creditable service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Election of coverage; creditable service; qualification for survivor annuities and disability benefits; contributions to thrift savings plan; certification concerning creditable service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_162b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health insurance coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Health insurance coverage Any individual who is employed by the Center on or after the date of enactment of this Act [December 21, 2000], shall be deemed an employee under section 8901(1) of title 5 for purposes of health insurance coverage under chapter 89 of such title. An individual who is an employee of the Center on the date of enactment of this Act may elect coverage under this subsection before the 60th day after the date of enactment of this Act, and during such periods as determined by the Office of Personnel Management for employees of the Center employed after such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_162b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life insurance coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Life insurance coverage An individual who is employed by the Center shall be deemed an employee under section 8701(a) of title 5 for purposes of life insurance coverage under chapter 87 of such title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_162b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government contributions by Librarian from available appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Government contributions by Librarian from available appropriations Government contributions for individuals receiving benefits under this section, as computed under sections 8423, 8432, 8708, and 8906 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by “of title 5”. shall be made by the Librarian of Congress from any appropriations available to the Library of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_162b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payroll and personnel functions of Library of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payroll and personnel functions of Library of Congress The Library of Congress, directly or by agreement with its designated representative, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_162b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Responsibilities of Center The Center shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_162b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement for certain compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reimbursement for certain compensation Notwithstanding paragraph (1) of subsection (f), in the case of expenses described in such paragraph which are attributable to the compensation of the Executive Director and Deputy Executive Director of the Center, the Librarian of Congress may reimburse the Center for such expenses from amounts appropriated or otherwise made available for salaries and expenses of the Library of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_162b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Librarian of Congress may prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>