<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/179p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/179p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/179p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_179p"><akn:num>179p</akn:num><akn:heading>National Film Registry Collection of Library of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 179p. National Film Registry Collection of Library of Congress(a) Acquisition of archival quality copiesThe Librarian shall endeavor to obtain, by gift from the owner, an archival quality copy of the Registry version of each film included in the National Film Registry. Whenever possible, the Librarian shall endeavor to obtain the best surviving materials, including preprint materials. Copyright owners and others possessing copies of such materials are strongly encouraged, to further the preservation purposes of this Act, to provide preprint and other archival elements to the Library of Congress.


(b) Additional materialsThe Librarian shall endeavor to obtain, for educational and research purposes, additional materials related to each film included in the National Film Registry, such as background materials, production reports, shooting scripts (including continuity scripts) and other similar materials.


(c) Property of United StatesAll copies of films on the National Film Registry that are received as gifts or bequests by the Librarian and other materials received by the Librarian under subsection (b), shall become the property of the United States Government, subject to the provisions of title 17.


(d) National Film Registry CollectionAll copies of films on the National Film Registry that are received by the Librarian under subsection (a) of this section, and other materials received by the Librarian under subsection (b), shall be maintained in the Library of Congress and be known as the “National Film Registry Collection of the Library of Congress”. The Librarian shall, by regulation, and in accordance with title 17, provide for reasonable access to the films and other materials in such collection for scholarly and research purposes.


(e) National Audio-Visual Conservation CenterThe Librarian shall utilize the National Audio-Visual Conservation Center of the Library of Congress at Culpeper, Virginia, to ensure that preserved films included in the National Fi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179p_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of archival quality copies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Acquisition of archival quality copies The Librarian shall endeavor to obtain, by gift from the owner, an archival quality copy of the Registry version of each film included in the National Film Registry. Whenever possible, the Librarian shall endeavor to obtain the best surviving materials, including preprint materials. Copyright owners and others possessing copies of such materials are strongly encouraged, to further the preservation purposes of this Act, to provide preprint and other archival elements to the Library of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179p_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional materials The Librarian shall endeavor to obtain, for educational and research purposes, additional materials related to each film included in the National Film Registry, such as background materials, production reports, shooting scripts (including continuity scripts) and other similar materials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179p_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Property of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Property of United States All copies of films on the National Film Registry that are received as gifts or bequests by the Librarian and other materials received by the Librarian under subsection (b), shall become the property of the United States Government, subject to the provisions of title 17.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179p_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Film Registry Collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) National Film Registry Collection All copies of films on the National Film Registry that are received by the Librarian under subsection (a) of this section, and other materials received by the Librarian under subsection (b), shall be maintained in the Library of Congress and be known as the “National Film Registry Collection of the Library of Congress”. The Librarian shall, by regulation, and in accordance with title 17, provide for reasonable access to the films and other materials in such collection for scholarly and research purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_179p_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Audio-Visual Conservation Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) National Audio-Visual Conservation Center The Librarian shall utilize the National Audio-Visual Conservation Center of the Library of Congress at Culpeper, Virginia, to ensure that preserved films included in the National Film Registry are stored in a proper manner, and disseminated to researchers, scholars, and the public as may be appropriate in accordance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>