<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1805a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1805a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1805a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1805a"><akn:num>1805a</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Architect of the Capitol to serve as acting in case of absence, disability, or vacancy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1805a. Deputy Architect of the Capitol to serve as acting in case of absence, disability, or vacancy(a) In generalThe Deputy Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Deputy Architect”) shall act as Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Architect”) if the Architect is absent or disabled or there is no Architect.


(b) Absence, disability, or vacancy in Office of Deputy ArchitectFor purposes of subsection (a), if the Deputy Architect is also absent or disabled or there is no Deputy Architect, the congressional commission described in section 1801a(a) of this title shall designate, by a majority vote of the members of the commission, an individual to serve as acting Architect until—(1) the end of the absence or disability of the Architect or the Deputy Architect; or

(2) in the case of vacancies in both positions, an Architect has been appointed under section 1801a(a) of this title.


(c) AuthorityAn officer serving as acting Architect under subsection (a) or (b) shall perform all the duties and exercise all the authorities of the Architect, including the authority to delegate the duties and authorities of the Architect in accordance with section 1803 of this title.


(Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LVII, § 5704, Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 961.)

Editorial Notes

CodificationSection is comprised of section 5704 of Pub. L. 118–31. Subsec. (d) of section 5704 of Pub. L. 118–31 repealed section 1804 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Deputy Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Deputy Architect”) shall act as Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Architect”) if the Architect is absent or disabled or there is no Architect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Absence, disability, or vacancy in Office of Deputy Architect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Absence, disability, or vacancy in Office of Deputy Architect For purposes of subsection (a), if the Deputy Architect is also absent or disabled or there is no Deputy Architect, the congressional commission described in section 1801a(a) of this title shall designate, by a majority vote of the members of the commission, an individual to serve as acting Architect until—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority An officer serving as acting Architect under subsection (a) or (b) shall perform all the duties and exercise all the authorities of the Architect, including the authority to delegate the duties and authorities of the Architect in accordance with section 1803 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>