<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1805" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1805/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1805/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1805"><akn:num>1805</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Architect of the Capitol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1805. Deputy Architect of the Capitol(a) Establishment of Deputy Architect of the CapitolThe Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Architect”) shall appoint a suitable individual to be the Deputy Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Deputy Architect”). The Architect may delegate to the Deputy Architect such duties as the Architect determines are necessary or appropriate.


(b) DeadlineThe Architect shall appoint a Deputy Architect under subsection (a) not later than 120 days after—(1) the date on which the Architect is appointed under section 1801a of this title, if there is no Deputy Architect on the date of the appointment; or

(2) the date on which a vacancy arises in the office of the Deputy Architect.


(c) CompensationThe Deputy Architect shall be paid at an annual rate of pay to be determined by the Architect but not to exceed $1,500 less than the annual rate of pay for the Architect.


(d) Failure to appointIf the Architect does not appoint a Deputy Architect on or before the applicable date specified in subsection (b), the congressional commission described in section 1801a(a) of this title shall appoint the Deputy Architect by a majority vote of the members of the commission.


(e) NotificationIf the position of Deputy Architect becomes vacant, the Architect shall immediately notify the members of the congressional commission described in section 1801a(a) of this title.


(Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1203, Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 373; Pub. L. 108–11, title II, § 2601(a), Apr. 16, 2003, 117 Stat. 599; Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b), July 7, 2004, 118 Stat. 814; Pub. L. 111–316, § 1(b), Dec. 18, 2010, 124 Stat. 3452; Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title VII, § 701(b), Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2154; Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, title LVII, § 5703, Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 961.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section is from the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2003, which is div. H of Pub. L. 108–7.

Amendments2023</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Deputy Architect of the Capitol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Deputy Architect of the Capitol The Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Architect”) shall appoint a suitable individual to be the Deputy Architect of the Capitol (in this section referred to as the “Deputy Architect”). The Architect may delegate to the Deputy Architect such duties as the Architect determines are necessary or appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deadline The Architect shall appoint a Deputy Architect under subsection (a) not later than 120 days after—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation The Deputy Architect shall be paid at an annual rate of pay to be determined by the Architect but not to exceed $1,500 less than the annual rate of pay for the Architect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to appoint</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Failure to appoint If the Architect does not appoint a Deputy Architect on or before the applicable date specified in subsection (b), the congressional commission described in section 1801a(a) of this title shall appoint the Deputy Architect by a majority vote of the members of the commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1805_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notification If the position of Deputy Architect becomes vacant, the Architect shall immediately notify the members of the congressional commission described in section 1801a(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>