<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1808" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1808/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1808/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1808"><akn:num>1808</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1808. Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Architect of the Capitol Inspector General Act of 2007”.


(b) Office of Inspector GeneralThere is an Office of Inspector General within the Office of the Architect of the Capitol which is an independent objective office to—(1) conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to the Architect of the Capitol;

(2) provide leadership and coordination and recommend policies to promote economy, efficiency, and effectiveness; and

(3) provide a means of keeping the Architect of the Capitol and the Congress fully and currently informed about problems and deficiencies relating to the administration of programs and operations of the Architect of the Capitol.


(c) Appointment of Inspector General; supervision; removal; pay; limits on bonuses; counsel(1) Appointment and supervision(A) In generalThere shall be at the head of the Office of Inspector General, an Inspector General who shall be appointed by the Architect of the Capitol, in consultation with the Inspectors General of the Library of Congress, Government Publishing Office, Government Accountability Office, and United States Capitol Police. The appointment shall be made without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations. The Inspector General shall report to, and be under the general supervision of, the Architect of the Capitol.


(B) Audits, investigations, reports, and other duties and responsibilitiesThe Architect of the Capitol shall have no authority to prevent or prohibit the Inspector General from—(i) initiating, carrying out, or completing any audit or investigation;

(ii) issuing any subpoena during the course of any audit or investigation;

(iii) issuing any report; or

(iv) carrying out any other duty or responsibility of the Inspecto</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1808_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Architect of the Capitol Inspector General Act of 2007”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1808_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Inspector General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Office of Inspector General There is an Office of Inspector General within the Office of the Architect of the Capitol which is an independent objective office to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1808_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Inspector General; supervision; removal; pay; limits on bonuses; counsel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appointment of Inspector General; supervision; removal; pay; limits on bonuses; counsel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1808_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties, responsibilities, authority, and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties, responsibilities, authority, and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1808_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transfers All functions, personnel, and budget resources of the Office of the Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol as in effect before the effective date of this section are transferred to the Office of Inspector General described under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1808_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>References</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) References References in any other Federal law, Executive order, rule, regulation, or delegation of authority, or any document of or relating to the Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol shall be deemed to refer to the Inspector General as set forth under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1808_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>First appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) First appointment By the date occurring 180 days after December 26, 2007, the Architect of the Capitol shall appoint an individual to the position of Inspector General of the Architect of the Capitol described under subparagraph (A) of subsection (c)(1) in accordance with that subparagraph.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1808_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effective date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>