<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1816" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1816/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1816/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1816"><akn:num>1816</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1816. Construction contracts(a) Liquidated damagesThe Architect of the Capitol may not enter into or administer any construction contract with a value greater than $50,000 unless the contract includes a provision requiring the payment of liquidated damages in the amount determined under subsection (b) in the event that completion of the project is delayed because of the contractor.


(b) Amount of paymentThe amount of payment required under a liquidated damages provision described in subsection (a) shall be equal to the product of—(1) the daily liquidated damage payment rate; and

(2) the number of days by which the completion of the project is delayed.


(c) Daily liquidated damage payment rate(1) In generalIn subsection (b), the “daily liquidated damage payment rate” means—(A) $140, in the case of a contract with a value greater than $50,000 and less than $100,000;

(B) $200, in the case of a contract with a value equal to or greater than $100,000 and equal to or less than $500,000; and

(C) the sum of $200 plus $50 for each $100,000 increment by which the value of the contract exceeds $500,000, in the case of a contract with a value greater than $500,000.


(2) Adjustment in rate permittedNotwithstanding paragraph (1), the daily liquidated damage payment rate may be adjusted by the contracting officer involved to a rate greater or lesser than the rate described in such paragraph if the contracting officer makes a written determination that the rate described does not accurately reflect the anticipated damages which will be suffered by the United States as a result of the delay in the completion of the contract.



(d) Effective dateThis section shall apply with respect to contracts entered into during fiscal year 2002 or any succeeding fiscal year.


(Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 130, Nov. 12, 2001, 115 Stat. 580.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was classified to section 166j of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Propert</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1816_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidated damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liquidated damages The Architect of the Capitol may not enter into or administer any construction contract with a value greater than $50,000 unless the contract includes a provision requiring the payment of liquidated damages in the amount determined under subsection (b) in the event that completion of the project is delayed because of the contractor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1816_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of payment The amount of payment required under a liquidated damages provision described in subsection (a) shall be equal to the product of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1816_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Daily liquidated damage payment rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Daily liquidated damage payment rate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1816_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date This section shall apply with respect to contracts entered into during fiscal year 2002 or any succeeding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>