<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/182b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/182b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/182b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_182b"><akn:num>182b</akn:num><akn:heading>Revolving fund for sales shop and other services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 182b. Revolving fund for sales shop and other services(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established in the Treasury a revolving fund for the following programs and activities of the Librarian:(1) Decimal classification development.

(2) The operation of a gift shop or other sales of items associated with collections, exhibits, performances, and special events of the Library of Congress.

(3) Document reproduction and microfilming services.

(4) Special events and programs.

(5) Training.


(b) Individual accounting requirementA separate account shall be maintained in the revolving fund under this section with respect to the programs and activities described in each of the paragraphs of subsection (a).


(c) Fees for servicesThe Librarian may charge a fee for services under any of the programs and activities described in subsection (a), and shall deposit any such fees charged into the account of the revolving fund under this section for such program or activity.


(d) Contents of accounts in fund(1) In generalEach account of the revolving fund under this section shall consist of the following amounts:(A) Amounts deposited by the Librarian under subsection (c).

(B) Any other amounts received by the Librarian which are attributable to the programs and activities covered by such account.

(C) Amounts deposited by the Librarian under paragraph (2).

(D) Such other amounts as may be appropriated under law.


(2) Deposit of funds during transitionThe Librarian shall transfer to each account of the revolving fund under this section the following:(A) Any obligated, unexpended balances existing as of the date of the transfer which are attributable to the programs and activities covered by such account.

(B) An amount equal to the difference as of such date between—(i) the total value of the supplies, inventories, equipment, gift fund balances, and other assets attributable to such programs and activities; and

(ii) the total value of the liabilities attributable to such pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_182b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established in the Treasury a revolving fund for the following programs and activities of the Librarian:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_182b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individual accounting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Individual accounting requirement A separate account shall be maintained in the revolving fund under this section with respect to the programs and activities described in each of the paragraphs of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_182b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fees for services The Librarian may charge a fee for services under any of the programs and activities described in subsection (a), and shall deposit any such fees charged into the account of the revolving fund under this section for such program or activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_182b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of accounts in fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contents of accounts in fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_182b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>