<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1847" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1847/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1847/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1847"><akn:num>1847</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization to fix basic rate of compensation for certain positions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1847. Authorization to fix basic rate of compensation for certain positions
On and after August 21, 1959, the Architect of the Capitol is authorized, without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, to fix the compensation of four positions under the appropriation “Salaries, Office of the Architect of the Capitol”, of two positions under the appropriation “Capitol Buildings”, and of one position under the appropriation “House Office Buildings” at a basic rate of $8,200 per annum each: Provided, That this provision shall not be applicable to the positions of Architect or Assistant Architect.
On and after August 21, 1959, the Architect of the Capitol is authorized, without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5, to fix the compensation of one position under the appropriation “Senate Office Buildings”, at a basic rate of $8,200 per annum.
(Pub. L. 86–176, Aug. 21, 1959, 73 Stat. 407; Pub. L. 89–309, ch. VII, Oct. 31, 1965, 79 Stat. 1147; Pub. L. 90–206, title II, § 214(p), Dec. 16, 1967, 81 Stat. 638; Pub. L. 90–239, ch. IV, Jan. 2, 1968, 81 Stat. 775; Pub. L. 94–157, title I, ch. IV, Dec. 18, 1975, 89 Stat. 835; Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 106(c), Nov. 21, 1989, 103 Stat. 1056.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was classified to section 166b–3 of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by Pub. L. 107–217, § 1, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1062.
“Chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5” substituted for “the Classification Act of 1949, as amended” in text on authority of Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b), Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 631, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.

Amendments1989—Pub. L. 101–163 substituted “four positions” for “three positions” and “Architect or Assistant Architect” for “Architect, Assistant Architect, or Second Assistant Architect of the Capitol”.
1975—Pub. L. 94–157 increased to two position</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>