<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1848" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1848/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1848/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1848"><akn:num>1848</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of certain positions in Office of Architect of the Capitol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1848. Compensation of certain positions in Office of Architect of the Capitol(a) Amount of compensation to be that specified in appropriations ActsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the pay for positions described in subsection (b) shall be the amounts specified for such positions in appropriations Acts.


(b) Positions coveredThe positions referred to in subsection (a) are—(1) the position of assistant referred to in the proviso in the first undesignated paragraph under the center subheadings “Office of the Architect of the Capitol” and “salaries” in the first section of the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1971 [2 U.S.C. 1804],11 See References in Text note below. and

(2) the eight positions provided for in the third and fourth undesignated paragraphs under the center subheadings “Office of the Architect of the Capitol” and “salaries” in the first section of the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1960 [2 U.S.C. 1847].


(c) Calculation of amountsThe pay for each position described in subsection (b) shall be the pay payable for such position with respect to the last pay period before this section takes effect, subject to any applicable adjustment during fiscal year 1988 under, or by reference to any applicable adjustment during fiscal year 1988 under, subchapter I of chapter 53 of title 5.


(d) Effective dateThis section shall apply in fiscal years beginning after September 30, 1987, with respect to pay periods beginning after December 22, 1987.


(Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(i) [title III, § 308], Dec. 22, 1987, 101 Stat. 1329–290, 1329–309; Pub. L. 101–163, title I, § 106(e), Nov. 21, 1989, 103 Stat. 1057.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe first undesignated paragraph under the center subheadings “Office of the Architect of the Capitol” and “salaries” in the first section of the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1971, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), was classified to section 1804 of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 118–31, div. E, t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1848_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of compensation to be that specified in appropriations Acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amount of compensation to be that specified in appropriations Acts Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the pay for positions described in subsection (b) shall be the amounts specified for such positions in appropriations Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1848_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Positions covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Positions covered The positions referred to in subsection (a) are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1848_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Calculation of amounts The pay for each position described in subsection (b) shall be the pay payable for such position with respect to the last pay period before this section takes effect, subject to any applicable adjustment during fiscal year 1988 under, or by reference to any applicable adjustment during fiscal year 1988 under, subchapter I of chapter 53 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1848_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date This section shall apply in fiscal years beginning after September 30, 1987, with respect to pay periods beginning after December 22, 1987.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>