<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1865" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1865/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1865/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1865"><akn:num>1865</akn:num><akn:heading>Capitol Police Buildings and Grounds Account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1865. Capitol Police Buildings and Grounds Account(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States an account for the Architect of the Capitol to be known as “Capitol Police Buildings and Grounds” (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “account”).


(b) Use of fundsFunds in the account shall be used by the Architect of the Capitol for all necessary expenses for—(1) resilience and security programs of the Architect of the Capitol; and

(2) the maintenance, care, and operation of buildings, grounds, and security enhancements for facilities of the United States Capitol Police and for other facilities associated with such resilience and security programs at any location.


(c) Approval of transfers of appropriations from Legislative Branch agencies(1) For carrying out the purposes of the account, the Architect of the Capitol may receive transfers of appropriations from any agency of the Legislative Branch upon the approval of—(A) the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, in the case of a transfer from an office of the House of Representatives;

(B) the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, in the case of a transfer from an office of the Senate; or

(C) the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, in the case of a transfer from any other office of the Government.


(2) Amounts transferred under this subsection shall be merged with the account and made available under this section.

(3) This subsection shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2019 and each succeeding fiscal year.


(d) Effective date; transfer of fundsThis section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year. Any amounts provided to the Architect of the Capitol prior to August 2, 2002, for the maintenance, care, and operation of buildings of the United States Capitol Police during fiscal year 2002 shall be transferred to the account.


(Pub. L. 107–206, title I, § 906,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States an account for the Architect of the Capitol to be known as “Capitol Police Buildings and Grounds” (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “account”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds Funds in the account shall be used by the Architect of the Capitol for all necessary expenses for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of transfers of appropriations from Legislative Branch agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Approval of transfers of appropriations from Legislative Branch agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date; transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date; transfer of funds This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year. Any amounts provided to the Architect of the Capitol prior to August 2, 2002, for the maintenance, care, and operation of buildings of the United States Capitol Police during fiscal year 2002 shall be transferred to the account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>