<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1905"><akn:num>1905</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit and use of reimbursements for law enforcement assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1905. Deposit and use of reimbursements for law enforcement assistance(a)(1) Any funds received by the Capitol Police as reimbursement for law enforcement assistance from any Federal, State, or local government agency (including any agency of the District of Columbia), and from any other source in the case of assistance provided in connection with an activity that was not sponsored by Congress shall be deposited in the United States Treasury for credit to the appropriation for “general expenses” under the heading “United States Capitol Police”, or “security enhancements” under the heading “United States Capitol Police”.

(2) Funds deposited under this subsection may be expended by the Chief of the United States Capitol Police for any authorized purpose, including overtime pay expenditures relating to any law enforcement assistance for which reimbursement described in paragraph (1) is made, and shall remain available until expended.


(b) This section shall take effect on July 24, 2001, and shall apply to fiscal year 2001 and each fiscal year thereafter.

(Pub. L. 107–20, title II, § 2802, July 24, 2001, 115 Stat. 184; Pub. L. 111–145, § 2(b)(1), Mar. 4, 2010, 124 Stat. 51; Pub. L. 114–113, div. I, title I, § 1001(a), (b), Dec. 18, 2015, 129 Stat. 2663.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was classified to section 207e of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by Pub. L. 107–217, § 1, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1062.
Section is from the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2001.

Amendments2015—Subsec. (a)(1). Pub. L. 114–113, § 1001(a), substituted “District of Columbia), and from any other source in the case of assistance provided in connection with an activity that was not sponsored by Congress” for “District of Columbia)”.
Subsec. (a)(2). Pub. L. 114–113, § 1001(b), substituted “any law enforcement assistance for which reimbursement described in paragraph (1) is made” for “law enforcement assistance to any Feder</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) This section shall take effect on July 24, 2001, and shall apply to fiscal year 2001 and each fiscal year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>