<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1907"><akn:num>1907</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of disbursing function</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1907. Transfer of disbursing function(a) In general(1) Disbursing officerThe Chief of the Capitol Police shall be the disbursing officer for the Capitol Police. Any reference in any law or resolution before February 20, 2003, to funds paid or disbursed by the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate relating to the pay and allowances of Capitol Police employees shall be deemed to refer to the Chief of the Capitol Police.


(2) TransferAny statutory function, duty, or authority of the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate as disbursing officers for the Capitol Police shall transfer to the Chief of the Capitol Police as the single disbursing officer for the Capitol Police.


(3) Continuity of function during transitionUntil such time as the Chief notifies the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate that systems are in place for discharging the disbursing functions under this subsection, the House of Representatives and the Senate shall continue to serve as the disbursing authority on behalf of the Capitol Police.



(b) Treasury accounts(1) Salaries(A) In generalThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a separate account for the Capitol Police, into which shall be deposited appropriations received by the Chief of the Capitol Police and available for the salaries of the Capitol Police.


(B) Transfer authority during transitionUntil such time as the Chief notifies the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate that systems are in place for discharging the disbursing functions under subsection (a), the Chief shall have the authority to transfer amounts in the account to the House of Representatives and the Senate to the extent necessary to enable the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate to c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treasury accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treasury accounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of funds, assets, accounts, records, and authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer of funds, assets, accounts, records, and authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1907_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unexpended balances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Unexpended balances Except as may otherwise be provided in law, the unexpended balances of appropriations for the fiscal year 2003 and succeeding fiscal years that are subject to disbursement by the Chief of the Capitol Police shall be withdrawn as of September 30 of the fifth fiscal year following the period or year for which provided. Unpaid obligations chargeable to any of the balances so withdrawn or appropriations for prior years shall be liquidated from any appropriations for the same general purpose, which, at the time of payment, are available for disbursement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1907_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hiring authority; eligibility for same benefits as House employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Hiring authority; eligibility for same benefits as House employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1907_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 113–76, div. I, title I, § 1002(b), Jan. 17, 2014, 128 Stat. 424</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1907_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on existing law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect on existing law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1907_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1907_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Effective date This section and the amendments made by this section shall take effect on February 20, 2003, and shall apply to fiscal year 2003 and each fiscal year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>