<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1911" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1911/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1911/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1911"><akn:num>1911</akn:num><akn:heading>General Counsel to the Chief of Police and the United States Capitol Police</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1911. General Counsel to the Chief of Police and the United States Capitol Police(1) In generalThere shall be within the United States Capitol Police the General Counsel to the Chief of Police and the United States Capitol Police (in this subsection referred to as the “General Counsel”), who shall report to and serve at the pleasure of the Chief of the United States Capitol Police.


(2) AppointmentThe General Counsel shall be appointed by the Chief of the Capitol Police in accordance with section 1907(e)(1) of this title (as amended by section 2(a)(4)),11 See References in Text note below. after consultation with the Capitol Police Board, without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the position.


(3) Compensation(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B), the annual rate of pay for the General Counsel shall be fixed by the Chief of the Capitol Police.


(B) LimitationThe annual rate of pay for the General Counsel may not exceed an annual rate equal to $1,000 less than the annual rate of pay in effect for the Chief of the Capitol Police.



(4) Omitted

(5) No effect on current General CounselNothing in this section or the amendments made by this section may be construed to affect the status of the individual serving as the General Counsel to the Chief of Police and the United States Capitol Police as of March 4, 2010.


(Pub. L. 111–145, § 3(a), Mar. 4, 2010, 124 Stat. 51.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 2(a)(4), referred to in par. (2), means section 2(a)(4) of Pub. L. 111–145.
For the amendments made by this section, referred to in par. (5), see Codification note below.

Codification
Section is comprised of subsec. (a) of section 3 of Pub. L. 111–145. Subsec. (a)(4) of section 3 of Pub. L. 111–145 repealed section 84–2 of this title, now section 5521 of this title, and provisions set out as a note under section 1901 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1911_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) In general There shall be within the United States Capitol Police the General Counsel to the Chief of Police and the United States Capitol Police (in this subsection referred to as the “General Counsel”), who shall report to and serve at the pleasure of the Chief of the United States Capitol Police.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1911_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appointment The General Counsel shall be appointed by the Chief of the Capitol Police in accordance with section 1907(e)(1) of this title (as amended by section 2(a)(4)),11 See References in Text note below. after consultation with the Capitol Police Board, without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the position.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1911_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1911_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1911_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>No effect on current General Counsel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) No effect on current General Counsel Nothing in this section or the amendments made by this section may be construed to affect the status of the individual serving as the General Counsel to the Chief of Police and the United States Capitol Police as of March 4, 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>