<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1927" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1927/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1927/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1927"><akn:num>1927</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonuses, retention allowances, and additional compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1927. Bonuses, retention allowances, and additional compensation(a) Recruitment and relocation bonuses(1) Authorization of paymentThe Capitol Police Board (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Board”) may authorize the Chief of the United States Capitol Police (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Chief”) to pay a bonus to an individual who is newly appointed to a position as an officer or employee of the Capitol Police, and to pay an additional bonus to an individual who must relocate to accept a position as an officer or employee of the Capitol Police, if the Chief, in the Chief’s sole discretion, determines that such a bonus will assist the Capitol Police in recruitment efforts.


(2) Amount of paymentThe amount of a bonus under this subsection shall be determined by regulations of the Board, but the amount of any bonus paid to an individual under this subsection may not exceed 25 percent of the annual rate of basic pay of the position to which the individual is being appointed.


(3) Minimum period of service requiredPayment of a bonus under this subsection shall be contingent upon the individual entering into an agreement with the Capitol Police to complete a period of employment with the Capitol Police, with the required period determined pursuant to regulations of the Board. If the individual voluntarily fails to complete such period of service or is separated from the service before completion of such period of service for cause on charges of misconduct or delinquency, the individual shall repay the bonus on a pro rata basis.


(4) Bonus not considered part of basic payA bonus under this subsection shall be paid as a lump sum, and may not be considered to be part of the basic pay of the officer or employee.


(5) Payment permitted prior to commencement of dutyUnder regulations of the Board, a bonus under this subsection may be paid to a newly-hired officer or employee before the officer or employee enters on duty.


(6) Determination not </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recruitment and relocation bonuses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recruitment and relocation bonuses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Retention allowances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lump sum incentive and merit bonus payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Lump sum incentive and merit bonus payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service step increases for meritorious service for officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Service step increases for meritorious service for officers Upon the approval of the Chief—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective date This section shall apply with respect to fiscal year 2002 and each succeeding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>