<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1974" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1974/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1974/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1974"><akn:num>1974</akn:num><akn:heading>Capitol Police special officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1974. Capitol Police special officers(a) In generalIn the event of an emergency, as determined by the Capitol Police Board or in a concurrent resolution of Congress, or as determined by the Chief of the Capitol Police in accordance with section 1970(a)(4)(B)(ii)(III) of this title, the Chief of the Capitol Police may appoint—(1) any law enforcement officer from any Federal agency or State or local government agency made available by that agency to serve as a special officer of the Capitol Police within the authorities of the Capitol Police in policing the Capitol buildings and grounds; and

(2) any member of the uniformed services, including members of the National Guard, made available by the appropriate authority to serve as a special officer of the Capitol Police within the authorities of the Capitol Police in policing the Capitol buildings and grounds.


An appointment under this section due to an emergency determined by the Chief of the Capitol Police under paragraph (4)(B)(ii)(III) of section 1970(a) of this title shall be in effect for the period of the emergency, unless and until the Capitol Police Board revokes the request for assistance under paragraph (5) of such section.

(b) Conditions of appointmentAn individual appointed as a special officer under this section shall—(1) serve without pay for service performed as a special officer (other than pay received from the applicable employing agency or service);

(2) serve as a special officer no longer than a period specified at the time of appointment;

(3) not be a Federal employee by reason of service as a special officer, except as provided under paragraph (4); and

(4) shall be an employee of the Government for purposes of chapter 171 of title 28 if that individual is acting within the scope of his office or employment in service as a special officer.


(c) Reimbursement agreementsNothing in this section shall prohibit the Capitol Police from entering into an agreement for the reimbursement of services</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1974_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the event of an emergency, as determined by the Capitol Police Board or in a concurrent resolution of Congress, or as determined by the Chief of the Capitol Police in accordance with section 1970(a)(4)(B)(ii)(III) of this title, the Chief of the Capitol Police may appoint— An appointment under this section due to an emergency determined by the Chief of the Capitol Police under paragraph (4)(B)(ii)(III) of section 1970(a) of this title shall be in effect for the period of the emergency, unless and until the Capitol Police Board revokes the request for assistance under paragraph (5) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1974_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conditions of appointment An individual appointed as a special officer under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1974_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reimbursement agreements Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Capitol Police from entering into an agreement for the reimbursement of services provided under this section with any Federal, State, or local agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1974_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations Subject to approval by the Speaker of the House of Representatives (in consultation with the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives) and the Majority Leader of the Senate (in consultation with the Minority Leader of the Senate), acting jointly, the Capitol Police Board may prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1974_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date This section shall take effect on February 20, 2003, and shall apply to fiscal year 2003 and each fiscal year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>