<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1979" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1979/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/1979/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1979"><akn:num>1979</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of security information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1979. Release of security information(a) DefinitionIn this section, the term “security information” means information that—(1) is sensitive with respect to the policing, protection, physical security, intelligence, counterterrorism actions, or emergency preparedness and response relating to Congress, any statutory protectee of the Capitol Police, and the Capitol buildings and grounds; and

(2) is obtained by, on behalf of, or concerning the Capitol Police Board, the Capitol Police, or any incident command relating to emergency response.


(b) Authority of Board to determine conditions of releaseNotwithstanding any other provision of law, any security information in the possession of the Capitol Police may be released by the Capitol Police to another entity, including an individual, only if the Capitol Police Board determines in consultation with other appropriate law enforcement officials, experts in security preparedness, and appropriate committees of Congress, that the release of the security information will not compromise the security and safety of the Capitol buildings and grounds or any individual whose protection and safety is under the jurisdiction of the Capitol Police.


(c) Rule of constructionNothing in this section may be construed to affect the ability of the Senate and the House of Representatives (including any Member, officer, or committee of either House of Congress) to obtain information from the Capitol Police regarding the operations and activities of the Capitol Police that affect the Senate and House of Representatives.


(d) RegulationsThe Capitol Police Board may promulgate regulations to carry out this section, with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.


(e) Effective dateThis section shall take effect on December 8, 2004, and apply with respect to—(1) any remaining portion of fiscal year 2004, if this Act is enacted before Octobe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1979_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition In this section, the term “security information” means information that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1979_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Board to determine conditions of release</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority of Board to determine conditions of release Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any security information in the possession of the Capitol Police may be released by the Capitol Police to another entity, including an individual, only if the Capitol Police Board determines in consultation with other appropriate law enforcement officials, experts in security preparedness, and appropriate committees of Congress, that the release of the security information will not compromise the security and safety of the Capitol buildings and grounds or any individual whose protection and safety is under the jurisdiction of the Capitol Police.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1979_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construed to affect the ability of the Senate and the House of Representatives (including any Member, officer, or committee of either House of Congress) to obtain information from the Capitol Police regarding the operations and activities of the Capitol Police that affect the Senate and House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1979_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations The Capitol Police Board may promulgate regulations to carry out this section, with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1979_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date This section shall take effect on December 8, 2004, and apply with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>