<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2009" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2009/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2009/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2009"><akn:num>2009</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of rooms to Commissioner from Puerto Rico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2009. Assignment of rooms to Commissioner from Puerto Rico
In the matter of the assignment of rooms under sections 2004 to 2011 of this title, Delegates in Congress and the Commissioner from Puerto Rico shall be treated the same as Representatives.
(May 28, 1908, No. 30, 35 Stat. 579; May 17, 1932, ch. 190, 47 Stat. 158; Proc. No. 2695, eff. July 4, 1946, 11 F.R. 7517, 60 Stat. 1352.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was classified to section 182 of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by Pub. L. 107–217, § 1, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1062.
Words “and the Philippine Islands” after “Puerto Rico” were omitted pursuant to 1946 Proc. No. 2695, eff. July 4, 1946, 11 F.R. 7517, 60 Stat. 1352, which granted independence to the Philippine Islands on July 4, 1946, under the authority of act Mar. 24, 1934, ch. 84, § 10, 48 Stat. 463, as amended, which is classified to section 1394 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
“Puerto Rico” substituted in text for “Porto Rico” pursuant to act May 17, 1932, which is classified to section 731a of Title 48, Territories and Insular Possessions.

Commissioner From Puerto Rico as Resident CommissionerSection 2106 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, provides that the term “Members of Congress” shall include the “Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>