<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/201...226" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/201...226/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/201...226/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_201___226"><akn:num>201...226</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 91–138, § 18, Dec. 5, 1969, 83 Stat. 290</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 201 to 226. Repealed. Pub. L. 91–138, § 18, Dec. 5, 1969, 83 Stat. 290

The subject matter of former sections 201 to 226 of this title is covered generally by chapter 12 of this title.


Section 201, R.S. § 105, provided that whenever any person intended to contest an election of any member of House of Representatives he had to give notice in writing to that member within thirty days of result of such election.


Section 202, R.S. § 106, provided that a member of House of Representatives whose election was contested serve an answer within thirty days after service of notice upon him.


Section 203, R.S. § 107; Mar. 2, 1875, ch. 119, § 2, 18 Stat. 338, provided time and order for taking testimony.


Section 204, R.S. § 108, provided for taking of depositions upon notice to other party.


Section 205, R.S. § 109, provided that testimony in contested election cases could be taken at two or more places at same time.


Section 206, R.S. § 110; June 7, 1878, ch. 160, 20 Stat. 99; July 1, 1898, ch. 541, § 38, 30 Stat. 555, made provision for issuance of subpoenas by specified officers.


Section 207, R.S. § 111, set forth requisite contents of subpoenas.


Section 208, R.S. § 112, authorized issuance of subpoenas by justices of the peace.


Section 209, R.S. § 113, made provision for taking of depositions by written consent.


Section 210, R.S. § 114, required that each witness be served with a subpoena at least five days prior to date he was required to attend.


Section 211, R.S. § 115, exempted witness from attendance at examinations out of county in which they resided or were served with a subpoena.


Section 212, R.S. § 116, mandated a $20 penalty to be recovered by party issuing subpoena, and a possible indictment for a misdemeanor, for failure of party summoned to attend or testify, unless prevented by sickness or unavoidable necessity.


Section 213, R.S. § 117, provided that depositions of witnesses residing outside district be taken before any officer authoriz</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>