<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2021"><akn:num>2021</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Senate office building</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2021. Additional Senate office building
Upon completion of the additional office building for the United States Senate, the building and the grounds and sidewalks surrounding the same shall be subject to the provisions of sections 1922, 1961, 1966, 1967, 1969, 2023, and 2024 of this title and sections 5101 to 5107 and 5109 of title 40, in the same manner and to the same extent as the present Senate Office Building and the grounds and sidewalks surrounding the same.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 658, title I, 62 Stat. 1029.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSections 1922, 1961, 1966, 1967, and 1969 of this title and sections 5101 to 5107 and 5109 of title 40, referred to in text, was in the original a reference to the Act of July 31, 1946, ch. 707, 60 Stat. 718. Sections 9, 9A, 9B, 9C, and 14 of the Act are classified, respectively, to sections 1961, 1966, 1967, 1922, and 1969 of this title, and section 16(b) of the Act is set out as a note under section 1961 of this title. Sections 1 to 8, 10 to 13, and 16(a) of the Act, which were classified to sections 193a to 193m of former Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, were repealed and reenacted as sections 5101 to 5107 and 5109 of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by Pub. L. 107–217, §§ 1, 6(b), Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1062, 1312, the first section of which enacted Title 40. Section 5(c) of Pub. L. 107–217, set out as a note preceding section 101 of Title 40, provides that a reference to a law replaced by section 1 of Pub. L. 107–217 is deemed to refer to the corresponding provision enacted by Pub. L. 107–217. For complete classification of the act of July 31, 1946, to the Code, see Tables. For disposition of sections of former Title 40, see table at the beginning of Title 40.
Sections 2023 and 2024 of this title, referred to in text, was in the original a reference to “the Act of June 8, 1942 (U.S.C., title 40, sec. 174(c) and (d))”, which, to reflect the probable intent of Congress, was translat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>