<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2105"><akn:num>2105</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2105. Authorization of appropriations
There is hereby authorized to be appropriated out of the contingent fund of the Senate for the expenses of the Commission such amount as may be necessary each fiscal year, to be disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate on vouchers signed by the Executive Secretary of the Commission and approved by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate: Provided, That no payment shall be made from such appropriation as salary.
(Pub. L. 100–696, title IX, § 901(a), Nov. 18, 1988, 102 Stat. 4610; Pub. L. 107–68, title I, § 108(b), Nov. 12, 2001, 115 Stat. 569.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was classified to section 188b–4 of former Title 40, prior to the enactment of Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works, by Pub. L. 107–217, § 1, Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1062.
Section is based on section 5 of Senate Resolution No. 382, Ninetieth Congress, Oct. 1, 1968, which was enacted into permanent law by Pub. L. 100–696.

Amendments2001—Pub. L. 107–68 substituted “such amount as may be necessary each fiscal year,” for “the sum of $15,000 each fiscal year,” and “the Executive Secretary of the Commission and approved by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate” for “the Chairman or Vice Chairman of the Commission”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2001 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 107–68 applicable to fiscal year 2002 and all succeeding fiscal years, see section 108(c) of Pub. L. 107–68, set out as a note under section 2103 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>