<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2108"><akn:num>2108</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to Senate Commission on Art</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2108. Provisions relating to Senate Commission on Art(a) Authority to acquire and dispose(1) In generalThe Senate Commission on Art (referred to in this section as the “Commission”) may—(A) accept gifts of money; and

(B) acquire (by gift, purchase, or otherwise) any work of art, historical object, document, or material relating to historical matters, or exhibit, for placement or exhibition in the Senate Wing of the Capitol, the Senate Office Buildings, or in rooms, spaces, or corridors thereof.


(2) Accession or disposalAll works of art, historical objects, documents, or material related to historical matters, or exhibits, acquired by the Commission may, as determined by the Commission and after consultation with the Curatorial Advisory Board, be—(A) retained for accession to the United States Senate Collection or other use; or

(B) disposed of by sale or other transaction.


(3) Omitted


(b) Advisory boards(1) Curatorial Advisory BoardThere is established a Board which shall be chaired by the Senate Curator. The Curatorial Advisory Board shall provide advice and assistance to the Commission on the acquisition, care, and disposition of items for or within the United States Senate Collection, and on such other matters as the Commission determines appropriate.


(2) Additional advisory boards(A) In generalThe Commission, or the chairman and vice chairman acting jointly on behalf of the Commission and after giving notice to the Commission, may establish 1 or more additional advisory boards.


(B) TermThe term of existence for an additional advisory board—(i) shall be specified by the Commission but no longer than 4 years; and

(ii) shall be renewable.


(C) PurposeThe purpose of an additional advisory board shall be to provide advice and assistance to the Commission and to further the purposes of the Commission.



(3) Appointments(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B), the Curatorial Advisory Board and other advisory boards established by the Commission under </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to acquire and dispose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to acquire and dispose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advisory boards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Senate Preservation Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of Senate Preservation Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>