<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2212"><akn:num>2212</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and supervision of Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2212. Appointment and supervision of Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services(a) AppointmentThe Chief Executive Officer shall be appointed by the Architect of the Capitol.


(b) Supervision and oversightThe Chief Executive Officer shall report directly to the Architect of the Capitol and shall be subject to oversight by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.


(c) RemovalUpon removal of the Chief Executive Officer, the Architect of the Capitol shall immediately provide notice of the removal to the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate. The notice shall include the reasons for the removal.


(d) CompensationThe Chief Executive Officer shall be paid at an annual rate of pay equal to the annual rate of pay of the Deputy Architect of the Capitol.


(e) Transition for current Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services(1) AppointmentThe individual who serves as the Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services under section 1806 of this title as of October 20, 2008, shall be the first Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services appointed by the Architect under this section.


(2) Omitted


(Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 202, Oct. 20, 2008, 122 Stat. 4986.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 1806 of this title, referred to in subsec. (e)(1), was repealed by Pub. L. 110–437, title II, § 202(e)(2), Oct. 20, 2008, 122 Stat. 4987.

Codification
Section is comprised of section 202 of Pub. L. 110–437. Subsec. (e)(2) of section 202 of Pub. L. 110–437 repealed section 1806 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment The Chief Executive Officer shall be appointed by the Architect of the Capitol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision and oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Supervision and oversight The Chief Executive Officer shall report directly to the Architect of the Capitol and shall be subject to oversight by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Removal Upon removal of the Chief Executive Officer, the Architect of the Capitol shall immediately provide notice of the removal to the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate. The notice shall include the reasons for the removal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation The Chief Executive Officer shall be paid at an annual rate of pay equal to the annual rate of pay of the Deputy Architect of the Capitol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition for current Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transition for current Chief Executive Officer for Visitor Services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>