<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2242" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2242/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2242/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2242"><akn:num>2242</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of employees of Capitol Guide Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2242. Duties of employees of Capitol Guide Service(a) Provision of guided tours(1) ToursIn accordance with this section, the Capitol Guide Service shall provide without charge guided tours of the interior of the United States Capitol, including the Capitol Visitor Center, for the education and enlightenment of the general public.


(2) Acceptance of fees prohibitedAn employee of the Capitol Guide Service shall not charge or accept any fee, or accept any gratuity, for or on account of the official services of that employee.


(3) Regulations of the Architect of the CapitolAll such tours shall be conducted in compliance with regulations approved by the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer.



(b) Authority of the Architect of the CapitolIn providing for the direction, supervision, and control of the Capitol Guide Service, the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, is authorized to—(1) subject to the availability of appropriations, establish and revise such number of positions of Guide in the Capitol Guide Service as the Architect of the Capitol considers necessary to carry out effectively the activities of the Capitol Guide Service;

(2) appoint, on a permanent basis without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform their duties, a Chief Guide and such deputies as the Architect of the Capitol considers appropriate for the effective administration of the Capitol Guide Service and, in addition, such number of Guides as may be authorized;

(3) with the approval of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, with respect to the individuals appointed under paragraph (2)—(A) prescribe the individual’s duties and responsibilities; and

(B) fix, and adjust from time to time, respective rates of pay at single per annum (gross) rates;


(4) with respect to the individuals appoi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of guided tours</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Provision of guided tours</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the Architect of the Capitol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority of the Architect of the Capitol In providing for the direction, supervision, and control of the Capitol Guide Service, the Architect of the Capitol, upon recommendation of the Chief Executive Officer, is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of accessible tours in coordination with Office of Congressional Accessibility Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provision of accessible tours in coordination with Office of Congressional Accessibility Services The Chief Executive Officer shall coordinate the provision of accessible tours for individuals with disabilities with the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services established under part B.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Detail of personnel The Architect of the Capitol shall detail personnel of the Capitol Guide Service based on a request from the Capitol Police Board to assist the United States Capitol Police by providing ushering and informational services, and other services not directly involving law enforcement, in connection with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date This section shall take effect on the transfer date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>