<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2273" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2273/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/2273/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2273"><akn:num>2273</akn:num><akn:heading>Coins treated as gifts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2273. Coins treated as gifts(a) DefinitionIn this section, the term “covered grounds” means—(1) the grounds described under section 5102 of title 40;

(2) the Capitol Buildings defined under section 5101 of title 40, including the Capitol Visitor Center; and

(3) the Library of Congress buildings and grounds described under section 167j of this title.


(b) Treatment of coinsIn the case of any coins in any fountains on covered grounds—(1) such coins shall be treated as gifts to the United States; and

(2) the Architect of the Capitol shall—(A) collect such coins at such times and in such manner as the Architect determines appropriate; and

(B) except as provided under subsection (c), deposit the collected coins in accordance with subsection (d).



(c) Cost reimbursementAny amount collected under this section shall first be used to reimburse the Architect of the Capitol for any costs incurred in the collection and processing of the coins, and maintaining fountains under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol. The amount of any such reimbursement is appropriated to the account from which such costs were paid and may be used for any authorized purpose of that account.


(d) Deposit of coinsThe Architect of the Capitol shall deposit coins collected under this section in the Miscellaneous Receipts Account of the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund established under section 2231 of this title.


(e) Authorized use and availabilityAmounts deposited in the Miscellaneous Receipts Account of the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund under this section shall be available as provided under section 2233(b) of this title.


(Pub. L. 110–437, title V, § 504, Oct. 20, 2008, 122 Stat. 4998; Pub. L. 117–103, div. I, title I, § 131, Mar. 15, 2022, 136 Stat. 516.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2022—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 117–103 inserted “, and maintaining fountains under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol” before period at end of first sentence.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2273_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition In this section, the term “covered grounds” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2273_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of coins</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treatment of coins In the case of any coins in any fountains on covered grounds—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2273_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cost reimbursement Any amount collected under this section shall first be used to reimburse the Architect of the Capitol for any costs incurred in the collection and processing of the coins, and maintaining fountains under the jurisdiction of the Architect of the Capitol. The amount of any such reimbursement is appropriated to the account from which such costs were paid and may be used for any authorized purpose of that account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2273_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of coins</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deposit of coins The Architect of the Capitol shall deposit coins collected under this section in the Miscellaneous Receipts Account of the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund established under section 2231 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2273_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized use and availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorized use and availability Amounts deposited in the Miscellaneous Receipts Account of the Capitol Visitor Center Revolving Fund under this section shall be available as provided under section 2233(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>