<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/274" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/274/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/274/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_274"><akn:num>274</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff; office equipment and supplies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 274. Staff; office equipment and supplies
The Legislative Counsel shall, subject to the approval of the President pro tempore of the Senate, employ and fix the compensation of such Assistant Counsel, clerks, and other employees, and purchase such furniture, office equipment, books, stationery, and other supplies, as may be necessary for the proper performance of the duties of the Office and as may be appropriated for by Congress.
(Feb. 24, 1919, ch. 18, title XIII, § 1303(a), (d), 40 Stat. 1141; June 2, 1924, ch. 234, title XI, § 1101, 43 Stat. 353; Sept. 20, 1941, ch. 412, title VI, § 602, 55 Stat. 726.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
As originally enacted, section also provided for legislative counsel of House of Representatives, subject to approval of Speaker, to employ and fix the compensation of assistant counsel, clerks, etc. In view of nonapplicability of section to Speaker, employee, etc., of the House of Representatives pursuant to section 531 of Pub. L. 91–510, set out as a note under section 281 of this title, section has been revised to limit applicability to authority of Legislative Counsel of the Senate. See section 282a et seq. of this title for provisions relating to appointment of staff, etc., for Office of Legislative Counsel of the House of Representatives.

Amendments1941—Act Sept. 20, 1941, substituted “President pro tempore of the Senate” for “President of the Senate”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Designation of Deputy Legislative CounselPub. L. 106–57, title I, § 6, Sept. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 412, provided that: “The Legislative Counsel may, subject to the approval of the President pro tempore of the Senate, designate one of the Senior Counsels appointed under section 102 of the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1979 (2 U.S.C. 274 note; Public Law 95–391; 92 Stat. 771) as Deputy Legislative Counsel. The Deputy Legislative Counsel shall perform the functions of the Legislative Counsel during the absence or disability of the Leg</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>