<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/28" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/28/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/28/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_28"><akn:num>28</akn:num><akn:heading>Parliamentary precedents of House of Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 28. Parliamentary precedents of House of Representatives(a) Periodic compilation; other useful materials; index digest; date of completionThe Parliamentarian of the House of Representatives, at the beginning of the fifth fiscal year following the completion and publication of the parliamentary precedents of the House authorized by the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1966 (79 Stat. 270; Public Law 89–90), and at the beginning of each fifth fiscal year thereafter, shall commence the compilation and preparation for printing of the parliamentary precedents of the House of Representatives, together with such other materials as may be useful in connection therewith, and an index digest of such precedents and other materials. Each such compilation and preparation for printing of the parliamentary precedents of the House shall be completed by the close of the fiscal year immediately following the fiscal year in which such work is commenced.


(b) Form, number, and distribution of compilationAs so compiled and prepared, such precedents and other materials and index digest shall be printed on pages of such size, and in such type and format, as the Parliamentarian may determine and shall be printed in such numbers and for such distribution as may be provided by law enacted prior to printing.


(c) Appointment and compensation of personnel; utilization of services of personnel of Federal agenciesFor the purpose of carrying out each such compilation and preparation, the Parliamentarian may—(1) subject to the approval of the Speaker, appoint (as employees of the House of Representatives) clerical and other personnel and fix their respective rates of pay; and

(2) utilize the services of personnel of the Library of Congress and the Government Publishing Office.


(Pub. L. 91–510, title III, § 331, Oct. 26, 1970, 84 Stat. 1186; Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(b), Dec. 16, 2014, 128 Stat. 2537.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Legislative Branch Appropriatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic compilation; other useful materials; index digest; date of completion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Periodic compilation; other useful materials; index digest; date of completion The Parliamentarian of the House of Representatives, at the beginning of the fifth fiscal year following the completion and publication of the parliamentary precedents of the House authorized by the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1966 (79 Stat. 270; Public Law 89–90), and at the beginning of each fifth fiscal year thereafter, shall commence the compilation and preparation for printing of the parliamentary precedents of the House of Representatives, together with such other materials as may be useful in connection therewith, and an index digest of such precedents and other materials. Each such compilation and preparation for printing of the parliamentary precedents of the House shall be completed by the close of the fiscal year immediately following the fiscal year in which such work is commenced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form, number, and distribution of compilation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form, number, and distribution of compilation As so compiled and prepared, such precedents and other materials and index digest shall be printed on pages of such size, and in such type and format, as the Parliamentarian may determine and shall be printed in such numbers and for such distribution as may be provided by law enacted prior to printing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_28_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and compensation of personnel; utilization of services of personnel of Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appointment and compensation of personnel; utilization of services of personnel of Federal agencies For the purpose of carrying out each such compilation and preparation, the Parliamentarian may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>