<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/288" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/288/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/288/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_288"><akn:num>288</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Senate Legal Counsel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 288. Office of Senate Legal Counsel(a) Establishment; appointment of Counsel and Deputy Counsel; Senate approval; reappointment; compensation(1) There is established, as an office of the Senate, the Office of Senate Legal Counsel (hereinafter referred to as the “Office”), which shall be headed by a Senate Legal Counsel (hereinafter referred to as the “Counsel”); and there shall be a Deputy Senate Legal Counsel (hereinafter referred to as the “Deputy Counsel”) who shall perform such duties as may be assigned to him by the Counsel and who, during any absence, disability, or vacancy in the position of the Counsel, shall serve as Acting Senate Legal Counsel.

(2) The Counsel and the Deputy Counsel each shall be appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate from among recommendations submitted by the majority and minority leaders of the Senate. Any appointment made under this paragraph shall be made without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of the position. Any person appointed as Counsel or Deputy Counsel shall be learned in the law, a member of the bar of a State or the District of Columbia, and shall not engage in any other business, vocation, or employment during the term of such appointment.

(3)(A) Any appointment made under paragraph (2) shall become effective upon approval by resolution of the Senate. The Counsel and the Deputy Counsel shall each be appointed for a term of service which shall expire at the end of the Congress following the Congress during which the Counsel or Deputy Counsel, respectively, is appointed except that the Senate may, by resolution, remove either the Counsel or the Deputy Counsel prior to the termination of any term of service. The Counsel and the Deputy Counsel may be reappointed at the termination of any term of service.

(B) The first Counsel and the first Deputy Counsel shall be appointed, approved, and begin service within ninety days after January 3, 1979, and therea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; appointment of Counsel and Deputy Counsel; Senate approval; reappointment; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; appointment of Counsel and Deputy Counsel; Senate approval; reappointment; compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant counsels and other personnel; compensation; appointment; removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assistant counsels and other personnel; compensation; appointment; removal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultants In carrying out the functions of the Office, the Counsel may procure the temporary (not to exceed one year) or intermittent services of individual consultants (including outside counsel), or organizations thereof, in the same manner and under the same conditions as a standing committee of the Senate may procure such services under section 4301(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policies and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Policies and procedures The Counsel may establish such policies and procedures as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Delegation of duties The counsel 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. may delegate authority for the performance of any function imposed by this chapter except any function imposed upon the Counsel under section 288e(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney-client relationship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Attorney-client relationship The Counsel and other employees of the Office shall maintain the attorney-client relationship with respect to all communications between them and any Member, officer, or employee of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>