<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/288d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/288d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/288d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_288d"><akn:num>288d</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of Senate subpena or order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 288d. Enforcement of Senate subpena or order(a) Institution of civil actionsWhen directed to do so pursuant to section 288b(b) of this title, the Counsel shall bring a civil action under any statute conferring jurisdiction on any court of the United States (including section 1365 of title 28), to enforce, to secure a declaratory judgment concerning the validity of, or to prevent a threatened failure or refusal to comply with, any subpena or order issued by the Senate or a committee or a subcommittee of the Senate authorized to issue a subpena or order.


(b) Actions in name of committees and subcommitteesAny directive to the Counsel to bring a civil action pursuant to subsection (a) in the name of a committee or subcommittee of the Senate shall, for such committee or subcommittee, constitute authorization to bring such action within the meaning of any statute conferring jurisdiction on any court of the United States.


(c) Consideration of resolutions authorizing actionsIt shall not be in order in the Senate to consider a resolution to direct the Counsel to bring a civil action pursuant to subsection (a) in the name of a committee or subcommittee unless—(1) such resolution is reported by a majority of the members voting, a majority being present, of such committee or committee of which such subcommittee is a subcommittee, and

(2) the report filed by such committee or committee of which such subcommittee is a subcommittee contains a statement of—(A) the procedure followed in issuing such subpena;

(B) the extent to which the party sub­penaed has complied with such subpena;

(C) any objections or privileges raised by the subpenaed party; and

(D) the comparative effectiveness of bringing a civil action under this section, certification of a criminal action for contempt of Congress, and initiating a contempt proceeding before the Senate.



(d) Rules of SenateThe provisions of subsection (c) are enacted—(1) as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate, and, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Institution of civil actions When directed to do so pursuant to section 288b(b) of this title, the Counsel shall bring a civil action under any statute conferring jurisdiction on any court of the United States (including section 1365 of title 28), to enforce, to secure a declaratory judgment concerning the validity of, or to prevent a threatened failure or refusal to comply with, any subpena or order issued by the Senate or a committee or a subcommittee of the Senate authorized to issue a subpena or order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions in name of committees and subcommittees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Actions in name of committees and subcommittees Any directive to the Counsel to bring a civil action pursuant to subsection (a) in the name of a committee or subcommittee of the Senate shall, for such committee or subcommittee, constitute authorization to bring such action within the meaning of any statute conferring jurisdiction on any court of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of resolutions authorizing actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consideration of resolutions authorizing actions It shall not be in order in the Senate to consider a resolution to direct the Counsel to bring a civil action pursuant to subsection (a) in the name of a committee or subcommittee unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of Senate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rules of Senate The provisions of subsection (c) are enacted—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Committee reports A report filed pursuant to subsection (c)(2) shall not be receivable in any court of law to the extent such report is in compliance with such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of failure to testify; contempt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certification of failure to testify; contempt Nothing in this section shall limit the discretion of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>