<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/288i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/288i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/288i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_288i"><akn:num>288i</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation conflict or inconsistency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 288i. Representation conflict or inconsistency(a) NotificationIn the carrying out of the provisions of this chapter, the Counsel shall notify the Joint Leadership Group, and any party represented or person affected, of the existence and nature of any conflict or inconsistency between the representation of such party or person and the carrying out of any other provision of this chapter or compliance with professional standards and responsibilities.


(b) Solution; publication in Congressional Record; reviewUpon receipt of such notification, the members of the Joint Leadership Group shall recommend the action to be taken to avoid or resolve the conflict or inconsistency. If such recommendation is made by a two-thirds vote, the Counsel shall take such steps as may be necessary to resolve the conflict or inconsistency as recommended. If not, the members of the Joint Leadership Group shall cause the notification of conflict or inconsistency and recommendation with respect to resolution thereof to be published in the Congressional Record of the Senate. If the Senate does not direct the Counsel within fifteen days from the date of publication in the Record to resolve the conflict in another manner, the Counsel shall take such action as may be necessary to resolve the conflict or inconsistency as recommended. Any instruction or determination made pursuant to this subsection shall not be reviewable in any court of law.


(c) Computation of period following publicationFor purposes of the computation of the fifteen day period in subsection (b)—(1) continuity of session is broken only by an adjournment of Congress sine die; and

(2) the days on which the Senate is not in session because of an adjournment of more than three days to a date certain are excluded.


(d) ReimbursementThe Senate may by resolution authorize the reimbursement of any Member, officer, or employee of the Senate who is not represented by the Counsel for fees and costs, including attorneys’ fees, reasonabl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notification In the carrying out of the provisions of this chapter, the Counsel shall notify the Joint Leadership Group, and any party represented or person affected, of the existence and nature of any conflict or inconsistency between the representation of such party or person and the carrying out of any other provision of this chapter or compliance with professional standards and responsibilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solution; publication in Congressional Record; review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Solution; publication in Congressional Record; review Upon receipt of such notification, the members of the Joint Leadership Group shall recommend the action to be taken to avoid or resolve the conflict or inconsistency. If such recommendation is made by a two-thirds vote, the Counsel shall take such steps as may be necessary to resolve the conflict or inconsistency as recommended. If not, the members of the Joint Leadership Group shall cause the notification of conflict or inconsistency and recommendation with respect to resolution thereof to be published in the Congressional Record of the Senate. If the Senate does not direct the Counsel within fifteen days from the date of publication in the Record to resolve the conflict in another manner, the Counsel shall take such action as may be necessary to resolve the conflict or inconsistency as recommended. Any instruction or determination made pursuant to this subsection shall not be reviewable in any court of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of period following publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Computation of period following publication For purposes of the computation of the fifteen day period in subsection (b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reimbursement The Senate may by resolution authorize the reimbursement of any Member, officer, or employee of the Senate who is not represented by the Counsel for fees and costs, including attorneys’ fees, reasonably incurred in obtaining representation. Such reimbursement shall be from funds appropriated to the contingent fund of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>