<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/29a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/29a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/29a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_29a"><akn:num>29a</akn:num><akn:heading>Early organization of House of Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 29a. Early organization of House of Representatives(a) Caucus or conference for incumbent Members reelected to and Members-elect of ensuing Congress; time and procedure for calling(1) The majority leader or minority leader of the House of Representatives after consultation with the Speaker may at any time during any even-numbered year call a caucus or conference of all incumbent Members of his or her political party who have been reelected to the ensuing Congress and all other Members-elect of such party, for the purpose of taking all steps necessary to achieve the prompt organization of the Members and Members-elect of such party for the ensuing Congress.

(2) If the majority leader or minority leader calls an organizational caucus or conference under paragraph (1), he or she shall file with the Clerk of the House a written notice designating the date upon which the caucus or conference is to convene. As soon as possible after the election of Members to the ensuing Congress, the Clerk shall furnish each Member-elect of the party involved with appropriate written notification of the caucus or conference.

(3) If a vacancy occurs in the office of majority leader or minority leader during any even-numbered year (and has not been filled), the chairman of the caucus or conference of the party involved for the current Congress may call an organizational caucus or conference under paragraph (1) by filing written notice thereof as provided by paragraph (2).


(b) Payment and reimbursement for travel and per diem expenses for Members attending caucus or conference; exceptions; regulations governing payments and reimbursements; reimbursement vouchers(1)(A) Each Member-elect (other than an incumbent Member reelected to the ensuing Congress) who attends a caucus or conference called under subsection (a), and each incumbent Member reelected to the ensuing Congress who attends any such caucus or conference convening after the adjournment sine die of the Congress in the year in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Caucus or conference for incumbent Members reelected to and Members-elect of ensuing Congress; time and procedure for calling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Caucus or conference for incumbent Members reelected to and Members-elect of ensuing Congress; time and procedure for calling</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment and reimbursement for travel and per diem expenses for Members attending caucus or conference; exceptions; regulations governing payments and reimbursements; reimbursement vouchers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment and reimbursement for travel and per diem expenses for Members attending caucus or conference; exceptions; regulations governing payments and reimbursements; reimbursement vouchers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of applicable accounts of House</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of applicable accounts of House The applicable accounts of the House of Representatives are made available to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_29a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Orientation programs for new Members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Orientation programs for new Members With the approval of the majority leader (in the case of a Member or Member-elect of the majority party) or the minority leader (in the case of a Member or Member-elect of the minority party), subsections (b) and (c) shall apply with respect to the attendance of a Member or Member-elect at a program conducted by the Committee on House Administration for the orientation of new members 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. in the same manner as such provisions apply to the attendance of the Member or Member-elect at the organizational caucus or conference.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>