<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/352" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/352/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/352/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_352"><akn:num>352</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 352. Membership(1) The Commission shall be composed of 11 members, who shall be appointed from private life as follows:(A) 2 appointed by the President of the United States;

(B) 1 appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate, upon the recommendation of the majority and minority leaders of the Senate;

(C) 1 appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives;

(D) 2 appointed by the Chief Justice of the United States; and

(E) 5 appointed by the Administrator of General Services in accordance with paragraph (4).


(2) No person shall serve as a member of the Commission who is—(A) an officer or employee of the Federal Government;

(B) registered (or required to register) under the Federal Regulation of Lobbying Act; 11 See References in Text note below. or

(C) a parent, sibling, spouse, child, or dependent relative, of anyone under subparagraph (A) or (B).


(3) The persons appointed under subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1) shall be selected without regard to political affiliation, and should be selected from among persons who have experience or expertise in such areas as government, personnel management, or public administration.

(4) The Administrator of General Services shall by regulation establish procedures under which persons shall be selected for appointment under paragraph (1)(E). Such procedures—(A) shall be designed in such a way so as to provide for the maximum degree of geographic diversity practicable among members under paragraph (1)(E);

(B) shall include provisions under which those members shall be chosen by lot from among names randomly selected from voter registration lists; and

(C) shall otherwise comply with applicable provisions of this section.


(5) The chairperson shall be designated by the President.

(6) A vacancy in the membership of the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.

(7) Each member of the Commission shall be paid at the rate of $100 for each day such me</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The Commission shall be composed of 11 members, who shall be appointed from private life as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) No person shall serve as a member of the Commission who is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The persons appointed under subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1) shall be selected without regard to political affiliation, and should be selected from among persons who have experience or expertise in such areas as government, personnel management, or public administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The Administrator of General Services shall by regulation establish procedures under which persons shall be selected for appointment under paragraph (1)(E). Such procedures—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The chairperson shall be designated by the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) A vacancy in the membership of the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Each member of the Commission shall be paid at the rate of $100 for each day such member is engaged upon the work of the Commission and shall be allowed travel expenses, including a per diem allowance, in accordance with section 5703 of title 5, when engaged in the performance of services for the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>