<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/383" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/383/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/383/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_383"><akn:num>383</akn:num><akn:heading>Response of contestee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 383. Response of contestee(a) AnswerAny contestee upon whom a notice of contest as described in section 382 of this title shall be served, shall, within thirty days after the service thereof, serve upon contestant a written answer to such notice, admitting or denying the averments upon which contestant relies. If contestee is without knowledge or information sufficient to form a belief as to the truth of an averment, he shall so state and this shall have the effect of a denial. Such answer shall set forth affirmatively any other defenses, in law or fact, on which contestee relies. Contestee shall sign and verify such answer by oath or affirmation.


(b) Defenses by motion prior to answerAt the option of contestee, the following defenses may be made by motion served upon contestant prior to contestee’s answer:(1) Insufficiency of service of notice of contest.

(2) Lack of standing of contestant.

(3) Failure of notice of contest to state grounds sufficient to change result of election.

(4) Failure of contestant to claim right to contestee’s seat.


(c) Motion for more definite statementIf a notice of contest to which an answer is required is so vague or ambiguous that the contestee cannot reasonably be required to frame a responsive answer, he may move for a more definite statement before interposing his answer. The motion shall point out the defects complained of and the details desired. If the motion is granted and the order of the committee is not obeyed within ten days after notice of the order or within such other time as the committee may fix, the committee may dismiss the action, or make such order as it deems just.


(d) Time for serving answer after service of motionService of a motion permitted under this section alters the time for serving the answer as follows, unless a different time is fixed by order of the committee: If the committee denies the motion or postpones its disposition until the hearing on the merits, the answer shall be served within ten</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_383_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Answer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Answer Any contestee upon whom a notice of contest as described in section 382 of this title shall be served, shall, within thirty days after the service thereof, serve upon contestant a written answer to such notice, admitting or denying the averments upon which contestant relies. If contestee is without knowledge or information sufficient to form a belief as to the truth of an averment, he shall so state and this shall have the effect of a denial. Such answer shall set forth affirmatively any other defenses, in law or fact, on which contestee relies. Contestee shall sign and verify such answer by oath or affirmation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_383_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defenses by motion prior to answer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Defenses by motion prior to answer At the option of contestee, the following defenses may be made by motion served upon contestant prior to contestee’s answer:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_383_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motion for more definite statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Motion for more definite statement If a notice of contest to which an answer is required is so vague or ambiguous that the contestee cannot reasonably be required to frame a responsive answer, he may move for a more definite statement before interposing his answer. The motion shall point out the defects complained of and the details desired. If the motion is granted and the order of the committee is not obeyed within ten days after notice of the order or within such other time as the committee may fix, the committee may dismiss the action, or make such order as it deems just.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_383_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for serving answer after service of motion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time for serving answer after service of motion Service of a motion permitted under this section alters the time for serving the answer as follows, unless a different time is fixed by order of the committee: If the committee denies the motion or postpones its disposition until the hearing on the merits, the answer shall be served within ten days after notice of such action. If the committee grants a motion for a more definite statement the answer shall be served within ten days after service of the more definite statement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>