<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/387" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/387/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/387/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_387"><akn:num>387</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of depositions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 387. Notice of depositions(a) Time for service; formA party desiring to take the deposition of any person upon oral examination shall serve written notice on the opposing party not later than two days before the date of the examination. The notice shall state the time and place for taking the deposition and the name and address of each person to be examined. A copy of such notice, together with proof of such service thereof, shall be attached to the deposition when it is filed with the Clerk.


(b) Testimony by stipulationBy written stipulation of the parties, the deposition of a witness may be taken without notice. A copy of such stipulation shall be attached to the deposition when it is filed with the Clerk.


(c) Testimony by affidavit; time for filingBy written stipulation of the parties, the testimony of any witness of either party may be filed in the form of an affidavit by such witness or the parties may agree what a particular witness would testify to if his deposition were taken. Such testimonial affidavits or stipulations shall be filed within the time limits prescribed for the taking of testimony in section 386 of this title.


(Pub. L. 91–138, § 8, Dec. 5, 1969, 83 Stat. 287.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable with respect to any general or special election for Representative in, or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress of the United States occurring after Dec. 5, 1969, see section 19 of Pub. L. 91–138, set out as a note under section 381 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for service; form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Time for service; form A party desiring to take the deposition of any person upon oral examination shall serve written notice on the opposing party not later than two days before the date of the examination. The notice shall state the time and place for taking the deposition and the name and address of each person to be examined. A copy of such notice, together with proof of such service thereof, shall be attached to the deposition when it is filed with the Clerk.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testimony by stipulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Testimony by stipulation By written stipulation of the parties, the deposition of a witness may be taken without notice. A copy of such stipulation shall be attached to the deposition when it is filed with the Clerk.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testimony by affidavit; time for filing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Testimony by affidavit; time for filing By written stipulation of the parties, the testimony of any witness of either party may be filed in the form of an affidavit by such witness or the parties may agree what a particular witness would testify to if his deposition were taken. Such testimonial affidavits or stipulations shall be filed within the time limits prescribed for the taking of testimony in section 386 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>