<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4301"><akn:num>4301</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee staffs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4301. Committee staffs(a) Appointment of professional members; number; qualifications; termination of employmentEach standing committee of the Senate (other than the Committee on Appropriations) is authorized to appoint, by majority vote of the committee, not more than six professional staff members in addition to the clerical staffs. Such professional staff members shall be assigned to the chairman and the ranking minority member of such committee as the committee may deem advisable, except that whenever a majority of the minority members of such committee so request, two of such professional staff members may be selected for appointment by majority vote of the minority members and the committee shall appoint any staff members so selected. A staff member or members appointed pursuant to a request by the minority members of the committee shall be assigned to such committee business as such minority members deem advisable. Services of professional staff members appointed by majority vote of the committee may be terminated by a majority vote of the committee and services of professional staff members appointed pursuant to a request by the minority members of the committee shall be terminated by the committee when a majority of such minority members so request. Professional staff members authorized by this subsection shall be appointed on a permanent basis, without regard to political affiliation, and solely on the basis of fitness to perform the duties of their respective positions. Such professional staff members shall not engage in any work other than committee business and no other duties may be assigned to them.


(b) Professional members for Committee on Appropriations; examinations of executive agencies’ operationSubject to appropriations which it shall be in order to include in appropriation bills, the Committee on Appropriations of each House is authorized to appoint such staff, in addition to the clerk thereof and assistants for the minority, as each such c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of professional members; number; qualifications; termination of employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment of professional members; number; qualifications; termination of employment Each standing committee of the Senate (other than the Committee on Appropriations) is authorized to appoint, by majority vote of the committee, not more than six professional staff members in addition to the clerical staffs. Such professional staff members shall be assigned to the chairman and the ranking minority member of such committee as the committee may deem advisable, except that whenever a majority of the minority members of such committee so request, two of such professional staff members may be selected for appointment by majority vote of the minority members and the committee shall appoint any staff members so selected. A staff member or members appointed pursuant to a request by the minority members of the committee shall be assigned to such committee business as such minority members deem advisable. Services of professional staff members appointed by majority vote of the committee ma</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Professional members for Committee on Appropriations; examinations of executive agencies’ operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Professional members for Committee on Appropriations; examinations of executive agencies’ operation Subject to appropriations which it shall be in order to include in appropriation bills, the Committee on Appropriations of each House is authorized to appoint such staff, in addition to the clerk thereof and assistants for the minority, as each such committee, by a majority vote, shall determine to be necessary, such personnel, other than the minority assistants, to possess such qualifications as the committees respectively may prescribe, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House also is authorized to conduct studies and examinations of the organization and operation of any executive agency (including any agency the majority of the stock of which is owned by the Government of the United States) as it may deem necessary to assist it in connection with the determination of matters within its jurisdiction and in accordance with procedures authorized by the committee by a majority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clerical employees; appointment; number; duties; termination of employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Clerical employees; appointment; number; duties; termination of employment The clerical staff of each standing committee of the Senate (other than the Committee on Appropriations), which shall be appointed by a majority vote of the committee, shall consist of not more than six clerks to be attached to the office of the chairman, to the ranking minority member, and to the professional staff, as the committee may deem advisable, except that whenever a majority of the minority members of such committee so requests, one of the members of the clerical staff may be selected for appointment by majority vote of such minority members and the committee shall appoint any staff member so selected. The clerical staff shall handle committee correspondence and stenographic work, both for the committee staff and for the chairman and ranking minority member on matters related to committee work, except that if a member of the clerical staff is appointed pursuant to a request by the minority members </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordation of committee hearings, data, etc.; access to records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recordation of committee hearings, data, etc.; access to records All committee hearings, records, data, charts, and files shall be kept separate and distinct from the congressional office records of the Member serving as chairman of the committee; and such records shall be the property of the Congress and all members of the committee and the respective Houses shall have access to such records. Each committee is authorized to have printed and bound such testimony and other data presented at hearings held by the committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 91–510, title IV, § 477(a)(3), Oct. 26, 1970, 84 Stat. 1195</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on appointment of professional members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitations on appointment of professional members No committee shall appoint to its staff any experts or other personnel detailed or assigned from any department or agency of the Government, except with the written permission of the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate or the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointments when no vacancy exists; payment from Senate contingent fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Appointments when no vacancy exists; payment from Senate contingent fund In any case in which a request for the appointment of a minority staff member under subsection (a) or subsection (c) is made at any time when no vacancy exists to which the appointment requested may be made—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Salary rates, assignment of facilities, and accessibility of committee records for minority staff appointees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Salary rates, assignment of facilities, and accessibility of committee records for minority staff appointees Staff members appointed pursuant to a request by minority members of a committee under subsection (a) or subsection (c), and staff members appointed to assist minority members of subcommittees pursuant to authority of Senate resolution, shall be accorded equitable treatment with respect to the fixing of salary rates, the assignment of facilities, and the accessibility of committee records.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultants for Senate and House standing committees; procurement of temporary or intermittent services; contracts; advertisement requirements inapplicable; selection method; qualifications report to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Consultants for Senate and House standing committees; procurement of temporary or intermittent services; contracts; advertisement requirements inapplicable; selection method; qualifications report to Congressional committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4301_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specialized training for professional staffs of Senate and House standing committees, Senate Appropriations Committee, Senate Majority and Minority Policy Committees, and joint committees whose funding is disbursed by Secretary of Senate or Chief Administrative Officer of House; assistance: pay, tuition, etc. while training; continued employment agreement; service credit: retirement, life insurance and health insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Specialized training for professional staffs of Senate and House standing committees, Senate Appropriations Committee, Senate Majority and Minority Policy Committees, and joint committees whose funding is disbursed by Secretary of Senate or Chief Administrative Officer of House; assistance: pay, tuition, etc. while training; continued employment agreement; service credit: retirement, life insurance and health insurance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>