<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4313"><akn:num>4313</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of House of Representatives allowances by Committee on House Oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4313. Adjustment of House of Representatives allowances by Committee on House Oversight(a) In generalSubject to the provision of law specified in subsection (b), the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives may, by order of the Committee, fix and adjust the amounts, terms, and conditions of, and other matters relating to, allowances of the House of Representatives within the following categories:(1) For Members of the House of Representatives, the Members’ Representational Allowance, including all aspects of official mail within the jurisdiction of the Committee under section 503 of this title.

(2) For committees, the Speaker, the Majority and Minority Leaders, the Clerk, the Sergeant at Arms, and the Chief Administrative Officer, allowances for official mail (including all aspects of official mail within the jurisdiction of the Committee under section 503 of this title), stationery, and telephone and telegraph and other communications.


(b) Provision specifiedThe provision of law referred to in subsection (a) is section 4314 of this title.


(c) “Member of the House of Representatives” definedAs used in this section, the term “Member of the House of Representatives” means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.


(Pub. L. 92–184, ch. IV, Dec. 15, 1971, 85 Stat. 636; Pub. L. 104–186, title I, § 102, Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1719; Pub. L. 106–57, title I, § 103(a)(4)(A), Sept. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 415.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 57 of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.
Section is based on House Resolution No. 457, Ninety-second Congress, July 21, 1971, which was enacted into permanent law by Pub. L. 92–184.

Amendments1999—Subsec. (a)(1), (2). Pub. L. 106–57 substituted “all aspects of official mail” for “all aspects of the Official Mail Allowance”.
1996—Pub. L. 104–186 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to the provision of law specified in subsection (b), the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives may, by order of the Committee, fix and adjust the amounts, terms, and conditions of, and other matters relating to, allowances of the House of Representatives within the following categories:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision specified</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Provision specified The provision of law referred to in subsection (a) is section 4314 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Member of the House of Representatives” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Member of the House of Representatives” defined As used in this section, the term “Member of the House of Representatives” means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>