<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4503"><akn:num>4503</akn:num><akn:heading>Jury and witness service by Senate and House employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4503. Jury and witness service by Senate and House employees(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) “employee” means any individual whose pay is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate or the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives; and

(2) “court of the United States” has the meaning given it by section 451 of title 28 and includes the United States District Court for the District of the Canal Zone, the District Court of Guam, and the District Court of the Virgin Islands.


(b) Service as juror or witness in connection with a judicial proceeding; prohibition against reduction of payThe pay of an employee shall not be reduced during a period of absence with respect to which the employee is summoned (and permitted to respond to such summons by the appropriate authority of the House of the Congress disbursing his pay), in connection with a judicial proceeding by a court or authority responsible for the conduct of that proceeding, to serve—(1) as a juror; or

(2) other than as provided in subsection (c) of this section, as a witness on behalf of any party in connection with any judicial proceeding to which the United States, the District of Columbia, or a State or local government is a party;


in the District of Columbia, a State, territory, or possession of the United States including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Canal Zone, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands. For purposes of this subsection, “judicial proceeding” means any action, suit, or other judicial proceeding, including any condemnation, preliminary, informational, or other proceeding of a judicial nature, but does not include an administrative proceeding.

(c) Official dutyAn employee is performing official duty during the period with respect to which he is summoned (and is authorized to respond to such summons by the House of the Congress disbursing his pay), or is assigned by such House, to—(1) testify or produce official records on behalf of the United St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service as juror or witness in connection with a judicial proceeding; prohibition against reduction of pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Service as juror or witness in connection with a judicial proceeding; prohibition against reduction of pay The pay of an employee shall not be reduced during a period of absence with respect to which the employee is summoned (and permitted to respond to such summons by the appropriate authority of the House of the Congress disbursing his pay), in connection with a judicial proceeding by a court or authority responsible for the conduct of that proceeding, to serve— in the District of Columbia, a State, territory, or possession of the United States including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Canal Zone, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands. For purposes of this subsection, “judicial proceeding” means any action, suit, or other judicial proceeding, including any condemnation, preliminary, informational, or other proceeding of a judicial nature, but does not include an administrative proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Official duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Official duty An employee is performing official duty during the period with respect to which he is summoned (and is authorized to respond to such summons by the House of the Congress disbursing his pay), or is assigned by such House, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on receipt of jury or witness fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition on receipt of jury or witness fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Travel expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rules and regulations The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives are authorized to prescribe, for employees of their respective Houses, such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4503_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional consent not conferred for production of official records or to testimony concerning activities related to employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Congressional consent not conferred for production of official records or to testimony concerning activities related to employment No provision of this section shall be construed to confer the consent of either House of the Congress to the production of official records of that House or to testimony by an employee of that House concerning activities related to his employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>