<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4507" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4507/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4507/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4507"><akn:num>4507</akn:num><akn:heading>Longevity compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4507. Longevity compensation(a) Eligible employeesThis section shall apply 11 See Inapplicability of Section to Certain Employees note below. to—(1) each employee of the Senate whose compensation is paid from the appropriation for Salaries, Officers and Employees under the following headings:(A) Office of the Secretary, including individuals employed under authority of section 6538 of this title;

(B) Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper, except employees designated as “special employees”; and

(C) Offices of the Secretaries for the Majority and the Minority;


(2) each employee of the Senate authorized by Senate resolution to be appointed by the Secretary of the Senate or the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper, except employees designated as “special employees”; and

(3) each employee of the Capitol Guide Service established under section 2166 22 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(b) Rate of compensation; limitation on increases; computation of service; effective date of payment(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), an employee to whom this section applies shall be paid, during any period of continuous creditable service, additional annual compensation (hereinafter referred to as “longevity compensation”) at the rate of $482 for (A) each year of creditable service performed for the first five years and (B) each two years of creditable service performed during the twenty-year period following the first five years.

(2) The amount of longevity compensation which may be paid to an employee, when added to his regular annual compensation, shall not exceed the maximum annual compensation which may be paid to Senate employees generally as prescribed by law or orders of the President pro tempore issued under authority of section 4571 of this title.

(3) For purposes of this section—(A) creditable service includes (i) service performed as an employee described in subsection (a), (ii) service performed as a member of the Capitol Police or as an em</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4507_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligible employees This section shall apply 11 See Inapplicability of Section to Certain Employees note below. to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4507_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate of compensation; limitation on increases; computation of service; effective date of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rate of compensation; limitation on increases; computation of service; effective date of payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>