<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4575" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4575/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4575/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4575"><akn:num>4575</akn:num><akn:heading>Gross rate of compensation of employees paid by Secretary of Senate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4575. Gross rate of compensation of employees paid by Secretary of Senate(a) Annual rate; certification(1) Whenever the rate of compensation of any employee whose compensation is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate is fixed or adjusted on or after October 1, 1980, such rate as so fixed or adjusted shall be at a single whole dollar per annum gross rate and may not include a fractional part of a dollar.

(2) New or changed rates of compensation (other than changes in rates which are made by law) of any such employee (other than an employee who is an elected officer of the Senate) shall be certified in writing to the Disbursing Office of the Senate (and, for purposes of this paragraph, a new rate of compensation refers to compensation in the case of an appointment, transfer from one Senate appointing authority to another, or promotion by an appointing authority to a position the compensation for which is fixed by law). In the case of an appointment or other new rate of compensation, the certification must be received by such office on or before the day the rate of new compensation is to become effective. In any other case, the changed rate of compensation shall take effect on the first day of the month in which such certification is received (if such certification is received within the first ten days of such month), on the first day of the month after the month in which such certification is received (if the day on which such certification is received is after the twenty-fifth day of the month in which it is received), and on the sixteenth day of the month in which such certification is received (if such certification is received after the tenth day and before the twenty-sixth day of such month). Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, if the certification for a changed rate of compensation for an employee specifies an effective date of such change, such change shall become effective on the date so specified, but only if the date so specified is the first or si</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4575_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual rate; certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual rate; certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4575_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion; increase in compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conversion; increase in compensation The rate of compensation of each employee whose compensation is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate which was fixed before August 1, 1967, at a basic rate with respect to which additional compensation is payable by law shall be converted as of such date to the lowest per annum gross rate which is a multiple of $180 and which is not less than the aggregate rate of compensation (basic compensation plus additional compensation provided by law) which such employee was receiving immediately prior to such date. Any increments of longevity compensation to which an employee became entitled prior to August 1, 1967, under section 4507(b) of this title shall be excluded in converting such employee’s rate of compensation under this subsection, but such employee’s rate of gross compensation shall be increased by $540 (which shall be considered to be an increase under section 4507(b) of this title) for each such increment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4575_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reference in other provisions to basic rates and additional compensation as reference to per annum gross rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reference in other provisions to basic rates and additional compensation as reference to per annum gross rate In any case in which the rate of compensation of any employee or position, or class of employees or positions, the compensation for which is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate, or any maximum or minimum rate with respect to any such employee, position, or class, is referred to in or provided by statute or Senate resolution, and the rate so referred to or provided is a basic rate with respect to which additional compensation is provided by law, such statutory provision or resolution shall be deemed to refer, in lieu of such basic rate, to the per annum gross rate which an employee receiving such basic rate immediately prior to August 1, 1967, would receive (without regard to such statutory provision or resolution) under subsection (b) on and after such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4575_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of employees in office of Senator; limitation; titles of positions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation of employees in office of Senator; limitation; titles of positions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4575_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gross rate of compensation of employee of committee of Senate employed by joint committee, select committee, or standing committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Gross rate of compensation of employee of committee of Senate employed by joint committee, select committee, or standing committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4575_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>General limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) General limitation No officer or employee whose compensation is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate shall be paid gross compensation at a rate less than $3,293 1 or in excess of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of title 5, unless expressly authorized by law. The limitation on the minimum rate of gross compensation under this subsection shall not apply to any member or civilian employee of the Capitol Police whose compensation is disbursed by the Secretary of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>