<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/476" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/476/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/476/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_476"><akn:num>476</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology Assessment Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 476. Technology Assessment Advisory Council(a) Establishment; compositionThe Office shall establish a Technology Assessment Advisory Council (hereinafter referred to as the “Council”). The Council shall be composed of the following twelve members:(1) ten members from the public, to be appointed by the Board, who shall be persons eminent in one or more fields of the physical, biological, or social sciences or engineering or experienced in the administration of technological activities, or who may be judged qualified on the basis of contributions made to educational or public activities;

(2) the Comptroller General; and

(3) the Director of the Congressional Research Service of the Library of Congress.


(b) DutiesThe Council, upon request by the Board, shall—(1) review and make recommendations to the Board on activities undertaken by the Office or on the initiation thereof in accordance with section 472(d) of this title;

(2) review and make recommendations to the Board on the findings of any assessment made by or for the Office; and

(3) undertake such additional related tasks as the Board may direct.


(c) Chairman and Vice Chairman; election by Council from members appointed from public; terms and conditions of serviceThe Council by majority vote, shall elect from its members appointed under subsection (a)(1) of this section a Chairman and a Vice Chairman, who shall serve for such time and under such conditions as the Council may prescribe. In the absence of the Chairman, or in the event of his incapacity, the Vice Chairman shall act as Chairman.


(d) Terms of office of members appointed from public; reappointmentThe term of office of each member of the Council appointed under subsection (a)(1) shall be four years except that any such member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. No person shall be appointed a member of the Council unde</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_476_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; composition The Office shall establish a Technology Assessment Advisory Council (hereinafter referred to as the “Council”). The Council shall be composed of the following twelve members:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_476_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Council, upon request by the Board, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_476_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman and Vice Chairman; election by Council from members appointed from public; terms and conditions of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chairman and Vice Chairman; election by Council from members appointed from public; terms and conditions of service The Council by majority vote, shall elect from its members appointed under subsection (a)(1) of this section a Chairman and a Vice Chairman, who shall serve for such time and under such conditions as the Council may prescribe. In the absence of the Chairman, or in the event of his incapacity, the Vice Chairman shall act as Chairman.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_476_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of office of members appointed from public; reappointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms of office of members appointed from public; reappointment The term of office of each member of the Council appointed under subsection (a)(1) shall be four years except that any such member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. No person shall be appointed a member of the Council under subsection (a)(1) more than twice. Terms of the members appointed under subsection (a)(1) shall be staggered so as to establish a rotating membership according to such method as the Board may devise.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_476_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment to Comptroller General and Director of Congressional Research Service of travel and other necessary expenses; payment to members appointed from public of compensation and reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment to Comptroller General and Director of Congressional Research Service of travel and other necessary expenses; payment to members appointed from public of compensation and reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>