<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/477" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/477/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/477/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_477"><akn:num>477</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of services of Library of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 477. Utilization of services of Library of Congress(a) Authority of Librarian to make available services and assistance of Congressional Research ServiceTo carry out the objectives of this chapter, the Librarian of Congress is authorized to make available to the Office such services and assistance of the Congressional Research Service as may be appropriate and feasible.


(b) Scope of services and assistanceSuch services and assistance made available to the Office shall include, but not be limited to, all of the services and assistance which the Congressional Research Service is otherwise authorized to provide to the Congress.


(c) Services or responsibilities performed by Congressional Research Service for Congress not altered or modified; authority of Librarian to establish within Congressional Research Service additional divisions, etc.Nothing in this section shall alter or modify any services or responsibilities, other than those performed for the Office, which the Congressional Research Service under law performs for or on behalf of the Congress. The Librarian is, however, authorized to establish within the Congressional Research Service such additional divisions, groups, or other organizational entities as may be necessary to carry out the purpose of this chapter.


(d) Reimbursement for services and assistanceServices and assistance made available to the Office by the Congressional Research Service in accordance with this section may be provided with or without reimbursement from funds of the Office, as agreed upon by the Board and the Librarian of Congress.


(Pub. L. 92–484, § 8, Oct. 13, 1972, 86 Stat. 801.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_477_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Librarian to make available services and assistance of Congressional Research Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Librarian to make available services and assistance of Congressional Research Service To carry out the objectives of this chapter, the Librarian of Congress is authorized to make available to the Office such services and assistance of the Congressional Research Service as may be appropriate and feasible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_477_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of services and assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scope of services and assistance Such services and assistance made available to the Office shall include, but not be limited to, all of the services and assistance which the Congressional Research Service is otherwise authorized to provide to the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_477_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services or responsibilities performed by Congressional Research Service for Congress not altered or modified; authority of Librarian to establish within Congressional Research Service additional divisions, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Services or responsibilities performed by Congressional Research Service for Congress not altered or modified; authority of Librarian to establish within Congressional Research Service additional divisions, etc. Nothing in this section shall alter or modify any services or responsibilities, other than those performed for the Office, which the Congressional Research Service under law performs for or on behalf of the Congress. The Librarian is, however, authorized to establish within the Congressional Research Service such additional divisions, groups, or other organizational entities as may be necessary to carry out the purpose of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_477_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement for services and assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reimbursement for services and assistance Services and assistance made available to the Office by the Congressional Research Service in accordance with this section may be provided with or without reimbursement from funds of the Office, as agreed upon by the Board and the Librarian of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>