<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4915" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4915/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/4915/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4915"><akn:num>4915</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of page during academic year and summer term; filling of vacancies; eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4915. Service of page during academic year and summer term; filling of vacancies; eligibility(a)(1) Except as provided in subsection (b), a page serving during an academic year—(A) shall be in the eleventh grade; and

(B) shall serve for one full semester or two full semesters.


(2) Except as provided in subsection (b), a page serving during the summer term—(A) shall have completed the tenth grade; and

(B) shall not have begun the twelfth grade.



(b)(1) An unforeseen vacancy occurring in a page position during an academic year may be filled, except that no appointment may be made under this paragraph for service to begin on or after October 1 with respect to the first semester or on or after March 1 with respect to the second semester.

(2) An individual who has served as a congressional page at any time during each of any three semesters or terms, as the case may be, shall not be eligible to serve as a page.


(Pub. L. 98–367, title I, § 103, July 17, 1984, 98 Stat. 479; Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 204(40)(C)–(E), Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1736.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 88c–3 of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.
Section is based on section 3 of House Resolution No. 234, Ninety-eighth Congress, June 29, 1983, which was enacted into permanent law by Pub. L. 98–367.

Amendments1996—Subsec. (a)(1)(B). Pub. L. 104–186, § 204(40)(C), substituted “semester or two full semesters” for “term or two full terms”.
Subsec. (b)(1). Pub. L. 104–186, § 204(40)(D), substituted “except that no appointment may be made under this paragraph for service to begin on or after October 1 with respect to the first semester or on or after March 1 with respect to the second semester” for “but no appointment to fill that vacancy shall be for a period of less than two months”.
Subsec. (b)(2). Pub. L. 104–186, § 204(40)(E), substituted “semesters or terms, as the case may be,” for “terms”.

Statuto</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4915_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4915_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>