<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_501"><akn:num>501</akn:num><akn:heading>House Communications Standards Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 501. House Communications Standards Commission(a) Establishment; designationThere is established a special commission of the House of Representatives, designated the “House Communications Standards Commission” (herein referred to as the “Commission”).


(b) Membership; political party representation; Chairman; vacancies; quorumThe Commission shall be composed of six Members appointed by the Speaker of the House, three from the majority political party, and three from the minority political party, in the House. The Speaker shall designate as Chairman of the Commission, from among the members of the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House, one of the Members appointed to the Commission. A vacancy in the membership of the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. Four members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum to do business.


(c) Assistance and use of personnel, including chief counsel, of Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the HouseIn performing its duties and functions, the Commission may use such personnel, office space, equipment, and facilities of, and obtain such other assistance from, the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House, as such committee shall make available to the Commission. Such personnel and assistance shall include, in all cases, the services and assistance of the chief counsel or other head of the professional staff (by whatever title designated) of such committee. All assistance so furnished to the Commission by the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service shall be sufficient to enable the Commission to perform its duties and functions efficiently and effectively.


(d) Advisory opinions or consultations respecting franked mail for persons entitled to franking privilege; franking privilege regulations(1) The Commission shall provide guidance, assistance, advice, and counsel, through advisory opinions or consultations, in connection with the mailing or conte</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; designation There is established a special commission of the House of Representatives, designated the “House Communications Standards Commission” (herein referred to as the “Commission”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership; political party representation; Chairman; vacancies; quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership; political party representation; Chairman; vacancies; quorum The Commission shall be composed of six Members appointed by the Speaker of the House, three from the majority political party, and three from the minority political party, in the House. The Speaker shall designate as Chairman of the Commission, from among the members of the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House, one of the Members appointed to the Commission. A vacancy in the membership of the Commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. Four members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum to do business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance and use of personnel, including chief counsel, of Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance and use of personnel, including chief counsel, of Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House In performing its duties and functions, the Commission may use such personnel, office space, equipment, and facilities of, and obtain such other assistance from, the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service of the House, as such committee shall make available to the Commission. Such personnel and assistance shall include, in all cases, the services and assistance of the chief counsel or other head of the professional staff (by whatever title designated) of such committee. All assistance so furnished to the Commission by the Committee on Post Office and Civil Service shall be sufficient to enable the Commission to perform its duties and functions efficiently and effectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory opinions or consultations respecting franked mail for persons entitled to franking privilege; franking privilege regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Advisory opinions or consultations respecting franked mail for persons entitled to franking privilege; franking privilege regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Complaint of franked mail violations; investigation; notice and hearing; conclusiveness of findings; decision of Commission; judicial review; reference of certain violations to Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of the House for appropriate action and enforcement; administrative procedure regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Complaint of franked mail violations; investigation; notice and hearing; conclusiveness of findings; decision of Commission; judicial review; reference of certain violations to Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of the House for appropriate action and enforcement; administrative procedure regulations Any complaint that a violation of any provision of law or any rule or regulation of the House of Representatives to which subsection (d) applies is about to occur, or has occurred within the immediately preceding period of one year, by any person referred to in such subsection (d), shall contain pertinent factual material and shall conform to regulations prescribed by the Commission. The Commission, if it determines there is reasonable justification for the complaint, shall conduct an investigation of the matter, including an investigation of reports and statements filed by the complainant with respect to the matter which is the subject of the complaint. The Commission shall af</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedural considerations; sessions, place and time; subpenas, issuance and service; oaths and affirmations; testimony; printing and binding; expenditures; organizational and procedural regulations; majority assent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Procedural considerations; sessions, place and time; subpenas, issuance and service; oaths and affirmations; testimony; printing and binding; expenditures; organizational and procedural regulations; majority assent The Commission may sit and act at such places and times during the sessions, recesses, and adjourned periods of Congress, require by subpena or otherwise the attendance of such witnesses and the production of such books, papers, and documents, administer such oaths and affirmations, take such testimony, procure such printing and binding, and make such expenditures, as the Commission considers advisable. The Commission may make such rules respecting its organization and procedures as it considers necessary, except that no action shall be taken by the Commission unless a majority of the Commission assent. Subpenas may be issued over the signature of the Chairman of the Commission or of any member designated by him or by the Commission, and may be served by such person or p</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Property of Commission; records; voting record; location of records, data, and files</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Property of Commission; records; voting record; location of records, data, and files The Commission shall keep a complete record of all its actions, including a record of the votes on any question on which a record vote is demanded. All records, data, and files of the Commission shall be the property of the Commission and shall be kept in the offices of the Commission or such other places as the Commission may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of mass communication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definition of mass communication In this section, the term “mass communication” means a mass mailing described in section 3210(a)(6)(E) of title 39 or any other unsolicited communication of substantially identical content which is transmitted to 500 or more persons in a session of Congress, as provided under regulations of the Commission, except that such term does not include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>