<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/506" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/506/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/506/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_506"><akn:num>506</akn:num><akn:heading>Mass mailing sent by House Members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 506. Mass mailing sent by House Members(a) Notice that mailing is at taxpayer expense(1) Each mass mailing sent by a Member of the House of Representatives shall bear in a prominent place on its face, or on the envelope or outside cover or wrapper in which the mail matter is sent, one of the notices described in paragraph (2) or a notice to the same effect in words which may be prescribed under subsection (c). The notice shall be printed in a type size not smaller than 7-point.

(2) The notices described in this paragraph are as follows:(A) “Paid for with official funds from the office of _____.”, with the blank filled in with the name of the Member sending the mailing.

(B) “Paid for by the funds authorized by the House of Representatives for District __ of _____.”, with the first blank filled in with the name of the congressional district number, and the second blank filled in with the name of the State, of the Member sending the mailing.

(C) “Paid for by official funds authorized by the House of Representatives.”



(b) Publication of each Member’s total expense and amount(1) There shall be published in the itemized report of disbursements of the House of Representatives as required by law, a summary tabulation setting forth, for the office of each Member of the House of Representatives, the total number of pieces of mass mail mailed during the period involved and the total cost of those mass mailings.

(2) Each such tabulation shall also include—(A) the total cost (as referred to in paragraph (1)) divided by the number (as determined by the Postmaster General) of addresses (other than business possible delivery stops) in the Congressional district from which the Member was elected (as such addresses are described in section 3210(d)(7)(B) of title 39); and

(B) the total number of pieces of mass mail (as referred to in paragraph (1)) divided by the number (as determined by the Postmaster General) of addresses (other than business possible delivery stops) in th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice that mailing is at taxpayer expense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice that mailing is at taxpayer expense</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of each Member’s total expense and amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Publication of each Member’s total expense and amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations The Committee on House Oversight shall prescribe such rules and regulations and shall take such other action as the Committee considers necessary and proper for Members to conform to the provisions of this subsection and applicable rules and regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability This section shall apply with respect to sessions of Congress beginning after September 16, 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>