<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5143" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5143/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5143/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5143"><akn:num>5143</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of certain House minority employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5143. Compensation of certain House minority employees
Effective January 3, 1977, and until otherwise provided by law, the rate of pay for each of the six positions of minority employee authorized by the Legislative Pay Act of 1929 and referred to in House Resolution 441 of the Ninety-first Congress shall be a per annum gross rate equal to the annual rate of basic pay of level IV of the Executive Schedule of section 5315 of title 5, unless a lower rate is established by the Minority Leader.
(Pub. L. 95–94, title I, § 115, Aug. 5, 1977, 91 Stat. 668.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Legislative Pay Act of 1929, referred to in text, is act June 20, 1929, ch. 33, 46 Stat. 32. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
House Resolution 441, referred to in text, is set out as a Prior Provisions note below.

Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 74c of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.
Section is based on section 1 of House Resolution 119, Ninety-fifth Congress, Jan. 19, 1977, which was enacted into permanent law by Pub. L. 95–94.

Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in House Resolution 441, Ninety-first Congress, June 17, 1969, as enacted into permanent law by Pub. L. 91–145, § 103, Dec. 12, 1969, 83 Stat. 359, which provided: 
“That, until otherwise provided by law—
“(1) The six positions of minority employee listed in House Resolution 8, Ninety-first Congress, as supplemented by House Resolution 238, Ninety-first Congress, and House Resolution 265, Ninety-first Congress, are hereby given position titles in the descending order in which those six positions are listed in House Resolution 8, as follows:“(A) the position title of the position listed first is ‘Floor Assistant to the Minority’;

“(B) the position title of the position listed second is ‘Floor Assistant to the Minority’;

“(C) the position title of the position listed third is </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>