<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5306"><akn:num>5306</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductions for absence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5306. Deductions for absence
The Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives (upon certification by the Clerk of the House of Representatives) shall deduct from the monthly payments (or other periodic payments authorized by law) of each Member or Delegate the amount of his salary for each day that he has been absent from the House, unless such Member or Delegate assigns as the reason for such absence the sickness of himself or of some member of his family.
(R.S. § 40; Pub. L. 97–51, § 112(d), Oct. 1, 1981, 95 Stat. 963; Pub. L. 104–186, title II, § 203(7), Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1726; Pub. L. 109–55, title I, § 5, Aug. 2, 2005, 119 Stat. 568.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 39 of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.
R.S. § 40 derived from act Aug. 16, 1856, ch. 123, § 6, 11 Stat. 49.

Amendments2005—Pub. L. 109–55 struck out “Secretary of the Senate and the” before “Chief Administrative Officer”, “, respectively,” before “shall deduct from”, “, respectively” before “, unless such Member”, and “Senate or” after “absent from the”.
1996—Pub. L. 104–186 substituted “the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives (upon certification by the Clerk of the House of Representatives)” for “Sergeant-at-Arms of the House”.
1981—Pub. L. 97–51 substituted “from the monthly payments (or other periodic payments authorized by law)” for “from the monthly payments”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1981 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 97–51 effective in the case of compensation payable for months after December 1981, see section 112(e) of Pub. L. 97–51, set out as a note under section 6301 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>