<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5322"><akn:num>5322</akn:num><akn:heading>Lyndon Baines Johnson congressional interns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5322. Lyndon Baines Johnson congressional interns(a) Hiring authority of House Members, Delegates, and Resident Commissioners; allowance for payment of compensationUntil otherwise provided by law and notwithstanding any other provision of law, each Member of, Delegate to, and Resident Commissioner in, the House of Representatives is authorized to hire for two months in any year one additional employee to be known as a Lyndon Baines Johnson congressional intern in honor of the former President. Each such intern shall be a student or a teacher and certified as such under subsection (b) of this section. Each such Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner shall have available for payment of compensation to such intern a total allowance of $1,000, to be payable to such intern at a rate not to exceed $500 per month, out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives. Such intern and such allowance shall be in addition to all personnel and allowances made available to such Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner under other provisions of law or other authority.


(b) Certification of intern status; filingNo person shall be paid compensation as a Lyndon Baines Johnson congressional intern who does not have on file with the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, at all times during the period of his employment as such intern, an appropriate certificate which is applicable to his intern status, as described below:(1) if the intern is a student, a certificate that such intern was during the academic year immediately preceding his employment, a bona fide student at a college, university, or similar institution of higher learning; or

(2) if the intern is a teacher, a certificate that such intern was, in the year immediately preceding his employment, a bona fide teacher in government or social studies at a secondary school or a postsecondary school.


(c) Regulations by Committee on House OversightThe Committee on House Oversight shall pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hiring authority of House Members, Delegates, and Resident Commissioners; allowance for payment of compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Hiring authority of House Members, Delegates, and Resident Commissioners; allowance for payment of compensation Until otherwise provided by law and notwithstanding any other provision of law, each Member of, Delegate to, and Resident Commissioner in, the House of Representatives is authorized to hire for two months in any year one additional employee to be known as a Lyndon Baines Johnson congressional intern in honor of the former President. Each such intern shall be a student or a teacher and certified as such under subsection (b) of this section. Each such Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner shall have available for payment of compensation to such intern a total allowance of $1,000, to be payable to such intern at a rate not to exceed $500 per month, out of the applicable accounts of the House of Representatives. Such intern and such allowance shall be in addition to all personnel and allowances made available to such Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner under other</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of intern status; filing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certification of intern status; filing No person shall be paid compensation as a Lyndon Baines Johnson congressional intern who does not have on file with the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, at all times during the period of his employment as such intern, an appropriate certificate which is applicable to his intern status, as described below:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations by Committee on House Oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations by Committee on House Oversight The Committee on House Oversight shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>