<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5341" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5341/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5341/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5341"><akn:num>5341</akn:num><akn:heading>Representational allowance for Members of House of Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5341. Representational allowance for Members of House of Representatives(a) In generalThere is established for the House of Representatives a single allowance, to be known as the “Members’ Representational Allowance”, which shall be available to support the conduct of the official and representational duties of a Member or Member-elect of the House of Representatives with respect to the district from which the Member or Member-elect is elected.


(b) MergerThe Clerk Hire Allowance, the Official Expenses Allowance, and the Official Mail Allowance, as in effect on the day before September 1, 1995, are merged into the Members’ Representational Allowance.


(c) “Member of the House of Representatives” definedAs used in this section, the term “Member of the House of Representatives” means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.


(d) RegulationsThe Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives shall have authority to prescribe regulations to carry out this section, including regulations establishing under subsection (a) the official and representational duties during a Congress of a Member-elect of the House of Representatives who is not an incumbent Member re-elected to the ensuing Congress.


(e) Effective dateThis section shall take effect on September 1, 1995 and shall apply with respect to official and representational duties carried out on or after that date.


(Pub. L. 104–186, title I, § 101, Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1719; Pub. L. 116–260, div. I, title I, § 117(a), (b), Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 1641.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 57b of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.

Amendments2020—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 116–260, § 117(a), substituted “a Member or Member-elect” for “a Member” and “the Member or Member-elect” for “the Member”.
Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 116–260, § 117(b), substituted “, including regulations establishing und</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5341_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established for the House of Representatives a single allowance, to be known as the “Members’ Representational Allowance”, which shall be available to support the conduct of the official and representational duties of a Member or Member-elect of the House of Representatives with respect to the district from which the Member or Member-elect is elected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5341_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Merger</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Merger The Clerk Hire Allowance, the Official Expenses Allowance, and the Official Mail Allowance, as in effect on the day before September 1, 1995, are merged into the Members’ Representational Allowance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5341_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Member of the House of Representatives” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Member of the House of Representatives” defined As used in this section, the term “Member of the House of Representatives” means a Representative in, or a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5341_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations The Committee on House Oversight of the House of Representatives shall have authority to prescribe regulations to carry out this section, including regulations establishing under subsection (a) the official and representational duties during a Congress of a Member-elect of the House of Representatives who is not an incumbent Member re-elected to the ensuing Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5341_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date This section shall take effect on September 1, 1995 and shall apply with respect to official and representational duties carried out on or after that date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>