<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5501"><akn:num>5501</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary appointments in case of vacancies or incapacity of House officers; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5501. Temporary appointments in case of vacancies or incapacity of House officers; compensation(a) Temporary appointments in case of vacancy or incapacity in office of Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer, or Chaplain of HouseIn case of a vacancy, from whatever cause, in the office of Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer or Chaplain, of the House of Representatives, or in case of the incapacity or inability of the incumbent of any such office to perform the duties thereof, the Speaker of the House of Representatives may appoint a person to act as, and to exercise temporarily the duties of, Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer or Chaplain, as the case may be, until a person is chosen by the House of Representatives and duly qualifies as Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer or Chaplain, as the case may be, or until the termination of the incapacity or inability of the incumbent.


(b) Duties of temporary appointeesAny person appointed pursuant to this section shall exercise all the duties, shall have all the powers, and shall be subject to all the requirements and limitations applicable with respect to one chosen by the House of Representatives to fill the office involved.


(c) Compensation of temporary appointeeAny person appointed pursuant to this section shall be paid the compensation which he would receive if he were chosen by the House of Representatives to fill the office involved, unless such person is concurrently serving in any office or position the compensation for which is paid from the funds of the United States, in which case he shall receive no compensation for services rendered pursuant to his appointment under this section, and his compensation for performing the duties of such office other than the one to which he is appointed pursuant to this section shall be in full discharge for all services he performs for the United States while serving in such dual capacity.


(Aug. 2, 1946,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary appointments in case of vacancy or incapacity in office of Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer, or Chaplain of House</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Temporary appointments in case of vacancy or incapacity in office of Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer, or Chaplain of House In case of a vacancy, from whatever cause, in the office of Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer or Chaplain, of the House of Representatives, or in case of the incapacity or inability of the incumbent of any such office to perform the duties thereof, the Speaker of the House of Representatives may appoint a person to act as, and to exercise temporarily the duties of, Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer or Chaplain, as the case may be, until a person is chosen by the House of Representatives and duly qualifies as Clerk, Sergeant at Arms, Chief Administrative Officer or Chaplain, as the case may be, or until the termination of the incapacity or inability of the incumbent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of temporary appointees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties of temporary appointees Any person appointed pursuant to this section shall exercise all the duties, shall have all the powers, and shall be subject to all the requirements and limitations applicable with respect to one chosen by the House of Representatives to fill the office involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5501_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of temporary appointee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation of temporary appointee Any person appointed pursuant to this section shall be paid the compensation which he would receive if he were chosen by the House of Representatives to fill the office involved, unless such person is concurrently serving in any office or position the compensation for which is paid from the funds of the United States, in which case he shall receive no compensation for services rendered pursuant to his appointment under this section, and his compensation for performing the duties of such office other than the one to which he is appointed pursuant to this section shall be in full discharge for all services he performs for the United States while serving in such dual capacity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>