<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5571" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5571/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/5571/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5571"><akn:num>5571</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of General Counsel of House; administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5571. Office of General Counsel of House; administrative provisions(a) Compliance with admission requirementsThe General Counsel of the House of Representatives and any other counsel in the Office of the General Counsel of the House of Representatives, including any counsel specially retained by the Office of General Counsel, shall be entitled, for the purpose of performing the counsel’s functions, to enter an appearance in any proceeding before any court of the United States or of any State or political subdivision thereof without compliance with any requirements for admission to practice before such court, except that the authorization conferred by this subsection shall not apply with respect to the admission of any such person to practice before the United States Supreme Court.


(b) Notification by Attorney GeneralThe Attorney General shall notify the General Counsel of the House of Representatives as required by section 530D of title 28.


(c) General Counsel definitionIn this section, the term “General Counsel of the House of Representatives” means—(1) the head of the Office of General Counsel established and operating under clause 8 of rule II of the Rules of the House of Representatives;

(2) the head of any successor office to the Office of General Counsel which is established after September 29, 1999; and

(3) any other person authorized and directed in accordance with the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide legal assistance and representation to the House in connection with the matters described in this section.


(d) Effective dateThe provisions of this section shall become effective beginning with September 29, 1999.


(Pub. L. 106–57, title I, § 101, Sept. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 414; Pub. L. 107–273, div. A, title II, § 202(b)(5), Nov. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 1775; Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 110(a), Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 355.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 130f of this title prior to editorial</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5571_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with admission requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compliance with admission requirements The General Counsel of the House of Representatives and any other counsel in the Office of the General Counsel of the House of Representatives, including any counsel specially retained by the Office of General Counsel, shall be entitled, for the purpose of performing the counsel’s functions, to enter an appearance in any proceeding before any court of the United States or of any State or political subdivision thereof without compliance with any requirements for admission to practice before such court, except that the authorization conferred by this subsection shall not apply with respect to the admission of any such person to practice before the United States Supreme Court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5571_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification by Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification by Attorney General The Attorney General shall notify the General Counsel of the House of Representatives as required by section 530D of title 28.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5571_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Counsel definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General Counsel definition In this section, the term “General Counsel of the House of Representatives” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5571_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date The provisions of this section shall become effective beginning with September 29, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>