<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_611"><akn:num>611</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee development program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 611. Employee development program(a) EstablishmentThe Director of the Congressional Budget Office may, by regulation, make applicable such provisions of section 3396 of title 5 as the Director determines necessary to establish a program providing opportunities for employees of the Office to engage in details or other temporary assignments in other agencies, study, or uncompensated work experience which will contribute to the employees’ development and effectiveness.


(b) Effective dateThis section shall apply to fiscal year 2003 and each fiscal year thereafter.


(Pub. L. 108–7, div. H, title I, § 1101, Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 370.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2003, which is div. H of the Consolidated Appropriations Resolution, 2003, and not as part of title II of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Executive Exchange Program for the Congressional Budget OfficePub. L. 110–161, div. H, title I, § 1201, Dec. 26, 2007, 121 Stat. 2238, as amended by Pub. L. 111–68, div. A, title I, § 1201, Oct. 1, 2009, 123 Stat. 2032, which established an executive exchange program and was formerly set out as a note under this section, was transferred to section 612 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_611_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Director of the Congressional Budget Office may, by regulation, make applicable such provisions of section 3396 of title 5 as the Director determines necessary to establish a program providing opportunities for employees of the Office to engage in details or other temporary assignments in other agencies, study, or uncompensated work experience which will contribute to the employees’ development and effectiveness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_611_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effective date This section shall apply to fiscal year 2003 and each fiscal year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>