<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6314" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6314/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6314/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6314"><akn:num>6314</akn:num><akn:heading>Mail, telegraph, telephone, stationery, office supplies, and home State office and travel expenses f</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6314. Mail, telegraph, telephone, stationery, office supplies, and home State office and travel expenses for Senators(a) Authorization for payment from Senate contingent fundThe contingent fund of the Senate is made available for payment (including reimbursement) to or on behalf of each Senator, upon certification of the Senator, for the following expenses incurred by the Senator and his staff:(1) telecommunications equipment and services subject to such regulations as may be promulgated by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate;

(2)(A) stationery and other office supplies procured for use for official business, and

(B) metered charges for use of copying equipment provided by the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate;


(3)[(A) Repealed. Pub. L. 101–520, title I, § 11, Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 2260] (B) postage on, and fees and charges in connection with official mail matter sent through the mail other than the franking privilege upon certification by the Senate Sergeant at Arms and subject to such regulations as may be promulgated by the Committee on Rules and Administration, and (C) costs incurred in the preparation of required official reports, and the acquisition of mailing lists to be used for official purposes, and in the mailing, delivery, or transmitting of matters relating to official business;

(4) official office expenses incurred (other than for equipment and furniture and expenses described in paragraphs (1) through (3)) for an office in his home State;

(5) expenses incurred for publications printed or recorded in any way for auditory and visual use (including subscriptions to books, newspapers, magazines, clipping, and other information services);

(6) subject to the provisions of subsection (e) of this section, reimbursement of travel expenses incurred by the Senator and employees in his office;

(7) expenses incurred for additional office equipment and services related thereto (but not including personal services), in acc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for payment from Senate contingent fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization for payment from Senate contingent fund The contingent fund of the Senate is made available for payment (including reimbursement) to or on behalf of each Senator, upon certification of the Senator, for the following expenses incurred by the Senator and his staff: Payment under this section shall be made only upon presentation of itemized vouchers for expenses incurred and, in the case of expenses paid or reimbursed under paragraphs (6) and (9), only upon presentation of detailed itemized vouchers for such expenses. Vouchers presented for payment under this section shall be accompanied by such documentation as is required under regulations promulgated by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate. No payment shall be made under paragraph (4) or (9) for any expense incurred for entertainment or meals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limits for authorized expenses; recalculation formula</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limits for authorized expenses; recalculation formula</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 97–51, § 122, Oct. 1, 1981, 95 Stat. 965</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 93–371, § 101(3)(e), Aug. 13, 1974, 88 Stat. 429</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation, essential travel-related expenses, and per diem expenses; coverage; limitations; amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transportation, essential travel-related expenses, and per diem expenses; coverage; limitations; amounts Subject to and in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate, a Senator and the employees in his office shall be reimbursed under this section for travel expenses incurred by the Senator or employee while traveling on official business within the United States. The term “travel expenses” includes actual transportation expenses, essential travel-related expenses, and, where applicable, per diem expenses (but not in excess of actual expenses). A Senator or an employee of the Senator shall not be reimbursed for any travel expenses (other than actual transportation expenses) for any travel occurring during the sixty days immediately before the date of any primary or general election (whether regular, special, or runoff) in which the Senator is a candidate for public office (within the meaning of section 30101(b) 11 So in origin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Closing of deceased Senator’s State offices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Closing of deceased Senator’s State offices In the case of the death of any Senator, the chairman of the Committee on Rules and Administration may certify for such deceased Senator for any portion of such sum already obligated but not certified to at the time of such Senator’s death, and for any additional amount which may be reasonably needed for the purpose of closing such deceased Senator’s State offices, for payment to the person or persons designated as entitled to such payment by such chairman.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals serving on panels or other bodies recommending nominees for Federal judgeships, service academies, United States Attorneys, or United States Marshals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Individuals serving on panels or other bodies recommending nominees for Federal judgeships, service academies, United States Attorneys, or United States Marshals For purposes of subsections (a) and (e), an individual who is selected by a Senator to serve on a panel or other body to make recommendations for nominees to one or more Federal judgeships or to one or more service academies or one or more positions of United States Attorney or United States Marshal shall be considered to be an employee in the office of that Senator with respect to travel and official expenses incurred in performing duties as a member of such panel or other body, and shall be reimbursed (A) for actual transportation expenses and per diem expenses (but not exceeding actual travel expenses) incurred while traveling in performing such duties within the Senator’s home State or between that State and Washington, District of Columbia, and each of the service academies, (B) for official expenses incurred in perfo</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Secretary of Senate to pay reimbursable expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of Secretary of Senate to pay reimbursable expenses Whenever a Senator or an employee in his office has incurred an expense for which reimbursement may be made under this section, the Secretary of the Senate is authorized to make payment to that Senator or employee for the expense incurred, subject to the same terms and conditions as apply to reimbursement of the expense under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advances from Senate contingent fund for travel expenses for official business trips; vouchers; settlement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Advances from Senate contingent fund for travel expenses for official business trips; vouchers; settlement Whenever a Senator or employee of his office plans an official business trip with respect to which reimbursement for travel expenses is authorized under the preceding provisions of section (a), the Senator (or such an employee who has been designated by the Senator to do so) may, prior to the commencement of such trip and in accordance with applicable regulations of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, obtain from any moneys in the contingent fund of the Senate which are available to him for purposes specified in subsection (a)(6) of this section, such advance sum as he shall certify (and be accountable for), to the Secretary of the Senate, to be necessary to defray some or all of the expenses to be incurred on such trip which expenses are reimbursable under the preceding provisions of this section. The receipt by any Senator for any sum so advanced to him or his </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>