<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/640" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/640/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/640/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_640"><akn:num>640</akn:num><akn:heading>House approval of regular appropriation bills</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 640. House approval of regular appropriation bills
It shall not be in order in the House of Representatives to consider any resolution providing for an adjournment period of more than three calendar days during the month of July until the House of Representatives has approved annual appropriation bills providing new budget authority under the jurisdiction of all the subcommittees of the Committee on Appropriations for the fiscal year beginning on October 1 of such year. For purposes of this section, the chairman of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives shall periodically advise the Speaker as to changes in jurisdiction among its various subcommittees.
(Pub. L. 93–344, title III, § 309, July 12, 1974, 88 Stat. 314; Pub. L. 99–177, title II, § 201(b), Dec. 12, 1985, 99 Stat. 1052.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 1330 of Title 31 prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 31, Money and Finance, by Pub. L. 97–258, § 1, Sept. 13, 1982, 96 Stat. 877.

Amendments1985—Pub. L. 99–177 substituted “House approval of regular appropriation bills” for “Completion of action on bills providing new budget authority and certain new spending authority” in section catchline, and amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “Except as otherwise provided pursuant to this subchapter, not later than the seventh day after Labor Day of each year, the Congress shall complete action on all bills and resolutions—
“(1) providing new budget authority for the fiscal year beginning on October 1 of such year, other than supplemental, deficiency, and continuing appropriation bills and resolutions, and other than the reconciliation bill for such year, if required to be reported under section 641(c) of this title; and
“(2) providing new spending authority described in section 651(c)(2)(C) of this title which is to become effective during such fiscal year.
Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any bill </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>