<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6519" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6519/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6519/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6519"><akn:num>6519</akn:num><akn:heading>McCain-Mansfield and SFC Sean Cooley and SPC Christopher Horton Congressional Gold Star Family Fello</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6519. McCain-Mansfield and SFC Sean Cooley and SPC Christopher Horton Congressional Gold Star Family Fellowships Programs(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “appropriate committees of the Senate” means the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate;

(2) the term “Fellowships Programs” means the SFC Sean Cooley and SPC Christopher Horton Congressional Gold Star Family Fellowship Program (commonly referred to as the “Green and Gold Congressional Aide Program”) established under Senate Resolution 442 (117th Congress), agreed to November 4, 2021, and the McCain-Mansfield Fellowship Program established under Senate Resolution 443 (117th Congress), agreed to November 4, 2021, or any successor program to such programs;

(3) the term “Fund” means the Sergeant at Arms Fellowships Fund established under subsection (b); and

(4) the term “Sergeant at Arms” means the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.


(b) EstablishmentThere is established under the heading “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” an account to be known as the “sergeant at arms fellowships fund”.


(c) Use of amounts(1) In generalAmounts in the Fund shall be available to the Sergeant at Arms for the costs of compensation of fellows under the Fellowships Programs and the administration of the Fellowships Programs, except as provided in paragraph (2).


(2) Agency contributionsAgency contributions for the Fellowships Programs shall be paid from the appropriations account for “Salaries, Officers and Employees” of the Senate.



(d) OversightThe Sergeant at Arms shall provide to the appropriate committees of the Senate—(1) a plan regarding the administration of the Fund by the Sergeant at Arms prior to obligation of any funds, to be updated and resubmitted following any changes to the plan; and

(2) annual reports regarding the costs of the Fellowships Programs paid from the Fund.


(e) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6519_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6519_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment There is established under the heading “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” an account to be known as the “sergeant at arms fellowships fund”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6519_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6519_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Oversight The Sergeant at Arms shall provide to the appropriate committees of the Senate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6519_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund for fiscal year 2023, and each fiscal year thereafter, such sums as are necessary for the compensation of fellows under the Fellowships Programs during the fiscal year and for the administration of the Fellowships Programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6519_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion for purposes of staffing limits on the Office of the Sergeant at Arms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exclusion for purposes of staffing limits on the Office of the Sergeant at Arms The payment of compensation to any individual serving in a fellowship under the Fellowships Programs by the Sergeant at Arms shall not be included for purposes of any limitation on staffing levels of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>