<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6578" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6578/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6578/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6578"><akn:num>6578</akn:num><akn:heading>Senate Leader’s Lecture Series</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6578. Senate Leader’s Lecture Series(a) EstablishmentThere is established the Senate Leader’s Lecture Series (hereinafter referred to as the “lecture series”). Expenses incurred in connection with the lecture series shall be paid from the appropriations account “Secretary of the Senate” within the contingent fund of the Senate and shall not exceed $30,000 in any fiscal year.


(b) Expenses coveredPayments for expenses in connection with the lecture series may cover expenses incurred by speakers, including travel, subsistence, and per diem, and the cost of receptions, including food, food related items, and hospitality.


(c) Payments for expensesPayments for expenses of the lecture series shall be made on vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Senate.


(d) Effective dateThis section is effective on and after October 1, 1997.


(Pub. L. 105–275, title I, § 5, Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2433.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 69b of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.
Section is from the Congressional Operations Appropriations Act, 1999, which is title I of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6578_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established the Senate Leader’s Lecture Series (hereinafter referred to as the “lecture series”). Expenses incurred in connection with the lecture series shall be paid from the appropriations account “Secretary of the Senate” within the contingent fund of the Senate and shall not exceed $30,000 in any fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6578_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expenses covered Payments for expenses in connection with the lecture series may cover expenses incurred by speakers, including travel, subsistence, and per diem, and the cost of receptions, including food, food related items, and hospitality.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6578_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments for expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments for expenses Payments for expenses of the lecture series shall be made on vouchers approved by the Secretary of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6578_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date This section is effective on and after October 1, 1997.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>