<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/658b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/658b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/658b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_658b"><akn:num>658b</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 658b. Duties of Congressional committees(a) In generalWhen a committee of authorization of the Senate or the House of Representatives reports a bill or joint resolution of public character that includes any Federal mandate, the report of the committee accompanying the bill or joint resolution shall contain the information required by subsections (c) and (d).


(b) Submission of bills to DirectorWhen a committee of authorization of the Senate or the House of Representatives orders reported a bill or joint resolution of a public character, the committee shall promptly provide the bill or joint resolution to the Director of the Congressional Budget Office and shall identify to the Director any Federal mandates contained in the bill or resolution.


(c) Reports on Federal mandatesEach report described under subsection (a) shall contain—(1) an identification and description of any Federal mandates in the bill or joint resolution, including the direct costs to State, local, and tribal governments, and to the private sector, required to comply with the Federal mandates;

(2) a qualitative, and if practicable, a quantitative assessment of costs and benefits anticipated from the Federal mandates (including the effects on health and safety and the protection of the natural environment); and

(3) a statement of the degree to which a Federal mandate affects both the public and private sectors and the extent to which Federal payment of public sector costs or the modification or termination of the Federal mandate as provided under section 658d(a)(2) of this title would affect the competitive balance between State, local, or tribal governments and the private sector including a description of the actions, if any, taken by the committee to avoid any adverse impact on the private sector or the competitive balance between the public sector and the private sector.


(d) Intergovernmental mandatesIf any of the Federal mandates in the bill or joint resolution are Federal intergovernme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general When a committee of authorization of the Senate or the House of Representatives reports a bill or joint resolution of public character that includes any Federal mandate, the report of the committee accompanying the bill or joint resolution shall contain the information required by subsections (c) and (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of bills to Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submission of bills to Director When a committee of authorization of the Senate or the House of Representatives orders reported a bill or joint resolution of a public character, the committee shall promptly provide the bill or joint resolution to the Director of the Congressional Budget Office and shall identify to the Director any Federal mandates contained in the bill or resolution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports on Federal mandates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports on Federal mandates Each report described under subsection (a) shall contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intergovernmental mandates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Intergovernmental mandates If any of the Federal mandates in the bill or joint resolution are Federal intergovernmental mandates, the report required under subsection (a) shall also contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption clarification and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preemption clarification and information When a committee of authorization of the Senate or the House of Representatives reports a bill or joint resolution of public character, the committee report accompanying the bill or joint resolution shall contain, if relevant to the bill or joint resolution, an explicit statement on the extent to which the bill or joint resolution is intended to preempt any State, local, or tribal law, and, if so, an explanation of the effect of such preemption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of statement from Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Publication of statement from Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>