<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/658e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/658e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/658e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_658e"><akn:num>658e</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to House of Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 658e. Provisions relating to House of Representatives(a) Enforcement in House of RepresentativesIt shall not be in order in the House of Representatives to consider a rule or order that waives the application of section 658d of this title.


(b) Disposition of points of order(1) Application to House of RepresentativesThis subsection shall apply only to the House of Representatives.


(2) Threshold burdenIn order to be cognizable by the Chair, a point of order under section 658d of this title or subsection (a) of this section must specify the precise language on which it is premised.


(3) Question of considerationAs disposition of points of order under section 658d of this title or subsection (a) of this section, the Chair shall put the question of consideration with respect to the proposition that is the subject of the points of order.


(4) Debate and intervening motionsA question of consideration under this section shall be debatable for 10 minutes by each Member initiating a point of order and for 10 minutes by an opponent on each point of order, but shall otherwise be decided without intervening motion except one that the House adjourn or that the Committee of the Whole rise, as the case may be.


(5) Effect on amendment in order as original textThe disposition of the question of consideration under this subsection with respect to a bill or joint resolution shall be considered also to determine the question of consideration under this subsection with respect to an amendment made in order as original text.



(Pub. L. 93–344, title IV, § 426, as added Pub. L. 104–4, title I, § 101(a)(2), Mar. 22, 1995, 109 Stat. 59.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Jan. 1, 1996, or on the date 90 days after appropriations are made available as authorized under section 1516 of this title, whichever is earlier, and applicable to legislation considered on and after such date, see section 110 of Pub. L. 104–4, set out as a note under secti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement in House of Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enforcement in House of Representatives It shall not be in order in the House of Representatives to consider a rule or order that waives the application of section 658d of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of points of order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disposition of points of order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>