<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/6611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6611"><akn:num>6611</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer authority and Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6611. Transfer authority and Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund(a) In generalThe Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized, with the approval of the Senate Committee on Appropriations, to transfer, during any fiscal year, from the appropriations account, appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper”, such sums as he shall specify to the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate; and any funds so transferred shall be available in like manner and for the same purposes as are other funds in the account to which the funds are transferred.


(b) Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund(1) DefinitionsIn this subsection—(A) the term “Fund” means the Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund established under paragraph (2); and

(B) the term “Sergeant at Arms” means the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.


(2) EstablishmentThere is established under the heading “Contingent Expenses of the Senate” an account to be known as the “Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund”.


(3) Use of amountsAmounts in the Fund shall be available to the Sergeant at Arms for purposes of the business continuity and disaster recovery needs of the Senate.


(4) Authority to transfer(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (C), prior to the date of the withdrawal of amounts appropriated under the heading “Contingent Expenses of the Senate—sergeant at arms and doorkeeper of the senate” in accordance with section 4107 of this title, any unobligated balances of expired discretionary appropriations of such amounts may be transferred by the Sergeant at Arms to the Fund.


(B) Period of availabilityAmounts transferred under subparagraph (A) shall remain available until expended.


(C) NoticeIf the Sergeant </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate is authorized, with the approval of the Senate Committee on Appropriations, to transfer, during any fiscal year, from the appropriations account, appropriated under the headings “Salaries, Officers and Employees” and “Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper”, such sums as he shall specify to the appropriations account, within the contingent fund of the Senate, for expenses of the Office of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate; and any funds so transferred shall be available in like manner and for the same purposes as are other funds in the account to which the funds are transferred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6611_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sergeant at Arms Business Continuity and Disaster Recovery Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>