<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/661a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/661a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/661a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_661a"><akn:num>661a</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 661a. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter—(1) The term “direct loan” means a disbursement of funds by the Government to a non-Federal borrower under a contract that requires the repayment of such funds with or without interest. The term includes the purchase of, or participation in, a loan made by another lender and financing arrangements that defer payment for more than 90 days, including the sale of a government 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. asset on credit terms. The term does not include the acquisition of a federally guaranteed loan in satisfaction of default claims or the price support loans of the Commodity Credit Corporation.

(2) The term “direct loan obligation” means a binding agreement by a Federal agency to make a direct loan when specified conditions are fulfilled by the borrower.

(3) The term “loan guarantee” means any guarantee, insurance, or other pledge with respect to the payment of all or a part of the principal or interest on any debt obligation of a non-Federal borrower to a non-Federal lender, but does not include the insurance of deposits, shares, or other withdrawable accounts in financial institutions.

(4) The term “loan guarantee commitment” means a binding agreement by a Federal agency to make a loan guarantee when specified conditions are fulfilled by the borrower, the lender, or any other party to the guarantee agreement.

(5)(A) The term “cost” means the estimated long-term cost to the Government of a direct loan or loan guarantee or modification thereof, calculated on a net present value basis, excluding administrative costs and any incidental effects on governmental receipts or outlays.

(B) The cost of a direct loan shall be the net present value, at the time when the direct loan is disbursed, of the following estimated cash flows:(i) loan disbursements;

(ii) repayments of principal; and

(iii) payments of interest and other payments by or to the Government over the life of the loan after adjusting </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “direct loan” means a disbursement of funds by the Government to a non-Federal borrower under a contract that requires the repayment of such funds with or without interest. The term includes the purchase of, or participation in, a loan made by another lender and financing arrangements that defer payment for more than 90 days, including the sale of a government 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. asset on credit terms. The term does not include the acquisition of a federally guaranteed loan in satisfaction of default claims or the price support loans of the Commodity Credit Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “direct loan obligation” means a binding agreement by a Federal agency to make a direct loan when specified conditions are fulfilled by the borrower.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “loan guarantee” means any guarantee, insurance, or other pledge with respect to the payment of all or a part of the principal or interest on any debt obligation of a non-Federal borrower to a non-Federal lender, but does not include the insurance of deposits, shares, or other withdrawable accounts in financial institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “loan guarantee commitment” means a binding agreement by a Federal agency to make a loan guarantee when specified conditions are fulfilled by the borrower, the lender, or any other party to the guarantee agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “credit program account” means the budget account into which an appropriation to cover the cost of a direct loan or loan guarantee program is made and from which such cost is disbursed to the financing account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “financing account” means the non-budget account or accounts associated with each credit program account which holds balances, receives the cost payment from the credit program account, and also includes all other cash flows to and from the Government resulting from direct loan obligations or loan guarantee commitments made on or after October 1, 1991.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “liquidating account” means the budget account that includes all cash flows to and from the Government resulting from direct loan obligations or loan guarantee commitments made prior to October 1, 1991.These accounts shall be shown in the budget on a cash basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “modification” means any Government action that alters the estimated cost of an outstanding direct loan (or direct loan obligation) or an outstanding loan guarantee (or loan guarantee commitment) from the current estimate of cash flows. This includes the sale of loan assets, with or without recourse, and the purchase of guaranteed loans. This also includes any action resulting from new legislation, or from the exercise of administrative discretion under existing law, that directly or indirectly alters the estimated cost of outstanding direct loans (or direct loan obligations) or loan guarantees (or loan guarantee commitments) such as a change in collection procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661a_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “current” has the same meaning as in section 900(c)(9) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>