<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/688" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/688/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/688/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_688"><akn:num>688</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure in House of Representatives and Senate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 688. Procedure in House of Representatives and Senate(a) ReferralAny rescission bill introduced with respect to a special message or impoundment resolution introduced with respect to a proposed deferral of budget authority shall be referred to the appropriate committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate, as the case may be.


(b) Discharge of committee(1) If the committee to which a rescission bill or impoundment resolution has been referred has not reported it at the end of 25 calendar days of continuous session of the Congress after its introduction, it is in order to move either to discharge the committee from further consideration of the bill or resolution or to discharge the committee from further consideration of any other rescission bill with respect to the same special message or impoundment resolution with respect to the same proposed deferral, as the case may be, which has been referred to the committee.

(2) A motion to discharge may be made only by an individual favoring the bill or resolution, may be made only if supported by one-fifth of the Members of the House involved (a quorum being present), and is highly privileged in the House and privileged in the Senate (except that it may not be made after the committee has reported a bill or resolution with respect to the same special message or the same proposed deferral, as the case may be); and debate thereon shall be limited to not more than 1 hour, the time to be divided in the House equally between those favoring and those opposing the bill or resolution, and to be divided in the Senate equally between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees. An amendment to the motion is not in order, and it is not in order to move to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to.


(c) Floor consideration in House(1) When the committee of the House of Representatives has reported, or has been discharged from further consideration of, a res</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Referral Any rescission bill introduced with respect to a special message or impoundment resolution introduced with respect to a proposed deferral of budget authority shall be referred to the appropriate committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge of committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Discharge of committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Floor consideration in House</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Floor consideration in House</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Floor consideration in Senate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Floor consideration in Senate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>