<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_901"><akn:num>901</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcing discretionary spending limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 901. Enforcing discretionary spending limits(a) Enforcement(1) SequestrationWithin 15 calendar days after Congress adjourns to end a session there shall be a sequestration to eliminate a budget-year breach, if any, within any category.


(2) Eliminating a breachEach non-exempt account within a category shall be reduced by a dollar amount calculated by multiplying the enacted level of sequestrable budgetary resources in that account at that time by the uniform percentage necessary to eliminate a breach within that category.


(3) Military personnelIf the President uses the authority to exempt any personnel account from sequestration under section 905(f) of this title, each account within subfunctional category 051 (other than those military personnel accounts for which the authority provided under section 905(f) of this title has been exercised) shall be further reduced by a dollar amount calculated by multiplying the enacted level of non-exempt budgetary resources in that account at that time by the uniform percentage necessary to offset the total dollar amount by which outlays are not reduced in military personnel accounts by reason of the use of such authority.


(4) Part-year appropriationsIf, on the date specified in paragraph (1), there is in effect an Act making or continuing appropriations for part of a fiscal year for any budget account, then the dollar sequestration calculated for that account under paragraphs (2) and (3) shall be subtracted from—(A) the annualized amount otherwise available by law in that account under that or a subsequent part-year appropriation; and

(B) when a full-year appropriation for that account is enacted, from the amount otherwise provided by the full-year appropriation for that account.


(5) Look-backIf, after June 30, an appropriation for the fiscal year in progress is enacted that causes a breach within a category for that year (after taking into account any sequestration of amounts within that category), the discretionary </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments to discretionary spending limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjustments to discretionary spending limits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretionary spending limit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Discretionary spending limit As used in this subchapter, the term “discretionary spending limit” means— as adjusted in strict conformance with subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revised discretionary spending limits for fiscal year 2024</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Revised discretionary spending limits for fiscal year 2024</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_901_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revised discretionary spending limits for fiscal year 2025</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Revised discretionary spending limits for fiscal year 2025</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>