<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_903"><akn:num>903</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcing deficit targets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 903. Enforcing deficit targets(a) SequestrationWithin 15 calendar days after Congress adjourns to end a session (other than of the One Hundred First Congress) and on the same day as a sequestration (if any) under section 901 of this title and section 902 of this title, but after any sequestration required by section 901 of this title (enforcing discretionary spending limits) or section 902 of this title (enforcing pay-as-you-go), there shall be a sequestration to eliminate the excess deficit (if any remains) if it exceeds the margin.


(b) Excess deficit; marginThe excess deficit is, if greater than zero, the estimated deficit for the budget year, minus—(1) the maximum deficit amount for that year;

(2) the amounts for that year designated as emergency direct spending or receipts legislation under section 902(e) of this title; and

(3) for any fiscal year in which there is not a full adjustment for technical and economic reestimates, the deposit insurance reestimate for that year, if any, calculated under subsection (h).


The “margin” for fiscal year 1992 or 1993 is zero and for fiscal year 1994 or 1995 is $15,000,000,000.

(c) Dividing sequestrationTo eliminate the excess deficit in a budget year, half of the required outlay reductions shall be obtained from non-exempt defense accounts (accounts designated as function 050 in the President’s fiscal year 1991 budget submission) and half from non-exempt, non-defense accounts (all other non-exempt accounts).


(d) DefenseEach non-exempt defense account shall be reduced by a dollar amount calculated by multiplying the level of sequestrable budgetary resources in that account at that time by the uniform percentage necessary to carry out subsection (c), except that, if any military personnel are exempt, adjustments shall be made under the procedure set forth in section 901(a)(3) of this title.


(e) Non-defenseActions to reduce non-defense accounts shall be taken in the following order:(1) FirstAll reductions in automa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sequestration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sequestration Within 15 calendar days after Congress adjourns to end a session (other than of the One Hundred First Congress) and on the same day as a sequestration (if any) under section 901 of this title and section 902 of this title, but after any sequestration required by section 901 of this title (enforcing discretionary spending limits) or section 902 of this title (enforcing pay-as-you-go), there shall be a sequestration to eliminate the excess deficit (if any remains) if it exceeds the margin.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess deficit; margin</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Excess deficit; margin The excess deficit is, if greater than zero, the estimated deficit for the budget year, minus— The “margin” for fiscal year 1992 or 1993 is zero and for fiscal year 1994 or 1995 is $15,000,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dividing sequestration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dividing sequestration To eliminate the excess deficit in a budget year, half of the required outlay reductions shall be obtained from non-exempt defense accounts (accounts designated as function 050 in the President’s fiscal year 1991 budget submission) and half from non-exempt, non-defense accounts (all other non-exempt accounts).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Defense Each non-exempt defense account shall be reduced by a dollar amount calculated by multiplying the level of sequestrable budgetary resources in that account at that time by the uniform percentage necessary to carry out subsection (c), except that, if any military personnel are exempt, adjustments shall be made under the procedure set forth in section 901(a)(3) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Non-defense Actions to reduce non-defense accounts shall be taken in the following order:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Baseline assumptions; part-year appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Baseline assumptions; part-year appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments to maximum deficit amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Adjustments to maximum deficit amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_903_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of deposit insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Treatment of deposit insurance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>