<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_905"><akn:num>905</akn:num><akn:heading>Exempt programs and activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 905. Exempt programs and activities(a) Social security benefits and tier I railroad retirement benefitsBenefits payable under the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.), and benefits payable under sections 231b and 231c 11 See References in Text note below. of title 45, shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter.


(b) Veterans programsThe following programs shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter:
All programs administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs.
Special benefits for certain World War II veterans (28–0401–0–1–701).


(c) Net interestNo reduction of payments for net interest (all of major functional category 900) shall be made under any order issued under this subchapter.


(d) Refundable income tax credits and certain elective payments(1) Refundable income tax creditsPayments to individuals made pursuant to provisions of title 26 establishing refundable tax credits shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter.


(2) Certain elective paymentsPayments made to taxpayers pursuant to elections under subsection (d) of section 48D of title 26, or amounts treated as payments which are made by taxpayers under paragraph (1) of such subsection, shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter.



(e) Non-defense unobligated balancesUnobligated balances of budget authority carried over from prior fiscal years, except balances in the defense category, shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter.


(f) Optional exemption of military personnel(1) In generalThe President may, with respect to any military personnel account, exempt that account from sequestration or provide for a lower uniform percentage reduction than would otherwise apply.


(2) LimitationThe President may not use the authority provided by paragraph (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Social security benefits and tier I railroad retirement benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Social security benefits and tier I railroad retirement benefits Benefits payable under the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.), and benefits payable under sections 231b and 231c 11 See References in Text note below. of title 45, shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterans programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Veterans programs The following programs shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter:
All programs administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs.
Special benefits for certain World War II veterans (28–0401–0–1–701).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Net interest No reduction of payments for net interest (all of major functional category 900) shall be made under any order issued under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refundable income tax credits and certain elective payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Refundable income tax credits and certain elective payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-defense unobligated balances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Non-defense unobligated balances Unobligated balances of budget authority carried over from prior fiscal years, except balances in the defense category, shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Optional exemption of military personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Optional exemption of military personnel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other programs and activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Other programs and activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-income programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Low-income programs The following programs shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter:
Academic Competitiveness/Smart Grant Program (91–0205–0–1–502).
Child Care Entitlement to States (75–1550–0–1–609).
Child Enrollment Contingency Fund (75–5551–0–2–551).
Child Nutrition Programs (with the exception of special milk programs) (12–3539–0–1–605).
Children’s Health Insurance Fund (75–0515–0–1–551).
Commodity Supplemental Food Program (12–3507–0–1–605).
Contingency Fund (75–1522–0–1–609).
Family Support Programs (75–1501–0–1–609).
Federal Pell Grants under section 1070a of title 20.
Grants to States for Medicaid (75–0512–0–1–551).
Payments for Foster Care and Permanency (75–1545–0–1–609).
Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (12–3505–0–1–605).
Supplemental Security Income Program (28–0406–0–1–609).
Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (75–1552–0–1–609).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic recovery programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Economic recovery programs The following programs shall be exempt from reduction under any order issued under this subchapter:
GSE Preferred Stock Purchase Agreements (20–0125–0–1–371).
Office of Financial Stability (20–0128–0–1–376).
Special Inspector General for the Troubled Asset Relief Program (20–0133–0–1–376).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_905_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Split treatment programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Split treatment programs Each of the following programs shall be exempt from any order under this subchapter to the extent that the budgetary resources of such programs are subject to obligation limitations in appropriations bills:
Federal-Aid Highways (69–8083–0–7–401).
Highway Traffic Safety Grants (69–8020–0–7–401).
Operations and Research NHTSA and National Driver Register (69–8016–0–7–401).
Motor Carrier Safety Operations and Programs (69–8159–0–7–401).
Motor Carrier Safety Grants (69–8158–0–7–401).
Formula and Bus Grants (69–8350–0–7–401).
Grants-In-Aid for Airports (69–8106–0–7–402).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>