<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/939" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/939/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/2/939/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_939"><akn:num>939</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on changes to the Social Security Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 939. Limitation on changes to the Social Security Act(a) Limitation on changes to the Social Security ActNotwithstanding any other provision of law, it shall not be in order in the Senate or the House of Representatives to consider any bill or resolution pursuant to any expedited procedure to consider the recommendations of a Task Force for Responsible Fiscal Action or other commission that contains recommendations with respect to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.], or the taxes received under subchapter A of chapter 9; the taxes imposed by subchapter E of chapter 1; and the taxes collected under section 86 of part II of subchapter B of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code.


(b) WaiverThis section may be waived or suspended in the Senate only by the affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members, duly chosen and sworn.


(c) AppealsAn affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members of the Senate, duly chosen and sworn, shall be required in the Senate to sustain an appeal of the ruling of the Chair on a point of order raised under this section.


(Pub. L. 111–139, title I, § 13, Feb. 12, 2010, 124 Stat. 29.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, 49 Stat. 620. Title II of the Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 401 et seq.) of chapter 7 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 1305 of Title 42 and Tables.
Subchapter A of chapter 9 and subchapter E of chapter 1, referred to in subsec. (a), probably mean subchapter A of chapter 9 and subchapter E of chapter 1, respectively, of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, which were comprised of sections 1400 to 1432 and 480 to 482, respectively, and were repealed (subject to certain exceptions) by section 7851(a)(1)(A), (3) of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_939_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on changes to the Social Security Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitation on changes to the Social Security Act Notwithstanding any other provision of law, it shall not be in order in the Senate or the House of Representatives to consider any bill or resolution pursuant to any expedited procedure to consider the recommendations of a Task Force for Responsible Fiscal Action or other commission that contains recommendations with respect to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.], or the taxes received under subchapter A of chapter 9; the taxes imposed by subchapter E of chapter 1; and the taxes collected under section 86 of part II of subchapter B of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_939_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Waiver This section may be waived or suspended in the Senate only by the affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members, duly chosen and sworn.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_939_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appeals An affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members of the Senate, duly chosen and sworn, shall be required in the Senate to sustain an appeal of the ruling of the Chair on a point of order raised under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>