<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/1/1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/1/1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/1/1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1"><akn:num>1</akn:num><akn:heading>Words denoting number, gender, and so forth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1. Words denoting number, gender, and so forth
In determining the meaning of any Act of Congress, unless the context indicates otherwise—
words importing the singular include and apply to several persons, parties, or things;
words importing the plural include the singular;
words importing the masculine gender include the feminine as well;
words used in the present tense include the future as well as the present;
the words “insane” and “insane person” shall include every idiot, insane person, and person non compos mentis;
the words “person” and “whoever” include corporations, companies, associations, firms, partnerships, societies, and joint stock companies, as well as individuals;
“officer” includes any person authorized by law to perform the duties of the office;
“signature” or “subscription” includes a mark when the person making the same intended it as such;
“oath” includes affirmation, and “sworn” includes affirmed;
“writing” includes printing and typewriting and reproductions of visual symbols by photographing, multigraphing, mimeographing, manifolding, or otherwise.
(July 30, 1947, ch. 388, 61 Stat. 633; June 25, 1948, ch. 645, § 6, 62 Stat. 859; Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 1, 65 Stat. 710; Pub. L. 112–231, § 2(a), Dec. 28, 2012, 126 Stat. 1619.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2012—Pub. L. 112–231, in fifth clause after opening clause, struck out “and ‘lunatic’ ” before “shall include every” and “lunatic,” before “insane person,”.
1951—Act Oct. 31, 1951, substituted, in fourth clause after opening clause, “used” for “use”.
1948—Act June 25, 1948, included “tense”, “whoever”, “signature”, “subscription”, “writing” and a broader definition of “person”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short Title of 2022 AmendmentPub. L. 117–228, § 1, Dec. 13, 2022, 136 Stat. 2305, provided that: “This Act [enacting section 1738C of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, amending section 7 of this title, repealing section 1738C of Title 28, and enacting provisions set </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>