<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/1/106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/1/106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/1/106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_106"><akn:num>106</akn:num><akn:heading>Printing bills and joint resolutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 106. Printing bills and joint resolutions
Every bill or joint resolution in each House of Congress shall, when such bill or resolution passes either House, be printed, and such printed copy shall be called the engrossed bill or resolution as the case may be. Said engrossed bill or resolution shall be signed by the Clerk of the House or the Secretary of the Senate, and shall be sent to the other House, and in that form shall be dealt with by that House and its officers, and, if passed, returned signed by said Clerk or Secretary. When such bill, or joint resolution shall have passed both Houses, it shall be printed and shall then be called the enrolled bill, or joint resolution, as the case may be, and shall be signed by the presiding officers of both Houses and sent to the President of the United States. During the last six days of a session such engrossing and enrolling of bills and joint resolutions may be done otherwise than as above prescribed, upon the order of Congress by concurrent resolution.
(July 30, 1947, ch. 388, 61 Stat. 634.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Reference to OBRA; Effective Date; Ratification of Enrollment Corrections and Printed EnrollmentPub. L. 100–360, title IV, § 411(a), July 1, 1988, 102 Stat. 768, provided that:
“(1) Reference.—In this section, the term ‘OBRA’ refers to the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987 (Public Law 100–203) [Pub. L. 100–203, Dec. 22, 1987, 101 Stat. 1330, see Tables for classification].

“(2) Effective date.—Except as specifically provided in this section, the amendments made by this section [amending sections 254o, 294f, 300aa–12, 300aa–15, 300aa–21, 426, 704, 912, 1320a–7, 1320a–7a, 1320a–7b, 1320b–5, 1320b–7, 1320b–8, 1320c–3, 1320c–5, 1320c–9, 1395e, 1395h, 1395i–2, 1395i–3, 1395k, 1395l, 1395m, 1395u, 1395w–1, 1395w–2, 1395x, 1395y, 1395aa, 1395bb, 1395cc, 1395dd, 1395gg, 1395mm, 1395ss, 1395tt, 1395ww, 1395aaa, 1395bbb, 1395ccc, 1396a, 1396b, 1396d, 1396j, 1396n, 1396o, 1396p, 1396r, 1396</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>