<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/225d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/225d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/225d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_225d"><akn:num>225d</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition provisions for employees of Hospital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 225d. Transition provisions for employees of Hospital(a) Retirement opportunityEmployees of the Hospital directly affected by the assumption of programs and functions by the District government who meet the requirements for immediate retirement under the provisions of section 8336(d) of title 5 shall be accorded the opportunity to retire during the 30-day period prior to the assumption of such programs and functions.


(b) Specific number and types of positions; transfer to District employment(1) The system implementation plan shall prescribe the specific number and types of positions needed by the District government at the end of the service coordination period.

(2) Notwithstanding section 3503 of title 5, employees of the Hospital shall only be transferred to District employment under the provisions of this section.


(c) Retention list; reemployment priority list; right-of-first-refusal; retention registers; employee appeals(1) While on the retention list or the District or Federal agency reemployment priority list, the system implementation plan shall provide to Hospital employees a right-of-first-refusal to District employment in positions for which such employees may qualify, (A) created under the system implementation plan in the comprehensive District mental health system, (B) available under the Department of Human Services of the District, and (C) available at the District of Columbia General Hospital.

(2) In accordance with Federal regulations, the Secretary shall establish retention registers of Hospital employees and provide such retention registers to the District government. Employment in positions identified in the system implementation plan under subsection (b) shall be offered to Hospital employees by the District government according to each such employee’s relative standing on the retention registers.

(3) Employee appeals concerning the retention registers established by the Secretary shall be in accordance with Federal regulations.

(4) Em</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_225d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement opportunity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Retirement opportunity Employees of the Hospital directly affected by the assumption of programs and functions by the District government who meet the requirements for immediate retirement under the provisions of section 8336(d) of title 5 shall be accorded the opportunity to retire during the 30-day period prior to the assumption of such programs and functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_225d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specific number and types of positions; transfer to District employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Specific number and types of positions; transfer to District employment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_225d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention list; reemployment priority list; right-of-first-refusal; retention registers; employee appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Retention list; reemployment priority list; right-of-first-refusal; retention registers; employee appeals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_225d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agency reemployment priority list; right-of-first-refusal; Department of Health and Human Services; separation; maintenance of lists; District agency reemployment priority list; refusal of employment offer; acceptance of nontemporary employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal agency reemployment priority list; right-of-first-refusal; Department of Health and Human Services; separation; maintenance of lists; District agency reemployment priority list; refusal of employment offer; acceptance of nontemporary employment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_225d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts; mental health services; preferences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contracts; mental health services; preferences Any contract entered into by the District of Columbia for the provision of mental health services formerly provided by or at the Hospital shall require the contractor or provider, in filling new positions created to perform under the contract, to give preference to qualified candidates on the District agency reemployment priority list created pursuant to subsection (d) of this section. An individual who is offered nontemporary employment with a contractor shall have his or her name remain on the District agency reemployment priority list under subsection (d) for not more than 24 months from the date of acceptance of such employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>