<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/295a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/295a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/295a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_295a"><akn:num>295a</akn:num><akn:heading>Arlington Memorial Amphitheater</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 295a. Arlington Memorial Amphitheater(a) Recommendations of Secretary of Defense for memorials and entombmentsThe Secretary of Defense or his designee may send to Congress in January of each year, his recommendations with respect to the memorials to be erected, and the remains of deceased members of the Armed Forces to be entombed, in the Arlington Memorial Amphitheater, Arlington National Cemetery, Virginia.


(b) Specific authorization from CongressNo memorial may be erected and no remains may be entombed in such amphitheater unless specifically authorized by Congress.


(c) Character of memorialsThe character, design, or location of any memorial authorized by Congress is subject to the approval of the Secretary of Defense or his designee.


(Pub. L. 86–694, § 1, Sept. 2, 1960, 74 Stat. 739.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Memorial to Veterans of Vietnam ConflictPub. L. 95–479, title III, § 307, Oct. 18, 1978, 92 Stat. 1566, provided that: “The Secretary of Defense shall have placed in the Trophy Hall of the Memorial Amphitheater at Arlington National Cemetery a memorial plaque which shall bear the following inscription: ‘The people of the United States of America pay tribute to those members of the Armed Forces of the United States who served honorably in Southeast Asia during the Vietnam conflict.’. To further honor those members of the Armed Forces who lost their lives in hostile action in Southeast Asia during the Vietnam conflict, the Secretary of Defense shall have placed near such plaque in a suitable repository a display of the Purple Heart Medal and other medals, ribbons, and decorations associated with service in Southeast Asia during the Vietnam conflict.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations of Secretary of Defense for memorials and entombments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recommendations of Secretary of Defense for memorials and entombments The Secretary of Defense or his designee may send to Congress in January of each year, his recommendations with respect to the memorials to be erected, and the remains of deceased members of the Armed Forces to be entombed, in the Arlington Memorial Amphitheater, Arlington National Cemetery, Virginia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specific authorization from Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Specific authorization from Congress No memorial may be erected and no remains may be entombed in such amphitheater unless specifically authorized by Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Character of memorials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Character of memorials The character, design, or location of any memorial authorized by Congress is subject to the approval of the Secretary of Defense or his designee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>