<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/30" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/30/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/30/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30"><akn:num>30</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to donors of blood for persons undergoing treatment at Government expense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30. Payments to donors of blood for persons undergoing treatment at Government expense
Any person, whether or not in the employ of the United States, who shall furnish blood from his or her veins for transfusion into the veins of a person entitled to and undergoing treatment at Government expense, whether in a Federal hospital or institution or in a civilian hospital or institution, or who shall furnish blood for blood banks or for other scientific and research purposes in connection with the care of any person entitled to treatment at Government expense, shall be entitled to be paid therefor such reasonable sum, not to exceed $50, for each blood withdrawal as may be determined by the head of the department or independent agency concerned, from public funds available to such department or independent agency for medical and hospital supplies: Provided, That no payment shall be made under this authority to any person for blood withdrawn for the benefit of the person from whom it is withdrawn.
(Feb. 9, 1927, ch. 91, 44 Stat. 1066; June 2, 1939, ch. 173, 53 Stat. 803; July 30, 1941, ch. 332, 55 Stat. 609.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1941—Act July 30, 1941, struck out requirement that donor had to be in the Military Establishment or a Government employee and that patient had to be in a Government hospital to have donor qualify for payment.
1939—Act June 2, 1939, included the furnishing of blood by employees of the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>