<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/35" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/35/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/35/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_35"><akn:num>35</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of medical, surgical or hospital services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 35. Limitation of medical, surgical or hospital services
Hospitalization of the dependents of naval and Marine Corps personnel and of the persons outside the naval service mentioned in section 34 of this title shall be furnished only for acute medical and surgical conditions, exclusive of nervous, mental, or contagious diseases or those requiring domiciliary care. Routine dental care, other than dental prosthesis and orthodontia, may be furnished to such persons who are outside the naval service under the same conditions as are prescribed in section 34 of this title for hospital and dispensary care for such persons.
(May 10, 1943, ch. 95, § 5, 57 Stat. 81; Pub. L. 99–251, title III, § 304, Feb. 27, 1986, 100 Stat. 26.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1986—Pub. L. 99–251 amended second sentence generally. Prior to amendment, second sentence read as follows: “Dental treatment shall be administered only as an adjunct to inpatient hospital care and shall not include dental prosthesis or orthodontia.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Partial Repeal; Effective DateAct June 7, 1956, ch. 374, § 306(2), 70 Stat. 254, repealed this section except insofar as it relates to persons outside the Naval Service mentioned in section 34 of this title. Section 307 of act June 7, 1956, ch. 374, 70 Stat. 254, provided that such repeal was effective six months after June 7, 1956.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>