<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/411" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/411/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/411/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_411"><akn:num>411</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Armed Forces Retirement Home</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 411. Establishment of the Armed Forces Retirement Home(a) Independent establishmentThe Armed Forces Retirement Home is an independent establishment in the executive branch.


(b) PurposeThe purpose of the Retirement Home is to provide, through the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington and the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Gulfport, residences and related services for certain retired and former members of the Armed Forces.


(c) Facilities(1) Each facility of the Retirement Home referred to in paragraph (2) is a separate establishment of the Retirement Home.

(2) The United States Soldiers’ and Airmen’s Home is hereby redesignated as the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington. The Naval Home is hereby redesignated as the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Gulfport.


(d) Operation(1) The Chief Operating Officer of the Armed Forces Retirement Home is the head of the Retirement Home. The Chief Operating Officer is subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense.

(2) Each facility of the Retirement Home shall be maintained as a separate establishment of the Retirement Home for administrative purposes and shall be under the authority, direction, and control of the Administrator of that facility. The Administrator of each facility of the Retirement Home is subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Chief Operating Officer.

(3) The administration of the Retirement Home, including administration for the provision of health care and medical care for residents, shall remain under the control and administration of the Secretary of Defense.


(e) Property and facilities(1) The Retirement Home shall include such property and facilities as may be acquired under paragraph (2) or accepted under section 415(f) of this title for inclusion in the Retirement Home.

(2) The Chief Operating Officer may acquire, for the benefit of the Retirement Home, property and facilities for inclusion in the Retirement Home. If the purchase price to acquire fe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_411_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Independent establishment The Armed Forces Retirement Home is an independent establishment in the executive branch.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_411_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the Retirement Home is to provide, through the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington and the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Gulfport, residences and related services for certain retired and former members of the Armed Forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_411_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_411_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Operation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_411_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Property and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Property and facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_411_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Defense support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Department of Defense support The Secretary of Defense may make available from the Department of Defense to the Retirement Home, on a nonreimbursable basis, administrative support and office services, legal and policy planning assistance, access to investigative facilities of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense and of the military departments, and any other support necessary to enable the Retirement Home to carry out its functions under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_411_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Accreditation The Chief Operating Officer shall secure and maintain accreditation by a nationally recognized civilian accrediting organization for each aspect of each facility of the Retirement Home, including medical and dental care, pharmacy, independent living, and assisted living and nursing care.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_411_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Annual report The Secretary of Defense shall transmit to Congress an annual report on the financial and other affairs of the Retirement Home for each fiscal year. The annual report shall include an assessment of all aspects of each facility of the Retirement Home, including the quality of care at the facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_411_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to lease non-excess property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authority to lease non-excess property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>