<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/412" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/412/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/412/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_412"><akn:num>412</akn:num><akn:heading>Residents of Retirement Home</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 412. Residents of Retirement Home(a) Persons eligible to be residentsExcept as provided in subsection (b), the following persons who served as members of the Armed Forces, at least one-half of whose service was not commissioned service (other than as a warrant officer or limited-duty officer), are eligible to become residents of the Retirement Home:(1) Persons who were discharged or released from service in the Armed Forces after 20 or more years of active service.

(2) Persons who are determined under rules prescribed by the Chief Operating Officer to be suffering from a service-connected disability incurred in the line of duty in the Armed Forces.

(3) Persons who served in a war theater during a time of war declared by Congress or were eligible for hostile fire special pay under section 310 or 351 of title 37 and who are determined under rules prescribed by the Chief Operating Officer to be suffering from injuries, disease, or disability.

(4) Persons who served in a women’s component of the Armed Forces before June 12, 1948, and are determined under rules prescribed by the Chief Operating Officer to be eligible for admission because of compelling personal circumstances.

(5) Persons who are eligible for retired pay under chapter 1223 of title 10 and are—(A) eligible for care under section 1710 of title 38;

(B) enrolled in coverage under chapter 55 of title 10; or

(C) enrolled in a qualified health plan (as defined in section 18021(a) of title 42) that is acceptable to the Chief Operating Officer.



(b) Persons ineligible to be residentsThe following persons are ineligible to become a resident of the Retirement Home:(1) A person who—(A) has been convicted of a felony; or

(B) was discharged or released from service in the Armed Forces under other than honorable conditions.


(2) A person with substance abuse or mental health problems, except upon a judgment and satisfactory determination by the Chief Operating Officer that—(A) the person has been evaluated b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons eligible to be residents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Persons eligible to be residents Except as provided in subsection (b), the following persons who served as members of the Armed Forces, at least one-half of whose service was not commissioned service (other than as a warrant officer or limited-duty officer), are eligible to become residents of the Retirement Home:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons ineligible to be residents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Persons ineligible to be residents The following persons are ineligible to become a resident of the Retirement Home:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Acceptance To apply for acceptance as a resident of a facility of the Retirement Home, a person eligible to be a resident shall submit to the Administrator of that facility an application in such form and containing such information as the Chief Operating Officer may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities for acceptance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priorities for acceptance The Chief Operating Officer shall establish a system of priorities for the acceptance of residents so that the most deserving applicants will be accepted whenever the number of eligible applicants is greater than the Retirement Home can accommodate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_412_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Spouses of residents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Spouses of residents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>