<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/414" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/414/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/414/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_414"><akn:num>414</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees paid by residents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 414. Fees paid by residents(a) Monthly feesThe Administrator of each facility of the Retirement Home shall collect a monthly fee from each resident of that facility.


(b) Deposit of feesThe Administrators shall deposit fees collected under subsection (a) in the Armed Forces Retirement Home Trust Fund.


(c) Fixing fees(1) The Chief Operating Officer, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense, shall from time to time prescribe the fees required by subsection (a). Changes to such fees shall be based on the financial needs of the Retirement Home and the ability of the residents to pay. A change of a fee may not take effect until 120 days after the Secretary of Defense transmits a notification of the change to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives.

(2)(A) The fee shall be fixed as a percentage of the monthly income and monthly payments (including Federal payments) received by a resident. The percentage shall be the same for each facility of the Retirement Home. The Secretary of Defense may make any adjustment in a percentage that the Secretary determines appropriate.

(B) The calculation of monthly income and monthly payments under subparagraph (A) for a resident eligible under section 412(a)(5) of this title shall not be less than the retirement pay for equivalent active duty service as determined by the Chief Operating Officer, except as the Chief Operating Officer may provide because of the compelling personal circumstances of such resident.


(3) The fee shall be subject to a limitation on maximum monthly amount. The amount of the limitation shall be increased, effective on January 1 of each year, by the percentage of the increase in retired pay and retainer pay that takes effect on the preceding December 1 under subsection (b) of section 1401a of title 10 without regard to paragraph (3) of such subsection.

(4) The Administrator of each facility of the Retirement Home may collect a fee upon admission from a resident</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monthly fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Monthly fees The Administrator of each facility of the Retirement Home shall collect a monthly fee from each resident of that facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deposit of fees The Administrators shall deposit fees collected under subsection (a) in the Armed Forces Retirement Home Trust Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_414_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fixing fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fixing fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>