<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/416" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/416/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/416/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_416"><akn:num>416</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 416. Advisory Council(a) EstablishmentThe Retirement Home shall have an Advisory Council, to be known as the “Armed Forces Retirement Home Advisory Council”. The Advisory Council shall serve the interests of both facilities of the Retirement Home.


(b) Duties(1) The Advisory Council shall provide to the Chief Operating Officer and the Administrator of each facility such guidance and recommendations on the administration of the Retirement Home and the quality of care provided to residents as the Advisory Council considers appropriate.

(2) Not less often than annually, the Advisory Council shall submit to the Secretary of Defense a report summarizing its activities during the preceding year and providing such observations and recommendations with respect to the Retirement Home as the Advisory Council considers appropriate.

(3) In carrying out its functions, the Advisory Council shall provide for participation in its activities by a representative of the Resident Advisory Committee of each facility of the Retirement Home.


(c) Composition(1) The Advisory Council shall consist of at least 15 members.

(2) Members of the Advisory Council shall be designated by the Secretary of Defense, except that an individual who is not an employee of the Department of Defense shall be designated, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, by the head of the Federal department or agency that employs the individual.

(3) The Advisory Council shall include the following members:(A) One member who is an expert in nursing home or retirement home administration and financing.

(B) One member who is an expert in gerontology.

(C) One member who is an expert in financial management.

(D) Two representatives of the Department of Veterans Affairs, one to be designated from each of the regional offices nearest in proximity to the facilities of the Retirement Home.

(E) The Chairpersons of the Resident Advisory Committees.

(F) One enlisted representative of the Services’ Retiree Adviso</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Retirement Home shall have an Advisory Council, to be known as the “Armed Forces Retirement Home Advisory Council”. The Advisory Council shall serve the interests of both facilities of the Retirement Home.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Composition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Term of service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Vacancies A vacancy in the Advisory Council shall be filled in the manner in which the original designation was made. A member designated to fill a vacancy occurring before the end of the term of the predecessor shall be designated for the remainder of the term of the predecessor. A vacancy in the Advisory Council shall not affect its authority to perform its duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_416_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>