<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/418" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/418/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/418/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_418"><akn:num>418</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic inspection of retirement home facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 418. Periodic inspection of retirement home facilities(a) InspectionsThe Chief Operating Officer shall request the inspection of each facility of the Retirement Home by a nationally recognized civilian accrediting organization in accordance with section 411(g) of this title on a frequency consistent with the standards of such organization.


(b) Availability of staff and recordsThe Chief Operating Officer and the Administrator of a facility being inspected under this section shall make all staff, other personnel, and records of the facility available to the civilian accrediting organization in a timely manner for purposes of inspections under this section.


(c) ReportsNot later than 60 days after receiving a report on an inspection from the civilian accrediting organization under this section, the Chief Operating Officer shall submit to the Secretary of Defense, the Senior Medical Advisor, and the Advisory Council a report containing—(1) the results of the inspection; and

(2) a plan to address any recommendations and other matters set forth in the report.


(Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XV, § 1518, Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1730; Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1042(a), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2125; Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XIV, § 1404(b)(1)(C), Dec. 28, 2001, 115 Stat. 1260; Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title XIV, § 1422(f), Jan. 28, 2008, 122 Stat. 422; Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, §§ 563(b)(3), 564(b)(1), 566, 567(c)(5), Dec. 31, 2011, 125 Stat. 1423–1426; Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title X, § 1051(d), title XIV, § 1413(a)(3), Dec. 12, 2017, 131 Stat. 1562, 1707; Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title X, § 1081(c)(3), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1985; Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XIV, § 1413(a), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4031.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2021—Pub. L. 116–283 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section consisted of subsecs. (a) to (e) relating to periodic inspection of retirement home facilities by Department of Defense Inspector Gener</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Inspections The Chief Operating Officer shall request the inspection of each facility of the Retirement Home by a nationally recognized civilian accrediting organization in accordance with section 411(g) of this title on a frequency consistent with the standards of such organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of staff and records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of staff and records The Chief Operating Officer and the Administrator of a facility being inspected under this section shall make all staff, other personnel, and records of the facility available to the civilian accrediting organization in a timely manner for purposes of inspections under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_418_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports Not later than 60 days after receiving a report on an inspection from the civilian accrediting organization under this section, the Chief Operating Officer shall submit to the Secretary of Defense, the Senior Medical Advisor, and the Advisory Council a report containing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>