<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/420" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/420/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/420/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_420"><akn:num>420</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of effects of deceased persons; unclaimed property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 420. Disposition of effects of deceased persons; unclaimed property(a) Disposition of effects of deceased personsThe Administrator of a facility of the Retirement Home shall safeguard and dispose of the estate and personal effects of deceased residents, including effects delivered to such facility under sections 7712(f) and 9712(f) of title 10, and shall ensure the following:(1) A will or other instrument of a testamentary nature involving property rights executed by a resident shall be promptly delivered, upon the death of the resident, to the proper court of record.

(2) If a resident dies intestate and the heirs or legal representative of the deceased cannot be immediately ascertained, the Administrator shall retain all property left by the decedent for a three-year period beginning on the date of the death. If entitlement to such property is established to the satisfaction of the Administrator at any time during the three-year period, the Administrator shall distribute the decedent’s property, in equal pro-rata shares when multiple beneficiaries have been identified, to the highest following categories of identified survivors (listed in the order of precedence indicated):(A) The surviving spouse or legal representative.

(B) The children of the deceased.

(C) The parents of the deceased.

(D) The siblings of the deceased.

(E) The next-of-kin of the deceased.



(b) Sale of effects(1)(A) If the disposition of the estate of a resident of the Retirement Home cannot be accomplished under subsection (a)(2) or if a resident dies testate and the nominated fiduciary, legatees, or heirs of the resident cannot be immediately ascertained, the entirety of the deceased resident’s domiciliary estate and the entirety of any ancillary estate that is unclaimed at the end of the three-year period beginning on the date of the death of the resident shall escheat to the Retirement Home.

(B) Upon the sale of any such unclaimed estate property, the proceeds of the sale shall be de</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_420_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of effects of deceased persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disposition of effects of deceased persons The Administrator of a facility of the Retirement Home shall safeguard and dispose of the estate and personal effects of deceased residents, including effects delivered to such facility under sections 7712(f) and 9712(f) of title 10, and shall ensure the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_420_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of effects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sale of effects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_420_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of proceeds to Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer of proceeds to Fund The net proceeds received by the Administrators from the sale of effects under subsection (b) shall be deposited in the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_420_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent claim</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subsequent claim</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_420_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unclaimed property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Unclaimed property In the case of property delivered to the Retirement Home under section 2575 of title 10, the Administrator of the facility shall deliver the property to the owner, the heirs or next of kin of the owner, or the legal representative of the owner, if a right to the property is established to the satisfaction of the Administrator of the facility within two years after the delivery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>