<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/423" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/423/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/24/423/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_423"><akn:num>423</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of historic buildings and grounds at the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 423. Preservation of historic buildings and grounds at the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington(a) Historic nature of facilityCongress finds the following:(1) Four buildings located on six acres of the establishment of the Retirement Home known as the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington are included on the National Register of Historic Places maintained by the Secretary of the Interior.

(2) Amounts in the Armed Forces Retirement Home Trust Fund, which consists primarily of deductions from the pay of members of the Armed Forces, are insufficient to both maintain and operate the Retirement Home for the benefit of the residents of the Retirement Home and adequately maintain, repair, and preserve these historic buildings and grounds.

(3) Other sources of funding are available to contribute to the maintenance, repair, and preservation of these historic buildings and grounds.


(b) Authority to accept assistanceThe Chief Operating Officer and the Administrator of the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington may apply for and accept a direct grant from the Secretary of the Interior under section 302904 of title 54 for the purpose of maintaining, repairing, and preserving the historic buildings and grounds of the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington included on the National Register of Historic Places.


(c) Requirements and limitationsAmounts received as a grant under subsection (b) shall be deposited in the Fund, but shall be kept separate from other amounts in the Fund. The amounts received may only be used for the purpose specified in subsection (b).


(Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XV, § 1523, as added Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title III, § 383, Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 583; amended Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title XIV, §§ 1404(b)(5), 1410(a)(4), Dec. 28, 2001, 115 Stat. 1261, 1266; Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 564(b)(1), Dec. 31, 2011, 125 Stat. 1424.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
In subsec. (b), “section 302904 of title 54” substituted for “section 10</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Historic nature of facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Historic nature of facility Congress finds the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to accept assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to accept assistance The Chief Operating Officer and the Administrator of the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington may apply for and accept a direct grant from the Secretary of the Interior under section 302904 of title 54 for the purpose of maintaining, repairing, and preserving the historic buildings and grounds of the Armed Forces Retirement Home—Washington included on the National Register of Historic Places.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_423_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements and limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements and limitations Amounts received as a grant under subsection (b) shall be deposited in the Fund, but shall be kept separate from other amounts in the Fund. The amounts received may only be used for the purpose specified in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>