<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/100903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/100903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/100903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_100903"><akn:num>100903</akn:num><akn:heading>Solid waste disposal operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 100903. Solid waste disposal operations(a) In General 11 So in original. A period probably should appear. —To protect the air, land, water, and natural and cultural values of the System and the property of the United States in the System, no solid waste disposal site (including any site for the disposal of domestic or industrial solid waste) may be operated within the boundary of any System unit, other than—(1) a site that was operating as of September 1, 1984; or

(2) a site used only for disposal of waste generated within that System unit so long as the site will not degrade any of the natural or cultural resources of the System unit.


(b) Regulations.—The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section, including reasonable regulations to mitigate the adverse effects of solid waste disposal sites in operation as of September 1, 1984, on property of the United States.

(Pub. L. 113–287, § 3, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3115.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


10090316 U.S.C. 460l–22(c).Pub. L. 90–401, § 5(c), as added Pub. L. 98–506, § 2, Oct. 19, 1984, 98 Stat. 2338.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_100903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General 11 So in original. A period probably should appear. —</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To protect the air, land, water, and natural and cultural values of the System and the property of the United States in the System, no solid waste disposal site (including any site for the disposal of domestic or industrial solid waste) may be operated within the boundary of any System unit, other than—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_100903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section, including reasonable regulations to mitigate the adverse effects of solid waste disposal sites in operation as of September 1, 1984, on property of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>