<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/101923" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/101923/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/101923/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_101923"><akn:num>101923</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 101923. Recordkeeping requirements(a) In General.—A concessioner and any subconcessioner shall keep such records as the Secretary may prescribe to enable the Secretary to determine that all terms of a concession contract have been and are being faithfully performed. The Secretary and any authorized representative of the Secretary shall, for the purpose of audit and examination, have access to those records and to other records of the concessioner or subconcessioner pertinent to the concession contract and all terms and conditions of the concession contract.

(b) Access to Records by Comptroller General.—The Comptroller General and any authorized representative of the Comptroller General shall, until the expiration of 5 calendar years after the close of the business year of each concessioner or subconcessioner, have access to and the right to examine any pertinent records described in subsection (a) of the concessioner or subconcessioner related to the contract involved.

(Pub. L. 113–287, § 3, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3150.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


10192316 U.S.C. 5963.Pub. L. 105–391, title IV, § 414, Nov. 13, 1998, 112 Stat. 3515.


In this section, the word “duly” is omitted as unnecessary.
In subsection (a), the words “and any subconcessioner” and “or subconcessioner” are added for clarity. See 36 CFR 51.98. The word “records” is substituted for “books, documents, and papers” for consistency in the revised title and with other titles of the United States Code.
In subsection (b), the words “books, papers, documents” are omitted as included in “records”. The words “described in subsection (a)” are added for clarity.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101923_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A concessioner and any subconcessioner shall keep such records as the Secretary may prescribe to enable the Secretary to determine that all terms of a concession contract have been and are being faithfully performed. The Secretary and any authorized representative of the Secretary shall, for the purpose of audit and examination, have access to those records and to other records of the concessioner or subconcessioner pertinent to the concession contract and all terms and conditions of the concession contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101923_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to Records by Comptroller General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Comptroller General and any authorized representative of the Comptroller General shall, until the expiration of 5 calendar years after the close of the business year of each concessioner or subconcessioner, have access to and the right to examine any pertinent records described in subsection (a) of the concessioner or subconcessioner related to the contract involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>