<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/101924" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/101924/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/101924/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_101924"><akn:num>101924</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion of sale of Indian, Alaska Native, Native Samoan, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 101924. Promotion of sale of Indian, Alaska Native, Native Samoan, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts(a) In General.—Promoting the sale of authentic United States Indian, Alaskan Native, Native Samoan, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts relating to the cultural, historical, and geographic characteristics of System units is encouraged, and the Secretary shall ensure that there is a continuing effort to enhance the handicraft trade where it exists and establish the trade in appropriate areas where the trade does not exist.

(b) Exemption From Franchise Fee.—In furtherance of the purposes of subsection (a), the revenue derived from the sale of United States Indian, Alaska Native, Native Samoan, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts shall be exempt from any franchise fee payments under this subchapter.

(Pub. L. 113–287, § 3, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3150.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


10192416 U.S.C. 5964.Pub. L. 105–391, title IV, § 416, Nov. 13, 1998, 112 Stat. 3516.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101924_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Promoting the sale of authentic United States Indian, Alaskan Native, Native Samoan, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts relating to the cultural, historical, and geographic characteristics of System units is encouraged, and the Secretary shall ensure that there is a continuing effort to enhance the handicraft trade where it exists and establish the trade in appropriate areas where the trade does not exist.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101924_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption From Franchise Fee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In furtherance of the purposes of subsection (a), the revenue derived from the sale of United States Indian, Alaska Native, Native Samoan, and Native Hawaiian handicrafts shall be exempt from any franchise fee payments under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>