<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/101915" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/101915/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/101915/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_101915"><akn:num>101915</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of concessioner investment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 101915. Protection of concessioner investment(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Capital improvement.—The term “capital improvement” means a structure, a fixture, or nonremovable equipment provided by a concessioner pursuant to the terms of a concession contract and located on land of the United States within a System unit.

(2) Consumer price index.—The term “Consumer Price Index” means—(A) the “Consumer Price Index—All Urban Consumers” published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor; or

(B) if the Index is not published, another regularly published cost-of-living index approximating the Consumer Price Index.



(b) Leasehold Surrender Interest in Capital Improvements.—A concessioner that constructs a capital improvement on land owned by the United States within a System unit pursuant to a concession contract shall have a leasehold surrender interest in the capital improvement subject to the following terms and conditions:(1) In general.—A concessioner shall have a leasehold surrender interest in each capital improvement constructed by a concessioner under a concession contract, consisting solely of a right to compensation for the capital improvement to the extent of the value of the concessioner’s leasehold surrender interest in the capital improvement.

(2) Pledge as security.—A leasehold surrender interest may be pledged as security for financing of a capital improvement or the acquisition of a concession contract when approved by the Secretary pursuant to this subchapter.

(3) Transfer and relinquishment or waiver of interest.—A leasehold surrender interest shall be transferred by the concessioner in connection with any transfer of the concession contract and may be relinquished or waived by the concessioner.

(4) Limit on extinguishing or taking interest.—A leasehold surrender interest shall not be extinguished by the expiration or other termination of a concession contract and may not be taken for public use except on payment of jus</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101915_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101915_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leasehold Surrender Interest in Capital Improvements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A concessioner that constructs a capital improvement on land owned by the United States within a System unit pursuant to a concession contract shall have a leasehold surrender interest in the capital improvement subject to the following terms and conditions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101915_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Rule for Possessory Interest Existing Before November 13, 1998.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101915_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition to Successor Concessioner.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) On expiration or termination of a concession contract entered into after November 13, 1998, a concessioner shall be entitled under the terms of the concession contract to receive from the United States or a successor concessioner the value of any leasehold surrender interest in a capital improvement as of the date of the expiration or termination. A successor concessioner shall have a leasehold surrender interest in the capital improvement under the terms of a new concession contract and the initial value of the leasehold surrender interest in the capital improvement (instead of construction cost) shall be the amount of money the new concessioner is required to pay the prior concessioner for its leasehold surrender interest under the terms of the prior concession contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101915_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Title to Improvements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Title to any capital improvement constructed by a concessioner on land owned by the United States in a System unit shall be vested in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>