<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/102712" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/102712/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/102712/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_102712"><akn:num>102712</akn:num><akn:heading>Aid to visitors, grantees, permittees, or licensees in emergencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 102712. Aid to visitors, grantees, permittees, or licensees in emergencies(a) Visitors.—The Secretary may aid visitors within a System unit in an emergency, when no other source is available for the procurement of food or supplies, by the sale, at cost, of food or supplies in quantities sufficient to enable the visitors to reach safely a point where food or supplies can be purchased. Receipts from the sales shall be deposited as a refund to the appropriation current at the date of the deposit and shall be available for the purchase of similar food or supplies.

(b) Grantees, Permittees, and Licensees.—The Secretary may in an emergency, when no other source is available for the immediate procurement of supplies, materials, or special services, aid grantees, permittees, or licensees conducting operations for the benefit of the public in a System unit by the sale, at cost, including transportation and handling, of supplies, materials, or special services as may be necessary to relieve the emergency and ensure uninterrupted service to the public. Receipts from the sales shall be deposited as a refund to the appropriation current at the date of the deposit and shall be available for expenditure for System unit purposes.

(Pub. L. 113–287, § 3, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3162.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


102712(a)16 U.S.C. 12.July 3, 1926, ch. 792, § 1, 44 Stat. 900.
102712(b)16 U.S.C. 17c.May 26, 1930, ch. 324, § 4, 46 Stat. 382.



Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Fees for Medical ServicesPub. L. 116–260, div. G, title I, § 118, Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 1506, provided that: “Beginning in fiscal year 2022 and for each fiscal year thereafter, fees collected pursuant to section 2404 of Public Law 116–9 [see note below] shall be deposited into the National Park Medical Services Fund established pursuant to such section of such Act as discretionary offsetting receipts.”

Pub. L. 116–9, title</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_102712_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Visitors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary may aid visitors within a System unit in an emergency, when no other source is available for the procurement of food or supplies, by the sale, at cost, of food or supplies in quantities sufficient to enable the visitors to reach safely a point where food or supplies can be purchased. Receipts from the sales shall be deposited as a refund to the appropriation current at the date of the deposit and shall be available for the purchase of similar food or supplies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_102712_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grantees, Permittees, and Licensees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may in an emergency, when no other source is available for the immediate procurement of supplies, materials, or special services, aid grantees, permittees, or licensees conducting operations for the benefit of the public in a System unit by the sale, at cost, including transportation and handling, of supplies, materials, or special services as may be necessary to relieve the emergency and ensure uninterrupted service to the public. Receipts from the sales shall be deposited as a refund to the appropriation current at the date of the deposit and shall be available for expenditure for System unit purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>