<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/120102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/120102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/120102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_120102"><akn:num>120102</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of National Heritage Area System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 120102. Establishment of National Heritage Area System(a) In General.—To recognize certain areas of the United States that tell nationally significant stories and to conserve, enhance, and interpret those nationally significant stories and the natural, historic, scenic, and cultural resources of areas that illustrate significant aspects of the heritage of the United States, there is established a National Heritage Area System through the administration of which the Secretary may provide technical and financial assistance to local coordinating entities to support the establishment, development, and continuity of the National Heritage Areas.

(b) National Heritage Area System Components.—The National Heritage Area System shall be composed of—(1) each National Heritage Area, National Heritage Corridor, National Heritage Canalway, Cultural Heritage Corridor, National Heritage Route, and National Heritage Partnership designated by Congress before or on the date of enactment of this chapter; and

(2) each National Heritage Area designated by Congress after the date of enactment of this chapter.


(c) Relationship to the System.—(1) Relationship to system units.—The Secretary shall—(A) ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, participation and assistance by any administrator of the System unit that is located near or encompassed by a National Heritage Area in local initiatives for the National Heritage Area to conserve and interpret resources consistent with the applicable management plan for the National Heritage Area; and

(B) work with local coordinating entities to promote public enjoyment of System units and System-related resources.


(2) Treatment.—(A) In general.—A National Heritage Area shall not be—(i) considered to be a System unit; or

(ii) subject to the authorities applicable to System units.


(B) Effect.—Nothing in this paragraph affects the administration of a System unit located within the boundaries of a National Heritage Area.



(d) Authorities.—In</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_120102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To recognize certain areas of the United States that tell nationally significant stories and to conserve, enhance, and interpret those nationally significant stories and the natural, historic, scenic, and cultural resources of areas that illustrate significant aspects of the heritage of the United States, there is established a National Heritage Area System through the administration of which the Secretary may provide technical and financial assistance to local coordinating entities to support the establishment, development, and continuity of the National Heritage Areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_120102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Heritage Area System Components.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The National Heritage Area System shall be composed of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_120102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to the System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_120102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>