<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/200402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/200402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/200402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_200402"><akn:num>200402</akn:num><akn:heading>National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 200402. National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund(a) Establishment.—There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund”.

(b) Deposits.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025, there shall be deposited in the Fund an amount equal to 50 percent of all energy development revenues due and payable to the United States from oil, gas, coal, or alternative or renewable energy development on Federal land and water credited, covered, or deposited as miscellaneous receipts under Federal law in the preceding fiscal year.

(2) Maximum amount.—The amount deposited in the Fund under paragraph (1) shall not exceed $1,900,000,000 for any fiscal year.

(3) Effect on other revenues.—Nothing in this section affects the disposition of revenues that—(A) are due to the United States, special funds, trust funds, or States from mineral and energy development on Federal land and water; or

(B) have been otherwise appropriated—(i) under Federal law, including—(I) the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 (43 U.S.C. 1331 note; Public Law 109–432); and

(II) the Mineral Leasing Act (30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.); or


(ii) from—(I) the Land and Water Conservation Fund established under chapter 2003; or

(II) the Historic Preservation Fund established under chapter 3031.





(c) Availability of Funds.—Amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available to the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture, as provided in subsection (e), without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation.

(d) Investment of Amounts.—(1) In general.—The Secretary may request the Secretary of the Treasury to invest any portion of the Fund that is not, as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, required to meet the current needs of the Fund.

(2) Requirement.—An investment requested under paragraph (1) shall be made by th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “National Parks and Public Land Legacy Restoration Fund”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amounts deposited in the Fund shall be available to the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture, as provided in subsection (e), without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited Use of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No amounts in the Fund shall be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of Priority List of Projects to Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources and Appropriations of the Senate and the Committees on Natural Resources and Appropriations of the House of Representatives a list of projects to be funded for fiscal year 2021 that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of Annual List of Projects to Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Until the date on which all of the amounts in the Fund are expended, the President shall annually submit to Congress, together with the annual budget of the United States, a list of projects to be funded from the Fund that includes a detailed description of each project, including the estimated expenditures from the Fund for the project for the applicable fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternate Allocation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200402_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Donations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>