<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/200504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/200504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/200504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_200504"><akn:num>200504</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery action programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 200504. Recovery action programs(a) Evidence of Local Commitment to Ongoing Programs.—As a requirement for project approval, local governments applying for assistance under this chapter shall submit to the Secretary evidence of their commitments to ongoing planning, rehabilitation, service, operation, and maintenance programs for their park and recreation systems. These commitments will be expressed in local park and recreation recovery action programs that maximize coordination of all community resources, including other federally supported urban development and recreation programs. During an initial interim period to be established by regulations under this chapter, this requirement may be satisfied by local government submissions of preliminary action programs that briefly define objectives, priorities, and implementation strategies for overall system recovery and maintenance and commit the applicant to a scheduled program development process. Following this interim period, all local applicants shall submit to the Secretary, as a condition of eligibility, a 5-year action program for park and recreation recovery that satisfactorily demonstrates—(1) systematic identification of recovery objectives, priorities, and implementation strategies;

(2) adequate planning for rehabilitation of specific recreation areas and facilities, including projections of the cost of proposed projects;

(3) the capacity and commitment to ensure that facilities provided or improved under this chapter shall continue to be adequately maintained, protected, staffed, and supervised;

(4) the intention to maintain total local public outlays for park and recreation purposes at levels at least equal to those in the year preceding that in which grant assistance is sought except in any case where a reduction in park and recreation outlays is proportionate to a reduction in overall spending by the applicant; and

(5) the relationship of the park and recreation recovery program to overall communi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evidence of Local Commitment to Ongoing Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) As a requirement for project approval, local governments applying for assistance under this chapter shall submit to the Secretary evidence of their commitments to ongoing planning, rehabilitation, service, operation, and maintenance programs for their park and recreation systems. These commitments will be expressed in local park and recreation recovery action programs that maximize coordination of all community resources, including other federally supported urban development and recreation programs. During an initial interim period to be established by regulations under this chapter, this requirement may be satisfied by local government submissions of preliminary action programs that briefly define objectives, priorities, and implementation strategies for overall system recovery and maintenance and commit the applicant to a scheduled program development process. Following this interim period, all local applicants shall submit to the Secretary, as a condition of eligibility, a 5-yea</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing Planning Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Where appropriate, the Secretary may encourage local governments to meet action program requirements through a continuing planning process that includes periodic improvements and updates in action program submissions to eliminate identified gaps in program information and policy development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Action programs shall address, but are not limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication in Federal Register.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall establish and publish in the Federal Register requirements for preparation, submission, and updating of local park and recreation recovery action programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200504_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for At-Risk Youth Recreation Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) To be eligible to receive at-risk youth recreation grants a local government shall amend its 5-year action program to incorporate the goal of reducing crime and juvenile delinquency and to provide a description of the implementation strategies to achieve this goal. The plan shall also address how the local government is coordinating its recreation programs with crime prevention efforts of law enforcement, juvenile corrections, and youth social service agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200504_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching Recovery Action Program Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary may provide up to 50 percent matching recovery action program grants to eligible local governments for program development and planning specifically to meet the objectives of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>