<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/200501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/200501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/200501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_200501"><akn:num>200501</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 200501. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) At-risk youth recreation grant.—(A) In general.—The term “at-risk youth recreation grant” means a grant in a neighborhood or community with a high prevalence of crime, particularly violent crime or crime committed by youthful offenders.

(B) Inclusions.—The term “at-risk youth recreation grant” includes—(i) a rehabilitation grant;

(ii) an innovation grant; and

(iii) a matching grant for continuing program support for a program of demonstrated value or success in providing constructive alternatives to youth at risk for engaging in criminal behavior, including a grant for operating, or coordinating, a recreation program or service.


(C) Additional uses of rehabilitation grant.—In addition to the purposes specified in paragraph (8), a rehabilitation grant that serves as an at-risk youth recreation grant may be used for the provision of lighting, emergency phones, or any other capital improvement that will improve the security of an urban park.


(2) General purpose local government.—The term “general purpose local government” means—(A) a city, county, town, township, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State; and

(B) the District of Columbia.


(3) Innovation grant.—The term “innovation grant” means a matching grant to a local government to cover costs of personnel, facilities, equipment, supplies, or services designed to demonstrate innovative and cost-effective ways to augment park and recreation opportunities at the neighborhood level and to address common problems related to facility operations and improved delivery of recreation service, not including routine operation and maintenance activities.

(4) Maintenance.—The term “maintenance” means all commonly accepted practices necessary to keep recreation areas and facilities operating in a state of good repair and to protect them from deterioration resulting from normal wear and tear.

(5) Private, nonprofit agency.—The term “private, nonprofit a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>At-risk youth recreation grant.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>General purpose local government.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “general purpose local government” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Innovation grant.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “innovation grant” means a matching grant to a local government to cover costs of personnel, facilities, equipment, supplies, or services designed to demonstrate innovative and cost-effective ways to augment park and recreation opportunities at the neighborhood level and to address common problems related to facility operations and improved delivery of recreation service, not including routine operation and maintenance activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “maintenance” means all commonly accepted practices necessary to keep recreation areas and facilities operating in a state of good repair and to protect them from deterioration resulting from normal wear and tear.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private, nonprofit agency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “private, nonprofit agency” means a community-based, nonprofit organization, corporation, or association organized for purposes of providing recreational, conservation, and educational services directly to urban residents on a neighborhood or communitywide basis through voluntary donations, voluntary labor, or public or private grants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery action program grant.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recreation area or facility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “recreation area or facility” means an indoor or outdoor park, building, site, or other facility that is dedicated to recreation purposes and administered by a public or private nonprofit agency to serve the recreation needs of community residents. Emphasis shall be on public facilities readily accessible to residential neighborhoods, including multiple-use community centers that have recreation as one of their primary purposes, but excluding major sports arenas, exhibition areas, and conference halls used primarily for commercial sports, spectator, or display activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation grant.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “rehabilitation grant” means a matching capital grant to a local government for rebuilding, remodeling, expanding, or developing an existing outdoor or indoor recreation area or facility, including improvements in park landscapes, buildings, and support facilities, but excluding routine maintenance and upkeep activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special purpose local government.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_200501_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>State.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “State” means a State, an instrumentality of a State approved by the Governor of the State, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>