<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/302105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/302105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/302105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_302105"><akn:num>302105</akn:num><akn:heading>Owner participation in nomination process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 302105. Owner participation in nomination process(a) Regulations.—The Secretary shall promulgate regulations requiring that before any property may be included on the National Register or designated as a National Historic Landmark, the owner of the property, or a majority of the owners of the individual properties within a district in the case of a historic district, shall be given the opportunity (including a reasonable period of time) to concur in, or object to, the nomination of the property for inclusion or designation. The regulations shall include provisions to carry out this section in the case of multiple ownership of a single property.

(b) When Property Shall Not Be Included on National Register or Designated as National Historic Landmark.—If the owner of any privately owned property, or a majority of the owners of privately owned properties within the district in the case of a historic district, object to inclusion or designation, the property shall not be included on the National Register or designated as a National Historic Landmark until the objection is withdrawn.

(c) Review by Secretary.—The Secretary shall review the nomination of the property when an objection has been made and shall determine whether or not the property is eligible for inclusion or designation. If the Secretary determines that the property is eligible for inclusion or designation, the Secretary shall inform the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, the appropriate State Historic Preservation Officer, the appropriate chief elected local official, and the owner or owners of the property of the Secretary’s determination.

(Pub. L. 113–287, § 3, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3193.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


302105(a)16 U.S.C. 470a(a)(6) (1st, last sentences).Pub. L. 89–665, title I, § 101(a)(6), Oct. 15, 1966, 80 Stat. 915; Pub. L. 91–383, § 11, as added Pub. L. 94–458, § 2, Oct. 7, 1976, 90 Stat. 1942; P</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall promulgate regulations requiring that before any property may be included on the National Register or designated as a National Historic Landmark, the owner of the property, or a majority of the owners of the individual properties within a district in the case of a historic district, shall be given the opportunity (including a reasonable period of time) to concur in, or object to, the nomination of the property for inclusion or designation. The regulations shall include provisions to carry out this section in the case of multiple ownership of a single property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>When Property Shall Not Be Included on National Register or Designated as National Historic Landmark.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If the owner of any privately owned property, or a majority of the owners of privately owned properties within the district in the case of a historic district, object to inclusion or designation, the property shall not be included on the National Register or designated as a National Historic Landmark until the objection is withdrawn.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall review the nomination of the property when an objection has been made and shall determine whether or not the property is eligible for inclusion or designation. If the Secretary determines that the property is eligible for inclusion or designation, the Secretary shall inform the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, the appropriate State Historic Preservation Officer, the appropriate chief elected local official, and the owner or owners of the property of the Secretary’s determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>