<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/302103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/302103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/302103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_302103"><akn:num>302103</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria and regulations relating to National Register, National Historic Landmarks, and World Herit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 302103. Criteria and regulations relating to National Register, National Historic Landmarks, and World Heritage List
The Secretary, in consultation with national historical and archeological associations, shall—(1) establish criteria for properties to be included on the National Register and criteria for National Historic Landmarks; and

(2) promulgate regulations for—(A) nominating properties for inclusion on, and removal from, the National Register and the recommendation of properties by certified local governments;

(B) designating properties as National Historic Landmarks and removing that designation;

(C) considering appeals from recommendations, nominations, removals, and designations (or any failure or refusal by a nominating authority to nominate or designate);

(D) nominating historic property for inclusion in the World Heritage List in accordance with the World Heritage Convention;

(E) making determinations of eligibility of properties for inclusion on the National Register; and

(F) notifying the owner of a property, any appropriate local governments, and the general public, when the property is being considered for inclusion on the National Register, for designation as a National Historic Landmark, or for nomination to the World Heritage List.


(Pub. L. 113–287, § 3, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3192.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


30210316 U.S.C. 470a(a)(2).Pub. L. 89–665, title I, § 101(a)(2), Oct. 15, 1966, 80 Stat. 915; Pub. L. 91–383, § 11, as added Pub. L. 94–458, § 2, Oct. 7, 1976, 90 Stat. 1942; Pub. L. 93–54, § 1(d), July 1, 1973, 87 Stat. 139; Pub. L. 96–205, title VI, § 608(a)(1), (2), Mar. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 92; Pub. L. 96–515, title II, § 201(a), Dec. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 2988.


The words “or revise” are omitted as being included in “establish” and “promulgate”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302103_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) establish criteria for properties to be included on the National Register and criteria for National Historic Landmarks; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302103_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) promulgate regulations for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>