<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/302104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/302104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/302104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_302104"><akn:num>302104</akn:num><akn:heading>Nominations for inclusion on National Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 302104. Nominations for inclusion on National Register(a) Nomination by State.—Subject to the requirements of section 302107 of this title, any State that is carrying out a program approved under chapter 3023 shall nominate to the Secretary property that meets the criteria promulgated under section 302103 of this title for inclusion on the National Register. Subject to section 302107 of this title, any property nominated under this subsection or under section 306102 of this title shall be included on the National Register on the date that is 45 days after receipt by the Secretary of the nomination and the necessary documentation, unless the Secretary disapproves the nomination within the 45-day period or unless an appeal is filed under subsection (d).

(b) Nomination by Person or Local Government.—Subject to the requirements of section 302107 of this title, the Secretary may accept a nomination directly from any person or local government for inclusion of a property on the National Register only if the property is located in a State where there is no program approved under chapter 3023 of this title. The Secretary may include on the National Register any property for which such a nomination is made if the Secretary determines that the property is eligible in accordance with the regulations promulgated under section 302103 of this title. The determination shall be made within 90 days from the date of the nomination unless the nomination is appealed under subsection (d).

(c) Nomination by Federal Agency.—Subject to the requirements of section 302107 of this title, the regulations promulgated under section 302103 of this title, and appeal under subsection (d) of this section, the Secretary may accept a nomination directly by a Federal agency for inclusion of property on the National Register only if—(1) completed nominations are sent to the State Historic Preservation Officer for review and comment regarding the adequacy of the nomination, the significance of the pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nomination by State.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to the requirements of section 302107 of this title, any State that is carrying out a program approved under chapter 3023 shall nominate to the Secretary property that meets the criteria promulgated under section 302103 of this title for inclusion on the National Register. Subject to section 302107 of this title, any property nominated under this subsection or under section 306102 of this title shall be included on the National Register on the date that is 45 days after receipt by the Secretary of the nomination and the necessary documentation, unless the Secretary disapproves the nomination within the 45-day period or unless an appeal is filed under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nomination by Person or Local Government.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to the requirements of section 302107 of this title, the Secretary may accept a nomination directly from any person or local government for inclusion of a property on the National Register only if the property is located in a State where there is no program approved under chapter 3023 of this title. The Secretary may include on the National Register any property for which such a nomination is made if the Secretary determines that the property is eligible in accordance with the regulations promulgated under section 302103 of this title. The determination shall be made within 90 days from the date of the nomination unless the nomination is appealed under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nomination by Federal Agency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subject to the requirements of section 302107 of this title, the regulations promulgated under section 302103 of this title, and appeal under subsection (d) of this section, the Secretary may accept a nomination directly by a Federal agency for inclusion of property on the National Register only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Any person or local government may appeal to the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>