<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/304105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/304105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/304105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_304105"><akn:num>304105</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 304105. Administration(a) Executive Director.—There shall be an Executive Director of the Council who shall be appointed by the Chairman with the concurrence of the Council in the competitive service at a rate within the General Schedule, in the competitive service at a rate that may exceed the rate prescribed for the highest rate established for grade 15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5, or in the Senior Executive Service under section 3393 of title 5. The Executive Director shall report directly to the Chairman and perform such functions and duties as the Chairman may prescribe.

(b) General Counsel and Appointment of Other Attorneys.—(1) General counsel.—The Council shall have a General Counsel, who shall be appointed by the Executive Director. The General Counsel shall report directly to the Executive Director and serve as the Council’s legal advisor.

(2) Appointment of other attorneys.—The Executive Director shall appoint other attorneys as may be necessary to—(A) assist the General Counsel;

(B) represent the Council in court when appropriate, including enforcement of agreements with Federal agencies to which the Council is a party;

(C) assist the Department of Justice in handling litigation concerning the Council in court; and

(D) perform such other legal duties and functions as the Executive Director and the Council may direct.



(c) Appointment and Compensation of Officers and Employees.—The Executive Director of the Council may appoint and fix the compensation of officers and employees in the competitive service who are necessary to perform the functions of the Council at rates not to exceed that prescribed for the highest rate for grade 15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5. The Executive Director, with the concurrence of the Chairman, may appoint and fix the compensation of not to exceed 5 employees in the competitive service at rates that exceed that prescribed for the highest rate established for grade 15 o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Director.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There shall be an Executive Director of the Council who shall be appointed by the Chairman with the concurrence of the Council in the competitive service at a rate within the General Schedule, in the competitive service at a rate that may exceed the rate prescribed for the highest rate established for grade 15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5, or in the Senior Executive Service under section 3393 of title 5. The Executive Director shall report directly to the Chairman and perform such functions and duties as the Chairman may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Counsel and Appointment of Other Attorneys.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and Compensation of Officers and Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Executive Director of the Council may appoint and fix the compensation of officers and employees in the competitive service who are necessary to perform the functions of the Council at rates not to exceed that prescribed for the highest rate for grade 15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5. The Executive Director, with the concurrence of the Chairman, may appoint and fix the compensation of not to exceed 5 employees in the competitive service at rates that exceed that prescribed for the highest rate established for grade 15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5 or in the Senior Executive Service under section 3393 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and Compensation of Additional Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Executive Director may appoint and fix the compensation of such additional personnel as may be necessary to carry out the Council’s duties, without regard to the civil service laws and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expert and Consultant Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Executive Director may procure expert and consultant services in accordance with section 3109 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial and Administrative Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds, Personnel, Facilities, and Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights, Benefits, and Privileges of Transferred Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Any employee in the competitive service of the United States transferred to the Council under section 207 of the National Historic Preservation Act (Public Law 89–665) retains all the rights, benefits, and privileges pertaining to the competitive service held prior to the transfer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption From Chapter 10 of Title 5.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Council is exempt from chapter 10 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_304105_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions That Govern Operations of Council.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Subchapter II of chapter 5 and chapter 7 of title 5 shall govern the operations of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>