<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/305302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/305302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/305302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_305302"><akn:num>305302</akn:num><akn:heading>National Center for Preservation Technology and Training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 305302. National Center for Preservation Technology and Training(a) Establishment.—There is established within the Department of the Interior a National Center for Preservation Technology and Training. The Center shall be located at Northwestern State University of Louisiana in Natchitoches, Louisiana.

(b) Purposes.—The purposes of the Center shall be to—(1) develop and distribute preservation and conservation skills and technologies for the identification, evaluation, conservation, and interpretation of historic property;

(2) develop and facilitate training for Federal, State, and local resource preservation professionals, cultural resource managers, maintenance personnel, and others working in the preservation field;

(3) take steps to apply preservation technology benefits from ongoing research by other agencies and institutions;

(4) facilitate the transfer of preservation technology among Federal agencies, State and local governments, universities, international organizations, and the private sector; and

(5) cooperate with related international organizations including the International Council on Monuments and Sites, the International Center for the Study of Preservation and Restoration of Cultural Property, and the International Council on Museums.


(c) Programs.—The purposes shall be carried out through research, professional training, technical assistance, and programs for public awareness, and through a program of grants established under section 305304 of this title.

(d) Executive Director.—The Center shall be headed by an Executive Director with demonstrated expertise in historic preservation appointed by the Secretary with advice of the Board.

(e) Assistance From Secretary.—The Secretary shall provide the Center assistance in obtaining such personnel, equipment, and facilities as may be needed by the Center to carry out its activities.

(Pub. L. 113–287, § 3, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3221.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established within the Department of the Interior a National Center for Preservation Technology and Training. The Center shall be located at Northwestern State University of Louisiana in Natchitoches, Louisiana.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The purposes of the Center shall be to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The purposes shall be carried out through research, professional training, technical assistance, and programs for public awareness, and through a program of grants established under section 305304 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Director.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Center shall be headed by an Executive Director with demonstrated expertise in historic preservation appointed by the Secretary with advice of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance From Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall provide the Center assistance in obtaining such personnel, equipment, and facilities as may be needed by the Center to carry out its activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>