<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/307102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/307102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/307102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_307102"><akn:num>307102</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 307102. Effective date of regulations(a) Publication in Federal Register.—No final regulation of the Secretary shall become effective prior to the expiration of 30 calendar days after it is published in the Federal Register during which either or both Houses of Congress are in session.

(b) Disapproval of Regulation by Resolution of Congress.—The regulation shall not become effective if, within 90 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date of promulgation, both Houses of Congress adopt a concurrent resolution, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That Congress disapproves the regulation promulgated by the Secretary dealing with the matter of         , which regulation was transmitted to Congress on         ,” the blank spaces in the resolution being appropriately filled.

(c) Failure of Congress To Adopt Resolution of Disapproval of Regulation.—If at the end of 60 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date of promulgation of a regulation, no committee of either House of Congress has reported or been discharged from further consideration of a concurrent resolution disapproving the regulation, and neither House has adopted such a resolution, the regulation may go into effect immediately. If, within the 60 calendar days, a committee has reported or been discharged from further consideration of such a resolution, the regulation may go into effect not sooner than 90 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after its promulgation unless disapproved as provided for.

(d) Sessions of Congress.—For purposes of this section—(1) continuity of session is broken only by an adjournment sine die; and

(2) the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain are excluded in the computation of 60 and 90 calendar days of continuous session of Congress.


(e) Congressional Inaction or Rejection of Resolution of Disapproval Not Deemed Approval of Regulat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication in Federal Register.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) No final regulation of the Secretary shall become effective prior to the expiration of 30 calendar days after it is published in the Federal Register during which either or both Houses of Congress are in session.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disapproval of Regulation by Resolution of Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The regulation shall not become effective if, within 90 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date of promulgation, both Houses of Congress adopt a concurrent resolution, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That Congress disapproves the regulation promulgated by the Secretary dealing with the matter of         , which regulation was transmitted to Congress on         ,” the blank spaces in the resolution being appropriately filled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure of Congress To Adopt Resolution of Disapproval of Regulation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) If at the end of 60 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date of promulgation of a regulation, no committee of either House of Congress has reported or been discharged from further consideration of a concurrent resolution disapproving the regulation, and neither House has adopted such a resolution, the regulation may go into effect immediately. If, within the 60 calendar days, a committee has reported or been discharged from further consideration of such a resolution, the regulation may go into effect not sooner than 90 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after its promulgation unless disapproved as provided for.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sessions of Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_307102_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Inaction or Rejection of Resolution of Disapproval Not Deemed Approval of Regulation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Congressional inaction on or rejection of a resolution of disapproval shall not be deemed an expression of approval of the regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>