<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/312304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/312304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/54/312304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_312304"><akn:num>312304</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and powers; administrative support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 312304. Duties and powers; administrative support(a) Duties.—The Commission shall—(1) identify and publish a list of cemeteries, monuments, and historic buildings located abroad that are associated with the foreign heritage of United States citizens from eastern and central Europe, particularly cemeteries, monuments, and buildings that are in danger of deterioration or destruction;

(2) encourage the preservation and protection of those cemeteries, monuments, and historic buildings by obtaining, in cooperation with the Secretary of State, assurances from foreign governments that the cemeteries, monuments, and buildings will be preserved and protected; and

(3) prepare and disseminate reports on the condition of, and the progress toward preserving and protecting, those cemeteries, monuments, and historic buildings.


(b) Powers.—(1) Hold hearings, request attendance, take testimony, and receive evidence.—The Commission or any member it authorizes may, for the purposes of carrying out this chapter, hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, request such attendance, take such testimony, and receive such evidence, as the Commission considers appropriate.

(2) Appoint personnel and fix pay.—The Commission may appoint such personnel (subject to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service) and may fix the pay of such personnel (subject to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5), as the Commission considers desirable.

(3) Procure temporary and intermittent services.—The Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services to the same extent as is authorized by section 3109(b) of title 5, but at rates for individuals not to exceed the daily equivalent of the maximum annual rate of basic pay then in effect under section 5376 of title 5.

(4) Detail personnel to commisison 11 So in original. Probably should be “commission”..—On request of the Commission, the head of any Federal department</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative Support.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission on a reimbursable basis administrative support services as the Commission may request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>