<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1421i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1421i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1421i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1421i"><akn:num>1421i</akn:num><akn:heading>Income tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1421i. Income tax(a) Applicability of Federal laws; separate taxThe income-tax laws in force in the United States of America and those which may hereafter be enacted shall be held to be likewise in force in Guam: Provided, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Legislature of Guam may levy a separate tax on all taxpayers in an amount not to exceed 10 per centum of their annual income tax obligation to the Government of Guam.


(b) Guam Territorial income taxThe income-tax laws in force in Guam pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be deemed to impose a separate Territorial income tax, payable to the government of Guam, which tax is designated the “Guam Territorial income tax”.


(c) Enforcement of taxThe administration and enforcement of the Guam Territorial income tax shall be performed by or under the supervision of the Governor. Any function needful to the administration and enforcement of the income-tax laws in force in Guam pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be performed by any officer or employee of the government of Guam duly authorized by the Governor (either directly, or indirectly by one or more redelegations of authority) to perform such function.


(d) “Income-tax laws” defined; administration and enforcement; rules and regulations(1) The income-tax laws in force in Guam pursuant to subsection (a) of this section include but are not limited to the following provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, where not manifestly inapplicable or incompatible with the intent of this section: Subtitle A [26 U.S.C. 1 et seq.] (not including chapter 2 [26 U.S.C. 1401 et seq.] and section 931 [26 U.S.C. 931]); chapters 24 and 25 of subtitle C [26 U.S.C. 3401 et seq. and 3501 et seq.], with reference to the collection of income tax at source on wages; and all provisions of subtitle F [26 U.S.C. 6001 et seq.] which apply to the income tax, including provisions as to crimes, other offenses, and forfeitures contained in chapte</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Federal laws; separate tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability of Federal laws; separate tax The income-tax laws in force in the United States of America and those which may hereafter be enacted shall be held to be likewise in force in Guam: Provided, That notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Legislature of Guam may levy a separate tax on all taxpayers in an amount not to exceed 10 per centum of their annual income tax obligation to the Government of Guam.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guam Territorial income tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Guam Territorial income tax The income-tax laws in force in Guam pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be deemed to impose a separate Territorial income tax, payable to the government of Guam, which tax is designated the “Guam Territorial income tax”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement of tax The administration and enforcement of the Guam Territorial income tax shall be performed by or under the supervision of the Governor. Any function needful to the administration and enforcement of the income-tax laws in force in Guam pursuant to subsection (a) of this section shall be performed by any officer or employee of the government of Guam duly authorized by the Governor (either directly, or indirectly by one or more redelegations of authority) to perform such function.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Income-tax laws” defined; administration and enforcement; rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Income-tax laws” defined; administration and enforcement; rules and regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421i_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substitution of terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Substitution of terms In applying as the Guam Territorial income tax the income-tax laws in force in Guam pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, except where it is manifestly otherwise required, the applicable provisions of the Internal Revenue Codes of 1986 and 1939, shall be read so as to substitute “Guam” for “United States”, “Governor or his delegate” for “Secretary or his delegate”, “Governor or his delegate” for “Commissioner of Internal Revenue” and “Collector of Internal Revenue”, “District Court of Guam” for “district court” and with other changes in nomenclature and other language, including the omission of inapplicable language, where necessary to effect the intent of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421i_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal offenses; prosecution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Criminal offenses; prosecution Any act or failure to act with respect to the Guam Territorial income tax which constitutes a criminal offense under chapter 75 of subtitle F of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [26 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.], or the corresponding provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1939, as included in the income-tax laws in force in Guam pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, shall be an offense against the government of Guam and may be prosecuted in the name of the government of Guam by the appropriate officers thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421i_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Liens The government of Guam shall have a lien with respect to the Guam Territorial income tax in the same manner and with the same effect, and subject to the same conditions, as the United States has a lien with respect to the United States income tax. Such lien in respect of the Guam Territorial income tax shall be enforceable in the name of and by the government of Guam. Where filing of a notice of lien is prescribed by the income-tax laws in force in Guam pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, such notice shall be filed in the Office of the Clerk of the District Court of Guam.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421i_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of District Court; suits for recovery or collection of taxes; payment of judgment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Jurisdiction of District Court; suits for recovery or collection of taxes; payment of judgment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>