<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1422b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1422b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1422b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1422b"><akn:num>1422b</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancy in office of Governor or Lieutenant Governor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1422b. Vacancy in office of Governor or Lieutenant Governor(a) Temporary disability or temporary absence of GovernorIn case of the temporary disability or temporary absence of the Governor, the Lieutenant Governor shall have the powers of the Governor.


(b) Permanent vacancy in office of GovernorIn case of a permanent vacancy in the office of Governor, arising by reason of the death, resignation, removal by recall, or permanent disability of the Governor, or the death, resignation, or permanent disability of a Governor-elect, or for any other reason, the Lieutenant Governor or Lieutenant Governor-elect shall become the Governor, to hold office for the unexpired term and until he or his successor shall have been duly elected and qualified at the next regular election for Governor.


(c) Temporary disability or temporary absence of Lieutenant GovernorIn case of the temporary disability or temporary absence of the Lieutenant Governor, or during any period when the Lieutenant Governor is acting as Governor, the speaker of the Guam Legislature shall act as Lieutenant Governor.


(d) Permanent vacancy in office of Lieutenant GovernorIn case of a permanent vacancy in the office of Lieutenant Governor, arising by reason of the death, resignation, or permanent disability of the Lieutenant Governor, or because the Lieutenant Governor or Lieutenant Governor-elect has succeeded to the office of Governor, the Governor shall appoint a new Lieutenant Governor, with the advice and consent of the legislature, to hold office for the unexpired term and until he or his successor shall have been duly elected and qualified at the next regular election for Lieutenant Governor.


(e) Temporary disability or temporary absence of both Governor and Lieutenant GovernorIn case of the temporary disability or temporary absence of both the Governor and the Lieutenant Governor, the powers of the Governor shall be exercised, as Acting Governor, by such person as the laws of Guam may prescribe. In</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1422b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary disability or temporary absence of Governor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Temporary disability or temporary absence of Governor In case of the temporary disability or temporary absence of the Governor, the Lieutenant Governor shall have the powers of the Governor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1422b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent vacancy in office of Governor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Permanent vacancy in office of Governor In case of a permanent vacancy in the office of Governor, arising by reason of the death, resignation, removal by recall, or permanent disability of the Governor, or the death, resignation, or permanent disability of a Governor-elect, or for any other reason, the Lieutenant Governor or Lieutenant Governor-elect shall become the Governor, to hold office for the unexpired term and until he or his successor shall have been duly elected and qualified at the next regular election for Governor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1422b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary disability or temporary absence of Lieutenant Governor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Temporary disability or temporary absence of Lieutenant Governor In case of the temporary disability or temporary absence of the Lieutenant Governor, or during any period when the Lieutenant Governor is acting as Governor, the speaker of the Guam Legislature shall act as Lieutenant Governor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1422b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent vacancy in office of Lieutenant Governor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Permanent vacancy in office of Lieutenant Governor In case of a permanent vacancy in the office of Lieutenant Governor, arising by reason of the death, resignation, or permanent disability of the Lieutenant Governor, or because the Lieutenant Governor or Lieutenant Governor-elect has succeeded to the office of Governor, the Governor shall appoint a new Lieutenant Governor, with the advice and consent of the legislature, to hold office for the unexpired term and until he or his successor shall have been duly elected and qualified at the next regular election for Lieutenant Governor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1422b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary disability or temporary absence of both Governor and Lieutenant Governor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Temporary disability or temporary absence of both Governor and Lieutenant Governor In case of the temporary disability or temporary absence of both the Governor and the Lieutenant Governor, the powers of the Governor shall be exercised, as Acting Governor, by such person as the laws of Guam may prescribe. In case of a permanent vacancy in the offices of both the Governor and Lieutenant Governor, the office of Governor shall be filled for the unexpired term in the manner prescribed by the laws of Guam.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1422b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional compensation No additional compensation shall be paid to any person acting as Governor or Lieutenant Governor who does not also assume the office of Governor or Lieutenant Governor under the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>