<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1423" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1423/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1423/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1423"><akn:num>1423</akn:num><akn:heading>Legislature of Guam</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1423. Legislature of Guam(a) Unicameral nature; powerThe legislative power and authority of Guam shall be vested in a legislature, consisting of a single house, to be designated the “Legislature of Guam”, herein referred to as the legislature.


(b) Size of legislature; prohibition against denial of equal protection; at large and district representationThe legislature shall be composed of not to exceed twenty-one members, to be known as senators, elected at large, or elected from legislative districts or elected in part at large and in part from legislative districts, as the laws of Guam may direct: Provided, That any districting and any apportionment pursuant to this authorization and provided for by the laws of Guam shall not deny to any person in Guam the equal protection of the laws: And provided further, That in any elections to the legislature, every elector shall be permitted to vote for the whole number of at-large candidates to be elected, and every elector residing in a legislative district shall be permitted to vote for the whole number of candidates to be elected within that district.


(c) Reapportionment; Federal census baseAny districting and related apportionment pursuant to this section shall be based upon the then most recent Federal population census of Guam, and any such districting and apportionment shall be reexamined following each successive Federal population census of Guam and shall be modified, if necessary, to be consistent with that census.


(d) Timing of biennial electionsGeneral elections to the legislature shall be held on the Tuesday next after the first Monday in November, biennially in even-numbered years. The legislature in all respects shall be organized and shall sit according to the laws of Guam.


(Aug. 1, 1950, ch. 512, § 10, 64 Stat. 387; Pub. L. 89–552, § 1, Sept. 2, 1966, 80 Stat. 375; Pub. L. 98–213, § 5(b), Dec. 8, 1983, 97 Stat. 1460.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1983—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 98–213 substituted “Any” for </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1423_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unicameral nature; power</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unicameral nature; power The legislative power and authority of Guam shall be vested in a legislature, consisting of a single house, to be designated the “Legislature of Guam”, herein referred to as the legislature.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1423_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Size of legislature; prohibition against denial of equal protection; at large and district representation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Size of legislature; prohibition against denial of equal protection; at large and district representation The legislature shall be composed of not to exceed twenty-one members, to be known as senators, elected at large, or elected from legislative districts or elected in part at large and in part from legislative districts, as the laws of Guam may direct: Provided, That any districting and any apportionment pursuant to this authorization and provided for by the laws of Guam shall not deny to any person in Guam the equal protection of the laws: And provided further, That in any elections to the legislature, every elector shall be permitted to vote for the whole number of at-large candidates to be elected, and every elector residing in a legislative district shall be permitted to vote for the whole number of candidates to be elected within that district.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1423_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reapportionment; Federal census base</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reapportionment; Federal census base Any districting and related apportionment pursuant to this section shall be based upon the then most recent Federal population census of Guam, and any such districting and apportionment shall be reexamined following each successive Federal population census of Guam and shall be modified, if necessary, to be consistent with that census.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1423_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of biennial elections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Timing of biennial elections General elections to the legislature shall be held on the Tuesday next after the first Monday in November, biennially in even-numbered years. The legislature in all respects shall be organized and shall sit according to the laws of Guam.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>