<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1574b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1574b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1574b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1574b"><akn:num>1574b</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal guarantee for issuance of revenue bonds or other obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1574b. Federal guarantee for issuance of revenue bonds or other obligations(a) Application to Secretary of the Interior; contentsWhen authorized under subsection (b) of section 1574a of this title, the government of the Virgin Islands may apply to the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) for a guarantee of any issue of bonds or other obligations authorized to be issued under subsection (a) of section 1574a of this title. Any such application shall contain such information as the Secretary may prescribe.


(b) Terms and conditions of guarantee or commitment to guarantee; determination by Secretary of approvalThe Secretary is authorized, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, to guarantee and to enter into commitments to guarantee, upon such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, payment of principal and interest on bonds and other obligations issued by the government of the Virgin Islands under subsection (a) of section 1574a of this title. No guarantee or commitment to guarantee shall be made unless the Secretary determines—(1) that the proceeds of such issue will be used only for public works or other capital projects, except that $28,000,000 of the guaranteed bonding authority will be used for water producing and power projects, including maintenance and overhaul of electrical generating and distribution mechanisms, and $12,000,000 of the guaranteed bonding authority will be used for repair and improvements of the water distribution and storage systems;

(2) taking into account anticipated expenditures by the government of the Virgin Islands while the bonds or other obligations forming a part of such issue will be outstanding, all outstanding obligations of the government of the Virgin Islands which will mature while the bonds or other obligations forming a part of such issue will be outstanding, and such other factors as he deems pertinent, that the revenues expected to be received under section 7652(b)(3) of ti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1574b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to Secretary of the Interior; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application to Secretary of the Interior; contents When authorized under subsection (b) of section 1574a of this title, the government of the Virgin Islands may apply to the Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) for a guarantee of any issue of bonds or other obligations authorized to be issued under subsection (a) of section 1574a of this title. Any such application shall contain such information as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1574b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions of guarantee or commitment to guarantee; determination by Secretary of approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions of guarantee or commitment to guarantee; determination by Secretary of approval The Secretary is authorized, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, to guarantee and to enter into commitments to guarantee, upon such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, payment of principal and interest on bonds and other obligations issued by the government of the Virgin Islands under subsection (a) of section 1574a of this title. No guarantee or commitment to guarantee shall be made unless the Secretary determines—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1574b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs; deposit of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative costs; deposit of fees The Secretary shall charge and collect fees in amounts sufficient in his judgment to cover the costs of administering this section. Fees collected under this subsection shall be deposited in the revolving fund created under subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1574b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conclusiveness and incontestability; pledge of full faith and credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conclusiveness and incontestability; pledge of full faith and credit Any guarantee made by the Secretary shall be conclusive evidence of the eligibility of the obligation for such guarantee, and the validity of any guarantee so made shall be incontestable, except for fraud or material misrepresentation, in the hands of the holder of the guaranteed obligation. Such guarantee shall constitute a pledge of the full faith and credit of the United States for such obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1574b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest on guaranteed obligations taxable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interest on guaranteed obligations taxable The interest on any obligation guaranteed under this section shall be included in gross income for purposes of chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 [26 U.S.C. 1 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1574b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum amount guaranteed; time limitations on commitments to guarantee, obligation of guaranteed but unobligated funds, and repayment of unobligated proceeds of bonds or other obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Maximum amount guaranteed; time limitations on commitments to guarantee, obligation of guaranteed but unobligated funds, and repayment of unobligated proceeds of bonds or other obligations The aggregate principal amount of obligations which may be guaranteed under this Act shall not exceed $101,000,000. No commitment to guarantee may be issued by the Secretary, and no guaranteed but unobligated funds may be obligated by the government of the Virgin Islands after October 1, 1990. After October 1, 1990, any unobligated proceeds of bonds or other obligations issued by the government of the Virgin Islands pursuant to this section shall be repaid immediately by the government of the Virgin Islands to the lenders with the agreed upon interest. Should there be any delay in the government of the Virgin Islands’ making such repayment, the Secretary shall deduct the requisite amounts from moneys under his control that would otherwise be paid to the government of the Virgin Islands under sect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1574b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revolving fund; establishment; submission of budget to Congress; payments; transfers from fund to general fund of Treasury; issuance and sale of notes or other obligations for guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Revolving fund; establishment; submission of budget to Congress; payments; transfers from fund to general fund of Treasury; issuance and sale of notes or other obligations for guarantees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>