<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1806" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1806/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1806/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1806"><akn:num>1806</akn:num><akn:heading>Immigration and transition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1806. Immigration and transition(a) Application of the Immigration and Nationality Act and establishment of a transition program(1) In generalSubject to paragraphs (2) and (3), effective on the first day of the first full month commencing 1 year after May 8, 2008 (hereafter referred to as the “transition program effective date”), the provisions of the “immigration laws” (as defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17))) shall apply to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands (referred to in this section as the “Commonwealth”), except as otherwise provided in this section.


(2) Transition periodThere shall be a transition period beginning on the transition program effective date and ending on December 31, 2029, during which the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of the Interior, shall establish, administer, and enforce a transition program to regulate immigration to the Commonwealth, as provided in this section (hereafter referred to as the “transition program”).


(3) Delay of commencement of transition period(A) In generalThe Secretary of Homeland Security, in the Secretary’s sole discretion, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of State, the Attorney General, and the Governor of the Commonwealth, may determine that the transition program effective date be delayed for a period not to exceed more than 180 days after such date.


(B) Congressional notificationThe Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify the Congress of a determination under subparagraph (A) not later than 30 days prior to the transition program effective date.


(C) Congressional reviewA delay of the transition program effective date shall not take effect until 30 days after the date on which the notification under subparagraph (B) is made.



(4) Requirement for regulationsThe transit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of the Immigration and Nationality Act and establishment of a transition program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application of the Immigration and Nationality Act and establishment of a transition program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Numerical limitations for nonimmigrant workers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Numerical limitations for nonimmigrant workers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonimmigrant investor visas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nonimmigrant investor visas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special provision to ensure adequate employment; Commonwealth only transitional workers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special provision to ensure adequate employment; Commonwealth only transitional workers An alien who is seeking to enter the Commonwealth as a nonimmigrant worker may be admitted to perform work during the transition period subject to the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons lawfully admitted under the Commonwealth immigration law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Persons lawfully admitted under the Commonwealth immigration law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect on other laws The provisions of this section and of the immigration laws, as defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)), shall, on the transition program effective date, supersede and replace all laws, provisions, or programs of the Commonwealth relating to the admission of aliens and the removal of aliens from the Commonwealth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accrual of time for purposes of section 212(a)(9)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Accrual of time for purposes of section 212(a)(9)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act No time that an alien is present in the Commonwealth in violation of the immigration laws of the Commonwealth shall be counted for purposes of inadmissibility under section 212(a)(9)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(9)(B)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on nonresident guestworker population</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report on nonresident guestworker population The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Governor of the Commonwealth, shall report to the Congress not later than 2 years after May 8, 2008. The report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1806_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>