<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1841" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1841/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1841/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1841"><akn:num>1841</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1841. Funds and services(a) Acquisition and construction of powerplant and distribution facilitiesThere is hereby authorized to be appropriated for expenditure after October 1, 1978, not more than $12,000,000 plus or minus such amounts, if any, as may be justified by reason of ordinary fluctuations in construction costs from October 1978 price levels as indicated by engineering cost indexes applicable to the types of construction involved, to assist in the acquisition and construction of a powerplant for the Northern Mariana Islands together with upgrading, rehabilitation, or replacement of distribution facilities.


(b) Services and facilities of Federal agencies; grants-in-aid; availability of appropriations in succeeding fiscal years(1) The government of the Northern Marianas in carrying out the purposes of this Act, Public Law 95–134, or Public Law 94–241 [48 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.], may utilize, to the extent practicable, the available services and facilities of agencies and instrumentalities of the Federal Government on a reimbursable basis. Such amounts may be credited to the appropriation or fund which provided the services and facilities. Agencies and instrumentalities of the Federal Government may, when practicable, make available to the government of the Northern Marianas, upon request of the Secretary, such services and facilities as they are equipped to render or furnish, and they may do so without reimbursement if otherwise authorized by law.

(2) Any funds made available to the Northern Mariana Islands under grant-in-aid programs by section 502 of the Covenant To Establish a Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in Political Union With the United States of America (Public Law 94–241), or pursuant to any other Act of Congress enacted after March 24, 1976, are hereby authorized to remain available until expended.

(3) Any amount authorized by the Covenant described in paragraph (2) or by any other Act of Congress enacted after March 24, 1976, whic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition and construction of powerplant and distribution facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Acquisition and construction of powerplant and distribution facilities There is hereby authorized to be appropriated for expenditure after October 1, 1978, not more than $12,000,000 plus or minus such amounts, if any, as may be justified by reason of ordinary fluctuations in construction costs from October 1978 price levels as indicated by engineering cost indexes applicable to the types of construction involved, to assist in the acquisition and construction of a powerplant for the Northern Mariana Islands together with upgrading, rehabilitation, or replacement of distribution facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services and facilities of Federal agencies; grants-in-aid; availability of appropriations in succeeding fiscal years</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Services and facilities of Federal agencies; grants-in-aid; availability of appropriations in succeeding fiscal years</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits and distribution of donated foods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits and distribution of donated foods Notwithstanding the provisions of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 [7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.], the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, upon the request of the Governor of the Northern Mariana Islands, acting pursuant to legislation enacted in accordance with section 5 and 7 of article II of the Constitution of the Northern Mariana Islands, and for the period during which such legislation is effective, (1) to implement a supplemental nutrition assistance program in part or all of the Northern Mariana Islands with such income and household standards of eligibility, deductions, and allotment values as the Secretary determines, after consultation with the Governor, to be suited to the economic and social circumstances of such islands: Provided, That in no event shall such income standards of eligibility exceed those in the forty-eight contiguous States, and (2) to distribute or permit a distribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1841_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and enforcement of revenue and taxation provisions of Covenant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration and enforcement of revenue and taxation provisions of Covenant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>