<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1903"><akn:num>1903</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with and other provisions related to Marshall Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1903. Agreements with and other provisions related to Marshall Islands(a) Law enforcement assistance(1) AgreementThe President of the United States shall negotiate with the Government of the Marshall Islands an agreement pursuant to section 175 of the Compact which is in addition to the Agreement pursuant to such section dated May 30, 1982, and transmitted to the Congress by the President on February 20, 1985. Such additional agreement shall provide as follows:(A) Mutual assistance in law enforcementThe law enforcement agencies of the United States and the Marshall Islands shall assist one another, as mutually agreed, in the prevention and investigation of crimes and the enforcement of the laws of the United States and the Marshall Islands specified in subparagraph (C) of this paragraph. The United States and the Marshall Islands will authorize mutual assistance with respect to investigations, inquiries, audits and related activities by the law enforcement agencies of both Governments in the United States and the Marshall Islands. In conducting activities authorized in accordance with this section, the United States and the Marshall Islands will act in accordance with the constitution and laws of the jurisdiction in which such activities are conducted.


(B) Narcotics and control of illegal substancesThe United States and the Marshall Islands will take all reasonable and necessary steps, as mutually agreed, based upon consultations in which the Attorney General or other designated official of each Government participates, to prevent the use of the lands, waters, and facilities of the United States or the Marshall Islands for the purposes of cultivation of, production of, smuggling of, trafficking in, and abuse of any controlled substance as defined in section 802(6) of title 21 and Schedules I through V of Subchapter II of the Controlled Substances Act of the Marshall Islands, or for the distribution of any such substance to or from the Marshall Islands or to or f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law enforcement assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Law enforcement assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic development plans review process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Economic development plans review process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ejit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ejit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Kwajalein payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Kwajalein payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section 177 Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Section 177 Agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear test effects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nuclear test effects In approving the Compact, the Congress understands and intends that the peoples of Bikini, Enewetak, Rongelap, and Utrik, who were affected by the United States nuclear weapons testing program in the Marshall Islands, will receive the amounts of $75,000,000 (Bikini); $48,750,000 (Enewetak),22 So in original. The comma probably should be a semicolon. $37,500,000 (Rongelap); and $22,500,000 (Utrik), respectively, which amounts shall be paid out of proceeds from the fund established under Article I, section 1 of the subsidiary agreement for the implementation of section 177 of the Compact. The amounts specified in this subsection shall be in addition to any amounts which may be awarded to claimants pursuant to Article IV of the subsidiary agreement for the implementation of Section 177 of the Compact.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Espousal provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Espousal provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>DOE radiological health care program; USDA agricultural and food programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) DOE radiological health care program; USDA agricultural and food programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rongelap</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rongelap</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Four atoll health care program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Four atoll health care program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>