<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1904"><akn:num>1904</akn:num><akn:heading>Interpretation of and United States policy regarding Compact of Free Association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1904. Interpretation of and United States policy regarding Compact of Free Association(a) Human rightsIn approving the Compact, the Congress notes the conclusion in the Statement of Intent of the Report of The Future Political Status Commission of the Congress of Micronesia in July, 1969, that “our recommendation of a free associated state is indissolubly linked to our desire for such a democratic, representative, constitutional government” and notes that such desire and intention are reaffirmed and embodied in the Constitutions of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Marshall Islands. The Congress also notes and specifically endorses the preamble to the Compact, which affirms that the governments of the parties to the Compact are founded upon respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms for all. The Secretary of State shall include in the annual reports on the status of internationally recognized human rights in foreign countries, which are submitted to the Congress pursuant to sections 116 and 502B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2151n, 2304], a full and complete report regarding the status of internationally recognized human rights in the Federated States of Micronesia and the Marshall Islands.


(b) ImmigrationThe rights of a bona fide naturalized citizen of the Marshall Islands or the Federated States of Micronesia to enter the United States, to lawfully engage therein in occupations, and to establish residence therein as a non-immigrant, pursuant to the provisions of section 141(a)(3) of the Compact, shall not extend to any such naturalized citizen with respect to whom circumstances associated with the acquisition of the status of a naturalized citizen are such as to allow a reasonable inference, on the part of appropriate officials of the United States and subject to United States procedural requirements, that such naturalized status was acquired primarily in order to obtain such rights.


(c) Nonalienation of landsThe Congress e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1904_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Human rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Human rights In approving the Compact, the Congress notes the conclusion in the Statement of Intent of the Report of The Future Political Status Commission of the Congress of Micronesia in July, 1969, that “our recommendation of a free associated state is indissolubly linked to our desire for such a democratic, representative, constitutional government” and notes that such desire and intention are reaffirmed and embodied in the Constitutions of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Marshall Islands. The Congress also notes and specifically endorses the preamble to the Compact, which affirms that the governments of the parties to the Compact are founded upon respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms for all. The Secretary of State shall include in the annual reports on the status of internationally recognized human rights in foreign countries, which are submitted to the Congress pursuant to sections 116 and 502B of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2151n, 23</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1904_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immigration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Immigration The rights of a bona fide naturalized citizen of the Marshall Islands or the Federated States of Micronesia to enter the United States, to lawfully engage therein in occupations, and to establish residence therein as a non-immigrant, pursuant to the provisions of section 141(a)(3) of the Compact, shall not extend to any such naturalized citizen with respect to whom circumstances associated with the acquisition of the status of a naturalized citizen are such as to allow a reasonable inference, on the part of appropriate officials of the United States and subject to United States procedural requirements, that such naturalized status was acquired primarily in order to obtain such rights.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1904_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonalienation of lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nonalienation of lands The Congress endorses and encourages the maintenance of the policies of the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Government of the Marshall Islands to regulate, in accordance with their Constitutions and laws, the alienation of permanent and long-term interests in real property so as to restrict the acquisition of such interests to persons of Federated States of Micronesia citizenship and Marshall Islands citizenship, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1904_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear waste disposal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nuclear waste disposal In approving the Compact, the Congress understands that the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Government of the Marshall Islands will not permit any other government or any nongovernmental party to conduct, in the Marshall Islands or in the Federated States of Micronesia, any of the activities specified in subsection (a) of section 314 of the Compact.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1904_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact of Compact on U.S. areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Impact of Compact on U.S. areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1904_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fisheries management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fisheries management In clarification of Title One, Article II, section 121(b)(1) of the Compact:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1904_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Foreign loans The Congress hereby reaffirms the United States position that the United States Government is not responsible for foreign loans or debt obtained by the Governments of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Marshall Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>