<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1905"><akn:num>1905</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1905. Supplemental provisions(a) Domestic program requirementsExcept as may otherwise be provided in this joint resolution, all United States Federal programs and services extended to or operated in the Federated States of Micronesia or the Marshall Islands are and shall remain subject to all applicable criteria, standards, reporting requirements, auditing procedures, and other rules and regulations applicable to such programs when operating in the United States (including its territories and commonwealths).


(b) Relations with Federated States of Micronesia and Marshall Islands(1) The United States representatives to the Federated States of Micronesia and the Republic of the Marshall Islands pursuant to Article V of title I of the Compact shall be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall be under the supervision of the Secretary of State, who shall have responsibility for government to government relations between the United States and the Government with respect to whom they are appointed, consistent with the authority of the Secretary of the Interior as set forth in this section.

(2) Except for programs or services provided by or through other federal agencies or officials to the Federated States of Micronesia or the Republic of the Marshall Islands, or for which residents thereof are eligible pursuant to the Compact or any other provision of this joint resolution, appropriations made pursuant to the Compact or any other provision of this joint resolution may be made only to the Secretary of the Interior. The Secretary of the Interior shall coordinate and monitor any programs or activities, including such activities for which funding is made directly to such other agencies, provided to the Federated States of Micronesia or the Republic of the Marshall Islands by agencies of the Government of the United States and related economic development planning pursuant to the Compact or pursuant to any other authorization except f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Domestic program requirements Except as may otherwise be provided in this joint resolution, all United States Federal programs and services extended to or operated in the Federated States of Micronesia or the Marshall Islands are and shall remain subject to all applicable criteria, standards, reporting requirements, auditing procedures, and other rules and regulations applicable to such programs when operating in the United States (including its territories and commonwealths).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relations with Federated States of Micronesia and Marshall Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relations with Federated States of Micronesia and Marshall Islands</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing Trust Territory authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Continuing Trust Territory authorization The authorization provided by the Act of June 30, 1954, as amended (68 Stat. 330) shall remain available after the effective date of the Compact with respect to the Federated States of Micronesia and the Marshall Islands for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical referral debts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Medical referral debts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Survivability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Survivability In furtherance of the provisions of Title Four, Article V, sections 452 and 453 of the Compact, any provisions of the Compact which remain effective after the termination of the Compact by the act of any party thereto and which are affected in any manner by provisions of this part shall remain subject to such provisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration for agents of Governments of Federated States of Micronesia and Marshall Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Registration for agents of Governments of Federated States of Micronesia and Marshall Islands</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncompliance sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Noncompliance sanctions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing programs and laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Continuing programs and laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>College of Micronesia; education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) College of Micronesia; education programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1905_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trust Territory debts to U.S. Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Trust Territory debts to U.S. Federal agencies Neither the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia nor the Government of the Marshall Islands shall be required to pay to any department, agency, independent agency, office, or instrumentality of the United States any amounts owed to such department, agency, independent agency, office, or instrumentality by the Government of the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands as of the effective date of the Compact. There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>