<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1912" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1912/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1912/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1912"><akn:num>1912</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1912. Jurisdiction(a) With respect to section 321 of the Compact of Free Association and its related agreements, the jurisdictional provisions set forth in subsection (b) of this section shall apply only to the citizens and nationals of the United States and aliens lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence who are in the Marshall Islands or the Federated States of Micronesia.

(b)(1) The defense sites of the United States established in the Marshall Islands or the Federated States of Micronesia in accordance with the Compact of Free Association and its related agreements are within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States as set forth in section 7, title 18.

(2) Any person referred to in subsection (a) of this section who within or upon such defense sites is guilty of any act or omission which, although not made punishable by any enactment of Congress, would be punishable if committed or omitted within the jurisdiction of the State of Hawaii by the laws thereof, in force at the time of such act or omission, shall be guilty of a like offense and subject to a like punishment.

(3) The United States District Court for the District of Hawaii shall have jurisdiction to try all criminal offenses against the United States, including the laws of the State of Hawaii made applicable to the defense sites in the Marshall Islands or the Federated States of Micronesia by virtue of paragraph (2) of this subsection, committed by any person referred to in subsection (a) of this section.

(4) The United States District Court for the District of Hawaii may appoint one or more magistrate judges for the defense sites in the Marshall Islands. Such Magistrate Judges shall have the power and the status of Magistrate Judges appointed pursuant to chapter 43, title 28, provided, however that such Magistrate Judges shall have the power to try persons accused of and sentence persons convicted of petty offenses, as defined in section 1(3),11 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1912_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) With respect to section 321 of the Compact of Free Association and its related agreements, the jurisdictional provisions set forth in subsection (b) of this section shall apply only to the citizens and nationals of the United States and aliens lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence who are in the Marshall Islands or the Federated States of Micronesia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1912_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>