<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1921a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1921a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1921a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1921a"><akn:num>1921a</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with Federated States of Micronesia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1921a. Agreements with Federated States of Micronesia(a) Law enforcement assistancePursuant to sections 222 and 224 of the U.S.-FSM Compact, the United States shall provide non-reimbursable technical and training assistance as appropriate, including training and equipment for postal inspection of illicit drugs and other contraband, to enable the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia to develop and adequately enforce laws of the Federated States of Micronesia and to cooperate with the United States in the enforcement of criminal laws of the United States. Funds appropriated pursuant to section 1921d(j) of this title may be used to reimburse State or local agencies providing such assistance.


(b) Agreement on auditsThe Comptroller General (and his duly authorized representatives) shall have the authorities necessary to carry out his responsibilities under section 232 of the U.S.-FSM Compact and the agreement referred to in section 462(b)(4) of the U.S.-FSM Compact, including the following authorities:(1) General authority of the Comptroller General to audit(A) The Comptroller General of the United States (and his duly authorized representatives) shall have the authority to audit—(i) all grants, program assistance, and other assistance provided to the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia under Articles I and II of Title Two of the U.S.-FSM Compact; and

(ii) any other assistance provided by the Government of the United States to the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia.


Such authority shall include authority for the Comptroller General to conduct or cause to be conducted any of the audits provided for in section 232 of the U.S.-FSM Compact. The authority provided in this paragraph shall continue for at least three years after the last such grant has been made or assistance has been provided.

(B) The Comptroller General (and his duly authorized representatives) shall also have authority to review any audit conducted by or on beha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law enforcement assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Law enforcement assistance Pursuant to sections 222 and 224 of the U.S.-FSM Compact, the United States shall provide non-reimbursable technical and training assistance as appropriate, including training and equipment for postal inspection of illicit drugs and other contraband, to enable the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia to develop and adequately enforce laws of the Federated States of Micronesia and to cooperate with the United States in the enforcement of criminal laws of the United States. Funds appropriated pursuant to section 1921d(j) of this title may be used to reimburse State or local agencies providing such assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement on audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agreement on audits The Comptroller General (and his duly authorized representatives) shall have the authorities necessary to carry out his responsibilities under section 232 of the U.S.-FSM Compact and the agreement referred to in section 462(b)(4) of the U.S.-FSM Compact, including the following authorities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>