<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1921b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1921b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1921b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1921b"><akn:num>1921b</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with and other provisions related to the Republic of the Marshall Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1921b. Agreements with and other provisions related to the Republic of the Marshall Islands(a) Law enforcement assistancePursuant to sections 222 and 224 of the U.S.-RMI Compact, the United States shall provide non-reimbursable technical and training assistance as appropriate, including training and equipment for postal inspection of illicit drugs and other contraband, to enable the Government of the Marshall Islands to develop and adequately enforce laws of the Marshall Islands and to cooperate with the United States in the enforcement of criminal laws of the United States. Funds appropriated pursuant to section 1921d(j) of this title may be used to reimburse State or local agencies providing such assistance.


(b) Ejit(1) In the joint resolution of January 14, 1986 (Public Law 99–239) Congress provided that the President of the United States shall negotiate with the Government of the Marshall Islands an agreement whereby, without prejudice as to any claims which have been or may be asserted by any party as to rightful title and ownership of any lands on Ejit, the Government of the Marshall Islands shall assure that lands on Ejit used as of January 1, 1985, by the people of Bikini, will continue to be available without charge for their use, until such time as Bikini is restored and inhabitable and the continued use of Ejit is no longer necessary, unless a Marshall Islands court of competent jurisdiction finally determines that there are legal impediments to continued use of Ejit by the people of Bikini.

(2) In the joint resolution of January 14, 1986 (Public Law 99–239) Congress provided that if the impediments described in paragraph (1) do arise, the United States will cooperate with the Government of the Marshall Islands in assisting any person adversely affected by such judicial determination to remain on Ejit, or in locating suitable and acceptable alternative lands for such person’s use.

(3) In the joint resolution of January 14, 1986 (Public Law 99–239) C</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law enforcement assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Law enforcement assistance Pursuant to sections 222 and 224 of the U.S.-RMI Compact, the United States shall provide non-reimbursable technical and training assistance as appropriate, including training and equipment for postal inspection of illicit drugs and other contraband, to enable the Government of the Marshall Islands to develop and adequately enforce laws of the Marshall Islands and to cooperate with the United States in the enforcement of criminal laws of the United States. Funds appropriated pursuant to section 1921d(j) of this title may be used to reimburse State or local agencies providing such assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ejit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Ejit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section 177 Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Section 177 Agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear test effects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nuclear test effects In the joint resolution of January 14, 1986 (Public Law 99–239) Congress provided that in approving the Compact, the Congress understands and intends that the peoples of Bikini, Enewetak, Rongelap, and Utrik, who were affected by the United States nuclear weapons testing program in the Marshall Islands, will receive the amounts of $75,000,000 (Bikini); $48,750,000 (Enewetak); $37,500,000 (Rongelap); and $22,500,000 (Utrik), respectively, which amounts shall be paid out of proceeds from the fund established under Article I, section 1 of the subsidiary agreement for the implementation of section 177 of the Compact. The amounts specified in this subsection shall be in addition to any amounts which may be awarded to claimants pursuant to Article IV of the subsidiary agreement for the implementation of Section 177 of the Compact.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Espousal provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Espousal provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>DOE radiological health care program; USDA agricultural and food programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) DOE radiological health care program; USDA agricultural and food programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rongelap</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rongelap</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Four atoll health care program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Four atoll health care program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enjebi Community Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Enjebi Community Trust Fund In the joint resolution of January 14, 1986 (Public Law 99–239) Congress provided that notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the Treasury shall establish on the books of the Treasury of the United States a fund having the status specified in Article V of the subsidiary agreement for the implementation of Section 177 of the Compact, to be known as the “Enjebi Community Trust Fund” (hereafter in this subsection referred to as the “Fund”), and shall credit to the Fund the amount of $7,500,000. Such amount, which shall be ex gratia, shall be in addition to and not charged against any other funds provided for in the Compact and its subsidiary agreements, this joint resolution, or any other Act. Upon receipt by the President of the United States of the agreement described in this subsection, the Secretary of the Treasury, upon request of the Government of the Marshall Islands, shall transfer the Fund to the Government of the Marshall Isl</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bikini Atoll cleanup</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Bikini Atoll cleanup</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>