<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1921c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1921c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1921c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1921c"><akn:num>1921c</akn:num><akn:heading>Interpretation of and United States policy regarding U.S.-FSM Compact and U.S.-RMI Compact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1921c. Interpretation of and United States policy regarding U.S.-FSM Compact and U.S.-RMI Compact(a) Human rightsIn approving the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact, Congress notes the conclusion in the Statement of Intent of the Report of The Future Political Status Commission of the Congress of Micronesia in July, 1969, that “our recommendation of a free associated state is indissolubly linked to our desire for such a democratic, representative, constitutional government” and notes that such desire and intention are reaffirmed and embodied in the Constitutions of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Republic of the Marshall Islands. Congress also notes and specifically endorses the preamble to the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact, which affirms that the governments of the parties to the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact are founded upon respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms for all. The Secretary of State shall include in the annual reports on the status of internationally recognized human rights in foreign countries, which are submitted to Congress pursuant to sections 2151n and 2304 of title 22, a full and complete report regarding the status of internationally recognized human rights in the Federated States of Micronesia and the Republic of the Marshall Islands.


(b) Immigration and passport security(1) Naturalized citizensThe rights of a bona fide naturalized citizen of the Federated States of Micronesia or the Republic of the Marshall Islands to enter the United States, to lawfully engage therein in occupations, and to establish residence therein as a nonimmigrant, to the extent such rights are provided under section 141 of the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact, shall not be deemed to extend to any such naturalized citizen with respect to whom circumstances associated with the acquisition of the status of a naturalized citizen are such as to allow a reasonable inference, on the part of appropriate officials</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Human rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Human rights In approving the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact, Congress notes the conclusion in the Statement of Intent of the Report of The Future Political Status Commission of the Congress of Micronesia in July, 1969, that “our recommendation of a free associated state is indissolubly linked to our desire for such a democratic, representative, constitutional government” and notes that such desire and intention are reaffirmed and embodied in the Constitutions of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Republic of the Marshall Islands. Congress also notes and specifically endorses the preamble to the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact, which affirms that the governments of the parties to the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact are founded upon respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms for all. The Secretary of State shall include in the annual reports on the status of internationally recognized human rights in foreign countries, which are submitte</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immigration and passport security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Immigration and passport security</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonalienation of lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nonalienation of lands Congress endorses and encourages the maintenance of the policies of the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands to regulate, in accordance with their Constitutions and laws, the alienation of permanent interests in real property so as to restrict the acquisition of such interests to persons of Federated States of Micronesia citizenship and the Republic of the Marshall Islands citizenship, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear waste disposal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nuclear waste disposal In approving the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact, Congress understands that the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands will not permit any other government or any nongovernmental party to conduct, in the Republic of the Marshall Islands or in the Federated States of Micronesia, any of the activities specified in subsection (a) of section 314 of the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact of the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact on the State of Hawaii, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands and American Samoa; related authorization and continuing appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Impact of the U.S.-FSM Compact and the U.S.-RMI Compact on the State of Hawaii, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands and American Samoa; related authorization and continuing appropriation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Foreign loans Congress hereby reaffirms the United States position that the United States Government is not responsible for foreign loans or debt obtained by the Governments of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Republic of the Marshall Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress concerning funding of public infrastructure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sense of Congress concerning funding of public infrastructure It is the sense of Congress that not less than 30 percent of the United States annual grant assistance provided under section 211 of the Compact of Free Association, as amended, between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia, and not less than 30 percent of the total amount of section 211 funds allocated to each of the States of the Federated States of Micronesia, shall be invested in infrastructure improvements and maintenance in accordance with section 211(a)(6). It is further the sense of Congress that not less than 30 percent of the United States annual grant assistance provided under section 211 of the Compact of Free Association, as amended, between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, shall be invested in infrastructure improvements and maintenance in accordance with section 211(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports and reviews</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of section 141(f)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Construction of section 141(f) Section 141(f)(2) of the Compact of Free Association, as amended, between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Federated States of Micronesia and of the Compact of Free Association, as amended, between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, shall be construed as though, after “may by regulations prescribe”, there were included the following: “, except that any such regulations that would have a significant effect on the admission, stay and employment privileges provided under this section shall not become effective until 90 days after the date of transmission of the regulations to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on Resources, the Committee on International Relations, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1921c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inflation adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Inflation adjustment As of Fiscal Year 2015, if the United States Gross Domestic Product Implicit Price Deflator average for Fiscal Years 2009 through 2013 is greater than United States Gross Domestic Product Implicit Price Deflator average for Fiscal Years 2004 through 2008 (as reported in the Survey of Current Business or subsequent publication and compiled by the Department of the Interior), then section 217 of the U.S.-FSM Compact, paragraph 5 of Article II of the U.S.-FSM Fiscal Procedures Agreement, section 218 of the U.S.-RMI Compact, and paragraph 5 of Article II of the U.S.-RMI Fiscal Procedures Agreement shall be construed as if “the full” appeared in place of “two-thirds of the” each place those words appear. If an inflation adjustment is made under this subsection, the base year for calculating the inflation adjustment shall be fiscal year 2014.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>