<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1952" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1952/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1952/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1952"><akn:num>1952</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal procedures assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1952. Fiscal procedures assistance
Upon request of the Government of Palau, the Secretary of the Interior shall provide assistance to the Government of Palau to develop and promulgate regulations for the effective expenditure of funds received pursuant to this joint resolution, Public Laws 99–658 [48 U.S.C. 1931 et seq.] and 99–239 [48 U.S.C. 1901 et seq., 2001 et seq.], or any other Act of Congress.
(Pub. L. 101–219, title I, § 102, Dec. 12, 1989, 103 Stat. 1870.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis joint resolution, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 101–219, Dec. 12, 1989, 103 Stat. 1870, which enacted this part and sections 1846 and 1972 of this title, amended sections 1615 and 1933 of this title and section 10251 of Title 34, Crime Control and Law Enforcement, and enacted provisions set out as a note under section 1905 of Title 44, Public Printing and Documents. For complete classification of this joint resolution to the Code, see Tables.
Public Law 99–658, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 99–658, Nov. 14, 1986, 100 Stat. 3672, which is classified generally to part A of this subchapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
Public Law 99–239, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 99–239, Jan. 14, 1986, 99 Stat. 1770, known as the Compact of Free Association Act of 1985, which is classified principally to part A of subchapter I of this chapter and chapter 19 (§ 2001 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1901 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was formerly set out as a note under section 1681 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>