<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1974" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1974/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1974/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1974"><akn:num>1974</akn:num><akn:heading>Connecting Oceania’s Nations With Vanguard Exercises and National Empowerment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1974. Connecting Oceania’s Nations With Vanguard Exercises and National Empowerment(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Connecting Oceania’s Nations with Vanguard Exercises and National Empowerment Act of 2023” or the “CONVENE Act of 2023”.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—(A) the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate;

(B) the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and

(C) the congressional defense committees.


(2) National security council.—The term “national security council” means, with respect to a specified country, an intergovernmental body under the jurisdiction of the freely elected government of the specified country that acts as the primary coordinating entity for security cooperation, disaster response, and the activities described in subsection (c)(5).

(3) Specified country.—The term “specified country” means—(A) the Federated States of Micronesia;

(B) the Republic of the Marshall Islands; and

(C) the Republic of Palau.



(c) National security councils of specified countries(1) In generalThe Secretary of State, in consultation with other relevant Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, may consult and engage with each specified country to advise and provide assistance to a national security council (including by developing a national security council, if appropriate), or to identify a similar coordinating body for national security matters, comprised of citizens of the specified country—(A) that enables the specified country—(i) to better coordinate with the United States Government, including the Armed Forces, as appropriate;

(ii) to increase cohesion on activities, including emergency humanitarian response, law enforcement, and maritime security activities; and

(iii) to provide trained professionals to serve as members of the committees of the s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1974_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Connecting Oceania’s Nations with Vanguard Exercises and National Empowerment Act of 2023” or the “CONVENE Act of 2023”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1974_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1974_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National security councils of specified countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National security councils of specified countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>