<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1985" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1985/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1985/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1985"><akn:num>1985</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with and other provisions related to the Republic of the Marshall Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1985. Agreements with and other provisions related to the Republic of the Marshall Islands(a) Law enforcement assistance(1) In generalPursuant to sections 222 and 224 of the 2023 Amended U.S.-RMI Compact, the United States shall provide nonreimbursable technical and training assistance, as appropriate, including training and equipment for postal inspection of illicit drugs and other contraband, to enable the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands—(A) to develop and adequately enforce laws of the Marshall Islands; and

(B) to cooperate with the United States in the enforcement of criminal laws of the United States.


(2) Use of appropriated fundsFunds appropriated pursuant to subsection (j) of section 1921d of this title (as amended by section 209(j)) may be used in accordance with section 1921b(a) of this title.



(b) Espousal provisions(1) In generalCongress reaffirms that—(A) section 1903(g)(1) of this title and section 1921b(e)(1) of this title provided that “It is the intention of the Congress of the United States that the provisions of section 177 of the Compact of Free Association and the Agreement between the Government of the United States and the Government of the Marshall Islands for the Implementation of Section 177 of the Compact (hereafter in this subsection referred to as the ‘Section 177 Agreement’) constitute a full and final settlement of all claims described in Articles X and XI of the Section 177 Agreement, and that any such claims be terminated and barred except insofar as provided for in the Section 177 Agreement.”; and

(B) section 1903(g)(2) of this title and section 1921b(e)(2) of this title provided that “In furtherance of the intention of Congress as stated in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Section 177 Agreement is hereby ratified and approved. It is the explicit understanding and intent of Congress that the jurisdictional limitations set forth in Article XII of such Agreement are enacted solely and exclusively to acco</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1985_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law enforcement assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Law enforcement assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1985_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Espousal provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Espousal provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1985_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Section 177 Agreement provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certain Section 177 Agreement provisions Congress reaffirms that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1985_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States appointees to Joint Economic Management and Financial Accountability Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) United States appointees to Joint Economic Management and Financial Accountability Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1985_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States appointees to Trust Fund Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) United States appointees to Trust Fund Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1985_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Four Atoll Health Care Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Four Atoll Health Care Program Congress reaffirms that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1985_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Radiological health care program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Radiological health care program Notwithstanding any other provision of law, on the request of the Government of the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the President (through an appropriate department or agency of the United States) shall continue to provide special medical care and logistical support for the remaining members of the population of Rongelap and Utrik who were exposed to radiation resulting from the 1954 United States thermonuclear “Bravo” test, pursuant to Public Law 95–134 (91 Stat. 1159) and Public Law 96–205 (94 Stat. 84).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1985_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural and food programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Agricultural and food programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>