<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1986" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1986/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1986/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1986"><akn:num>1986</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with and other provisions related to the Republic of Palau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1986. Agreements with and other provisions related to the Republic of Palau(a) Bilateral economic consultationsUnited States participation in the annual economic consultations referred to in Article 8 of the 2023 U.S.-Palau Compact Review Agreement shall be by officers or employees of the Federal Government.


(b) Economic Advisory Group(1) QualificationsA member of the Economic Advisory Group described in Article 7 of the 2023 U.S.-Palau Compact Review Agreement (referred to in this subsection as the “Advisory Group”) who is appointed by the Secretary of the Interior shall be an individual who, by reason of knowledge, experience, or training, is especially qualified in private sector business development, economic development, or national development.


(2) FundsWith respect to the Advisory Group, the Secretary of the Interior may use available funds for—(A) the costs of the 2 members of the Advisory Group designated by the United States in accordance with Article 7 of the 2023 U.S.-Palau Compact Review Agreement;

(B) 50 percent of the costs of the 5th member of the Advisory Group designated by the Secretary of the Interior in accordance with the Article described in subparagraph (A); and

(C) the costs of—(i) technical and administrative assistance for the Advisory Group; and

(ii) other support necessary for the Advisory Group to accomplish the purpose of the Advisory Group.



(3) Reports to CongressNot later than 90 days after the date on which the Advisory Group receives or completes any report required under the 2023 U.S.-Palau Compact Review Agreement, or any related subsidiary agreement, the Secretary of the Interior shall submit the report to the appropriate committees of Congress.



(c) Reports to Congress(1) In generalNot later than 90 days after the date on which the Government of the Republic of Palau completes any report required under the 2023 U.S.-Palau Compact Review Agreement, or any related subsidiary agreement, the Secretary of the Interior </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1986_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bilateral economic consultations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Bilateral economic consultations United States participation in the annual economic consultations referred to in Article 8 of the 2023 U.S.-Palau Compact Review Agreement shall be by officers or employees of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1986_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic Advisory Group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Economic Advisory Group</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1986_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>