<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1988" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1988/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/1988/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1988"><akn:num>1988</akn:num><akn:heading>United States policy regarding the Freely Associated States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1988. United States policy regarding the Freely Associated States(a) Authorization for veterans’ services(1) Definition of Freely Associated StatesIn this subsection, the term “Freely Associated States” means—(A) the Federated States of Micronesia, during such time as it is a party to the Compact of Free Association set forth in section 201 of the Compact of Free Association Act of 1985 (Public Law 99–239; 48 U.S.C. 1901 note);

(B) the Republic of the Marshall Islands, during such time as it is a party to the Compact of Free Association set forth in section 201 of the Compact of Free Association Act of 1985 (Public Law 99–239; 48 U.S.C. 1901 note); and

(C) the Republic of Palau, during such time as it is a party to the Compact of Free Association between the United States and the Government of Palau set forth in section 201 of Joint Resolution entitled “Joint Resolution to approve the ‘Compact of Free Association’ between the United States and the Government of Palau, and for other purposes” (Public Law 99–658; 48 U.S.C. 1931 note).


(2), (3) Omitted

(4) Legal issues(A) Agreements to furnish care and services(i) In generalBefore delivering hospital care or medical services under subsection (f) of section 1724 of title 38, as added by paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall enter into agreements with the governments of the Freely Associated States to—(I) facilitate the furnishing of health services, including telehealth, under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to veterans in the Freely Associated States, such as by addressing—(aa) licensure, certification, registration, and tort issues relating to health care personnel;

(bb) the scope of health services the Secretary may furnish, as well as the means for furnishing such services; and

(cc) matters relating to delivery of pharmaceutical products and medical surgical products, including delivery of such products through the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for veterans’ services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization for veterans’ services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of education programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Department of Defense programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of Department of Defense programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Judicial training In addition to amounts provided under section 261(a)(4) of the 2023 Amended U.S.-FSM Compact and the 2023 Amended U.S.-RMI Compact and under subsections (a) and (b) of Article 1 of the 2023 U.S.-Palau Compact Review Agreement, for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2043, the Secretary of the Interior shall use the amounts made available to the Secretary of the Interior under section 1990(c) of this title to train judges and officials of the judiciary in the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau, in cooperation with the Pacific Islands Committee of the judicial council of the ninth judicial circuit of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for the Republic of Palau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligibility for the Republic of Palau</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with International Financial Institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Consultation with International Financial Institutions The Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of State, shall consult with appropriate officials of the Asian Development Bank and relevant international financial institutions (as defined in section 262r(c) of this title), as appropriate, with respect to overall economic conditions in, and the activities of other providers of assistance to, the Freely Associated States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of a unit for the Freely Associated States in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs of the Department of State and increasing personnel focused on Oceania</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Establishment of a unit for the Freely Associated States in the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs of the Department of State and increasing personnel focused on Oceania</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1988_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>