<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2104"><akn:num>2104</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2104. Definitions
In this chapter—(1) Agreed accounting standardsThe term “agreed accounting standards” means modified accrual accounting standards or, for any period during which the Oversight Board determines in its sole discretion that a territorial government is not reasonably capable of comprehensive reporting that complies with modified accrual accounting standards, such other accounting standards as proposed by the Oversight Board.


(2) BondThe term “Bond” means a bond, loan, letter of credit, other borrowing title, obligation of insurance, or other financial indebtedness for borrowed money, including rights, entitlements, or obligations whether such rights, entitlements, or obligations arise from contract, statute, or any other source of law, in any case, related to such a bond, loan, letter of credit, other borrowing title, obligation of insurance, or other financial indebtedness in physical or dematerialized form of which the issuer, obligor, or guarantor is the territorial government.


(3) Bond ClaimThe term “Bond Claim” means, as it relates to a Bond—(A) right to payment, whether or not such right is reduced to judgment, liquidated, unliquidated, fixed, contingent, matured, unmatured, disputed, undisputed, legal, equitable, secured, or unsecured; or

(B) right to an equitable remedy for breach of performance if such breach gives rise to a right to payment, whether or not such right to an equitable remedy is reduced to judgment, fixed, contingent, matured, unmatured, disputed, undisputed, secured, or unsecured.


(4) BudgetThe term “Budget” means the Territory Budget or an Instrumentality Budget, as applicable.


(5) Puerto RicoThe term “Puerto Rico” means the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.


(6) Compliant budgetThe term “compliant budget” means a budget that is prepared in accordance with—(A) agreed accounting standards; and

(B) the applicable Fiscal Plan.


(7) Covered territorial instrumentalityThe term “covered territorial instrumentality” means a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreed accounting standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agreed accounting standards The term “agreed accounting standards” means modified accrual accounting standards or, for any period during which the Oversight Board determines in its sole discretion that a territorial government is not reasonably capable of comprehensive reporting that complies with modified accrual accounting standards, such other accounting standards as proposed by the Oversight Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Bond The term “Bond” means a bond, loan, letter of credit, other borrowing title, obligation of insurance, or other financial indebtedness for borrowed money, including rights, entitlements, or obligations whether such rights, entitlements, or obligations arise from contract, statute, or any other source of law, in any case, related to such a bond, loan, letter of credit, other borrowing title, obligation of insurance, or other financial indebtedness in physical or dematerialized form of which the issuer, obligor, or guarantor is the territorial government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond Claim</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Bond Claim The term “Bond Claim” means, as it relates to a Bond—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Budget The term “Budget” means the Territory Budget or an Instrumentality Budget, as applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Puerto Rico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Puerto Rico The term “Puerto Rico” means the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliant budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Compliant budget The term “compliant budget” means a budget that is prepared in accordance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered territorial instrumentality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Covered territorial instrumentality The term “covered territorial instrumentality” means a territorial instrumentality designated by the Oversight Board pursuant to section 2121 of this title to be subject to the requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered territory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Covered territory The term “covered territory” means a territory for which an Oversight Board has been established under section 2121 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Executive Director The term “Executive Director” means an Executive Director appointed under section 2123(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2104_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Fiscal Plan The term “Fiscal Plan” means a Territory Fiscal Plan or an Instrumentality Fiscal Plan, as applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>