<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2121" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2121/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2121/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2121"><akn:num>2121</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial Oversight and Management Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2121. Financial Oversight and Management Board(a) PurposeThe purpose of the Oversight Board is to provide a method for a covered territory to achieve fiscal responsibility and access to the capital markets.


(b) Establishment(1) Puerto RicoA Financial Oversight and Management Board is hereby established for Puerto Rico.


(2) Constitutional basisThe Congress enacts this chapter pursuant to article IV, section 3 of the Constitution of the United States, which provides Congress the power to dispose of and make all needful rules and regulations for territories.



(c) TreatmentAn Oversight Board established under this section—(1) shall be created as an entity within the territorial government for which it is established in accordance with this subchapter; and

(2) shall not be considered to be a department, agency, establishment, or instrumentality of the Federal Government.


(d) Oversight of territorial instrumentalities(1) Designation(A) In generalAn Oversight Board, in its sole discretion at such time as the Oversight Board determines to be appropriate, may designate any territorial instrumentality as a covered territorial instrumentality that is subject to the requirements of this chapter.


(B) Budgets and reportsThe Oversight Board may require, in its sole discretion, the Governor to submit to the Oversight Board such budgets and monthly or quarterly reports regarding a covered territorial instrumentality as the Oversight Board determines to be necessary and may designate any covered territorial instrumentality to be included in the Territory Budget; except that the Oversight Board may not designate a covered territorial instrumentality to be included in the Territory Budget if applicable territory law does not require legislative approval of such covered territorial instrumentality’s budget.


(C) Separate Instrumentality Budgets and reportsThe Oversight Board in its sole discretion may or, if it requires a budget from a covered territorial instrumentality w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2121_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of the Oversight Board is to provide a method for a covered territory to achieve fiscal responsibility and access to the capital markets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2121_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2121_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment An Oversight Board established under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2121_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight of territorial instrumentalities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Oversight of territorial instrumentalities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2121_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2121_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for appointments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligibility for appointments An individual is eligible for appointment as a member of the Oversight Board only if the individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2121_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No compensation for service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No compensation for service Members of the Oversight Board shall serve without pay, but may receive reimbursement from the Oversight Board for any reasonable and necessary expenses incurred by reason of service on the Oversight Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2121_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of bylaws for conducting business of Oversight Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Adoption of bylaws for conducting business of Oversight Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>