<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2141" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2141/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2141/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2141"><akn:num>2141</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of Fiscal Plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2141. Approval of Fiscal Plans(a) In generalAs soon as practicable after all of the members and the Chair have been appointed to the Oversight Board in accordance with section 2121(e) of this title in the fiscal year in which the Oversight Board is established, and in each fiscal year thereafter during which the Oversight Board is in operation, the Oversight Board shall deliver a notice to the Governor providing a schedule for the process of development, submission, approval, and certification of Fiscal Plans. The notice may also set forth a schedule for revisions to any Fiscal Plan that has already been certified, which revisions must be subject to subsequent approval and certification by the Oversight Board. The Oversight Board shall consult with the Governor in establishing a schedule, but the Oversight Board shall retain sole discretion to set or, by delivery of a subsequent notice to the Governor, change the dates of such schedule as it deems appropriate and reasonably feasible.


(b) Requirements(1) In generalA Fiscal Plan developed under this section shall, with respect to the territorial government or covered territorial instrumentality, provide a method to achieve fiscal responsibility and access to the capital markets, and—(A) provide for estimates of revenues and expenditures in conformance with agreed accounting standards and be based on—(i) applicable laws; or

(ii) specific bills that require enactment in order to reasonably achieve the projections of the Fiscal Plan;


(B) ensure the funding of essential public services;

(C) provide adequate funding for public pension systems;

(D) provide for the elimination of structural deficits;

(E) for fiscal years covered by a Fiscal Plan in which a stay under subchapters III or IV is not effective, provide for a debt burden that is sustainable;

(F) improve fiscal governance, accountability, and internal controls;

(G) enable the achievement of fiscal targets;

(H) create independent forecasts of revenue fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2141_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general As soon as practicable after all of the members and the Chair have been appointed to the Oversight Board in accordance with section 2121(e) of this title in the fiscal year in which the Oversight Board is established, and in each fiscal year thereafter during which the Oversight Board is in operation, the Oversight Board shall deliver a notice to the Governor providing a schedule for the process of development, submission, approval, and certification of Fiscal Plans. The notice may also set forth a schedule for revisions to any Fiscal Plan that has already been certified, which revisions must be subject to subsequent approval and certification by the Oversight Board. The Oversight Board shall consult with the Governor in establishing a schedule, but the Oversight Board shall retain sole discretion to set or, by delivery of a subsequent notice to the Governor, change the dates of such schedule as it deems appropriate and reasonably feasible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2141_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2141_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development, review, approval, and certification of Fiscal Plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Development, review, approval, and certification of Fiscal Plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2141_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revised Fiscal Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Revised Fiscal Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2141_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval and certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Approval and certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2141_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint development of Fiscal Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Joint development of Fiscal Plan Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, if the Governor and the Oversight Board jointly develop a Fiscal Plan for the fiscal year that meets the requirements under this section, and that the Governor and the Oversight Board certify that the fiscal plan 11 So in original. Probably should be “Fiscal Plan”. reflects a consensus between the Governor and the Oversight Board, then such Fiscal Plan shall serve as the Fiscal Plan for the territory or territorial instrumentality for that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>