<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2142" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2142/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2142/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2142"><akn:num>2142</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of Budgets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2142. Approval of Budgets(a) Reasonable schedule for development of BudgetsAs soon as practicable after all of the members and the Chair have been appointed to the Oversight Board in the fiscal year in which the Oversight Board is established, and in each fiscal year thereafter during which the Oversight Board is in operation, the Oversight Board shall deliver a notice to the Governor and the Legislature providing a schedule for developing, submitting, approving, and certifying Budgets for a period of fiscal years as determined by the Oversight Board in its sole discretion but in any case a period of not less than one fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the notice is delivered. The notice may also set forth a schedule for revisions to Budgets that have already been certified, which revisions must be subject to subsequent approval and certification by the Oversight Board. The Oversight Board shall consult with the Governor and the Legislature in establishing a schedule, but the Oversight Board shall retain sole discretion to set or, by delivery of a subsequent notice to the Governor and the Legislature, change the dates of such schedule as it deems appropriate and reasonably feasible.


(b) Revenue forecastThe Oversight Board shall submit to the Governor and Legislature a forecast of revenues for the period covered by the Budgets by the time specified in the notice delivered under subsection (a), for use by the Governor in developing the Budget under subsection (c).


(c) Budgets developed by Governor(1) Governor’s proposed budgetsThe Governor shall submit to the Oversight Board proposed Budgets by the time specified in the notice delivered under subsection (a). In consultation with the Governor in accordance with the process specified in the notice delivered under subsection (a), the Oversight Board shall determine in its sole discretion whether each proposed Budget is compliant with the applicable Fiscal Plan and—(A) if a proposed Budget is a compliant</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2142_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable schedule for development of Budgets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reasonable schedule for development of Budgets As soon as practicable after all of the members and the Chair have been appointed to the Oversight Board in the fiscal year in which the Oversight Board is established, and in each fiscal year thereafter during which the Oversight Board is in operation, the Oversight Board shall deliver a notice to the Governor and the Legislature providing a schedule for developing, submitting, approving, and certifying Budgets for a period of fiscal years as determined by the Oversight Board in its sole discretion but in any case a period of not less than one fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the notice is delivered. The notice may also set forth a schedule for revisions to Budgets that have already been certified, which revisions must be subject to subsequent approval and certification by the Oversight Board. The Oversight Board shall consult with the Governor and the Legislature in establishing a schedule, but the Oversight Board shall</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2142_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revenue forecast</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Revenue forecast The Oversight Board shall submit to the Governor and Legislature a forecast of revenues for the period covered by the Budgets by the time specified in the notice delivered under subsection (a), for use by the Governor in developing the Budget under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2142_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budgets developed by Governor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Budgets developed by Governor</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2142_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget approval by Legislature</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Budget approval by Legislature</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2142_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of Budgets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certification of Budgets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2142_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint development of Budgets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Joint development of Budgets Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, if, in the case of a Territory Budget, the Governor, the Legislature, and the Oversight Board, or in the case of an Instrumentality Budget, the Governor and the Oversight Board, jointly develop such Budget for the fiscal year that meets the requirements under this section, and that the relevant parties certify that such budget reflects a consensus among them, then such Budget shall serve as the Budget for the territory or territorial instrumentality for that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>