<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2161" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2161/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2161/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2161"><akn:num>2161</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other laws; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2161. Applicability of other laws; definitions(a) Sections applicable to cases under this subchapterSections 101 (except as otherwise provided in this section), 102, 104, 105, 106, 107, 108, 112, 333, 344, 347(b), 349, 350(b), 351, 361, 362, 364(c), 364(d), 364(e), 364(f), 365, 366, 501, 502, 503, 504, 506, 507(a)(2), 509, 510, 524(a)(1), 524(a)(2), 544, 545, 546, 547, 548, 549(a), 549(c), 549(d), 550, 551, 552, 553, 555, 556, 557, 559, 560, 561, 562, 902 (except as otherwise provided in this section), 922, 923, 924, 925, 926, 927, 928, 942, 944, 945, 946, 1102, 1103, 1109, 1111(b), 1122, 1123(a)(1), 1123(a)(2), 1123(a)(3), 1123(a)(4), 1123(a)(5), 1123(b), 1123(d), 1124, 1125, 1126(a), 1126(b), 1126(c), 1126(e), 1126(f), 1126(g), 1127(d), 1128, 1129(a)(2), 1129(a)(3), 1129(a)(6), 1129(a)(8), 1129(a)(10), 1129(b)(1), 1129(b)(2)(A), 1129(b)(2)(B), 1142(b), 1143, 1144, 1145, and 1146(a) of title 11 apply in a case under this subchapter and section 930 of title 11 applies in a case under this subchapter; however, section 930 shall not apply in any case during the first 120 days after the date on which such case is commenced under this subchapter.


(b) Meanings of termsA term used in a section of title 11, made applicable in a case under this subchapter by subsection (a), has the meaning given to the term for the purpose of the applicable section, unless the term is otherwise defined in this subchapter.


(c) DefinitionsIn this subchapter:(1) AffiliateThe term “affiliate” means, in addition to the definition made applicable in a case under this subchapter by subsection (a)—(A) for a territory, any territorial instrumentality; and

(B) for a territorial instrumentality, the governing territory and any of the other territorial instrumentalities of the territory.


(2) DebtorThe term “debtor” means the territory or covered territorial instrumentality concerning which a case under this subchapter has been commenced.


(3) Holder of a claim or interestThe term “holder of a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2161_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sections applicable to cases under this subchapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sections applicable to cases under this subchapter Sections 101 (except as otherwise provided in this section), 102, 104, 105, 106, 107, 108, 112, 333, 344, 347(b), 349, 350(b), 351, 361, 362, 364(c), 364(d), 364(e), 364(f), 365, 366, 501, 502, 503, 504, 506, 507(a)(2), 509, 510, 524(a)(1), 524(a)(2), 544, 545, 546, 547, 548, 549(a), 549(c), 549(d), 550, 551, 552, 553, 555, 556, 557, 559, 560, 561, 562, 902 (except as otherwise provided in this section), 922, 923, 924, 925, 926, 927, 928, 942, 944, 945, 946, 1102, 1103, 1109, 1111(b), 1122, 1123(a)(1), 1123(a)(2), 1123(a)(3), 1123(a)(4), 1123(a)(5), 1123(b), 1123(d), 1124, 1125, 1126(a), 1126(b), 1126(c), 1126(e), 1126(f), 1126(g), 1127(d), 1128, 1129(a)(2), 1129(a)(3), 1129(a)(6), 1129(a)(8), 1129(a)(10), 1129(b)(1), 1129(b)(2)(A), 1129(b)(2)(B), 1142(b), 1143, 1144, 1145, and 1146(a) of title 11 apply in a case under this subchapter and section 930 of title 11 applies in a case under this subchapter; however, section 930 shall no</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2161_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meanings of terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Meanings of terms A term used in a section of title 11, made applicable in a case under this subchapter by subsection (a), has the meaning given to the term for the purpose of the applicable section, unless the term is otherwise defined in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2161_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this subchapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2161_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reference to subchapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reference to subchapter Solely for purposes of this subchapter, a reference to “this title”, “this chapter”, or words of similar import in a section of title 11 made applicable in a case under this subchapter by subsection (a) or to “this title”, “title 11”, “Chapter 9”, “Chapter 11”, “the Code”, or words of similar import in the Federal Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure made applicable in a case under this subchapter shall be deemed to be a reference to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2161_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantially similar</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Substantially similar In determining whether claims are “substantially similar” for the purpose of section 1122 of title 11, made applicable in a case under this subchapter by subsection (a), the Oversight Board shall consider whether such claims are secured and whether such claims have priority over other claims.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2161_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operative clauses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Operative clauses A section made applicable in a case under this subchapter by subsection (a) that is operative if the business of the debtor is authorized to be operated is operative in a case under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>