<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2164" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2164/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2164/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2164"><akn:num>2164</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition and proceedings relating to petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2164. Petition and proceedings relating to petition(a) Commencement of caseA voluntary case under this subchapter is commenced by the filing with the district court of a petition by the Oversight Board pursuant to the determination under section 2146 of this title.


(b) Objection to petitionAfter any objection to the petition, the court, after notice and a hearing, may dismiss the petition if the petition does not meet the requirements of this subchapter; however, this subsection shall not apply in any case during the first 120 days after the date on which such case is commenced under this subchapter.


(c) Order for reliefThe commencement of a case under this subchapter constitutes an order for relief.


(d) AppealThe court may not, on account of an appeal from an order for relief, delay any proceeding under this subchapter in the case in which the appeal is being taken, nor shall any court order a stay of such proceeding pending such appeal.


(e) Validity of debtThe reversal on appeal of a finding of jurisdiction shall not affect the validity of any debt incurred that is authorized by the court under section 364(c) or 364(d) of title 11.


(f) Joint filing of petitions and plans permittedThe Oversight Board, on behalf of debtors under this subchapter, may file petitions or submit or modify plans of adjustment jointly if the debtors are affiliates; provided, however, that nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as authorizing substantive consolidation of the cases of affiliated debtors.


(g) Joint administration of affiliated casesIf the Oversight Board, on behalf of a debtor and one or more affiliates, has filed separate cases and the Oversight Board, on behalf of the debtor or one of the affiliates, files a motion to administer the cases jointly, the court may order a joint administration of the cases.


(h) Public safetyThis chapter may not be construed to permit the discharge of obligations arising under Federal police or regulatory laws, including l</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2164_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of case</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Commencement of case A voluntary case under this subchapter is commenced by the filing with the district court of a petition by the Oversight Board pursuant to the determination under section 2146 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2164_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objection to petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Objection to petition After any objection to the petition, the court, after notice and a hearing, may dismiss the petition if the petition does not meet the requirements of this subchapter; however, this subsection shall not apply in any case during the first 120 days after the date on which such case is commenced under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2164_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order for relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Order for relief The commencement of a case under this subchapter constitutes an order for relief.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2164_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Appeal The court may not, on account of an appeal from an order for relief, delay any proceeding under this subchapter in the case in which the appeal is being taken, nor shall any court order a stay of such proceeding pending such appeal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2164_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Validity of debt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Validity of debt The reversal on appeal of a finding of jurisdiction shall not affect the validity of any debt incurred that is authorized by the court under section 364(c) or 364(d) of title 11.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2164_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint filing of petitions and plans permitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Joint filing of petitions and plans permitted The Oversight Board, on behalf of debtors under this subchapter, may file petitions or submit or modify plans of adjustment jointly if the debtors are affiliates; provided, however, that nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as authorizing substantive consolidation of the cases of affiliated debtors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2164_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint administration of affiliated cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Joint administration of affiliated cases If the Oversight Board, on behalf of a debtor and one or more affiliates, has filed separate cases and the Oversight Board, on behalf of the debtor or one of the affiliates, files a motion to administer the cases jointly, the court may order a joint administration of the cases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2164_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Public safety This chapter may not be construed to permit the discharge of obligations arising under Federal police or regulatory laws, including laws relating to the environment, public health or safety, or territorial laws implementing such Federal legal provisions. This includes compliance obligations, requirements under consent decrees or judicial orders, and obligations to pay associated administrative, civil, or other penalties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2164_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting on debt adjustment plans not stayed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Voting on debt adjustment plans not stayed Notwithstanding any provision in this subchapter to the contrary, including sections of title 11 incorporated by reference, nothing in this section shall prevent the holder of a claim from voting on or consenting to a proposed modification of such claim under subchapter VI of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>