<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2166" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2166/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2166/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2166"><akn:num>2166</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2166. Jurisdiction(a) Federal subject matter jurisdictionThe district courts shall have—(1) except as provided in paragraph (2), original and exclusive jurisdiction of all cases under this subchapter; and

(2) except as provided in subsection (b), and notwithstanding any Act of Congress that confers exclusive jurisdiction on a court or courts other than the district courts, original but not exclusive jurisdiction of all civil proceedings arising under this subchapter, or arising in or related to cases under this subchapter.


(b) Property jurisdictionThe district court in which a case under this subchapter is commenced or is pending shall have exclusive jurisdiction of all property, wherever located, of the debtor as of the commencement of the case.


(c) Personal jurisdictionThe district court in which a case under this subchapter is pending shall have personal jurisdiction over any person or entity.


(d) Removal, remand, and transfer(1) RemovalA party may remove any claim or cause of action in a civil action, other than a proceeding before the United States Tax Court or a civil action by a governmental unit to enforce the police or regulatory power of the governmental unit, to the district court for the district in which the civil action is pending, if the district court has jurisdiction of the claim or cause of action under this section.


(2) RemandThe district court to which the claim or cause of action is removed under paragraph (1) may remand the claim or cause of action on any equitable ground. An order entered under this subsection remanding a claim or cause of action, or a decision not to remand, is not reviewable by appeal or otherwise by the court of appeals under section 158(d), 1291 or 1292 of title 28 or by the Supreme Court of the United States under section 1254 of title 28.


(3) TransferA district court shall transfer any civil proceeding arising under this subchapter, or arising in or related to a case under this subchapter, to the district co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2166_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal subject matter jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal subject matter jurisdiction The district courts shall have—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2166_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Property jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Property jurisdiction The district court in which a case under this subchapter is commenced or is pending shall have exclusive jurisdiction of all property, wherever located, of the debtor as of the commencement of the case.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2166_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Personal jurisdiction The district court in which a case under this subchapter is pending shall have personal jurisdiction over any person or entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2166_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal, remand, and transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Removal, remand, and transfer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2166_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Appeal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2166_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocation of court staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reallocation of court staff Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, the clerk of the court in which a case is pending shall reallocate as many staff and assistants as the clerk deems necessary to ensure that the court has adequate resources to provide for proper case management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>