<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2178" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2178/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2178/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2178"><akn:num>2178</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure by professional persons seeking approval of compensation under section 2176 or 2177 of th</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2178. Disclosure by professional persons seeking approval of compensation under section 2176 or 2177 of this title(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) List of Material Interested PartiesThe term “List of Material Interested Parties” means the List of Material Interested Parties established under subsection (c)(1).


(2) Oversight BoardThe term “Oversight Board” has the meaning given the term in section 2104 of this title.



(b) Required disclosure(1) In generalIn a case commenced under section 2164 of this title, no attorney, accountant, appraiser, auctioneer, agent, or other professional person may be compensated under section 2176 or 2177 of this title unless prior to making a request for compensation, the professional person has filed with the court a verified statement conforming to the disclosure requirements of rule 2014(a) of the Federal Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure setting forth the connection of the professional person with any entity or person on the List of Material Interested Parties.


(2) SupplementA professional person that submits a statement under paragraph (1) shall promptly supplement the statement with any additional relevant information that becomes known to the person.


(3) DisclosureSubject to any other applicable law, rule, or regulation, a professional person that fails to file or update a statement required under paragraph (1) or files a statement that the court determines does not represent a good faith effort to comply with this section shall disclose such failure in any filing required to conform to the disclosure requirements under rule 2014(a) of the Federal Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure.



(c) List of Material Interested Parties(1) PreparationNot later than 30 days after January 20, 2022, the Oversight Board shall establish a List of Material Interested Parties subject to—(A) the approval of the court; and

(B) the right of the United States trustee or any party in interest to be heard on the approval.


(2) InclusionsExcept as pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2178_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2178_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2178_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of Material Interested Parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) List of Material Interested Parties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2178_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2178_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on compensation In a case commenced under section 2164 of this title, in connection with the review and approval of professional compensation under section 2176 or 2177 of this title filed after January 20, 2022, the court may deny allowance of compensation or reimbursement of expenses if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>