<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2211" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2211/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2211/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2211"><akn:num>2211</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2211. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Act 76The term “Act 76” means Puerto Rico Act 76–2000 (3 L.P.R.A. 1931 et seq.), approved on May 5, 2000, as amended.


(2) Critical ProjectThe term “Critical Project” means a project identified under the provisions of this subchapter and intimately related to addressing an emergency whose approval, consideration, permitting, and implementation shall be expedited and streamlined according to the statutory process provided by Act 76, or otherwise adopted pursuant to this subchapter.


(3) Energy Commission of Puerto RicoThe term “Energy Commission of Puerto Rico” means the Puerto Rico Energy Commission as established by Subtitle B of Puerto Rico Act 57–2014.


(4) Energy ProjectsThe term “Energy Projects” means those projects addressing the generation, distribution, or transmission of energy.


(5) EmergencyThe term “emergency” means any event or grave problem of deterioration in the physical infrastructure for the rendering of essential services to the people, or that endangers the life, public health, or safety of the population or of a sensitive ecosystem, or as otherwise defined by section 1 of Act 76 (3 L.P.R.A. 1931). This shall include problems in the physical infrastructure for energy, water, sewer, solid waste, highways or roads, ports, telecommunications, and other similar infrastructure.


(6) Environmental Quality BoardThe term “Environmental Quality Board” means the Puerto Rico Environmental Quality Board, a board within the executive branch of the Government of Puerto Rico as established by section 7 of Puerto Rico Act 416–2004 (12 L.P.R.A. 8002a).


(7) Expedited Permitting ProcessThe term “Expedited Permitting Process” means a Puerto Rico Agency’s alternate procedures, conditions, and terms mirroring those established under Act 76 (3 L.P.R.A. 1932) and pursuant to this subchapter shall not apply to any Federal law, statute, or requirement.


(8) GovernorThe term “Governor” means the Governor of Puerto Rico.

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Act 76</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Act 76 The term “Act 76” means Puerto Rico Act 76–2000 (3 L.P.R.A. 1931 et seq.), approved on May 5, 2000, as amended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Critical Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Critical Project The term “Critical Project” means a project identified under the provisions of this subchapter and intimately related to addressing an emergency whose approval, consideration, permitting, and implementation shall be expedited and streamlined according to the statutory process provided by Act 76, or otherwise adopted pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Commission of Puerto Rico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Energy Commission of Puerto Rico The term “Energy Commission of Puerto Rico” means the Puerto Rico Energy Commission as established by Subtitle B of Puerto Rico Act 57–2014.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Energy Projects The term “Energy Projects” means those projects addressing the generation, distribution, or transmission of energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Emergency The term “emergency” means any event or grave problem of deterioration in the physical infrastructure for the rendering of essential services to the people, or that endangers the life, public health, or safety of the population or of a sensitive ecosystem, or as otherwise defined by section 1 of Act 76 (3 L.P.R.A. 1931). This shall include problems in the physical infrastructure for energy, water, sewer, solid waste, highways or roads, ports, telecommunications, and other similar infrastructure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Quality Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Environmental Quality Board The term “Environmental Quality Board” means the Puerto Rico Environmental Quality Board, a board within the executive branch of the Government of Puerto Rico as established by section 7 of Puerto Rico Act 416–2004 (12 L.P.R.A. 8002a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited Permitting Process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Expedited Permitting Process The term “Expedited Permitting Process” means a Puerto Rico Agency’s alternate procedures, conditions, and terms mirroring those established under Act 76 (3 L.P.R.A. 1932) and pursuant to this subchapter shall not apply to any Federal law, statute, or requirement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Governor The term “Governor” means the Governor of Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Environmental Subcommittee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Interagency Environmental Subcommittee The term “Interagency Environmental Subcommittee” means the Interagency Subcommittee on Expedited Environmental Regulations as further described by section 2214 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2211_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Legislature</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Legislature The term “Legislature” means the Legislature of Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>