<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2212"><akn:num>2212</akn:num><akn:heading>Position of Revitalization Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2212. Position of Revitalization Coordinator(a) EstablishmentThere is established, under the Oversight Board, the position of the Revitalization Coordinator.


(b) Appointment(1) In generalThe Revitalization Coordinator shall be appointed by the Governor as follows:(A) Prior to the appointment of the Revitalization Coordinator and within 60 days of the appointment of the full membership of the Oversight Board, the Oversight Board shall submit to the Governor no less than three nominees for appointment.

(B) In consultation with the Oversight Board, not later than 10 days after receiving the nominations under subparagraph (A), the Governor shall appoint one of the nominees as the Revitalization Coordinator. Such appointment shall be effective immediately.

(C) If the Governor fails to select a Revitalization Coordinator, the Oversight Board shall, by majority vote, appoint a Revitalization Coordinator from the list of nominees provided under paragraph (A).


(2) QualificationsIn selecting nominees under paragraph (1)(A), the Oversight Board shall only nominate persons who—(A) have substantial knowledge and expertise in the planning, predevelopment, financing, development, operations, engineering, or market participation of infrastructure projects, provided that stronger consideration may be given to candidates who have experience with Energy Projects and the laws and regulations of Puerto Rico that may be subject to an Expedited Permitting Process;

(B) does 11 So in original. Probably should be “do”. not currently provide goods or services to the government of Puerto Rico (and, as applicable, is 22 So in original. Probably should be “are”. not the spouse, parent, child, or sibling of a person who provides or has provided goods and services to the government of Puerto Rico in the preceding 3 calendar years); and

(C) shall not be an officer, employee of, or former officer or employee of the government of Puerto Rico in the preceding 3 calendar years.


(3) Compensa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established, under the Oversight Board, the position of the Revitalization Coordinator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assignment of personnel The Executive Director of the Oversight Board may assign Oversight Board personnel to assist the Revitalization Coordinator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2212_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Removal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>