<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2214" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2214/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2214/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2214"><akn:num>2214</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2214. Miscellaneous provisions(a) Creation of Interagency Environmental Subcommittee(1) EstablishmentNot later than 60 days after the date on which the Revitalization Coordinator is appointed, the Interagency Environmental Subcommittee shall be established and shall evaluate environmental documents required under Puerto Rico law for any Critical Project within the Expedited Permitting Process established by the Revitalization Coordinator under section 2213(a)(3) of this title.


(2) CompositionThe Interagency Environmental Subcommittee shall consist of the Revitalization Coordinator, and a representative selected by the Governor in consultation with the Revitalization Coordinator representing each of the following agencies: The Environmental Quality Board, the Planning Board, the Puerto Rico Department of Natural and Environmental Resources, and any other Puerto Rico Agency determined to be relevant by the Revitalization Coordinator.



(b) Length of Expedited Permitting ProcessWith respect to a Puerto Rico Agency’s activities related only to a Critical Project, such Puerto Rico Agency shall operate as if the Governor has declared an emergency pursuant to section 2 of Act 76 (3 L.P.R.A. 1932). Section 12 of Act 76 (3 L.P.R.A. 1942) shall not be applicable to Critical Projects. Furthermore, any transactions, processes, projects, works, or programs essential to the completion of a Critical Project shall continue to be processed and completed under such Expedited Permitting Process regardless of the termination of the Oversight Board under section 2149 of this title.


(c) Expedited Permitting Process compliance(1) Written noticeA Critical Project Sponsor may in writing notify the Oversight Board of the failure of a Puerto Rico Agency or the Revitalization Coordinator to adhere to the Expedited Permitting Process.


(2) Finding of failureIf the Oversight Board finds either the Puerto Rico Agency or Revitalization Coordinator has failed to adhere to the Expedited Perm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2214_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation of Interagency Environmental Subcommittee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation of Interagency Environmental Subcommittee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2214_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Length of Expedited Permitting Process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Length of Expedited Permitting Process With respect to a Puerto Rico Agency’s activities related only to a Critical Project, such Puerto Rico Agency shall operate as if the Governor has declared an emergency pursuant to section 2 of Act 76 (3 L.P.R.A. 1932). Section 12 of Act 76 (3 L.P.R.A. 1942) shall not be applicable to Critical Projects. Furthermore, any transactions, processes, projects, works, or programs essential to the completion of a Critical Project shall continue to be processed and completed under such Expedited Permitting Process regardless of the termination of the Oversight Board under section 2149 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2214_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited Permitting Process compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expedited Permitting Process compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2214_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of Legislature acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of Legislature acts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2214_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of certain terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Establishment of certain terms and conditions No Puerto Rico Agency may include in any certificate, right-of-way, permit, lease, or other authorization issued for a Critical Project any term or condition that may be permitted, but is not required, by any applicable Puerto Rico law, if the Revitalization Coordinator determines the term or condition would prevent or impair the expeditious construction, operation, or expansion of the Critical Project. The Revitalization Coordinator may request a Puerto Rico Agency to include in any certificate, right-of-way, permit, lease, or other authorization, a term or condition that may be permitted in accordance with applicable laws if the Revitalization Coordinator determines such inclusion would support the expeditious construction, operation, or expansion of any Critical Project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2214_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosure All Critical Project reports, and justifications for approval or rejection of Critical Project status, shall be made publicly available online within 5 days of receipt or completion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>