<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2231" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2231/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/2231/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2231"><akn:num>2231</akn:num><akn:heading>Creditor collective action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2231. Creditor collective action(a) DefinitionsIn this subchapter:(1) Administrative SupervisorThe term “Administrative Supervisor” means the Oversight Board established under section 2121 of this title.


(2) Authorized Territorial InstrumentalityThe term “Authorized Territorial Instrumentality” means a covered territorial instrumentality authorized in accordance with subsection (e).


(3) Calculation AgentThe term “Calculation Agent” means a calculation agent appointed in accordance with subsection (k).


(4) Capital Appreciation BondThe term “Capital Appreciation Bond” means a Bond that does not pay interest on a current basis, but for which interest amounts are added to principal over time as specified in the relevant offering materials for such Bond, including that the accreted interest amount added to principal increases daily.


(5) Convertible Capital Appreciation BondThe term “Convertible Capital Appreciation Bond” means a Bond that does not pay interest on a current basis, but for which interest amounts are added to principal over time as specified in the relevant offering materials and which converts to a current pay bond on a future date.


(6) Information AgentThe term “Information Agent” means an information agent appointed in accordance with subsection (l).


(7) Insured BondThe term “Insured Bond” means a bond subject to a financial guarantee or similar insurance contract, policy or surety issued by a monoline insurer.


(8) IssuerThe term “Issuer” means, as applicable, the Territory Government Issuer or an Authorized Territorial Instrumentality that has issued or guaranteed at least one Bond that is Outstanding.


(9) ModificationThe term “Modification” means any modification, amendment, supplement or waiver affecting one or more series of Bonds, including those effected by way of exchange, repurchase, conversion, or substitution.


(10) OutstandingThe term “Outstanding,” in the context of the principal amount of Bonds, shall be determined in acco</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this subchapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outstanding Bonds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Outstanding Bonds In determining whether holders of the requisite principal amount of Outstanding Bonds have voted in favor of, or consented to, a proposed Qualifying Modification, a Bond will be deemed not to be outstanding, and may not be counted in a vote or consent solicitation for or against a proposed Qualifying Modification, if on the record date for the proposed Qualifying Modification— For purposes of this subsection, a corporation, trust or other legal entity is controlled by the Issuer or by an Authorized Territorial Instrumentality of the Territory Government Issuer if the Issuer or an Authorized Territorial Instrumentality of the Territory Government Issuer, as applicable, has the power, directly or indirectly, through the ownership of voting securities or other ownership interests, by contract or otherwise, to direct the management of or elect or appoint a majority of the board of directors or other persons performing similar functions in lieu of, or in addition to, t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of disenfranchised Bonds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certification of disenfranchised Bonds Prior to any vote on, or consent solicitation for, a Qualifying Modification, the Issuer shall deliver to the Calculation Agent a certificate signed by an authorized representative of the Issuer specifying any Bonds that are deemed not to be Outstanding for the purpose of subsection (b) above.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Pools for voting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Determination of Pools for voting The Administrative Supervisor, in consultation with the Issuer, shall establish Pools in accordance with the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Territory Instrumentalities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of Territory Instrumentalities A covered territorial instrumentality is an Authorized Territorial Instrumentality if it has been specifically authorized to be eligible to avail itself of the procedures under this section by the Administrative Supervisor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information delivery requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Information delivery requirement Before solicitation of acceptance or rejection of a Modification under subsection (h), the Issuer shall provide to the Calculation Agent, the Information Agent, and the Administrative Supervisor, the following information—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying Modification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Qualifying Modification A Modification is a Qualifying Modification if one of the following processes has occurred:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Solicitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Who may propose a Modification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Who may propose a Modification For each Issuer, a Modification may be proposed to the Administrative Supervisor by the Issuer or by one or more holders of the right to vote the Issuer’s Outstanding Bonds. To the extent a Modification proposed by one or more holders of the right to vote Outstanding Bonds otherwise complies with the requirements of this subchapter, the Administrative Supervisor may accept such Modification on behalf of the Issuer, in which case the Administrative Supervisor will instruct the Issuer to provide the information required in subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Voting For each Issuer, any Qualifying Modification may be made with the affirmative vote of the holders of the right to vote at least two-thirds of the Outstanding Principal amount of the Outstanding Bonds in each Pool that have voted to approve or reject the Qualifying Modification, provided that holders of the right to vote not less than a majority of the aggregate Outstanding Principal amount of all the Outstanding Bonds in each Pool have voted to approve the Qualifying Modification. The holder of the right to vote the Outstanding Bonds that are Insured Bonds shall be the monoline insurer insuring such Insured Bond to the extent such insurer is granted the right to vote Insured Bonds for purposes of directing remedies or consenting to proposed amendments or modifications as provided in the applicable documents pursuant to which such Insured Bond was issued and insured.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>