<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/353a...362" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/353a...362/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/353a...362/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_353a___362"><akn:num>353a...362</akn:num><akn:heading>Transferred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 353a to 362. Transferred
Editorial Notes
Codification
Section 353a, act May 31, 1938, ch. 304, 52 Stat. 593, which authorized Secretary of the Interior to reserve tracts in Alaska for school, hospitals, etc. for the Indians, Eskimos, and Aleuts of Alaska, was transferred to section 497 of Title 25, Indians, and was subsequently repealed by Pub. L. 94–579, § 704(a), Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2792.
Section 354, act Mar. 4, 1915, ch. 181, § 2, 38 Stat. 1215, which set aside a site for an agricultural college and school of mines, is set out as note under section 852 of Title 43, Public Lands.
Section 354a, acts Jan. 21, 1929, ch. 92, §§ 1–7, 45 Stat. 1091–1093; July 12, 1960, Pub. L. 86–620, 74 Stat. 408, which made additional grants for an agricultural college and school of mines and imposed certain conditions and limitations, is set out as a note under section 852 of Title 43.
Section 355, act Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 561, § 11, 26 Stat. 1099, which permitted lands to be entered for town-site purposes and set out the requirements for the proper execution of the trust created thereby, was transferred to section 732 of Title 43, and was subsequently repealed by Pub. L. 94–579, § 703(a), Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2789.
Section 355a, act May 25, 1926, ch. 379, § 1, 44 Stat. 629, which authorized town-site trustee to issue a deed setting aside lands on survey of town site for Indian or Eskimo lands, was transferred to section 733 of Title 43, and was subsequently repealed by Pub. L. 94–579, § 703(a), Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2789.
Section 355b, act May 25, 1926, ch. 379, § 2, 44 Stat. 630, which authorized the extension of streets and alleys across Indian or Eskimo lands, was transferred to section 734, of Title 43, and was subsequently repealed by Pub. L. 94–579, § 703(a), Oct. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 2789.
Section 355c, act May 25, 1926, ch. 379, § 3, 44 Stat. 630, which authorized the Secretary of the Interior to have nonmineral lands surveyed into lots and blocks, was transferred to</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>