<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/485...486j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/485...486j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/485...486j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_485___486j"><akn:num>485...486j</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 485 to 486j. Omitted
Editorial Notes
Codification
Sections 485 to 486, relating to Territory of Alaska, were omitted in view of admission of Alaska into the Union.
Section 485, acts May 28, 1948, ch. 354, § 1, 62 Stat. 277; Aug. 23, 1958, Pub. L. 85–726, title XIV, § 1402(d)(1), 72 Stat. 807, authorized Administrator of Civil Aeronautics to construct, protect, operate, improve, and maintain within Territory of Alaska a public airport at or near Anchorage and a public airport at or near Fairbanks.
Section 485a, act May 28, 1948, ch. 354, § 2, 62 Stat. 278, authorized Administrator of Civil Aeronautics to acquire by purchase, lease, condemnation or otherwise such lands and appurtenances necessary for construction, protection, maintenance, improvement, and operation of said airports.
Section 485b, act May 28, 1948, ch. 354, § 3, 62 Stat. 278, authorized Administrator to acquire rights-of-way or easements for roads, trails, pipe lines, power lines and other similar facilities necessary for operation of airports, and to construct any public highways and bridge to whatever airport locations may be selected.
Section 485c, acts May 28, 1948, ch. 354, § 4, 62 Stat. 278; Aug. 23, 1958, Pub. L. 85–726, title XIV, § 1402(d)(2), 72 Stat. 807, set out powers and duties of Administrator.
Section 485d, acts May 28, 1948, ch. 354, § 5, 62 Stat. 278; Oct. 10, 1951, ch. 457, 65 Stat. 371; July 3, 1958, Pub. L. 85–503, 72 Stat. 321; Aug. 23, 1958, Pub. L. 85–726, title XIV, § 1402(d)(3), 72 Stat. 807, empowered Administrator of Federal Aviation Agency to lease space or property within or upon airports.
Section 485e, act May 28, 1948, ch. 354, § 6, 62 Stat. 278, authorized Administrator to contract with any person for performance of services at or upon airports.
Section 485f, acts May 28, 1948, ch. 354, § 7, 62 Stat. 278; Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 654, § 2(25), 65 Stat. 707, authorized transfer of lands, building, property or equipment by other agencies of Federal Government to Administrato</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>