<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/864" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/864/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/48/864/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_864"><akn:num>864</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals, certiorari, removal of causes, etc.; use of English language</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 864. Appeals, certiorari, removal of causes, etc.; use of English language
The laws of the United States relating to appeals, certiorari, removal of causes, and other matters or proceedings as between the courts of the United States and the courts of the several States shall govern in such matters and proceedings as between the United States District Court for the District of Puerto Rico and the courts of Puerto Rico.
All pleadings and proceedings in the United States District Court for the District of Puerto Rico shall be conducted in the English language.
(Apr. 12, 1900, ch. 191, § 35, 31 Stat. 85; Mar. 2, 1917, ch. 145, § 42, 39 Stat. 966; Feb. 13, 1925, ch. 229, § 13, 43 Stat. 942; Jan. 31, 1928, ch. 14, § 1, 45 Stat. 54; May 17, 1932, ch. 190, 47 Stat. 158; June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 21, 62 Stat. 990.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe laws of the United States relating to appeals, certiorari, removal of causes, and other matters or proceedings, referred to in text, are classified to Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.

Codification
“United States District Court for the District of Puerto Rico” substituted in text for “District Court of the United States for Puerto Rico” in view of section 132(a) of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure, which states that “There shall be in each judicial district a district court which shall be a court of record known as the United States District Court for the district” and section 119 of Title 28, which states that “Puerto Rico constitutes one judicial district.”

Prior ProvisionsAct Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 244, 36 Stat. 1157, related to direct appeals from The Supreme Court and the United District Court for Puerto Rico to the United States Supreme Court, prior to repeal by act Jan. 28, 1915, ch. 22, § 3, 38 Stat. 804.
Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in act Apr. 12, 1900, ch. 191, § 34, 31 Stat. 84.

Amendments1948—Act June 25, 1948, amended section generally, and struck out pro</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>