<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/1126" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/1126/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/1126/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1126"><akn:num>1126</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Management Improvement Officers and Program Management Policy Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1126. Program Management Improvement Officers and Program Management Policy Council(a) Program Management Improvement Officers.—(1) Designation.—The head of each agency described in section 901(b) shall designate a senior executive of the agency, who has significant program and project management oversight responsibilities, as the Program Management Improvement Officer of the agency.

(2) Functions.—The Program Management Improvement Officer of an agency designated under paragraph (1) shall—(A) implement program management policies established by the agency under section 503(c); and

(B) develop a strategy for enhancing the role of program managers within the agency that includes the following:(i) Enhanced training and educational opportunities for program managers that shall include—(I) training in the relevant competencies encompassed with program and project manager within the private sector for program managers; and

(II) training that emphasizes cost containment for large projects and programs.


(ii) Mentoring of current and future program managers by experienced senior executives and program managers within the agency.

(iii) Improved career paths and career opportunities for program managers.

(iv) A plan to encourage the recruitment and retention of highly qualified individuals to serve as program managers.

(v) Improved means of collecting and disseminating best practices and lessons learned to enhance program management across the agency.

(vi) Common templates and tools to support improved data gathering and analysis for program management and oversight purposes.



(3) Application to department of defense.—This subsection shall not apply to the Department of Defense to the extent that the provisions of this subsection are substantially similar to or duplicative of the provisions of chapter 87 of title 10. For purposes of paragraph (1), the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment (or a designee of the Under Secretary) shall be consid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1126_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Management Improvement Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1126_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Management Policy Council.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>