<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/1306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/1306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/1306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1306"><akn:num>1306</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of foreign credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1306. Use of foreign credits(a) In General.—Foreign credits (including currencies) owed to or owned by the United States may be used by any agency for any purpose for which appropriations are made for the agency for the current fiscal year (including the carrying out of Acts requiring or authorizing the use of such credits), but only when reimbursement therefor is made to the Treasury from applicable appropriations of the agency.

(b) Exception to Reimbursement Requirement.—Credits described in subsection (a) that are received as exchanged allowances, or as the proceeds of the sale of personal property, may be used in whole or partial payment for the acquisition of similar items, to the extent and in the manner authorized by law, without reimbursement to the Treasury.

(Pub. L. 97–258, Sept. 13, 1982, 96 Stat. 918; Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 612(a)], Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–314, 3009–355.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised SectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


130631:724.July 15, 1952, ch. 758, § 1415, 66 Stat. 662.


The words “are not available for expenditure by agencies except as provided annually in general appropriation laws” are substituted for “will not be available for expenditure by agencies of the United States after June 30, 1953, except as may be provided for annually in appropriation Acts” because of section 101 of the revised title.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–208 reenacted section catchline without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Foreign credits owed to or owned by the Treasury are not available for expenditure by agencies except as provided annually in general appropriation laws.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1996 AmendmentPub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(f) [title VI, § 612(b)], Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–314, 3009–356, provided that: “The amendment made by this section [amend</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Foreign credits (including currencies) owed to or owned by the United States may be used by any agency for any purpose for which appropriations are made for the agency for the current fiscal year (including the carrying out of Acts requiring or authorizing the use of such credits), but only when reimbursement therefor is made to the Treasury from applicable appropriations of the agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception to Reimbursement Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Credits described in subsection (a) that are received as exchanged allowances, or as the proceeds of the sale of personal property, may be used in whole or partial payment for the acquisition of similar items, to the extent and in the manner authorized by law, without reimbursement to the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>