<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/1351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/1351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/1351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1351"><akn:num>1351</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports on violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1351. Reports on violations
If an officer or employee of an executive agency or an officer or employee of the District of Columbia government violates section 1341(a) or 1342 of this title, the head of the agency or the Mayor of the District of Columbia, as the case may be, shall report immediately to the President and Congress all relevant facts and a statement of actions taken. A copy of each report shall also be transmitted to the Comptroller General on the same date the report is transmitted to the President and Congress.
(Pub. L. 97–258, Sept. 13, 1982, 96 Stat. 926; Pub. L. 108–447, div. G, title I, § 1401(a), Dec. 8, 2004, 118 Stat. 3192.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised SectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


135131:665(i)(2)(related to (a), (b)).R.S. § 3679(i)(2)(related to (a), (b)); Mar. 3, 1905, ch. 1404, § 4(1st par.), 33 Stat. 1257; Feb. 27, 1906, ch. 510, § 3, 34 Stat. 48; restated Sept. 6, 1950, ch. 896, § 1211, 64 Stat. 768.


The words “executive agency” are substituted for “agency” because the definition of “agency” in 31:665(d)(2) applies to the source provisions restated in the section and because of section 102 of the revised title. The word “Mayor” is used because of Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1967 (eff. Aug. 11, 1967, 81 Stat. 948) and sections 421, 422, and 771 of the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act (Pub. L. 93–198, 87 Stat. 789, 818). The word “President” is substituted for “President, through the Director of the Office of Management and Budget” because sections 101 and 102(a) of Reorganization Plan No. 2 of 1970 (eff. July 1, 1970, 84 Stat. 2085) designated the Bureau of the Budget as the Office of Management and Budget and transferred all functions of the Bureau to the President.

Editorial Notes
Amendments2004—Pub. L. 108–447 inserted at end “A copy of each report shall also be transmitted to the Comptroller General on the same date the report is transmitted to</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>