<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/312" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/312/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/312/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_312"><akn:num>312</akn:num><akn:heading>Terrorism and financial intelligence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 312. Terrorism and financial intelligence(a) Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence.—(1) Establishment.—There is established within the Department of the Treasury the Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence (in this section referred to as “OTFI”), which shall be the successor to any such office in existence on the date of enactment of this section.

(2) Leadership.—(A) Undersecretary.—There is established within the Department of the Treasury, the Office of the Undersecretary for Terrorism and Financial Crimes, who shall serve as the head of the OTFI, and shall report to the Secretary of the Treasury through the Deputy Secretary of the Treasury. The Office of the Undersecretary for Terrorism and Financial Crimes shall be the successor to the Office of the Undersecretary for Enforcement.

(B) Appointment.—The Undersecretary for Terrorism and Financial Crimes shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(3) Assistant secretary for terrorist financing.—(A) Establishment.—There is established within the OTFI the position of Assistant Secretary for Terrorist Financing.

(B) Appointment.—The Assistant Secretary for Terrorist Financing shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.

(C) Duties.—The Assistant Secretary for Terrorist Financing shall be responsible for formulating and coordinating the counter terrorist financing and anti-money laundering efforts of the Department of the Treasury, and shall report directly to the Undersecretary for Terrorism and Financial Crimes.


(4) Functions.—The functions of the OTFI include providing policy, strategic, and operational direction to the Department on issues relating to—(A) implementation of titles I and II of the Bank Secrecy Act;

(B) United States economic sanctions programs;

(C) combating terrorist financing;

(D) combating financial crimes, including money laundering, counterfeiting, and other offenses threatening the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Intelligence and Analysis.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To the extent that any authorities, powers, and responsibilities over enforcement matters delegated to the Undersecretary for Terrorism and Financial Crimes, or the positions of Assistant Secretary for Terrorism and Financial Crimes, Assistant Secretary for Enforcement and Operations, or Deputy Assistant Secretary for Terrorist Financing and Financial Crimes, have not been transferred to the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, or the Assistant Secretary for Tax Policy (related to the customs revenue functions of the Bureau of Alcohol and Tobacco Tax and Trade), those remaining authorities, powers, and responsibilities are delegated to the Undersecretary for Terrorism and Financial Crimes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation as Enforcement Organization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence (including any components thereof) is designated as a law enforcement organization of the Department of the Treasury for purposes of section 9705 of title 31, United States Code, and other relevant authorities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Existing Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may employ personnel, facilities, and other Department of the Treasury resources available to the Secretary on the date of enactment of this section in carrying out this section, except as otherwise prohibited by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>References.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) References in this section to the “Secretary”, “Undersecretary”, “Deputy Secretary”, “Deputy Assistant Secretary”, “Office”, “Assistant Secretary”, and “Department” are references to positions and offices of the Department of the Treasury, unless otherwise specified.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Hiring Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_312_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deployment of Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of the Treasury may detail, without regard to the provisions of section 300.301 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, any employee in the OTFI to any position in the OTFI for which the Secretary has determined there is a need.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>