<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/333" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/333/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/333/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_333"><akn:num>333</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of misuse of Department of the Treasury names, symbols, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 333. Prohibition of misuse of Department of the Treasury names, symbols, etc.(a) General Rule.—No person may use, in connection with, or as a part of, any advertisement, solicitation, business activity, or product, whether alone or with other words, letters, symbols, or emblems—(1) the words “Department of the Treasury”, or the name of any service, bureau, office, or other subdivision of the Department of the Treasury,

(2) the titles “Secretary of the Treasury” or “Treasurer of the United States” or the title of any other officer or employee of the Department of the Treasury,

(3) the abbreviations or initials of any entity referred to in paragraph (1),

(4) the words “United States Savings Bond” or the name of any other obligation issued by the Department of the Treasury,

(5) any symbol or emblem of an entity referred to in paragraph (1) (including the design of any envelope or stationary used by such an entity), and

(6) any colorable imitation of any such words, titles, abbreviations, initials, symbols, or emblems,


in a manner which could reasonably be interpreted or construed as conveying the false impression that such advertisement, solicitation, business activity, or product is in any manner approved, endorsed, sponsored, or authorized by, or associated with, the Department of the Treasury or any entity referred to in paragraph (1) or any officer or employee thereof.

(b) Treatment of Disclaimers.—Any determination of whether a person has violated the provisions of subsection (a) shall be made without regard to any use of a disclaimer of affiliation with the United States Government or any particular agency or instrumentality thereof.

(c) Civil Penalty.—(1) In general.—The Secretary of the Treasury may impose a civil penalty on any person who violates the provisions of subsection (a).

(2) Amount of penalty.—The amount of the civil penalty imposed by paragraph (1) shall not exceed $5,000 for each use of any material in violation of subsection (a). If su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Rule.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) No person may use, in connection with, or as a part of, any advertisement, solicitation, business activity, or product, whether alone or with other words, letters, symbols, or emblems— in a manner which could reasonably be interpreted or construed as conveying the false impression that such advertisement, solicitation, business activity, or product is in any manner approved, endorsed, sponsored, or authorized by, or associated with, the Department of the Treasury or any entity referred to in paragraph (1) or any officer or employee thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Disclaimers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any determination of whether a person has violated the provisions of subsection (a) shall be made without regard to any use of a disclaimer of affiliation with the United States Government or any particular agency or instrumentality thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Penalty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal Penalty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>