<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/3730" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/3730/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/3730/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3730"><akn:num>3730</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions for false claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3730. Civil actions for false claims(a) Responsibilities of the Attorney General.—The Attorney General diligently shall investigate a violation under section 3729. If the Attorney General finds that a person has violated or is violating section 3729, the Attorney General may bring a civil action under this section against the person.

(b) Actions by Private Persons.—(1) A person may bring a civil action for a violation of section 3729 for the person and for the United States Government. The action shall be brought in the name of the Government. The action may be dismissed only if the court and the Attorney General give written consent to the dismissal and their reasons for consenting.

(2) A copy of the complaint and written disclosure of substantially all material evidence and information the person possesses shall be served on the Government pursuant to Rule 4(d)(4) 11 So in original. Probably should be a reference to Rule 4(i). of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure. The complaint shall be filed in camera, shall remain under seal for at least 60 days, and shall not be served on the defendant until the court so orders. The Government may elect to intervene and proceed with the action within 60 days after it receives both the complaint and the material evidence and information.

(3) The Government may, for good cause shown, move the court for extensions of the time during which the complaint remains under seal under paragraph (2). Any such motions may be supported by affidavits or other submissions in camera. The defendant shall not be required to respond to any complaint filed under this section until 20 days after the complaint is unsealed and served upon the defendant pursuant to Rule 4 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.

(4) Before the expiration of the 60-day period or any extensions obtained under paragraph (3), the Government shall—(A) proceed with the action, in which case the action shall be conducted by the Government; or

(B) notify the court th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3730_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of the Attorney General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Attorney General diligently shall investigate a violation under section 3729. If the Attorney General finds that a person has violated or is violating section 3729, the Attorney General may bring a civil action under this section against the person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3730_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by Private Persons.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3730_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of the Parties to Qui Tam Actions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3730_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award to Qui Tam Plaintiff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3730_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Actions Barred.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3730_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government Not Liable for Certain Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Government is not liable for expenses which a person incurs in bringing an action under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3730_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and Expenses to Prevailing Defendant.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In civil actions brought under this section by the United States, the provisions of section 2412(d) of title 28 shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3730_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relief From Retaliatory Actions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>