<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6102"><akn:num>6102</akn:num><akn:heading>Program information requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6102. Program information requirements(a) The Director shall collect and review information on domestic assistance programs and shall provide such information to the Administrator. The information on each domestic assistance program shall include the following:(1) identification of the program by—(A) title;

(B) authorizing law;

(C) administering office; and

(D) an identifying number assigned by the Director.


(2) a description of the—(A) program;

(B) objectives of the program;

(C) types of activities financed under the program;

(D) eligibility requirements;

(E) types of assistance;

(F) uses, and restrictions on the use, of assistance;

(G) uses of core-based statistical area (as defined in section 4 of the MAPS Act of 2021) delineations (as chosen from standardized categories of uses determined by the Director), for purposes including prime recipient and subrecipient eligibility for, and distribution of, any Federal service, benefit, or funding; and

(H) duties of recipients under the program.


(3) a specification of each formula governing eligibility for assistance or the distribution of assistance under the program, which shall be described through the use of—(A) the language used to specify each such formula in the law authorizing the program;

(B) the language used to specify each such formula in any Federal rule promulgated pursuant to the law authorizing the program; or

(C) a mathematical statement which is derived from the language referred to in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of this paragraph;


(4) a description of all data and statistical estimates used to carry out each formula specified pursuant to paragraph (3), and an identification of the sources of such data and estimates;

(5) financial information, including the—(A) amounts appropriated for the current fiscal year or, if unavailable, the amounts requested by the President and the amounts obligated; and

(B) average amounts of awards made in past years.


(6) identification of information c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Director shall collect and review information on domestic assistance programs and shall provide such information to the Administrator. The information on each domestic assistance program shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) On request of the Director, an agency shall give to the Director current information on all domestic assistance programs administered by the agency. The Director shall be responsible for ensuring that the Administrator incorporates all relevant information received on a regular basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>