<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6507" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6507/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6507/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6507"><akn:num>6507</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional review of grant programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6507. Congressional review of grant programs(a) The committees of Congress having jurisdiction over a grant program authorized by a law of the United States without a specified expiration date for the program shall study the program. The committees may conduct studies separately or jointly and shall report the results of their findings to their respective Houses of Congress not later than the end of each period specified in subsection (b) of this section. The committees shall give special attention to—(1) the extent to which the purposes of the grants have been met;

(2) the extent to which the objective of the program can be carried on without further assistance;

(3) whether a change in the purpose, direction, or administration of the original program, or in procedures and requirements applicable to the program, should be made; and

(4) the extent to which the program is adequate to meet the growing and changing needs that it was designed to support.


(b)(1) A study under subsection (a) of this section of a grant program authorized by a law of the United States enacted before October 16, 1968, shall be conducted before the end of each 4th calendar year after the year during which a study of the program was last conducted under this section.

(2) A study under subsection (a) of this section of a grant program authorized by a law of the United States enacted after October 16, 1968, shall be conducted before the end of the 4th calendar year after the year of enactment of the law and before the end of each 4th calendar year thereafter.


(Pub. L. 97–258, Sept. 13, 1982, 96 Stat. 1009.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised SectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


6507(a)42:4241(a).Oct. 16, 1968, Pub. L. 90–577, § 601, 82 Stat. 1106.
6507(b)42:4241(b).


In the section, the words “law of the United States” are substituted for “Act of Congress” for clarity. The word “grants” is substituted for “grants-in-aid”, and the words “grant program” a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6507_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The committees of Congress having jurisdiction over a grant program authorized by a law of the United States without a specified expiration date for the program shall study the program. The committees may conduct studies separately or jointly and shall report the results of their findings to their respective Houses of Congress not later than the end of each period specified in subsection (b) of this section. The committees shall give special attention to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6507_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>