<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6701"><akn:num>6701</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to local governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6701. Payments to local governments(a) Payment and Use.—(1) Payment.—The Secretary shall pay to each unit of general local government which qualifies for a payment under this chapter an amount equal to the sum of any amounts allocated to the government under this chapter for each payment period. The Secretary shall pay such amount out of the Local Government Fiscal Assistance Fund under section 6702.

(2) Use.—Amounts paid to a unit of general local government under this section shall be used by that unit for carrying out one or more programs of the unit related to—(A) education to prevent crime;

(B) substance abuse treatment to prevent crime; or

(C) job programs to prevent crime.


(3) Coordination.—Programs funded under this title shall be coordinated with other existing Federal programs to meet the overall needs of communities that benefit from funds received under this section.


(b) Timing of Payments.—The Secretary shall pay each amount allocated under this chapter to a unit of general local government for a payment period by the later of 90 days after the date the amount is available or the first day of the payment period provided that the unit of general local government has provided the Secretary with the assurances required by section 6703(d).

(c) Adjustments.—(1) In general.—Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall adjust a payment under this chapter to a unit of general local government to the extent that a prior payment to the government was more or less than the amount required to be paid.

(2) Considerations.—The Secretary may increase or decrease under this subsection a payment to a unit of local government only if the Secretary determines the need for the increase or decrease, or the unit requests the increase or decrease, within one year after the end of the payment period for which the payment was made.


(d) Reservation for Adjustments.—The Secretary may reserve a percentage of not more than 2 percent of the amount under this section fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment and Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall pay each amount allocated under this chapter to a unit of general local government for a payment period by the later of 90 days after the date the amount is available or the first day of the payment period provided that the unit of general local government has provided the Secretary with the assurances required by section 6703(d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation for Adjustments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may reserve a percentage of not more than 2 percent of the amount under this section for a payment period for all units of general local government in a State if the Secretary considers the reserve is necessary to ensure the availability of sufficient amounts to pay adjustments after the final allocation of amounts among the units of general local government in the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment of Unexpended Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditure With Disadvantaged Business Enterprises.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6701_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonsupplanting Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>