<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6713" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6713/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/6713/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6713"><akn:num>6713</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension and termination of payments in discrimination proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6713. Suspension and termination of payments in discrimination proceedings(a) Imposition and Continuation of Suspensions.—(1) In general.—The Secretary shall suspend payment under this chapter to a unit of general local government—(A) if an administrative law judge appointed under section 3105 of title 5, United States Code, issues a preliminary decision in a proceeding under section 6712(d)(1) that the government is not likely to prevail in showing compliance with section 6711(a) and (b);

(B) if the administrative law judge decides at the end of the proceeding that the government has not complied with section 6711(a) or (b), unless the government makes a compliance agreement under section 6714 by the 30th day after the decision; or

(C) if required under section 6712(c).


(2) Effectiveness.—A suspension already ordered under paragraph (1)(A) continues in effect if the administrative law judge makes a decision under paragraph (1)(B).


(b) Lifting of Suspensions and Terminations.—If a holding of discrimination is reversed by an appellate court, a suspension or termination of payments in a proceeding based on the holding shall be discontinued.

(c) Resumption of Payments Upon Attaining Compliance.—The Secretary may resume payment to a unit of general local government of payments suspended by the Secretary only—(1) as of the time of, and under the conditions stated in—(A) the approval by the Secretary of a compliance agreement under section 6714(a)(1); or

(B) a compliance agreement entered into by the Secretary under section 6714(a)(2);


(2) if the government complies completely with an order of a United States court, a State court, or administrative law judge that covers all matters raised in a notice of noncompliance submitted by the Secretary under section 6712(a);

(3) if a United States court, a State court, or an administrative law judge decides (including a judge in a proceeding under section 6712(d)(1)), that the government has complied with sections 11 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6713_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition and Continuation of Suspensions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6713_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lifting of Suspensions and Terminations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If a holding of discrimination is reversed by an appellate court, a suspension or termination of payments in a proceeding based on the holding shall be discontinued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6713_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resumption of Payments Upon Attaining Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may resume payment to a unit of general local government of payments suspended by the Secretary only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6713_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Damages as Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For purposes of subsection (c)(2), compliance by a government may consist of the payment of restitution to a person injured because the government did not comply with section 6711(a) or (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6713_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resumption of Payments Upon Reversal by Court.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may resume payment to a unit of general local government of payments terminated under section 6712(d)(2)(A) only if the decision resulting in the termination is reversed by an appellate court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>