<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/9705" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/9705/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/31/9705/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9705"><akn:num>9705</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9705. Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund(a) In General.—There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund” (referred to in this section as the “Fund”). The Fund shall be available to the Secretary, without fiscal year limitation, with respect to seizures and forfeitures made pursuant to any law (other than section 7301 or 7302 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) enforced or administered by the Department of the Treasury or the United States Coast Guard for the following law enforcement purposes:(1)(A) Payment of all proper expenses of seizure (including investigative costs incurred by a Department of the Treasury law enforcement organization leading to seizure) or the proceedings of forfeiture and sale, including the expenses of detention, inventory, security, maintenance, advertisement, or disposal of the property, and if condemned by a court and a bond for such costs was not given, the costs as taxed by the court.

(B) Payment for—(i) contract services;

(ii) the employment of outside contractors to operate and manage properties or to provide other specialized services necessary to dispose of such properties in an effort to maximize the return from such properties; and

(iii) reimbursing any Federal, State, or local agency for any expenditures made to perform the functions described in this subparagraph.


(C) Awards of compensation to informers under section 619 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (19 U.S.C. 1619).

(D) Satisfaction of—(i) liens for freight, charges, and contributions in general average, notice of which has been filed with the appropriate Customs officer according to law; and

(ii) subject to the discretion of the Secretary, other valid liens and mortgages against property that has been forfeited pursuant to any law enforced or administered by a Department of the Treasury law enforcement organization. To determine the validity of any such lien or mortgage, the amount </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund” (referred to in this section as the “Fund”). The Fund shall be available to the Secretary, without fiscal year limitation, with respect to seizures and forfeitures made pursuant to any law (other than section 7301 or 7302 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) enforced or administered by the Department of the Treasury or the United States Coast Guard for the following law enforcement purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds Available to United States Coast Guard.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits and Credits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amounts in the Fund, and in any holding accounts associated with the Fund, which are not currently needed for the purposes of this section may be kept on deposit or invested in obligations of, or guaranteed by, the United States and all earnings on such investments shall be deposited in the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall transmit to the Congress, not later than February 1 of each year— The Fund shall be subject to annual financial audits as authorized in the Chief Financial Officers Act of 1990 (Public Law 101–576).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention or Transfer of Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary may prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9705_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customs Forfeiture Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>