<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/11/101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/11/101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/11/101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_101"><akn:num>101</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 101. Definitions
In this title the following definitions shall apply:(1) The term “accountant” means accountant authorized under applicable law to practice public accounting, and includes professional accounting association, corporation, or partnership, if so authorized.

(2) The term “affiliate” means—(A) entity that directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds with power to vote, 20 percent or more of the outstanding voting securities of the debtor, other than an entity that holds such securities—(i) in a fiduciary or agency capacity without sole discretionary power to vote such securities; or

(ii) solely to secure a debt, if such entity has not in fact exercised such power to vote;


(B) corporation 20 percent or more of whose outstanding voting securities are directly or indirectly owned, controlled, or held with power to vote, by the debtor, or by an entity that directly or indirectly owns, controls, or holds with power to vote, 20 percent or more of the outstanding voting securities of the debtor, other than an entity that holds such securities—(i) in a fiduciary or agency capacity without sole discretionary power to vote such securities; or

(ii) solely to secure a debt, if such entity has not in fact exercised such power to vote;


(C) person whose business is operated under a lease or operating agreement by a debtor, or person substantially all of whose property is operated under an operating agreement with the debtor; or

(D) entity that operates the business or substantially all of the property of the debtor under a lease or operating agreement.


(3) The term “assisted person” means any person whose debts consist primarily of consumer debts and the value of whose nonexempt property is less than $150,000.11 See Adjustment of Dollar Amounts notes below.

(4) The term “attorney” means attorney, professional law association, corporation, or partnership, authorized under applicable law to practice law.

(4A) The term “bankruptcy assistance” means any go</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “accountant” means accountant authorized under applicable law to practice public accounting, and includes professional accounting association, corporation, or partnership, if so authorized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “affiliate” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “assisted person” means any person whose debts consist primarily of consumer debts and the value of whose nonexempt property is less than $150,000.11 See Adjustment of Dollar Amounts notes below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “attorney” means attorney, professional law association, corporation, or partnership, authorized under applicable law to practice law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_4A"><akn:num>(4A)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4A) The term “bankruptcy assistance” means any goods or services sold or otherwise provided to an assisted person with the express or implied purpose of providing information, advice, counsel, document preparation, or filing, or attendance at a creditors’ meeting or appearing in a case or proceeding on behalf of another or providing legal representation with respect to a case or proceeding under this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “claim” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “commodity broker” means futures commission merchant, foreign futures commission merchant, clearing organization, leverage transaction merchant, or commodity options dealer, as defined in section 761 of this title, with respect to which there is a customer, as defined in section 761 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “community claim” means claim that arose before the commencement of the case concerning the debtor for which property of the kind specified in section 541(a)(2) of this title is liable, whether or not there is any such property at the time of the commencement of the case.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_7A"><akn:num>(7A)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7A) The term “commercial fishing operation” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_101_7B"><akn:num>(7B)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7B) The term “commercial fishing vessel” means a vessel used by a family fisherman to carry out a commercial fishing operation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>