<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/11/930" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/11/930/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/11/930/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_930"><akn:num>930</akn:num><akn:heading>Dismissal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 930. Dismissal(a) After notice and a hearing, the court may dismiss a case under this chapter for cause, including—(1) want of prosecution;

(2) unreasonable delay by the debtor that is prejudicial to creditors;

(3) failure to propose a plan within the time fixed under section 941 of this title;

(4) if a plan is not accepted within any time fixed by the court;

(5) denial of confirmation of a plan under section 943(b) of this title and denial of additional time for filing another plan or a modification of a plan; or

(6) if the court has retained jurisdiction after confirmation of a plan—(A) material default by the debtor with respect to a term of such plan; or

(B) termination of such plan by reason of the occurrence of a condition specified in such plan.



(b) The court shall dismiss a case under this chapter if confirmation of a plan under this chapter is refused.

(Pub. L. 95–598, Nov. 6, 1978, 92 Stat. 2623, § 927; Pub. L. 98–353, title III, § 496, July 10, 1984, 98 Stat. 384; renumbered § 930, Pub. L. 100–597, § 7(1), Nov. 3, 1988, 102 Stat. 3029.)

Historical and Revision Notes
legislative statementsSection 927(b) of the House amendment is derived from section 927(b) of the Senate bill. The provision requires mandatory dismissal if confirmation of a plan is refused.
The House amendment deletes section 929 of the Senate amendment as unnecessary since the bankruptcy court has original exclusive jurisdiction of all cases under chapter 9.
The House amendment deletes section 930 of the Senate amendment and incorporates section 507(a)(1) by reference.

senate report no. 95–989Section 927 conforms to section 98 of current law [section 418 of former title 11]. The Section permits dismissal by the court for unreasonable delay by the debtor, failure to propose a plan, failure of acceptance of a plan, or default by the debtor under a conformed plan. Mandatory dismissal is required if confirmation is refused.

house report no. 95–595Section 926 [enacted as section 9</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_930_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) After notice and a hearing, the court may dismiss a case under this chapter for cause, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_930_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The court shall dismiss a case under this chapter if confirmation of a plan under this chapter is refused.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>