<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_106"><akn:num>106</akn:num><akn:heading>Constitution Day and Citizenship Day</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 106. Constitution Day and Citizenship Day(a) Designation.—September 17 is designated as Constitution Day and Citizenship Day.

(b) Purpose.—Constitution Day and Citizenship Day commemorate the formation and signing on September 17, 1787, of the Constitution and recognize all who, by coming of age or by naturalization, have become citizens.

(c) Proclamation.—The President may issue each year a proclamation calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on Constitution Day and Citizenship Day and inviting the people of the United States to observe Constitution Day and Citizenship Day, in schools and churches, or other suitable places, with appropriate ceremonies.

(d) State and Local Observances.—The civil and educational authorities of States, counties, cities, and towns are urged to make plans for the proper observance of Constitution Day and Citizenship Day and for the complete instruction of citizens in their responsibilities and opportunities as citizens of the United States and of the State and locality in which they reside.

(Pub. L. 105–225, Aug. 12, 1998, 112 Stat. 1255; Pub. L. 108–447, div. J, title I, § 111(c)(1), Dec. 8, 2004, 118 Stat. 3344.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


106(a)36:153 (1st par. 1st–13th words).Feb. 29, 1952, ch. 49, § 1, 66 Stat. 9.
106(b)36:153 (1st par. 14th word–words before “and the President”). 
106(c)36:153 (1st par. words after “of citizenship”). 
106(d)36:153 (2d, last pars.). 


In subsection (d), the text of 36:153 (last par.) is omitted as obsolete.

Editorial Notes
Amendments2004—Pub. L. 108–447, § 111(c)(1)(A), inserted “Constitution Day and” before “Citizenship Day” in section catchline.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 108–447, § 111(c)(1)(B), substituted “is designated as Constitution Day and Citizenship Day” for “is Citizenship Day”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 108–447, § 111(c)(1)(C), inserted “C</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) September 17 is designated as Constitution Day and Citizenship Day.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Constitution Day and Citizenship Day commemorate the formation and signing on September 17, 1787, of the Constitution and recognize all who, by coming of age or by naturalization, have become citizens.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proclamation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The President may issue each year a proclamation calling on United States Government officials to display the flag of the United States on all Government buildings on Constitution Day and Citizenship Day and inviting the people of the United States to observe Constitution Day and Citizenship Day, in schools and churches, or other suitable places, with appropriate ceremonies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and Local Observances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The civil and educational authorities of States, counties, cities, and towns are urged to make plans for the proper observance of Constitution Day and Citizenship Day and for the complete instruction of citizens in their responsibilities and opportunities as citizens of the United States and of the State and locality in which they reside.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>