<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/130302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/130302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/130302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_130302"><akn:num>130302</akn:num><akn:heading>Principles and purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 130302. Principles and purposes(a) Principles.—The principles underlying the corporation are patriotic allegiance to the United States of America, fidelity to the constitution and laws of the United States, the security of civil liberty, and the permanence of free institutions.

(b) Purposes.—The purposes of the corporation are—(1) to cherish the memories of the valiant deeds in arms for which the Congressional Medal of Honor, the Distinguished Service Cross, the Navy Cross, and the Air Force Cross are the insignia;

(2) to promote true fellowship among its members;

(3) to advance the best interests of members of the Armed Forces of the United States of America;

(4) to extend all possible relief to needy members of the corporation and their widows and children; and

(5) to stimulate patriotism in the minds of our youth by encouraging the study of the patriotic, military, and naval history of our Nation.


(Pub. L. 105–225, Aug. 12, 1998, 112 Stat. 1374.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


13030236:633.Aug. 4, 1955, ch. 546, § 3, 69 Stat. 487; June 21, 1961, Pub. L. 87–56, § 2, 75 Stat. 95.


In subsection (b), the word “purposes” is substituted for “objects” for consistency in the revised title. The words “Navy Cross” are restated before “Air Force Cross” in accordance with the order preferred by the Legion of Valor of the United States of America, Incorporated.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_130302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The principles underlying the corporation are patriotic allegiance to the United States of America, fidelity to the constitution and laws of the United States, the security of civil liberty, and the permanence of free institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_130302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The purposes of the corporation are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>