<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/150704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/150704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/150704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_150704"><akn:num>150704</akn:num><akn:heading>National officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 150704. National officers(a) National Officers.—The national officers of the corporation are a president, a first vice president, a second vice president, a third vice president, a secretary, and a treasurer. The president is chairman of the board of directors and of the executive committee described in section 150705(d) of this title.

(b) Election.—The national officers are elected biennially from among the officers and members of the member agencies and organizations participating in the annual national conference on citizenship, by a majority vote of the agencies and organizations sending delegates to, and participating in, the conference.

(Pub. L. 105–225, Aug. 12, 1998, 112 Stat. 1392.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


15070436:437.Aug. 13, 1953, ch. 427, § 7, 67 Stat. 563.


In subsection (b), the words “For the purposes of initiating the corporation, the national officers shall be elected within ten days of August 13, 1953, by the persons named in section 431 of this title, to serve until the final session of the next following annual conference. Thereafter” are omitted as obsolete. The words “one vote to each such agency and to each such organization” are omitted because section 150703(b) of the revised title already states that each of those agencies and organizations has one vote.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_150704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The national officers of the corporation are a president, a first vice president, a second vice president, a third vice president, a secretary, and a treasurer. The president is chairman of the board of directors and of the executive committee described in section 150705(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_150704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The national officers are elected biennially from among the officers and members of the member agencies and organizations participating in the annual national conference on citizenship, by a majority vote of the agencies and organizations sending delegates to, and participating in, the conference.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>