<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/170507" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/170507/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/170507/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_170507"><akn:num>170507</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 170507. Restrictions(a) Stock and Dividends.—The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.

(b) Political Activities.—The corporation or a director or officer as such may not contribute to, support, or participate in any political activity or in any manner attempt to influence legislation.

(c) Distribution of Income or Assets.—The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a director, officer, or member during the life of the charter granted by this chapter. This subsection does not prevent the payment of reasonable compensation to an officer or reimbursement for actual necessary expenses in amounts approved by the board of directors.

(d) Loans.—The corporation may not make a loan to a director, officer, or employee.

(e) Claim of Governmental Approval or Authorization.—The corporation may not claim congressional approval or the authority of the United States Government for any of its activities.

(Pub. L. 105–225, Aug. 12, 1998, 112 Stat. 1445.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


170507(a)36:2508(d).July 23, 1984, Pub. L. 98–372, § 8, 98 Stat. 1240.
170507(b)36:2508(c). 
170507(c)36:2508(a). 
170507(d)36:2508(b). 
170507(e)36:2508(e). 


In subsection (a), the words “any shares of” are omitted as unnecessary.
In subsection (c), the words “inure to the benefit of” are substituted for “inure to” for consistency in the revised title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170507_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stock and Dividends.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The corporation may not issue stock or declare or pay a dividend.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170507_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Political Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The corporation or a director or officer as such may not contribute to, support, or participate in any political activity or in any manner attempt to influence legislation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170507_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of Income or Assets.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The income or assets of the corporation may not inure to the benefit of, or be distributed to, a director, officer, or member during the life of the charter granted by this chapter. This subsection does not prevent the payment of reasonable compensation to an officer or reimbursement for actual necessary expenses in amounts approved by the board of directors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170507_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The corporation may not make a loan to a director, officer, or employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_170507_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claim of Governmental Approval or Authorization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The corporation may not claim congressional approval or the authority of the United States Government for any of its activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>