<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/2102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/2102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/2102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2102"><akn:num>2102</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2102. Employment of personnel(a) General.—Within the limits of an appropriation made to employ personnel, the American Battle Monuments Commission may employ personnel necessary to carry out this chapter. To ensure adequate care and maintenance of cemeteries, monuments, and memorials, the Commission, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall employ—(1) at least 50 individuals in the competitive service (as defined in section 2102 of title 5), of whom at least 43 shall be assigned to duty in foreign countries where the cemeteries, monuments, and memorials are located; and

(2) at least 348 individuals who are citizens of the countries where the cemeteries, monuments, and memorials are located.


(b) Detailed Personnel.—On request of the Commission, the heads of departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government may make available to the Commission their personnel and facilities to assist in carrying out this chapter, and may expend for that purpose amounts appropriated to the department, agency, and instrumentality. The Commission shall reimburse the department, agency, or instrumentality for the pay and allowances of personnel made available to the Commission.

(c) Station Allowance for Officers Assigned to the Commission.—For officers of the Armed Forces assigned to the Commission, the same station allowance shall be authorized for serving at foreign stations as the Secretary of the Army has authorized for officers of the Army.

(d) Citizenship Requirement.—An individual may be employed as the superintendent, or as an assistant superintendent, of a cemetery operated by the Commission only if the individual is a citizen of the United States.

(Pub. L. 105–225, Aug. 12, 1998, 112 Stat. 1269; Pub. L. 105–354, § 1(2), Nov. 3, 1998, 112 Stat. 3239; Pub. L. 106–117, title VI, § 604(2), Nov. 30, 1999, 113 Stat. 1580.)











Historical and Revision Notes



Pub. L. 105–225


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Lar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Within the limits of an appropriation made to employ personnel, the American Battle Monuments Commission may employ personnel necessary to carry out this chapter. To ensure adequate care and maintenance of cemeteries, monuments, and memorials, the Commission, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall employ—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detailed Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) On request of the Commission, the heads of departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government may make available to the Commission their personnel and facilities to assist in carrying out this chapter, and may expend for that purpose amounts appropriated to the department, agency, and instrumentality. The Commission shall reimburse the department, agency, or instrumentality for the pay and allowances of personnel made available to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Station Allowance for Officers Assigned to the Commission.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) For officers of the Armed Forces assigned to the Commission, the same station allowance shall be authorized for serving at foreign stations as the Secretary of the Army has authorized for officers of the Army.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizenship Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An individual may be employed as the superintendent, or as an assistant superintendent, of a cemetery operated by the Commission only if the individual is a citizen of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>