<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/2106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/2106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/2106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2106"><akn:num>2106</akn:num><akn:heading>War memorials not built by the United States Government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2106. War memorials not built by the United States Government(a) Cooperation With Others.—The American Battle Monuments Commission may cooperate with citizens of the United States, States, municipalities, or associations desiring to build war memorials outside the continental limits of the United States in the way the Commission decides. An administrative agency of the United States Government may give assistance to build the memorial only if a plan for the memorial has been approved under this chapter.

(b) Control, Administration, and Maintenance of War Memorials.—(1) The Commission may assume responsibility for the control, administration, and maintenance of any war memorial built outside the United States by a citizen of the United States, a State, a political subdivision of a State, a governmental authority (except a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government), a foreign agency, or a private association to commemorate the services of any of the Armed Forces in hostilities occurring since April 6, 1917, if—(A) the memorial is not built on the territory of the applicable former enemy; and

(B) the sponsors of the memorial consent to the Commission assuming those responsibilities and transfer to the Commission all their rights and interests in the memorial.


(2) If reasonable effort fails to locate the sponsors of a memorial, the Commission may assume responsibility for the memorial under this subsection by agreement with the appropriate foreign authorities. A decision of the Commission to assume responsibility for a war memorial under this subsection is final.

(3) Sponsors of a war memorial for which the Commission assumes responsibility under this subsection may transfer amounts accumulated to maintain and repair the memorial to the Commission for use in carrying out this chapter. Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section, the Commission shall deposit transferred amounts as provided in section 2103(e) of this title.


(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation With Others.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The American Battle Monuments Commission may cooperate with citizens of the United States, States, municipalities, or associations desiring to build war memorials outside the continental limits of the United States in the way the Commission decides. An administrative agency of the United States Government may give assistance to build the memorial only if a plan for the memorial has been approved under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control, Administration, and Maintenance of War Memorials.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Arrangements for Repair or Long-Term Maintenance of Memorials.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In assuming responsibility for a war memorial under subsection (b)(1) or (2) of this section, the Commission may arrange with the sponsors of the memorial to provide for repair or long-term maintenance of the memorial. An amount transferred to the Commission for the purpose of this subsection shall be deposited by the Commission in the fund established under subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund for Arrangements for Repair or Long-Term Maintenance of Memorials.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demolition of War Memorial Built in a Foreign Country and Disposition of Site.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Commission may take necessary action to demolish any war memorial built outside the United States by a citizen of the United States, a State, a political subdivision of a State, a governmental authority (except a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government), a foreign agency, or a private association and to dispose of the site of the memorial in a way the Commission decides is proper, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>