<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/2108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/2108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/2108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2108"><akn:num>2108</akn:num><akn:heading>Pacific War Memorial and other historical and memorial sites on Corregidor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2108. Pacific War Memorial and other historical and memorial sites on Corregidor(a) General.—After an agreement is made between the Government of the Republic of the Philippines and the United States Government, the American Battle Monuments Commission shall restore, operate, and maintain the Pacific War Memorial and other historical and memorial sites on Corregidor.

(b) Personnel.—The Commission may employ necessary personnel to carry out this section.

(c) Use of Other Departments, Agencies, and Instrumentalities.—Departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government may assist the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, in carrying out this section.

(d) Authority To Solicit Contributions.—To carry out this section, the Commission may solicit and accept private contributions and shall deposit the contributions in the fund established by subsection (f) of this section.

(e) Use of Private Amounts.—The Commission shall carry out this section with private amounts except to the extent amounts are appropriated under subsection (g) of this section.

(f) Fund.—(1) There is a fund in the Treasury that is available to the Commission only to carry out this section. The fund consists of—(A) amounts deposited into, and interest and proceeds credited to, the fund under paragraph (2) of this subsection; and

(B) obligations obtained under paragraph (3) of this subsection.


(2) The Chairman of the Commission shall deposit into the fund the amounts that are accepted under subsection (d) of this section. The Secretary of the Treasury shall credit to the fund the interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, obligations held in the fund.

(3) The Secretary shall invest any part of the fund that the Chairman decides is not required to meet current expenses. Each investment shall be made in an interest-bearing obligation of the United States Government, or an obligation that has its principal and interest guaranteed by the Government, that the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) After an agreement is made between the Government of the Republic of the Philippines and the United States Government, the American Battle Monuments Commission shall restore, operate, and maintain the Pacific War Memorial and other historical and memorial sites on Corregidor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Commission may employ necessary personnel to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Other Departments, Agencies, and Instrumentalities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government may assist the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Solicit Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) To carry out this section, the Commission may solicit and accept private contributions and shall deposit the contributions in the fund established by subsection (f) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Private Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Commission shall carry out this section with private amounts except to the extent amounts are appropriated under subsection (g) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2108_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) There are authorized to be appropriated—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>