<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220543" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220543/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220543/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_220543"><akn:num>220543</akn:num><akn:heading>Records, audits, and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 220543. Records, audits, and reports(a) Records.—The Center shall keep correct and complete records of account.

(b) Audits and Transparency.—(1) Annual audit.—(A) In general.—Not less frequently than annually, the financial statements of the Center for the preceding fiscal year shall be audited by an independent auditor in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles—(i) to ensure the adequacy of the internal controls of the Center; and

(ii) to prevent waste, fraud, or misuse of funds transferred to the Center by the corporation or the national governing bodies.


(B) Location.—An audit under subparagraph (A) shall be conducted at the location at which the financial statements of the Center normally are kept.

(C) Report.—Not later than 180 days after the date on which an audit under subparagraph (A) is completed, the independent auditor shall issue an audit report.

(D) Corrective action plan.—(i) In general.—On completion of the audit report under subparagraph (C) for a fiscal year, the Center shall prepare, in a separate document, a corrective action plan that responds to any corrective action recommended by the independent auditor.

(ii) Matters to be included.—A corrective action plan under clause (i) shall include the following for each such corrective action:(I) The name of the person responsible for the corrective action.

(II) A description of the planned corrective action.

(III) The anticipated completion date of the corrective action.

(IV) In the case of a recommended corrective action based on a finding in the audit report with which the Center disagrees, or for which the Center determines that corrective action is not required, an explanation and a specific reason for noncompliance with the recommendation.




(2) Access to records and personnel.—With respect to an audit under paragraph (1), the Center shall provide the independent auditor access to all records, documents, and personnel and financial statements of the Center necessary </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220543_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Center shall keep correct and complete records of account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220543_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits and Transparency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220543_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Center shall submit an annual report to Congress, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220543_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>