<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_220501"><akn:num>220501</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title and definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 220501. Short title and definitions(a) Short Title.—This chapter may be cited as the “Ted Stevens Olympic and Amateur Sports Act”.

(b) Definitions.—For purposes of this chapter—(1) “amateur athlete” means an athlete who meets the eligibility standards established by the national governing body or paralympic sports organization for the sport in which the athlete competes.

(2) “amateur athletic competition” means a contest, game, meet, match, tournament, regatta, or other event in which amateur athletes compete.

(3) “amateur sports organization” means a not-for-profit corporation, association, or other group organized in the United States that sponsors or arranges an amateur athletic competition.

(4) “Athletes’ Advisory Council” means the entity established and maintained under section 220504(b)(2)(A) that—(A) is composed of, and elected by, amateur athletes to ensure communication between the corporation and currently active amateur athletes; and

(B) serves as a source of amateur-athlete opinion and advice with respect to policies and proposed policies of the corporation.


(5) “Center” means the United States Center for SafeSport designated under section 220541.

(6) “child abuse” has the meaning given the term in section 212 of the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 (34 U.S.C. 20302).

(7) “corporation” means the United States Olympic and Paralympic Committee.

(8) “international amateur athletic competition” means an amateur athletic competition between one or more athletes representing the United States, individually or as a team, and one or more athletes representing a foreign country.

(9) “national governing body” means an amateur sports organization, a high-performance management organization, or a paralympic sports organization that is certified by the corporation under section 220521.

(10) “protected individual” means any amateur athlete, coach, trainer, manager, administrator, or official associated with the corporation or a national governing body</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short Title.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) This chapter may be cited as the “Ted Stevens Olympic and Amateur Sports Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For purposes of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>