<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220528" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220528/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220528/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_220528"><akn:num>220528</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications to replace an incumbent national governing body</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 220528. Applications to replace an incumbent national governing body(a) General.—An amateur sports organization may seek to replace an incumbent as the national governing body for a particular sport by filing a written application for certification with the corporation.

(b) Establishment of Procedures.—The corporation shall establish procedures for the filing and disposition of applications under this section. If 2 or more organizations file applications for the same sport, the applications shall be considered in a single proceeding.

(c) Filing Procedures.—(1) An application under this section must be filed within one year after the final day of—(A) any Olympic Games, for a sport in which competition is held in the Olympic Games or the Paralympic Games, or in each of the Olympic Games, the Paralympic Games, the Pan-American Games, and the Parapan American Games; or

(B) any Pan-American Games or Parapan American Games, for a sport in which competition is held in the Pan-American Games or the Parapan American Games, as applicable, but not in the Olympic Games or the Paralympic Games.


(2) The application shall be filed with the corporation by certified mail, and a copy of the application shall be served on the national governing body and with any other organization that has filed an application. The corporation shall inform the applicant that its application has been received.


(d) Hearings.—Within 180 days after receipt of an application filed under this section, the corporation shall conduct a formal hearing open to the public to determine the merits of the application. The corporation shall publish notice of the time and place of the hearing in a regular issue of its principal publication at least 30 days, but not more than 60 days, before the date of the hearing. The corporation also shall send written notice, including a copy of the application, at least 30 days prior to the date of the hearing to all amateur sports organizations known to the corporation i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220528_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An amateur sports organization may seek to replace an incumbent as the national governing body for a particular sport by filing a written application for certification with the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220528_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The corporation shall establish procedures for the filing and disposition of applications under this section. If 2 or more organizations file applications for the same sport, the applications shall be considered in a single proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220528_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220528_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Within 180 days after receipt of an application filed under this section, the corporation shall conduct a formal hearing open to the public to determine the merits of the application. The corporation shall publish notice of the time and place of the hearing in a regular issue of its principal publication at least 30 days, but not more than 60 days, before the date of the hearing. The corporation also shall send written notice, including a copy of the application, at least 30 days prior to the date of the hearing to all amateur sports organizations known to the corporation in that sport. In the hearing, the applicant and the national governing body shall be given a reasonable opportunity to present evidence supporting their positions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220528_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for Granting Applications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In the hearing, the applicant must establish by a preponderance of the evidence that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220528_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of Applications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Within 30 days after the close of the hearing required by this section, the corporation shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_220528_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation of Certification After Probation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) If the national governing body does not comply with sections 220522, 220524, and 220525 of this title within the probationary period prescribed under subsection (f)(4) of this section, the corporation shall revoke the certification of the national governing body and either—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>