<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220510" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220510/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/220510/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_220510"><akn:num>220510</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 220510. Service of process
As a condition to the exercise of any power or privilege granted by this chapter, the corporation shall have a designated agent in the State of Colorado to receive service of process for the corporation. Notice to or service on the agent, or mailed to the business address of the agent, is notice to or service on the corporation.
(Pub. L. 105–225, Aug. 12, 1998, 112 Stat. 1470; Pub. L. 105–277, div. C, title I, § 142(i), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–606.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


22051036:381.Sept. 21, 1950, ch. 975, title I, § 111, as added Nov. 8, 1978, Pub. L. 95–606, § 1(b), 92 Stat. 3049.


The words “precedent” and “or conferred” are omitted as unnecessary. The words “with the secretary of state or other designated official” are substituted for “in the office of the secretary of state, or similar office” for consistency in the revised title. The words “post-office” and “authorized” are omitted as unnecessary. The words “legal process” are substituted for “local process” for consistency in the revised title.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Pub. L. 105–277 amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “As a condition to the exercise of any power or privilege granted by this chapter, the corporation shall file, with the secretary of state or other designated official of each State, the name and address of an agent in that State on whom legal process or demands against the corporation may be served.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>