<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/230304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/230304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/230304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_230304"><akn:num>230304</akn:num><akn:heading>Governing body</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 230304. Governing body(a) National Convention.—(1) The national convention is the supreme governing authority of the corporation.

(2) The national convention is composed of officers and elected representatives from the States and other local subdivisions of the corporation as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation. However, the form of government of the corporation must be representative of the membership at large and may not permit concentration of control in a limited number of members or in a self-perpetuating group not representative of the membership at large. Each elected representative is entitled to one vote at the national convention.

(3) The meetings of the national convention may be held in the District of Columbia or in any State, territory, or possession of the United States.


(b) Board of Administration.—(1) During the intervals between the national convention, the board of administration is the governing board of the corporation and is responsible for the general policies, program, and activities of the corporation.

(2) The board shall consist of at least 7 members elected in the manner and for the term provided in the constitution and bylaws.


(c) Officers.—(1) The officers of the corporation are a national commander, a national senior vice commander, a national junior vice commander, a national quartermaster, a national adjutant, a national judge advocate, 9 regional vice commanders, and other officers as provided in the constitution and bylaws. One individual may hold the offices of national quartermaster and national adjutant.

(2) The titles, manner of selection, term of office, and duties of the officers are as provided in the constitution and bylaws.


(Pub. L. 105–225, Aug. 12, 1998, 112 Stat. 1483.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


230304(a)36:766(a).July 18, 1958, Pub. L. 85–530, §§ 6(a), 7, 8, 72 Stat. 372.
230304(b)(1)36:767(a). 
230304(b)(2)3</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_230304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Convention.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_230304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_230304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>