<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/40728" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/40728/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/40728/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40728"><akn:num>40728</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of firearms, ammunition, and parts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40728. Transfer of firearms, ammunition, and parts(a) Required Transfers.—In accordance with subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary of the Army shall transfer to the corporation all firearms and ammunition that, on February 9, 1996, were under the control of the director of civilian marksmanship (as that position existed under section 4307 of title 10 on February 9, 1996), including—(1) all firearms on loan to affiliated clubs and State associations;

(2) all firearms in the possession of the Civilian Marksmanship Support Detachment; and

(3) all M–1 Garand and caliber .22 rimfire rifles stored at Defense Distribution Depot, Anniston, Anniston, Alabama.


(b) Time for Transfers.—The Secretary shall transfer firearms and ammunition under subsection (a) of this section as and when necessary to enable the corporation—(1) to issue or loan firearms or ammunition under section 40731 of this title; or

(2) to sell firearms or ammunition under section 40732 of this title.


(c) Vesting of Title in Transferred Items.—Title to an item transferred to the corporation under this section shall vest in the corporation—(1) on the issuance of the item to an eligible recipient under section 40731 of this title; or

(2) immediately before the corporation delivers the item to a purchaser in accordance with a contract for sale of the item that is authorized under section 40732 of this title.


(d) Storage of Firearms.—Firearms stored at Defense Distribution Depot, Anniston, Anniston, Alabama, before February 10, 1996, and used for the Civilian Marksmanship Program (as that program existed under section 4308(e) of title 10 before February 10, 1996), shall remain at that facility or another storage facility designated by the Secretary, without cost to the corporation, until the firearms are issued, loaned, or sold by the corporation, or otherwise transferred to the corporation.

(e) Discretionary Transfer of Parts.—The Secretary may transfer from the inventory of the Department o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Transfers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In accordance with subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary of the Army shall transfer to the corporation all firearms and ammunition that, on February 9, 1996, were under the control of the director of civilian marksmanship (as that position existed under section 4307 of title 10 on February 9, 1996), including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Transfers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall transfer firearms and ammunition under subsection (a) of this section as and when necessary to enable the corporation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vesting of Title in Transferred Items.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Title to an item transferred to the corporation under this section shall vest in the corporation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Storage of Firearms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Firearms stored at Defense Distribution Depot, Anniston, Anniston, Alabama, before February 10, 1996, and used for the Civilian Marksmanship Program (as that program existed under section 4308(e) of title 10 before February 10, 1996), shall remain at that facility or another storage facility designated by the Secretary, without cost to the corporation, until the firearms are issued, loaned, or sold by the corporation, or otherwise transferred to the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretionary Transfer of Parts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may transfer from the inventory of the Department of the Army to the corporation any part from a rifle designated to be demilitarized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Demilitarization of M–1 Rifles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) After February 10, 1996, the Secretary may not demilitarize an M–1 Garand rifle in the inventory of the Army unless the Defense Logistics Agency decides the rifle is unserviceable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost of Transfers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A transfer of firearms, ammunition, or parts to the corporation under this section shall be made without cost to the corporation, except that the corporation shall assume the cost of preparation and transportation of firearms and ammunition transferred under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Transfers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Navy Transfers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>