<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/40728B" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/40728B/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/40728B/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40728B"><akn:num>40728B</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of excess rifles, ammunition, and parts granted to foreign countries and transfer to certai</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40728B. Recovery of excess rifles, ammunition, and parts granted to foreign countries and transfer to certain persons(a) Authority to Recover.—(1) Subject to paragraph (2) and subsection (b), the Secretary of the Army may acquire from any person any rifle, ammunition, repair parts, or other supplies described in section 40731(a) of this title which were—(A) provided to any country on a grant basis under the conditions imposed by section 505 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2314) that became excess to the needs of such country; and

(B) lawfully acquired by such person.


(2) The Secretary of the Army may not acquire anything under paragraph (1) except for transfer to a person in the United States under subsection (c).

(3) The Secretary of the Army may accept rifles, ammunition, repair parts, or other supplies under paragraph (1) notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31.


(b) Cost of Recovery.—The Secretary of the Army may not acquire anything under subsection (a) if the United States would incur any cost for such acquisition.

(c) Availability for Transfer.—Any rifles, ammunition, repair parts, or supplies acquired under subsection (a) shall be available for transfer in the United States to the person from whom acquired if such person—(1) is licensed as a manufacturer, importer, or dealer pursuant to section 923(a) of title 18; and

(2) uses an ammunition depot of the Army that is an eligible facility for receipt of any rifles, ammunition, repair parts, or supplies under this paragraph.


(d) Market Value.—The Secretary of the Army may only transfer an item under subsection (c) if the Secretary receives fair market value for the item.

(e) Contracts.—Notwithstanding section 3201(e) of title 10, the Secretary may enter into such contracts or cooperative agreements on a sole source basis pursuant to paragraphs (4) and (5) of section 3204(a) 11 So in original. Probably means section 3204(a) of title 10. to carry out this section.

(f) AECA.—Transfer</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728B_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Recover.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728B_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost of Recovery.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of the Army may not acquire anything under subsection (a) if the United States would incur any cost for such acquisition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728B_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability for Transfer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Any rifles, ammunition, repair parts, or supplies acquired under subsection (a) shall be available for transfer in the United States to the person from whom acquired if such person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728B_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Market Value.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of the Army may only transfer an item under subsection (c) if the Secretary receives fair market value for the item.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728B_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notwithstanding section 3201(e) of title 10, the Secretary may enter into such contracts or cooperative agreements on a sole source basis pursuant to paragraphs (4) and (5) of section 3204(a) 11 So in original. Probably means section 3204(a) of title 10. to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728B_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>AECA.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfers authorized under this section may only be made in accordance with applicable provisions of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2778).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40728B_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rifle Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section, the term “rifle” has the meaning given such term in section 921 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>