<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/70909" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/70909/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/70909/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70909"><akn:num>70909</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70909. Relationship to Federal agencies(a) In General.—On request of the board of directors, the FFA may collaborate with Federal agencies, including the Department of Education and the Department of Agriculture on matters of mutual interest and benefit.

(b) Agency Assistance.—Those Federal agencies may make personnel, services, and facilities available to administer or assist in the administration of the activities of the FFA.

(c) Agency Compensation.—Personnel of the Federal agencies may not receive compensation from the FFA for their services, except that travel and other legitimate expenses as defined by the Federal agencies and approved by the board may be paid.

(d) Cooperation With State Boards.—The Federal agencies also may cooperate with State boards and other organizations for career and technical education to assist in the promotion of activities of the FFA.

(Pub. L. 105–225, Aug. 12, 1998, 112 Stat. 1358; Pub. L. 116–7, § 10, Feb. 21, 2019, 133 Stat. 481.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


7090936:288.Aug. 30, 1950, ch. 823, § 18, 64 Stat. 567.


The words “Secretary of Education” and “Secretary” are substituted for “United States Commissioner of Education”, “Commissioner of Education”, and “Commissioner”, and the words “Department of Education” are substituted for “Office of Education”, in section 18 of the Act of August 30, 1950 (ch. 823, 64 Stat. 567), because of 20:3441 and 3507. The words “with the approval of the Federal Security Administrator” and “with the approval of the Administrator” are omitted because the functions of the Federal Security Administrator were transferred to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare by section 5 of Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1953 (5 App. U.S.C.), and were subsequently transferred to the Secretary of Education by 20:3441. See also 20:3507. Substitution of a reference to the “Secretary of Education” would result in a requirement of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70909_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) On request of the board of directors, the FFA may collaborate with Federal agencies, including the Department of Education and the Department of Agriculture on matters of mutual interest and benefit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70909_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Those Federal agencies may make personnel, services, and facilities available to administer or assist in the administration of the activities of the FFA.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70909_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Personnel of the Federal agencies may not receive compensation from the FFA for their services, except that travel and other legitimate expenses as defined by the Federal agencies and approved by the board may be paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70909_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation With State Boards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Federal agencies also may cooperate with State boards and other organizations for career and technical education to assist in the promotion of activities of the FFA.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>