<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/36/904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_904"><akn:num>904</akn:num><akn:heading>Hostage and Wrongful Detainee flag</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 904. Hostage and Wrongful Detainee flag(a) Designation.—The Hostage and Wrongful Detainee flag championed by the Bring Our Families Home Campaign is designated as the symbol of the commitment of the United States to recognizing, and prioritizing the freedom of, citizens and lawful permanent residents of the United States held as hostages or wrongfully detained abroad.

(b) Required Display.—(1) In general.—The Hostage and Wrongful Detainee flag shall be displayed at the locations specified in paragraph (3) on the days specified in paragraph (2).

(2) Days specified.—The days specified in this paragraph are the following:(A) U.S. Hostage and Wrongful Detainee Day, March 9.

(B) Flag Day, June 14.

(C) Independence Day, July 4.

(D) Any day on which a citizen or lawful permanent resident of the United States—(i) returns to the United States from being held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad; or

(ii) dies while being held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad.



(3) Locations specified.—The locations specified in this paragraph are the following:(A) The Capitol.

(B) The White House.

(C) The buildings containing the official office of—(i) the Secretary of State; and

(ii) the Secretary of Defense.




(c) Display To Be in a Manner Visible to the Public.—Display of the Hostage and Wrongful Detainee flag pursuant to this section shall be in a manner designed to ensure visibility to the public.

(d) Limitation.—This section may not be construed or applied so as to require any employee to report to work solely for the purpose of providing for the display of the Hostage and Wrongful Detainee flag.

(Added Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1804(a)(2)(A), Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 686.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Hostage and Wrongful Detainee flag championed by the Bring Our Families Home Campaign is designated as the symbol of the commitment of the United States to recognizing, and prioritizing the freedom of, citizens and lawful permanent residents of the United States held as hostages or wrongfully detained abroad.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Display.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Display To Be in a Manner Visible to the Public.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Display of the Hostage and Wrongful Detainee flag pursuant to this section shall be in a manner designed to ensure visibility to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_904_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) This section may not be construed or applied so as to require any employee to report to work solely for the purpose of providing for the display of the Hostage and Wrongful Detainee flag.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>