<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1"><akn:num>1</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of the Comptroller of the Currency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1. Office of the Comptroller of the Currency(a) Office of the Comptroller of the Currency establishedThere is established in the Department of the Treasury a bureau to be known as the “Office of the Comptroller of the Currency” which is charged with assuring the safety and soundness of, and compliance with laws and regulations, fair access to financial services, and fair treatment of customers by, the institutions and other persons subject to its jurisdiction.


(b) Comptroller of the Currency(1) In generalThe chief officer of the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency shall be known as the Comptroller of the Currency. The Comptroller of the Currency shall perform the duties of the Comptroller of the Currency under the general direction of the Secretary of the Treasury. The Secretary of the Treasury may not delay or prevent the issuance of any rule or the promulgation of any regulation by the Comptroller of the Currency, and may not intervene in any matter or proceeding before the Comptroller of the Currency (including agency enforcement actions), unless otherwise specifically provided by law.


(2) Additional authorityThe Comptroller of the Currency shall have the same authority with respect to functions transferred to the Comptroller of the Currency under the Enhancing Financial Institution Safety and Soundness Act of 2010 as was vested in the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision on the transfer date, as defined in section 311 of that Act [12 U.S.C. 5411].



(R.S. § 324; Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 10 (par.), 38 Stat. 261; June 3, 1922, ch. 205, 42 Stat. 621; Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614, title II, § 203(a), 49 Stat. 704; Pub. L. 89–427, § 1, May 20, 1966, 80 Stat. 161; Pub. L. 103–325, title III, § 331(b)(2), Sept. 23, 1994, 108 Stat. 2232; Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 314(a), July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 1523; Pub. L. 119–27, § 4(b)(2), July 18, 2025, 139 Stat. 434.)

Amendment of Subsection (b)Pub. L. 119–27, §§ 4(b)(2), 20, July 18, 2025, 139 Stat. 434, 466, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of the Comptroller of the Currency established</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Office of the Comptroller of the Currency established There is established in the Department of the Treasury a bureau to be known as the “Office of the Comptroller of the Currency” which is charged with assuring the safety and soundness of, and compliance with laws and regulations, fair access to financial services, and fair treatment of customers by, the institutions and other persons subject to its jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comptroller of the Currency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Comptroller of the Currency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>