<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1426a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1426a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1426a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1426a"><akn:num>1426a</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion from certain requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1426a. Exclusion from certain requirements(a) In generalThe Federal Home Loan Banks shall be exempt from compliance with—(1) sections 78m(e), 78n(a), and 78n(c) of title 15, and related Commission regulations;

(2) section 78o of title 15, and related Commission regulations, with respect to transactions in the capital stock of a Federal Home Loan Bank;

(3) section 78q–1 of title 15, and related Commission regulations, with respect to the transfer of the securities of a Federal Home Loan Bank; and

(4) the Trust Indenture Act of 1939 [15 U.S.C. 77aaa et seq.].


(b) Member exemptionThe members of the Federal Home Loan Bank System shall be exempt from compliance with sections 78m(d), 78m(f), 78m(g), 78n(d), and 78p of title 15, and related Commission regulations, with respect to ownership of or transactions in the capital stock of the Federal Home Loan Banks by such members.


(c) Exempted and Government securities(1) Capital stockThe capital stock issued by each of the Federal Home Loan Banks under section 1426 of this title are—(A) exempted securities, within the meaning of section 77c(a)(2) of title 15; and

(B) exempted securities, within the meaning of section 78c(a)(12)(A) of title 15, except to the extent provided in section 78oo of title 15.


(2) Other obligationsThe debentures, bonds, and other obligations issued under section 1431 of this title are—(A) exempted securities, within the meaning of section 77c(a)(2) of title 15;

(B) government securities, within the meaning of section 78c(a)(42) of title 15; and

(C) government securities, within the meaning of section 80a–2(a)(16) of title 15.


(3) Brokers and dealersA person (other than a Federal Home Loan Bank effecting transactions for members of the Federal Home Loan Bank System) that effects transactions in the capital stock or other obligations of a Federal Home Loan Bank, for the account of others or for that person’s own account, as applicable, is a broker or dealer, as those terms are defined in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Federal Home Loan Banks shall be exempt from compliance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Member exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Member exemption The members of the Federal Home Loan Bank System shall be exempt from compliance with sections 78m(d), 78m(f), 78m(g), 78n(d), and 78p of title 15, and related Commission regulations, with respect to ownership of or transactions in the capital stock of the Federal Home Loan Banks by such members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exempted and Government securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exempted and Government securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemption from reporting requirements The Federal Home Loan Banks shall be exempt from periodic reporting requirements under the securities laws pertaining to the disclosure of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tender offers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Tender offers Commission rules relating to tender offers shall not apply in connection with transactions in the capital stock of the Federal Home Loan Banks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>