<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1430" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1430/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1430/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1430"><akn:num>1430</akn:num><akn:heading>Advances to members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1430. Advances to members(a) In general(1) All advancesEach Federal Home Loan Bank is authorized to make secured advances to its members upon collateral sufficient, in the judgment of the Bank, to fully secure advances obtained from the Bank under this section or section 1431(g) of this title.


(2) Purposes of advancesA long-term advance may only be made for the purposes of—(A) providing funds to any member for residential housing finance; and

(B) providing funds to any community financial institution for small businesses, small farms, small agri-businesses, and community development activities.


(3) CollateralA Bank, at the time of origination or renewal of a loan or advance, shall obtain and maintain a security interest in collateral eligible pursuant to one or more of the following categories:(A) Fully disbursed, whole first mortgages on improved residential property (not more than 90 days delinquent), or securities representing a whole interest in such mortgages.

(B) Securities issued, insured, or guaranteed by the United States Government or any agency thereof (including without limitation, mortgage-backed securities issued or guaranteed by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the Federal National Mortgage Corporation, and the Government National Mortgage Association).

(C) Cash or deposits of a Federal Home Loan Bank.

(D) Other real estate related collateral acceptable to the Bank if such collateral has a readily ascertainable value and the Bank can perfect its interest in the collateral.

(E) Secured loans for small business, agriculture, or community development activities or securities representing a whole interest in such secured loans, in the case of any community financial institution.


(4) Additional bank authoritySubparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (3) shall not affect the ability of any Federal Home Loan Bank to take such steps as it deems necessary to protect its security position with respect to outstanding advances, including </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisals and other investigations; acceptance of home mortgages as collateral security only by approval of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appraisals and other investigations; acceptance of home mortgages as collateral security only by approval of Director For the purposes of this section, each Home Loan Bank shall have power to make, or to cause or require to be made, such appraisals and other investigations as it may deem necessary. No home mortgage otherwise eligible to be accepted as collateral security for an advance by a Home Loan Bank shall be accepted if any director, officer, employee, attorney or agent of the Home Loan Bank or of the borrowing institution is personally liable thereon, unless the Director has specifically approved such acceptance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notes of borrowing members; interest rate; lien on stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notes of borrowing members; interest rate; lien on stock Such advances shall be made upon the note or obligation of the member secured as provided in this section, bearing such rate of interest as the Federal home loan bank may approve or determine, and the Federal Home Loan Bank shall have a lien upon and shall hold the stock of such member as further collateral security for all indebtedness of the member to the Federal Home Loan Bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation to repay; additional security; sale of advances to other banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Obligation to repay; additional security; sale of advances to other banks The institution applying for an advance shall enter into a primary and unconditional obligation to pay off all advances, together with interest and any unpaid costs and expenses in connection therewith according to the terms under which they were made, in such form as shall meet the requirements of the bank. The bank shall reserve the right to require at any time, when deemed necessary for its protection, deposits of additional collateral security or substitutions of security by the borrowing institution, and each borrowing institution shall assign additional or substituted security when and as so required. Any Federal Home Loan Bank shall have power to sell to any other Federal Home Loan Bank, with or without recourse, any advance made under the provisions of this chapter, or to allow to such bank a participation therein, and any other Federal Home Loan Bank shall have power to purchase such advance or to ac</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority of certain secured interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority of certain secured interests Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any security interest granted to a Federal Home Loan Bank by any member of any Federal Home Loan Bank or any affiliate of any such member shall be entitled to priority over the claims and rights of any party (including any receiver, conservator, trustee, or similar party having rights of a lien creditor) other than claims and rights that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. No subsec. (f) has been enacted. Community support requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special liquidity advances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special liquidity advances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community investment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Community investment program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affordable housing program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Affordable housing program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1430_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public use database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) Public use database</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>