<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1440a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1440a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1440a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1440a"><akn:num>1440a</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of information among Federal Home Loan Banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1440a. Sharing of information among Federal Home Loan Banks(a) Information on financial conditionIn order to enable each Federal Home Loan Bank to evaluate the financial condition of one or more of the other Federal Home Loan Banks individually and the Federal Home Loan Bank System (including any risks associated with the issuance or repayment of consolidated Federal Home Loan Bank bonds and debentures or other borrowings and the joint and several liabilities of the Banks incurred due to such borrowings), as well as to comply with any of its obligations under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.), the Director shall make available to the Banks such reports, records, or other information as may be available, relating to the condition of any Federal Home Loan Bank.


(b) Sharing of information(1) In generalThe Director shall promulgate regulations to facilitate the sharing of information made available under subsection (a) directly among the Federal Home Loan Banks.


(2) LimitationNotwithstanding paragraph (1), a Federal Home Loan Bank responding to a request from another Bank or from the Director for information pursuant to this section may request that the Director determine that such information is proprietary and that the public interest requires that such information not be shared.



(c) LimitationNothing in this section shall affect the obligations of any Federal Home Loan Bank under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.) or the regulations issued by the Securities and Exchange Commission thereunder.


(d) No waiver of privilegeThe Director shall not be deemed to have waived any privilege applicable to any information concerning a Federal Home Loan Bank by transferring, or permitting the transfer of, that information to any other Federal Home Loan Bank for the purposes set out in subsection (a).


(July 22, 1932, ch. 522, § 20A, as added Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title II, § 1207, July 30, 2008, 122 Stat. 2787.)

Edi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on financial condition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information on financial condition In order to enable each Federal Home Loan Bank to evaluate the financial condition of one or more of the other Federal Home Loan Banks individually and the Federal Home Loan Bank System (including any risks associated with the issuance or repayment of consolidated Federal Home Loan Bank bonds and debentures or other borrowings and the joint and several liabilities of the Banks incurred due to such borrowings), as well as to comply with any of its obligations under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.), the Director shall make available to the Banks such reports, records, or other information as may be available, relating to the condition of any Federal Home Loan Bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sharing of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation Nothing in this section shall affect the obligations of any Federal Home Loan Bank under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.) or the regulations issued by the Securities and Exchange Commission thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1440a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No waiver of privilege</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No waiver of privilege The Director shall not be deemed to have waived any privilege applicable to any information concerning a Federal Home Loan Bank by transferring, or permitting the transfer of, that information to any other Federal Home Loan Bank for the purposes set out in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>