<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1441" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1441/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1441/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1441"><akn:num>1441</akn:num><akn:heading>Financing Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1441. Financing Corporation(a) EstablishmentNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director shall charter a corporation to be known as the Financing Corporation.


(b) Management of Financing Corporation(1) DirectorateThe Financing Corporation shall be under the management of a directorate composed of 3 members as follows:(A) The Director of the Office of Finance of the Federal Home Loan Banks (or the head of any successor to such office).

(B) 2 members selected by the Director from among the presidents of the Federal Home Loan Banks.


(2) TermsEach member appointed under paragraph (1)(B) shall be appointed for a term of 1 year.


(3) VacancyIf any member leaves the office in which such member was serving when appointed to the Directorate—(A) such member’s service on the Directorate shall terminate on the date such member leaves such office; and

(B) the successor to the office of such member shall serve the remainder of such member’s term.


(4) Equal representation of banksNo president of a Federal Home Loan Bank may be appointed to serve an additional term on the Directorate until such time as the presidents of each of the other Federal Home Loan Banks have served as many terms on the Directorate as the president of such bank (before the appointment of such president to such additional term).


(5) ChairpersonThe Director shall select the chairperson of the Directorate from among the 3 members of the Directorate.


(6) Staff(A) No paid employeesThe Financing Corporation shall have no paid employees.


(B) PowersThe Directorate may, with the approval of the Director, authorize the officers, employees, or agents of the Federal Home Loan Banks to act for and on behalf of the Financing Corporation in such manner as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Financing Corporation.



(7) Administrative expenses(A) In generalAll administrative expenses of the Financing Corporation shall be paid by the Federal Home Loan Banks.


(B) Pro rata distrib</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director shall charter a corporation to be known as the Financing Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Financing Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management of Financing Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of Financing Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Powers of Financing Corporation The Financing Corporation shall have only the following powers, subject to the other provisions of this section and such regulations, orders, and directions as the Director may prescribe:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capitalization of Financing Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Capitalization of Financing Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations of Financing Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Obligations of Financing Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sources of funds for interest payments; Financing Corporation assessment authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sources of funds for interest payments; Financing Corporation assessment authority The Financing Corporation shall obtain funds for anticipated interest payments, issuance costs, and custodial fees on obligations issued hereunder from the following sources:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use and disposition of assets of Financing Corporation not invested in FSLIC</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Use and disposition of assets of Financing Corporation not invested in FSLIC</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions relating to Financing Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Miscellaneous provisions relating to Financing Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Financing Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination of Financing Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations The Director may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section, including regulations defining terms used in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>