<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1453" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1453/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1453/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1453"><akn:num>1453</akn:num><akn:heading>Capitalization of Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1453. Capitalization of Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation(a) Common stock; issuanceThe common stock of the Corporation shall consist of voting common stock, which shall be issued to such holders in the manner and amount, and subject to any limitations on concentration of ownership, as may be established by the Corporation.


(b) Par valueThe voting common stock shall have such par value and other characteristics as the Corporation provides. The voting common stock shall be vested with all voting rights, each share being entitled to 1 vote. The free transferability of the voting common stock at all times to any person, firm, corporation or other entity shall not be restricted except that, as to the Corporation, it shall be transferable only on the books of the Corporation.


(Pub. L. 91–351, title III, § 304, July 24, 1970, 84 Stat. 454; Pub. L. 101–73, title VII, § 731(d)(1), (3), Aug. 9, 1989, 103 Stat. 432; Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1382(i), Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 4004.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1992—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 102–550, § 1382(i)(2), (3)(C), redesignated par. (1) as subsec. (a), struck out provisions of par. (1)(A) which related to common stock of Corporation consisting in part of nonvoting common stock issued only to Federal home loan banks, restate provisions of par. (1)(B) as text of subsec. (a), and redesignated par. (2) as subsec. (b).
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 102–550, § 1382(i)(1), (3), redesignated subsec. (a)(2) as (b), struck out “nonvoting common stock and the” before “voting common stock shall have such”, struck out at end “Nonvoting common stock of the Corporation shall be evidenced in the manner and shall be transferable only to the extent, to the transferees, and in the manner, provided by the Corporation.”, and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows: “The Federal home loan banks shall from time to time subscribe, at such price not less than par as the Corporation shall from time to time fix, for such amounts of non</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1453_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common stock; issuance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Common stock; issuance The common stock of the Corporation shall consist of voting common stock, which shall be issued to such holders in the manner and amount, and subject to any limitations on concentration of ownership, as may be established by the Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1453_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Par value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Par value The voting common stock shall have such par value and other characteristics as the Corporation provides. The voting common stock shall be vested with all voting rights, each share being entitled to 1 vote. The free transferability of the voting common stock at all times to any person, firm, corporation or other entity shall not be restricted except that, as to the Corporation, it shall be transferable only on the books of the Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>