<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1455" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1455/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1455/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1455"><akn:num>1455</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations and securities of the Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1455. Obligations and securities of the Corporation(a) Authority to issue; terms and conditions; validityThe Corporation is authorized, upon such terms and conditions as it may prescribe, to borrow, to give security, to pay interest or other return, and to issue notes, debentures, bonds, or other obligations, or other securities, including without limitation mortgage-backed securities guaranteed by the Government National Mortgage Association in the manner provided in section 1721(g) of this title. Any obligation or security of the Corporation shall be valid and binding notwithstanding that a person or persons purporting to have executed or attested the same may have died, become under disability, or ceased to hold office or employment before the issuance thereof.


(b) Prohibitions and restrictions; creation of liens and charges; rank and priority; causes of action to enforce; jurisdiction; service of processThe Corporation may, by regulation or by writing executed by the Corporation, establish prohibitions or restrictions upon the creation of indebtedness or obligations of the Corporation or of liens or charges upon property of the Corporation, including after-acquired property, and create liens and charges, which may be floating liens or charges, upon all or any part or parts of the property of the Corporation, including after-acquired property. Such prohibitions, restrictions, liens, and charges shall have such effect, including without limitation on the generality of the foregoing such rank and priority, as may be provided by regulations of the Corporation or by writings executed by the Corporation, and shall create causes of action which may be enforced by action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in the United States district court for any judicial district in which any of the property affected is located. Process in any such action may run to and be served in any judicial district or any place subject to the jurisdiction of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to issue; terms and conditions; validity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to issue; terms and conditions; validity The Corporation is authorized, upon such terms and conditions as it may prescribe, to borrow, to give security, to pay interest or other return, and to issue notes, debentures, bonds, or other obligations, or other securities, including without limitation mortgage-backed securities guaranteed by the Government National Mortgage Association in the manner provided in section 1721(g) of this title. Any obligation or security of the Corporation shall be valid and binding notwithstanding that a person or persons purporting to have executed or attested the same may have died, become under disability, or ceased to hold office or employment before the issuance thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions and restrictions; creation of liens and charges; rank and priority; causes of action to enforce; jurisdiction; service of process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibitions and restrictions; creation of liens and charges; rank and priority; causes of action to enforce; jurisdiction; service of process The Corporation may, by regulation or by writing executed by the Corporation, establish prohibitions or restrictions upon the creation of indebtedness or obligations of the Corporation or of liens or charges upon property of the Corporation, including after-acquired property, and create liens and charges, which may be floating liens or charges, upon all or any part or parts of the property of the Corporation, including after-acquired property. Such prohibitions, restrictions, liens, and charges shall have such effect, including without limitation on the generality of the foregoing such rank and priority, as may be provided by regulations of the Corporation or by writings executed by the Corporation, and shall create causes of action which may be enforced by action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in the Uni</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of obligations; funds, maximum amount of purchases, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purchase of obligations; funds, maximum amount of purchases, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Validity of provisions; validity of restrictions, prohibitions, liens, or charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Validity of provisions; validity of restrictions, prohibitions, liens, or charges The provisions of this section and of any restriction, prohibition, lien, or charge referred to in subsection (b) shall be fully effective notwithstanding any other law, including without limitation on the generality of the foregoing any law of or relating to sovereign immunity or priority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to purchase, hold, or invest by person, trust, or organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authority to purchase, hold, or invest by person, trust, or organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferred stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preferred stock The Corporation may have preferred stock on such terms and conditions as the Board of Directors shall prescribe. Any preferred stock shall not be entitled to vote with respect to the election of any member of the Board of Directors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Securities exempt from regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Securities exempt from regulation All securities issued or guaranteed by the Corporation (other than securities guaranteed by the Corporation that are backed by mortgages not purchased by the Corporation) shall, to the same extent as securities that are direct obligations of or obligations guaranteed as to principal or interest by the United States, be deemed to be exempt securities within the meaning of the laws administered by the Securities and Exchange Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Securities backed by mortgages not purchased by Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Securities backed by mortgages not purchased by Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on assessment or collection of fee or charge by United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Prohibition on assessment or collection of fee or charge by United States Except for fees paid pursuant to sections 1452(c) 11 See References in Text note below. and 1455(c) of this title and assessments pursuant to section 4516 of this title, no fee or charge may be assessed or collected by the United States (including any executive department, agency, or independent establishment of the United States) on or with regard to the purchase, acquisition, sale, pledge, issuance, guarantee, or redemption of any mortgage, asset, obligation, or other security by the Corporation. No provision of this subsection shall affect the purchase of any obligation by any Federal home loan bank pursuant to section 1452(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notes, debentures, or substantially identical types of unsecured obligations; issuance, maturities, interest rates, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Notes, debentures, or substantially identical types of unsecured obligations; issuance, maturities, interest rates, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>