<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1456" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1456/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1456/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1456"><akn:num>1456</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity of Corporation; audits and reporting requirements; data collection; Housing Advisory Counci</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1456. Immunity of Corporation; audits and reporting requirements; data collection; Housing Advisory Council(a) Rights and remedies of Corporation; State qualifications or similar statutesAll rights and remedies of the Corporation, including without limitation on the generality of the foregoing any rights and remedies of the Corporation on, under, or with respect to any mortgage or any obligation secured thereby, shall be immune from impairment, limitation, or restriction by or under (1) any law (except laws enacted by the Congress expressly in limitation of this sentence) which becomes effective after the acquisition by the Corporation of the subject or property on, under, or with respect to which such right or remedy arises or exists or would so arise or exist in the absence of such law, or (2) any administrative or other action which becomes effective after such acquisition. The Corporation is authorized to conduct its business without regard to any qualification or similar statute in any State.


(b) Government audits; procedure; access to records, etc.; reimbursement of costs(1) The programs, activities, receipts, expenditures, and financial transactions of the Corporation shall be subject to audit by the Comptroller General of the United States under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General. The representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, financial records, reports, files and all other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by the Corporation and necessary to facilitate the audit, and they shall be afforded full facilities for verifying transactions with the balances or securities held by depositaries, fiscal agents, and custodians. A report on each such audit shall be made by the Comptroller General to the Congress. The Corporation shall reimburse the Government Accountability Office for the full cost of any such audit as billed therefor by the Comptroller Gen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights and remedies of Corporation; State qualifications or similar statutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rights and remedies of Corporation; State qualifications or similar statutes All rights and remedies of the Corporation, including without limitation on the generality of the foregoing any rights and remedies of the Corporation on, under, or with respect to any mortgage or any obligation secured thereby, shall be immune from impairment, limitation, or restriction by or under (1) any law (except laws enacted by the Congress expressly in limitation of this sentence) which becomes effective after the acquisition by the Corporation of the subject or property on, under, or with respect to which such right or remedy arises or exists or would so arise or exist in the absence of such law, or (2) any administrative or other action which becomes effective after such acquisition. The Corporation is authorized to conduct its business without regard to any qualification or similar statute in any State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government audits; procedure; access to records, etc.; reimbursement of costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Government audits; procedure; access to records, etc.; reimbursement of costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial reports; submission to Director; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Financial reports; submission to Director; contents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent audits of financial statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Independent audits of financial statements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage data collection and reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Mortgage data collection and reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on housing activities; contents; public disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report on housing activities; contents; public disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1456_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affordable Housing Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Affordable Housing Advisory Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>