<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1462a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1462a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1462a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1462a"><akn:num>1462a</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1462a. Administrative provisions(a) PowersIn accordance with subtitle A of title III of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, the appropriate Federal banking agency shall have all powers which—(1) were vested in the Federal Home Loan Bank Board (in the Board’s capacity as such) or the Chairman of such Board on the day before the date of the enactment of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 [Aug. 9, 1989]; and

(2) were not—(A) transferred to the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Housing Finance Board, the Resolution Trust Corporation, or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation pursuant to any amendment made by such Act; or

(B) established under any provision of law repealed by such Act.



(b) State homestead provisionsNo provision of this chapter or any other provision of law administered by the appropriate Federal banking agency shall be construed as superseding any homestead provision of any State constitution, including any implementing State statute, in effect on September 29, 1994, or any subsequent amendment to such a State constitutional or statutory provision in effect on September 29, 1994, that exempts the homestead of any person from foreclosure, or forced sale, for the payment of all debts, other than a purchase money obligation relating to the homestead, taxes due on the homestead, or an obligation arising from work and material used in constructing improvements on the homestead.


(June 13, 1933, ch. 64, § 3, as added Pub. L. 101–73, title III, § 301, Aug. 9, 1989, 103 Stat. 278; amended Pub. L. 103–325, title III, § 331(c), Sept. 23, 1994, 108 Stat. 2232; Pub. L. 103–328, title I, § 102(b)(5), Sept. 29, 1994, 108 Stat. 2352; Pub. L. 109–351, title VII, § 712, Oct. 13, 2006, 120 Stat. 1994; Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 369(3), July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 1558.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, referred to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Powers In accordance with subtitle A of title III of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act, the appropriate Federal banking agency shall have all powers which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State homestead provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State homestead provisions No provision of this chapter or any other provision of law administered by the appropriate Federal banking agency shall be construed as superseding any homestead provision of any State constitution, including any implementing State statute, in effect on September 29, 1994, or any subsequent amendment to such a State constitutional or statutory provision in effect on September 29, 1994, that exempts the homestead of any person from foreclosure, or forced sale, for the payment of all debts, other than a purchase money obligation relating to the homestead, taxes due on the homestead, or an obligation arising from work and material used in constructing improvements on the homestead.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>