<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1464" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1464/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1464/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1464"><akn:num>1464</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal savings associations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1464. Federal savings associations(a) In generalIn order to provide thrift institutions for the deposit of funds and for the extension of credit for homes and other goods and services, the Comptroller of the Currency is authorized, under such regulations as the Comptroller of the Currency may prescribe—(1) to provide for the organization, incorporation, examination, operation, and regulation of associations to be known as Federal savings associations (including Federal savings banks), and

(2) to issue charters therefor,


giving primary consideration of the best practices of thrift institutions in the United States. The lending and investment powers conferred by this section are intended to encourage such institutions to provide credit for housing safely and soundly.

(b) Deposits and related powers(1) Deposit accounts(A) Subject to the terms of its charter and regulations of the Comptroller of the Currency, a Federal savings association may—(i) raise funds through such deposit, share, or other accounts, including demand deposit accounts (hereafter in this section referred to as “accounts”); and

(ii) issue passbooks, certificates, or other evidence of accounts.


(B) A Federal savings association may not permit any overdraft (including an intraday overdraft) on behalf of an affiliate, or incur any such overdraft in such savings association’s account at a Federal reserve bank or Federal home loan bank on behalf of an affiliate.All savings accounts and demand accounts shall have the same priority upon liquidation. Holders of accounts and obligors of a Federal savings association shall, to such extent as may be provided by its charter or by regulations of the Comptroller of the Currency, be members of the savings association, and shall have such voting rights and such other rights as are thereby provided.


(C) A Federal savings association may require not less than 14 days notice prior to payment of savings accounts if the charter of the savings association or the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In order to provide thrift institutions for the deposit of funds and for the extension of credit for homes and other goods and services, the Comptroller of the Currency is authorized, under such regulations as the Comptroller of the Currency may prescribe— giving primary consideration of the best practices of thrift institutions in the United States. The lending and investment powers conferred by this section are intended to encourage such institutions to provide credit for housing safely and soundly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits and related powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deposits and related powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans and investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Loans and investments To the extent specified in regulations of the Comptroller, a Federal savings association may invest in, sell, or otherwise deal in the following loans and other investments:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulatory authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Character and responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Character and responsibility A charter may be granted only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal home loan bank membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal home loan bank membership After the end of the 6-month period beginning on November 12, 1999, a Federal savings association may become a member of the Federal Home Loan Bank System, and shall qualify for such membership in the manner provided by the Federal Home Loan Bank Act [12 U.S.C. 1421 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferred shares</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Preferred shares</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discriminatory State and local taxation pro­hibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Discriminatory State and local taxation pro­hibited No State, county, municipal, or local taxing authority may impose any tax on Federal savings associations or their franchise, capital, reserves, surplus, loans, or income greater than that imposed by such authority on other similar local mutual or cooperative thrift and home financing institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Conversions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1464_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subscription for shares</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Subscription for shares</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>