<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1467" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1467/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1467/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1467"><akn:num>1467</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1467. Examination fees(a) Examination of savings associationsThe cost of conducting examinations of savings associations pursuant to section 1464(d) of this title shall be assessed by—(1) the Comptroller, against each such Federal savings association, as the Comptroller deems necessary or appropriate; and

(2) the Corporation, against each such State savings association, as the Corporation deems necessary or appropriate.


(b) Examination of affiliatesThe cost of conducting examinations of affiliates of savings associations pursuant to this chapter may be assessed by the Comptroller or Corporation, as appropriate 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. against each affiliate that is examined as the Comptroller or Corporation, as appropriate 1 deems necessary or appropriate.


(c) Assessment against association in case of affiliate’s refusal to pay(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), if any affiliate of any savings association—(A) refuses to pay any assessment under subsection (b); or

(B) fails to pay any such assessment before the end of the 60-day period beginning on the date of the assessment,


the appropriate Federal banking agency may assess such cost against, and collect such cost from, such savings association.

(2) Affiliate of more than 1 savings associationIf any affiliate referred to in paragraph (1) is an affiliate of more than 1 savings association, the assessment with respect to the affiliate against, and collected from, any affiliated savings association in such proportions as the appropriate Federal banking agency may prescribe.



(d) Civil money penalty for affiliate’s refusal to cooperate(1) Penalty imposedIf any affiliate of any savings association—(A) refuses to permit any examiner appointed by the appropriate Federal banking agency to make an examination; or

(B) refuses to provide any information required to be disclosed in the course of any examination,


the savings association shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of savings associations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Examination of savings associations The cost of conducting examinations of savings associations pursuant to section 1464(d) of this title shall be assessed by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of affiliates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Examination of affiliates The cost of conducting examinations of affiliates of savings associations pursuant to this chapter may be assessed by the Comptroller or Corporation, as appropriate 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. against each affiliate that is examined as the Comptroller or Corporation, as appropriate 1 deems necessary or appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment against association in case of affiliate’s refusal to pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assessment against association in case of affiliate’s refusal to pay</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil money penalty for affiliate’s refusal to cooperate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Civil money penalty for affiliate’s refusal to cooperate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Comptroller may prescribe regulations with respect to— Such regulations may establish formulas to determine a fee or schedule of fees to cover the costs of examinations and also to cover the cost of processing applications, filings, notices, and requests for approvals by the appropriate Federal banking agency or the designee of the Comptroller.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>[Reserved].</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) [Reserved].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs of other examinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Costs of other examinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Additional information Any savings association and any affiliate of any savings association shall provide the appropriate Federal banking agency with access to any information or report with respect to any examination made by any public regulatory authority and furnish any additional information with respect thereto as the appropriate Federal banking agency may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of examination assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Treatment of examination assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Processing fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Processing fee The appropriate Federal banking agency may, in the sole discretion of the appropriate Federal banking agency, assess against any person that submits to the appropriate Federal banking agency an application, filing, notice, or request a fee to cover the cost of processing such submission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>