<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1467a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1467a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1467a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1467a"><akn:num>1467a</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of holding companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1467a. Regulation of holding companies(a) Definitions(1) In generalAs used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires—(A) Savings associationThe term “savings association” includes a savings bank or cooperative bank which is deemed by the appropriate Federal banking agency to be a savings association under subsection (l).


(B) Uninsured institutionThe term “uninsured institution” means any depository institution the deposits of which are not insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.


(C) CompanyThe term “company” means any corporation, partnership, trust, joint-stock company, or similar organization, but does not include the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Resolution Trust Corporation, any Federal home loan bank, or any company the majority of the shares of which is owned by the United States or any State, or by an instrumentality of the United States or any State.


(D) Savings and loan holding company(i) In generalExcept as provided in clause (ii), the term “savings and loan holding company” means any company that directly or indirectly controls a savings association or that controls any other company that is a savings and loan holding company.


(ii) ExclusionThe term “savings and loan holding company” does not include—(I) a bank holding company that is registered under, and subject to, the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (12 U.S.C. 1841 et seq.), or to any company directly or indirectly controlled by such company (other than a savings association);

(II) a company that controls a savings association that functions solely in a trust or fiduciary capacity as described in section 2(c)(2)(D) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (12 U.S.C. 1841(c)(2)(D)); or

(III) a company described in subsection (c)(9)(C) solely by virtue of such company’s control of an intermediate holding company established pursuant to section 1467b of this title.



(E) Multiple savings and loan holding companyThe term “multiple savings and loan holdi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration and examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Registration and examination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Holding company activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Holding company activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions with affiliates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transactions with affiliates Transactions between any subsidiary savings association of a savings and loan holding company and any affiliate (of such savings association subsidiary) shall be subject to the limitations and prohibitions specified in section 1468 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Acquisitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of dividend</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Declaration of dividend Every subsidiary savings association of a savings and loan holding company shall give the Board not less than 30 days’ advance notice of the proposed declaration by its directors of any dividend on its guaranty, permanent, or other nonwithdrawable stock. Such notice period shall commence to run from the date of receipt of such notice by the Board. Any such dividend declared within such period, or without the giving of such notice to the Board, shall be invalid and shall confer no rights or benefits upon the holder of any such stock.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Administration and enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prohibited acts It shall be unlawful for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1467a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Judicial review Any party aggrieved by an order of the Board under this section may obtain a review of such order by filing in the court of appeals of the United States for the circuit in which the principal office of such party is located, or in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, within 30 days after the date of service of such order, a written petition praying that the order of the Board be modified, terminated, or set aside. A copy of the petition shall be forthwith transmitted by the clerk of the court to the Board, and thereupon the Board shall file in the court the record in the proceeding, as provided in section 2112 of title 28. Upon the filing of such petition, such court shall have jurisdiction, which upon the filing of the record shall be exclusive, to affirm, modify, terminate, or set aside, in whole or in part, the order of the Board. Review of such proceedings shall be had as provided in chapter 7 of title 5. The judgment and decr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>