<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701z–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701z–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701z–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701z_3"><akn:num>1701z–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Experimental housing allowance payment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701z–3. Experimental housing allowance payment program(a) Purpose of paymentsThe Secretary is authorized to undertake on an experimental basis programs to demonstrate the feasibility of providing housing allowance payments to assist families in meeting rental or homeownership expenses.


(b) Termination date of payments; termination date for contracts; contracts for performance of administrative functions(1) No housing allowance payments shall be made after July 1, 1985. After January 1, 1975, the Secretary shall not enter into contracts under the United States Housing Act of 1937 [42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.] to carry out the purposes of this section. The Secretary may contract with public or private agencies for the performance of administrative functions in connection with the programs authorized by this section.

(2) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, to the extent approved in appropriation Acts, extend the annual contributions contracts for the experimental housing allowance supply program through September 30, 1989, on the same terms and conditions as the original contracts, for the sole purpose of providing assistance for homeowners participating in such program on June 1, 1983. In extending such contracts, the Secretary may, to the extent approved in appropriation Acts, use authority available under section 5(c) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [42 U.S.C. 1437c(c)].


(c) Report to CongressThe Secretary shall report to the Congress on his findings pursuant to this section not later than eighteen months after August 22, 1974.


(Pub. L. 91–609, title V, § 504, Dec. 31, 1970, 84 Stat. 1786; Pub. L. 93–383, title VIII, § 804, Aug. 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 725; Pub. L. 94–375, § 23(b), Aug. 3, 1976, 90 Stat. 1078; Pub. L. 98–35, § 6(a), May 26, 1983, 97 Stat. 198.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe United States Housing Act of 1937, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is act Sept. 1, 1937, ch. 896, as revised generally by Pub.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose of payments The Secretary is authorized to undertake on an experimental basis programs to demonstrate the feasibility of providing housing allowance payments to assist families in meeting rental or homeownership expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination date of payments; termination date for contracts; contracts for performance of administrative functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Termination date of payments; termination date for contracts; contracts for performance of administrative functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report to Congress The Secretary shall report to the Congress on his findings pursuant to this section not later than eighteen months after August 22, 1974.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>