<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701x–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701x–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701x–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701x_2"><akn:num>1701x–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Legal assistance for foreclosure-related issues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701x–2. Legal assistance for foreclosure-related issues(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall establish a program for making grants for providing a full range of foreclosure legal assistance to low- and moderate-income homeowners and tenants related to home ownership preservation, home foreclosure prevention, and tenancy associated with home foreclosure.


(b) Competitive allocationThe Secretary shall allocate amounts made available for grants under this section to State and local legal organizations on the basis of a competitive process. For purposes of this subsection “State and local legal organizations” are those State and local organizations whose primary business or mission is to provide legal assistance.


(c) Priority to certain areasIn allocating amounts in accordance with subsection (b), the Secretary shall give priority consideration to State and local legal organizations that are operating in the 125 metropolitan statistical areas (as that term is defined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget) with the highest home foreclosure rates.


(d) Legal assistance(1) In generalAny State or local legal organization that receives financial assistance pursuant to this section may use such amounts only to assist—(A) homeowners of owner-occupied homes with mortgages in default, in danger of default, or subject to or at risk of foreclosure; and

(B) tenants at risk of or subject to eviction as a result of foreclosure of the property in which such tenant resides.


(2) Commence use within 90 daysAny State or local legal organization that receives financial assistance pursuant to this section shall begin using any financial assistance received under this section within 90 days after receipt of the assistance.


(3) Prohibition on class actionsNo funds provided to a State or local legal organization under this section may be used to support any class action litig</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall establish a program for making grants for providing a full range of foreclosure legal assistance to low- and moderate-income homeowners and tenants related to home ownership preservation, home foreclosure prevention, and tenancy associated with home foreclosure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Competitive allocation The Secretary shall allocate amounts made available for grants under this section to State and local legal organizations on the basis of a competitive process. For purposes of this subsection “State and local legal organizations” are those State and local organizations whose primary business or mission is to provide legal assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority to certain areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority to certain areas In allocating amounts in accordance with subsection (b), the Secretary shall give priority consideration to State and local legal organizations that are operating in the 125 metropolitan statistical areas (as that term is defined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget) with the highest home foreclosure rates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Legal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Legal assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on distribution of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on distribution of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2012 for grants under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>