<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701z–16" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701z–16/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701z–16/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701z_16"><akn:num>1701z–16</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy efficient mortgages pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701z–16. Energy efficient mortgages pilot program(a) Establishment of pilot program(1) In generalNot later than 6 months after October 24, 1992, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall establish an energy efficient mortgage pilot program in 5 States, to promote the purchase of existing energy efficient residential buildings and the installation of cost-effective improvements in existing residential buildings.


(2) Pilot programThe pilot program established under this subsection shall include the following criteria, where applicable:(A) OriginationThe lender shall originate a housing loan that is insured under title II of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1707 et seq.] in accordance with the applicable requirements.


(B) ApprovalThe mortgagor’s base loan application shall be approved if the mortgagor’s income and credit record is found to be satisfactory.


(C) Costs of improvementsThe cost of cost-effective energy efficiency improvements shall not exceed the greater of—(i) 5 percent of the property value (not to exceed 5 percent of the limit established under section 203(b)(2)(A)) of the National Housing Act (12 U.S.C. 1709(b)(2)(A); 11 So in original. There probably should be an additional closing parenthesis. or

(ii) 2 percent of the limit established under section 203(b)(2)(B) of such Act [12 U.S.C. 1709(b)(2)(B)].


(D) LimitationIn any fiscal year, the aggregate number of mortgages insured pursuant to this section may not exceed 5 percent of the aggregate number of mortgages for 1- to 4-family residences insured by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under title II of the National Housing Act (12 U.S.C. 1707 et seq.) during the preceding fiscal year.



(3) Authority for mortgageesIn granting mortgages under the pilot program established pursuant to this subsection, the Secretary shall grant mortgagees the authority—(A) to permit the final loan amount to exceed the loan limits establishe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_16_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of pilot program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_16_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expansion of program Not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of the implementation of the energy efficient mortgage pilot program under this section, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall expand the pilot program on a nationwide basis and shall expand the program to include new residential housing, unless the Secretary determines that either such expansion would not be practicable in which case the Secretary shall submit to the Congress, before the expiration of such period, a report explaining why either expansion would not be practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_16_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_16_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of construction This section may not be construed to affect any other programs of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for energy-efficient mortgages. The pilot program carried out under this section shall not replace or result in the termination of such other programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_16_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Secretary shall issue any regulations necessary to carry out this section not later than the expiration of the 180-day period beginning on October 24, 1992. The regulations shall be issued after notice and opportunity for public comment pursuant to the provisions of section 553 of title 5 (notwithstanding subsections (a)(2), (b)(B), and (d)(3) of such section).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_16_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>