<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701x" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701x/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701x/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701x"><akn:num>1701x</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance with respect to housing for low- and moderate-income families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701x. Assistance with respect to housing for low- and moderate-income families(a) Authorization to provide information, advice, and technical assistance; scope of assistance; authorization of appropriations(1) The Secretary is authorized to provide, or contract with public or private organizations to provide, information, advice, and technical assistance, including but not limited to—(i) the assembly, correlation, publication, and dissemination of information with respect to the construction, rehabilitation, and operation of low- and moderate-income housing;

(ii) the provision of advice and technical assistance to public bodies or to nonprofit or cooperative organizations with respect to the construction, rehabilitation, and operation of low- and moderate-income housing, including assistance with respect to self-help and mutual self-help programs;

(iii) counseling and advice to tenants and homeowners with respect to property maintenance, financial management, and such other matters as may be appropriate to assist them in improving their housing conditions and in meeting the responsibilities of tenancy or homeownership; and

(iv) the provision of technical assistance to communities, particularly smaller communities, to assist such communities in planning, developing, and administering Community Development Programs pursuant to title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 [42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.].


(2) The Secretary (A) shall provide the services described in clause (iii) of paragraph (1) for homeowners assisted under section 235 of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1715z]; (B) shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, provide such services for borrowers who are first-time homebuyers with guaranteed loans under section 502(h) of the Housing Act of 1949 [42 U.S.C. 1472(h)]; and (C) may provide such services for other owners of single family dwelling units insured under title II of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1707 et seq.]</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization to provide information, advice, and technical assistance; scope of assistance; authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization to provide information, advice, and technical assistance; scope of assistance; authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans to nonprofit organizations or public housing agencies; purpose and terms; repayment; authorization of appropriations; deposit of appropriations in Low and Moderate Income Sponsor Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Loans to nonprofit organizations or public housing agencies; purpose and terms; repayment; authorization of appropriations; deposit of appropriations in Low and Moderate Income Sponsor Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for homeownership counseling organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants for homeownership counseling organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prepurchase and foreclosure-prevention counseling demonstration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prepurchase and foreclosure-prevention counseling demonstration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Homeownership and rental counselor training and certification programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Homeownership and rental counselor training and certification programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures and activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Procedures and activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701x_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability for recipients of covered assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Accountability for recipients of covered assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>