<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701q"><akn:num>1701q</akn:num><akn:heading>Supportive housing for the elderly</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701q. Supportive housing for the elderly(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to enable elderly persons to live with dignity and independence by expanding the supply of supportive housing that—(1) is designed to accommodate the special needs of elderly persons; and

(2) provides a range of services that are tailored to the needs of elderly persons occupying such housing.


(b) General authorityThe Secretary is authorized to provide assistance to private nonprofit organizations and consumer cooperatives to expand the supply of supportive housing for the elderly. Such assistance shall be provided as (1) capital advances in accordance with subsection (c)(1), and (2) contracts for project rental assistance in accordance with subsection (c)(2). Such assistance may be used to finance the construction, reconstruction, or moderate or substantial rehabilitation of a structure or a portion of a structure, or the acquisition of a structure, to be used as supportive housing for the elderly in accordance with this section. Assistance may also cover the cost of real property acquisition, site improvement, conversion, demolition, relocation, and other expenses that the Secretary determines are necessary to expand the supply of supportive housing for the elderly.


(c) Forms of assistance(1) Capital advancesA capital advance provided under this section shall bear no interest and its repayment shall not be required so long as the housing remains available for very low-income elderly persons in accordance with this section. Such advance shall be in an amount calculated in accordance with the development cost limitation established in subsection (h).


(2) Project rental assistanceContracts for project rental assistance shall obligate the Secretary to make monthly payments to cover any part of the costs attributed to units occupied (or, as approved by the Secretary, held for occupancy) by very low-income elderly persons that is not met from project income. The annual contract a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to enable elderly persons to live with dignity and independence by expanding the supply of supportive housing that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General authority The Secretary is authorized to provide assistance to private nonprofit organizations and consumer cooperatives to expand the supply of supportive housing for the elderly. Such assistance shall be provided as (1) capital advances in accordance with subsection (c)(1), and (2) contracts for project rental assistance in accordance with subsection (c)(2). Such assistance may be used to finance the construction, reconstruction, or moderate or substantial rehabilitation of a structure or a portion of a structure, or the acquisition of a structure, to be used as supportive housing for the elderly in accordance with this section. Assistance may also cover the cost of real property acquisition, site improvement, conversion, demolition, relocation, and other expenses that the Secretary determines are necessary to expand the supply of supportive housing for the elderly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forms of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Forms of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of commitment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Term of commitment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applications Funds made available under this section shall be allocated by the Secretary among approvable applications submitted by private nonprofit organizations. Applications for assistance under this section shall be submitted by an applicant in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary shall establish. Such applications shall contain— The Secretary shall not reject an application on technical grounds without giving notice of that rejection and the basis therefor to the applicant and affording the applicant an opportunity to respond.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial selection criteria and processing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Initial selection criteria and processing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Provisions of services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development cost limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Development cost limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tenant selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Tenant selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Miscellaneous provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>