<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701g–5b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701g–5b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701g–5b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701g_5b"><akn:num>1701g–5b</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation of New Communities Program; cancellation of debt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701g–5b. Liquidation of New Communities Program; cancellation of debt(a) Law applicableIn order to provide for the management and orderly liquidation of the assets, and discharge the liabilities, acquired or incurred in connection with the new communities program authorized pursuant to title IV of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 [42 U.S.C. 3901 et seq.] and title VII of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1970 [42 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.] (hereafter referred to in this section as “title IV” and “title VII”, respectively), the liquidation of the new communities program shall be carried out pursuant to the provisions of law applicable to the revolving fund (liquidating programs) established pursuant to title II of the Independent Offices Appropriations Act, 1955 [12 U.S.C. 1701g–5], upon the transfer by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) of the assets and liabilities of the fund authorized under section 717 of title VII [42 U.S.C. 4518] to such revolving fund, as required in title I of the Department of Housing and Urban Development-Independent Agencies Appropriation Act, 1984 [12 U.S.C. 1701g–5a]. The Secretary shall report to the Congress not less than sixty days prior to taking any action with respect to the disposition of real property (other than a purchase money mortgage) which involves any further potential liability of or assistance from the Department of Housing and Urban Development with respect to any property so transferred.


(b) Availability of revolving fund moneys for administrative and other expensesIn carrying out the purposes of subsection (a), all moneys in the revolving fund (liquidating programs) shall be available for necessary administrative and other expenses of servicing and liquidating obligations guaranteed pursuant to section 403 and section 713 of title IV and title VII, respectively [42 U.S.C. 3902, 4514], including costs of services (including legal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701g_5b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Law applicable In order to provide for the management and orderly liquidation of the assets, and discharge the liabilities, acquired or incurred in connection with the new communities program authorized pursuant to title IV of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 [42 U.S.C. 3901 et seq.] and title VII of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1970 [42 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.] (hereafter referred to in this section as “title IV” and “title VII”, respectively), the liquidation of the new communities program shall be carried out pursuant to the provisions of law applicable to the revolving fund (liquidating programs) established pursuant to title II of the Independent Offices Appropriations Act, 1955 [12 U.S.C. 1701g–5], upon the transfer by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) of the assets and liabilities of the fund authorized under section 717 of title VII [42 U.S.C. 4518] to such revolving fund, as requir</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701g_5b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of revolving fund moneys for administrative and other expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of revolving fund moneys for administrative and other expenses In carrying out the purposes of subsection (a), all moneys in the revolving fund (liquidating programs) shall be available for necessary administrative and other expenses of servicing and liquidating obligations guaranteed pursuant to section 403 and section 713 of title IV and title VII, respectively [42 U.S.C. 3902, 4514], including costs of services (including legal services) performed on a contract or fee basis, and to discharge any other liability acquired or incurred in connection with the new communities program. Notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of real and other property by the United States, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall also have power, for the protection of the interests of the revolving fund (liquidating programs), to pay out of any moneys in such fund all expenses or charges in connection with the a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701g_5b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of obligations to Secretary of the Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Issuance of obligations to Secretary of the Treasury After making the transfer required in title I of the Department of Housing and Urban Development-Independent Agencies Appropriation Act, 1984 [12 U.S.C. 1701g–5a], the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may issue obligations to the Secretary of the Treasury in an amount sufficient to enable the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to satisfy any guarantee made pursuant to section 403 or 713 of title IV or title VII, respectively [42 U.S.C. 3902, 4514], and otherwise carry out the functions authorized by this section. The obligations issued under this subsection shall have such maturities and bear such rate or rates of interest as shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury. The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to purchase any obligations so issued, and for that purpose the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to use as a public debt transaction the proceeds from the sale of any securi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701g_5b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation of obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cancellation of obligations Upon the transfer required in title I of the Department of Housing and Urban Development-Independent Agencies Appropriation Act, 1984 [12 U.S.C. 1701g–5a], each obligation issued by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to section 407(a) or 717(b) of title IV or title VII, respectively [42 U.S.C. 3906(a), 4518(b)], together with any promise to repay the principal and unpaid interest which has accrued on each obligation, and any other term or condition specified by each such obligation, is canceled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>