<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701u" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701u/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701u/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701u"><akn:num>1701u</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic opportunities for low- and very low-income persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701u. Economic opportunities for low- and very low-income persons(a) FindingsThe Congress finds that—(1) Federal housing and community development programs provide State and local governments and other recipients of Federal financial assistance with substantial funds for projects and activities that produce significant employment and other economic opportunities;

(2) low- and very low-income persons, especially recipients of government assistance for housing, often have restricted access to employment and other economic opportunities;

(3) the employment and other economic opportunities generated by projects and activities that receive Federal housing and community development assistance offer an effective means of empowering low- and very low-income persons, particularly persons who are recipients of government assistance for housing; and

(4) prior Federal efforts to direct employment and other economic opportunities generated by Federal housing and community development programs to low- and very low-income persons have not been fully effective and should be intensified.


(b) PolicyIt is the policy of the Congress and the purpose of this section to ensure that the employment and other economic opportunities generated by Federal financial assistance for housing and community development programs shall, to the greatest extent feasible, be directed toward low- and very low-income persons, particularly those who are recipients of government assistance for housing.


(c) Employment(1) Public and Indian housing program(A) In generalThe Secretary shall require that public and Indian housing agencies, and their contractors and subcontractors, make their best efforts, consistent with existing Federal, State, and local laws and regulations, to give to low- and very low-income persons the training and employment opportunities generated by development assistance provided pursuant to section 1437c of title 42, operating assistance provided pursuant to section 1437g of tit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701u_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings The Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701u_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Policy It is the policy of the Congress and the purpose of this section to ensure that the employment and other economic opportunities generated by Federal financial assistance for housing and community development programs shall, to the greatest extent feasible, be directed toward low- and very low-income persons, particularly those who are recipients of government assistance for housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701u_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Employment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701u_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contracting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701u_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For the purposes of this section the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701u_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with other Federal agencies The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, and such other Federal agencies as the Secretary determines are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701u_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations Not later than 180 days after October 28, 1992, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>