<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701z–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701z–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701z–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701z_8"><akn:num>1701z–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy conservation and renewable-resource demonstration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701z–8. Energy conservation and renewable-resource demonstration(a) National demonstration program; purposeThe Secretary shall undertake a national demonstration program designed to test the feasibility and effectiveness of various forms of financial assistance for encouraging the installation or implementation of approved energy conservation measures and approved renewable-resource energy measures in existing dwelling units. The Secretary shall carry out such demonstration program with a view toward recommending a national program or programs designed to reduce significantly the consumption of energy in existing dwelling units.


(b) Financial assistance to owners and tenants of dwelling units; authorization of SecretaryThe Secretary is authorized to make financial assistance available pursuant to this section in the form of grants, low-interest-rate loans, interest subsidies, loan guarantees, and such other forms of assistance as the Secretary deems appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section. Assistance may be made available to both owners of dwelling units and tenants occupying such units.


(c) Duties of SecretaryIn carrying out the demonstration program required by this section, the Secretary shall—(1) provide assistance in a wide variety of geographic areas to reflect differences in climate, types of dwelling units, and income levels of recipients in order to provide a national profile for use in designing a program which is to be operational and effective nationwide;

(2) evaluate the appropriateness of various financial incentives for different income levels of owners and occupants of existing dwelling units;

(3) take into account and evaluate any other financial assistance which may be available for the installation or implementation of energy conservation and renewable-resource energy measures;

(4) make use of such State and local instrumentalities or other public or private entities as may be appropriate in carrying out the purposes of thi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National demonstration program; purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National demonstration program; purpose The Secretary shall undertake a national demonstration program designed to test the feasibility and effectiveness of various forms of financial assistance for encouraging the installation or implementation of approved energy conservation measures and approved renewable-resource energy measures in existing dwelling units. The Secretary shall carry out such demonstration program with a view toward recommending a national program or programs designed to reduce significantly the consumption of energy in existing dwelling units.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance to owners and tenants of dwelling units; authorization of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Financial assistance to owners and tenants of dwelling units; authorization of Secretary The Secretary is authorized to make financial assistance available pursuant to this section in the form of grants, low-interest-rate loans, interest subsidies, loan guarantees, and such other forms of assistance as the Secretary deems appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section. Assistance may be made available to both owners of dwelling units and tenants occupying such units.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties of Secretary In carrying out the demonstration program required by this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on grants; modification and exceptions to limitation; eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations on grants; modification and exceptions to limitation; eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions upon availability of financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conditions upon availability of financial assistance The Secretary may condition the availability of financial assistance with respect to the installation and implementation of any renewable-resource energy measure on such measure’s meeting performance standards for reliability and efficiency and such certification procedures as the Secretary may, in consultation with the Administrator, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and other appropriate Federal agencies, prescribe for the purpose of protecting consumers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Implementation of program In carrying out the demonstration program required by this section, the Secretary is authorized to delegate responsibilities to, or to contract with, other Federal agencies or with such State or local instrumentalities or other public or private bodies as the Secretary may deem desirable. Such demonstration program shall be coordinated, to the extent practicable, with the State energy conservation plans as described in, and implemented pursuant to, part C of title III of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act [42 U.S.C. 6321 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim and final reports on program progress, findings, and legislative recommendations; criteria for evaluation of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Interim and final reports on program progress, findings, and legislative recommendations; criteria for evaluation of projects The Secretary shall submit an interim report to the Congress not later than 6 months after August 14, 1976, (and every 6 months thereafter until the final report is made under this subsection) indicating the progress made in carrying out the demonstration program required by this section and shall submit a final report to the Congress, containing findings and legislative recommendations, not later than 2 years after August 14, 1976. As part of each report made under this subsection, the Secretary shall include an evaluation, based on the criteria described in subsection (h), of each demonstration project conducted under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on evaluation criteria to be used and results sought prior to funding of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report on evaluation criteria to be used and results sought prior to funding of projects Prior to undertaking any demonstration proj­ect under this section, the Secretary shall specify and report to the Congress the criteria by which the Secretary will evaluate the effectiveness of the project and the results to be sought.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701z_8_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated, for purposes of this section, not to exceed $200,000,000. Any amount appropriated pursuant to this subsection shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>