<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701s"><akn:num>1701s</akn:num><akn:heading>Rent supplement payments for qualified lower income families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701s. Rent supplement payments for qualified lower income families(a) Authorization; maximum term; maximum aggregate amountThe Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) is authorized to make, and contract to make, annual payments to a “housing owner” on behalf of “qualified tenants”, as those terms are defined herein, in such amounts and under such circumstances as are prescribed in or pursuant to this section. In no case shall a contract provide for such payments with respect to any housing for a period exceeding forty years. The aggregate amount of the contracts to make such payments shall not exceed amounts approved in appropriation Acts, and payments pursuant to such contracts shall not exceed $150,000,000 per annum prior to July 1, 1969, which maximum dollar amount shall be increased by $40,000,000, on July 1, 1969, by $100,000,000 on July 1, 1970, and by $40,000,000 on July 1, 1971.


(b) “Housing owner” defined; limitation on payments to housing ownerAs used in this section, the term “housing owner” means a private nonprofit corporation or other private nonprofit legal entity, a limited dividend corporation or other limited dividend legal entity, or a cooperative housing corporation, which is a mortgagor under section 221(d)(3) of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1715l(d)(3)] and which, after August 10, 1965, has been approved for mortgage insurance thereunder and has been approved for receiving the benefits of this section: Provided, That, except as provided in subsection (j), no payments under this section may be made with respect to any property financed with a mortgage receiving the benefits of the interest rate provided for in the proviso in section 221(d)(5) of that Act [12 U.S.C. 1715l(d)(5)]. Such term also includes a private nonprofit corporation or other private nonprofit legal entity, a limited dividend corporation or other limited dividend legal entity, or a cooperative housing corporation, which</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization; maximum term; maximum aggregate amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization; maximum term; maximum aggregate amount The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) is authorized to make, and contract to make, annual payments to a “housing owner” on behalf of “qualified tenants”, as those terms are defined herein, in such amounts and under such circumstances as are prescribed in or pursuant to this section. In no case shall a contract provide for such payments with respect to any housing for a period exceeding forty years. The aggregate amount of the contracts to make such payments shall not exceed amounts approved in appropriation Acts, and payments pursuant to such contracts shall not exceed $150,000,000 per annum prior to July 1, 1969, which maximum dollar amount shall be increased by $40,000,000, on July 1, 1969, by $100,000,000 on July 1, 1970, and by $40,000,000 on July 1, 1971.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Housing owner” defined; limitation on payments to housing owner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Housing owner” defined; limitation on payments to housing owner As used in this section, the term “housing owner” means a private nonprofit corporation or other private nonprofit legal entity, a limited dividend corporation or other limited dividend legal entity, or a cooperative housing corporation, which is a mortgagor under section 221(d)(3) of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1715l(d)(3)] and which, after August 10, 1965, has been approved for mortgage insurance thereunder and has been approved for receiving the benefits of this section: Provided, That, except as provided in subsection (j), no payments under this section may be made with respect to any property financed with a mortgage receiving the benefits of the interest rate provided for in the proviso in section 221(d)(5) of that Act [12 U.S.C. 1715l(d)(5)]. Such term also includes a private nonprofit corporation or other private nonprofit legal entity, a limited dividend corporation or other limited dividend legal ent</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions As used in this section, the term— The terms “qualified tenant” and “tenant” include a member of a cooperative who satisfies the foregoing requirements and who, upon resale of his membership to the cooperative, will not be reimbursed for any equity increment accumulated through payments under this section. With respect to members of a cooperative, the terms “rental” and “rental charges” mean the charges under the occupancy agreements between such members and the cooperative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual payment amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual payment amount The amount of the annual payment with respect to any dwelling unit shall be the lesser of (1) 70 per centum of the fair market rent, or (2) the amount by which the fair market rental for such unit exceeds 30 per centum of the tenant’s adjusted income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria and procedure for determining eligibility and rental charges; recertification of income; agreements for services required in selection of tenants; delegation of authority to issue certificates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Criteria and procedure for determining eligibility and rental charges; recertification of income; agreements for services required in selection of tenants; delegation of authority to issue certificates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authority of Secretary The Secretary is authorized to make such rules and regulations, to enter into such agreements, and to adopt such procedures as he may deem necessary or desirable to carry out the provisions of this section. Nothing contained in this section shall affect the authority of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development with respect to any housing assisted under this section, section 221(d)(3), section 231(c)(3), or section 236 of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1715l(d)(3), 1715v(c)(3), 1715z–1], or section 1701q of this title, including the authority to prescribe occupancy requirements under other provisions of law or to determine the portion of such housing which may be occupied by qualified tenants. To ensure that qualified tenants occupying that number of units with respect to which assistance was being provided under this section immediately prior to November 30, 1983, receive the benefit of assistance contracted for under this section, the Secretary sh</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section, including, but not limited to, such sums as may be necessary to make annual payments as prescribed in this section, pay for services provided under (or pursuant to agreements entered into under) subsection (e), and provide administrative expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701s_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional definition of housing owner; restrictions on payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Additional definition of housing owner; restrictions on payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>