<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701q–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701q–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1701q–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701q_1"><akn:num>1701q–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil money penalties against mortgagors under section 1701q of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701q–1. Civil money penalties against mortgagors under section 1701q of this title(a) In generalThe penalties set forth in this section shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or criminal penalty, and may be imposed whether or not the Secretary imposes other administrative sanctions. The Secretary may not impose penalties under this section for violations a material cause of which are the failure of the Department, an agent of the Department, or a public housing agency to comply with existing agreements.


(b) Penalty for violation of agreement as condition of transfer of physical assets, flexible subsidy loan, capital improvement loan, modification of mortgage terms, or workout agreement(1) In generalWhenever a mortgagor of property that includes 5 or more living units and that has a mortgage held pursuant to section 1701q of this title, who has agreed in writing, as a condition of a transfer of physical assets, a flexible subsidy loan, a capital improvement loan, a modification of the mortgage terms, or a workout agreement, to use nonproject income to make cash contributions for payments due under the note and mortgage, for payments to the reserve for replacements, to restore the project to good physical condition, or to pay other project liabilities, knowingly and materially fails to comply with any of these commitments, the Secretary may impose a civil money penalty on the mortgagor in accordance with the provisions of this section.


(2) AmountThe amount of the penalty, as determined by the Secretary, for a violation of this subsection may not exceed the amount of the loss the Secretary would incur at a foreclosure sale, or sale after foreclosure, with respect to the property involved.



(c) Violations of regulatory agreement(1) In generalThe Secretary may also impose a civil money penalty on a mortgagor or property that includes 5 or more living units and that has a mortgage held pursuant to section 1701q of this title for any knowing and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The penalties set forth in this section shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or criminal penalty, and may be imposed whether or not the Secretary imposes other administrative sanctions. The Secretary may not impose penalties under this section for violations a material cause of which are the failure of the Department, an agent of the Department, or a public housing agency to comply with existing agreements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for violation of agreement as condition of transfer of physical assets, flexible subsidy loan, capital improvement loan, modification of mortgage terms, or workout agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalty for violation of agreement as condition of transfer of physical assets, flexible subsidy loan, capital improvement loan, modification of mortgage terms, or workout agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations of regulatory agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Violations of regulatory agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Agency procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of agency determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Judicial review of agency determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to collect penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Action to collect penalty If a mortgagor fails to comply with the Secretary’s determination or order imposing a civil money penalty under subsection (b) or (c), after the determination or order is no longer subject to review as provided by subsections (d)(1) and (e), the Secretary may request the Attorney General of the United States to bring an action in an appropriate United States district court to obtain a monetary judgment against the mortgagor and such other relief as may be available. The monetary judgment may, in the court’s discretion, include the attorneys fees and other expenses incurred by the United States in connection with the action. In an action under this subsection, the validity and appropriateness of the Secretary’s determination or order imposing the penalty shall not be subject to review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Settlement by Secretary The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit any civil money penalty which may be, or has been, imposed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Knowingly” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Knowingly” defined The term “knowingly” means having actual knowledge of or acting with deliberate ignorance of or reckless disregard for the prohibitions under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Secretary shall issue such regulations as the Secretary deems appropriate to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701q_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of penalties in insurance funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Deposit of penalties in insurance funds Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all civil money penalties collected under this section shall be deposited in the fund established under section 1715z–1a(j) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>