<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1708" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1708/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1708/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1708"><akn:num>1708</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Housing Administration operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1708. Federal Housing Administration operations(a) Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund(1) EstablishmentSubject to the provisions of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 [2 U.S.C. 661 et seq.], there is hereby created a Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund (in this subchapter referred to as the “Fund”), which shall be used by the Secretary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter with respect to mortgages insured under section 1709 of this title. The Secretary may enter into commitments to guarantee, and may guarantee, such insured mortgages.


(2) Limit on loan guaranteesThe authority of the Secretary to enter into commitments to guarantee such insured mortgages shall be effective for any fiscal year only to the extent that the aggregate original principal loan amount under such mortgages, any part of which is guaranteed, does not exceed the amount specified in appropriations Acts for such fiscal year.


(3) Fiduciary responsibilityThe Secretary has a responsibility to ensure that the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund remains financially sound.


(4) Annual independent actuarial studyThe Secretary shall provide for an independent actuarial study of the Fund to be conducted annually, which shall analyze the financial position of the Fund. The Secretary shall submit a report annually to the Congress describing the results of such study and assessing the financial status of the Fund. The report shall recommend adjustments to underwriting standards, program participation, or premiums, if necessary, to ensure that the Fund remains financially sound. The report shall also include an evaluation of the quality control procedures and accuracy of information utilized in the process of underwriting loans guaranteed by the Fund. Such evaluation shall include a review of the risk characteristics of loans based not only on borrower information and performance, but on risks associated with loans originated or funded by various entities or financial institutions.


(5) Quarterly reports</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advisory Board There is created a Federal Housing Administration Advisory Board (“Board”) that shall review operation of the Federal Housing Administration, including the activities of the Mortgagee Review Board, and shall provide advice to the Federal Housing Commissioner with respect to the formulation of general policies of the Federal Housing Administration and such other matters as the Federal Housing Commissioner may deem appropriate. The Advisory Board shall, in all other respects, be subject to the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgagee Review Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mortgagee Review Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on participation in origination and mortgagee approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations on participation in origination and mortgagee approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of GNMA and FHA withdrawal action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination of GNMA and FHA withdrawal action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension or revocation of approval of mortgagee; notice and statement of reasons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Suspension or revocation of approval of mortgagee; notice and statement of reasons Whenever the Secretary has taken any discretionary action to suspend or revoke the approval of any mortgagee to participate in any mortgage insurance program under this subchapter, the Secretary shall provide prompt notice of the action and a statement of the reasons for the action to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Appraisal standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of name</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of name The Secretary shall, by regulation, require each mortgagee approved by the Secretary for participation in the FHA mortgage insurance programs of the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>