<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1709" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1709/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1709/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1709"><akn:num>1709</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance of mortgages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1709. Insurance of mortgages(a) AuthorizationThe Secretary is authorized, upon application by the mortgagee, to insure as hereinafter provided any mortgage offered to him which is eligible for insurance as hereinafter provided, and, upon such terms as the Secretary may prescribe, to make commitments for the insuring of such mortgages prior to the date of their execution or disbursement thereon.


(b) Eligibility for insurance; mortgage limitsTo be eligible for insurance under this section a mortgage shall comply with the following:(1) Have been made to, and be held by, a mortgagee approved by the Secretary as responsible and able to service the mortgage properly.

(2) Involve a principal obligation (including such initial service charges, appraisal, inspection, and other fees as the Secretary shall approve) in an amount—(A) not to exceed the lesser of—(i) in the case of a 1-family residence, 115 percent of the median 1-family house price in the area, as determined by the Secretary; and in the case of a 2-, 3-, or 4-family residence, the percentage of such median price that bears the same ratio to such median price as the dollar amount limitation determined under the sixth sentence of section 1454(a)(2) of this title for a 2-, 3-, or 4-family residence, respectively, bears to the dollar amount limitation determined under such section for a 1-family residence; or

(ii) 150 percent of the dollar amount limitation determined under the sixth sentence of such section 1454(a)(2) for a residence of applicable size;


except that the dollar amount limitation in effect under this subparagraph for any size residence for any area may not be less than the greater of: (I) the dollar amount limitation in effect under this section for the area on October 21, 1998; or (II) 65 percent of the dollar amount limitation determined under the sixth sentence of such section 1454(a)(2) for a residence of the applicable size; and

(B) not to exceed 100 percent of the appraised value of the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization The Secretary is authorized, upon application by the mortgagee, to insure as hereinafter provided any mortgage offered to him which is eligible for insurance as hereinafter provided, and, upon such terms as the Secretary may prescribe, to make commitments for the insuring of such mortgages prior to the date of their execution or disbursement thereon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for insurance; mortgage limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility for insurance; mortgage limits To be eligible for insurance under this section a mortgage shall comply with the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premium charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Premium charges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increase in maximum amount of mortgage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Increase in maximum amount of mortgage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract of insurance as evidence of eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contract of insurance as evidence of eligibility Any contract of insurance heretofore or hereafter executed by the Secretary under this subchapter shall be conclusive evidence of the eligibility of the loan or mortgage for insurance, and the validity of any contract of insurance so executed shall be incontestable in the hands of an approved financial institution or approved mortgagee from the date of the execution of such contract, except for fraud or misrepresentation on the part of such approved financial institution or approved mortgagee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of other mortgage products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosure of other mortgage products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of single family mortgage insurance by investors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on use of single family mortgage insurance by investors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disaster housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Disaster housing Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary is authorized to insure any mortgage which involves a principal obligation not in excess of the applicable maximum dollar limit under subsection (b) and not in excess of 100 per centum of the appraised value of a property upon which there is located a dwelling designed principally for a single-family residence, where the mortgagor establishes (to the satisfaction of the Secretary) that his home which he occupied as an owner or as a tenant was destroyed or damaged to such an extent that reconstruction is required as a result of a flood, fire, hurricane, earthquake, storm, or other catastrophe which the President, pursuant to sections 5122(2) and 5170 of title 42, has determined to be a major disaster.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 110–289, div. B, title I, § 2120(a)(1), July 30, 2008, 122 Stat. 2835</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Real estate loans by national banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Real estate loans by national banks Loans secured by mortgages insured under this section shall not be taken into account in determining the amount of real estate loans which a national bank may make in relation to its capital and surplus or its time and savings deposits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>