<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1711"><akn:num>1711</akn:num><akn:heading>General Surplus and Participating Reserve Accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1711. General Surplus and Participating Reserve Accounts(a) Establishment; abolishment of General Reinsurance AccountThe Secretary shall establish as of July 1, 1954, in the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund a General Surplus Account and a Participating Reserve Account. All of the assets of the General Reinsurance Account shall be transferred to the General Surplus Account whereupon the General Reinsurance Account shall be abolished. There shall be transferred from the various group accounts to the Participating Reserve Account as of July 1, 1954, an amount equal to the aggregate amount which would have been distributed under the provisions of this section in effect on June 30, 1954, if all outstanding mortgages in such group accounts had been paid in full on said date. All of the remaining balances of said group accounts shall as of said date be transferred to the General Surplus Account whereupon all of said group accounts shall be abolished.


(b) Credits and chargesThe aggregate net income thereafter received or any net loss thereafter sustained by the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund in any semiannual period shall be credited or charged to the General Surplus Account and/or the Participating Reserve Account in such manner and amounts as the Secretary may determine to be in accord with sound actuarial and accounting practice.


(c) Distribution of funds to terminating mortgagorsUpon termination of the insurance obligation of the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund by payment of any mortgage insured thereunder, the Secretary is authorized to distribute to the mortgagor a share of the Participating Reserve Account in such manner and amount as the Secretary shall determine to be equitable and in accordance with sound actuarial and accounting practice: Provided, That, in no event, shall any such distributable share exceed the aggregate scheduled annual premiums of the mortgagor to the year of termination of the insurance. The Secretary shall not distribute any share to an e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; abolishment of General Reinsurance Account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; abolishment of General Reinsurance Account The Secretary shall establish as of July 1, 1954, in the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund a General Surplus Account and a Participating Reserve Account. All of the assets of the General Reinsurance Account shall be transferred to the General Surplus Account whereupon the General Reinsurance Account shall be abolished. There shall be transferred from the various group accounts to the Participating Reserve Account as of July 1, 1954, an amount equal to the aggregate amount which would have been distributed under the provisions of this section in effect on June 30, 1954, if all outstanding mortgages in such group accounts had been paid in full on said date. All of the remaining balances of said group accounts shall as of said date be transferred to the General Surplus Account whereupon all of said group accounts shall be abolished.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credits and charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Credits and charges The aggregate net income thereafter received or any net loss thereafter sustained by the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund in any semiannual period shall be credited or charged to the General Surplus Account and/or the Participating Reserve Account in such manner and amounts as the Secretary may determine to be in accord with sound actuarial and accounting practice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of funds to terminating mortgagors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distribution of funds to terminating mortgagors Upon termination of the insurance obligation of the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund by payment of any mortgage insured thereunder, the Secretary is authorized to distribute to the mortgagor a share of the Participating Reserve Account in such manner and amount as the Secretary shall determine to be equitable and in accordance with sound actuarial and accounting practice: Provided, That, in no event, shall any such distributable share exceed the aggregate scheduled annual premiums of the mortgagor to the year of termination of the insurance. The Secretary shall not distribute any share to an eligible mortgagor under this subsection beginning on the date which is 6 years after the date the Secretary first transmitted written notification of eligibility to the last known address of the mortgagor, unless the mortgagor has applied in accordance with procedures prescribed by the Secretary for payment of the share within the 6-year period. Th</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights and liabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rights and liabilities No mortgagor or mortgagee of any mortgage insured under section 1709 of this title shall have any vested right in a credit balance in any such account or be subject to any liability arising out of the mutuality of the Fund and the determination of the Secretary as to the amount to be paid by him to any mortgagor shall be final and conclusive.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actuarial status of entire Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Actuarial status of entire Fund In determining whether there is a surplus for distribution to mortgagors under this section, the Secretary shall take into account the actuarial status of the entire Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital ratio for Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Capital ratio for Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>