<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–12" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–12/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–12/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715z_12"><akn:num>1715z–12</akn:num><akn:heading>Single-family mortgage insurance on Hawaiian home lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715z–12. Single-family mortgage insurance on Hawaiian home lands(a) One- to four-family residence; eligibilityThe Secretary, subject to such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, may insure under any provision of this subchapter that authorizes such insurance, a mortgage covering a property upon which there is located a one- to four-family residence, without regard to any limitation in this chapter relating to marketability of title or any other limitation in this chapter that the Secretary determines is contrary to promoting the availability of such insurance on Hawaiian home lands, if—(1) the mortgage is executed by a native Hawaiian on property located within Hawaiian home lands covered under a homestead lease issued under section 207(a) of the Hawaiian Homes Commission Act, 1920, or under the corresponding provision of the Constitution of the State of Hawaii adopted under section 4 of the Act entitled “An Act to provide for the admission of the State of Hawaii into the Union”, approved March 18, 1959 (73 Stat. 5);

(2) the property will be used as the principal residence of the mortgagor; and

(3) the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands of the State of Hawaii (A) is a comortgagor; (B) guarantees to reimburse the Secretary for any mortgage insurance claim paid in connection with a property on Hawaiian home lands; or (C) offers other security acceptable to the Secretary.


(b) Construction advancesNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Secretary may, with respect to mortgages eligible for insurance under subsection (a), insure and make commitments to insure advances made during construction if the Secretary determines that the proposed construction is otherwise acceptable and that no feasible financing alternative is available.


(c) Insurance of mortgage as obligation of General Insurance FundNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the insurance of a mortgage using the authority contained in this section shall be the obligatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_12_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>One- to four-family residence; eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) One- to four-family residence; eligibility The Secretary, subject to such conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, may insure under any provision of this subchapter that authorizes such insurance, a mortgage covering a property upon which there is located a one- to four-family residence, without regard to any limitation in this chapter relating to marketability of title or any other limitation in this chapter that the Secretary determines is contrary to promoting the availability of such insurance on Hawaiian home lands, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_12_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction advances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Construction advances Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Secretary may, with respect to mortgages eligible for insurance under subsection (a), insure and make commitments to insure advances made during construction if the Secretary determines that the proposed construction is otherwise acceptable and that no feasible financing alternative is available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_12_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance of mortgage as obligation of General Insurance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Insurance of mortgage as obligation of General Insurance Fund Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the insurance of a mortgage using the authority contained in this section shall be the obligation of the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund. The mortgagee shall be eligible to receive the benefits of insurance as provided in section 1710 of this title with respect to mortgages insured pursuant to this section, except that all references in section 1710 of this title to section 1709 of this title shall be construed to refer to the section under which the mortgage is insured.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_12_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Native Hawaiian” and “Hawaiian home lands” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Native Hawaiian” and “Hawaiian home lands” defined For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_12_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of eligibility for existing lessees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certification of eligibility for existing lessees Possession of a lease of Hawaiian home lands issued under section 207(a) of the Hawaiian Homes Commission Act of 1920 (42 Stat. 110), shall be sufficient to certify eligibility to receive a mortgage under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>