<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715l"><akn:num>1715l</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing for moderate income and displaced families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715l. Housing for moderate income and displaced families
(a) Purpose
This section is designed to assist private industry in providing housing for low and moderate income families and displaced families.
(b) Authorization
The Secretary is authorized, upon application by the mortgagee, to insure under this section as hereinafter provided any mortgage (including advances during construction on mortgages covering property of the character described in paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (d) of this section) which is eligible for insurance as provided herein and, upon such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, to make commitments for the insurance of such mortgages prior to the date of their execution or disbursement thereon.
(c) Definitions
As used in this section, the terms “mortgage”, “first mortgage”, “mortgagee”, “mortgagor”, “maturity date” and “State” shall have the same meaning as in section 1707 of this title.
(d) Eligibility for insurance; conditions; limits
To be eligible for insurance under this section, a mortgage shall—
(1) have been made to and be held by a mortgagee approved by the Secretary as responsible and able to service the mortgage properly;
(2) be secured by property upon which there is located a dwelling conforming to applicable standards prescribed by the Secretary under subsection (f) of this section, and meeting the requirements of all State laws, or local ordinances or regulations, relating to the public health or safety, zoning, or otherwise, which may be applicable thereto, and shall involve a principal obligation (including such initial service charges, appraisal, inspection, and other fees as the Secretary shall approve) in an amount (A) not to exceed (i) $31,000 (or $36,000, if the mortgagor’s family includes five or more persons) in the case of a property upon which there is located a dwelling designed principally for a single-family residence, (ii) $35,000 in the case of a property upon which there is located a dwell</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>