<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715u" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715u/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715u/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715u"><akn:num>1715u</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to assist mortgagors in default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715u. Authority to assist mortgagors in default(a) Loss mitigationUpon default or imminent default, as defined by the Secretary 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. of any mortgage insured under this subchapter, mortgagees shall engage in loss mitigation actions for the purpose of providing an alternative to foreclosure (including but not limited to actions such as special forbearance, loan modification, preforeclosure sale, support for borrower housing counseling, subordinate lien resolution, borrower incentives, and deeds in lieu of foreclosure, as required, but not including assignment of mortgages to the Secretary under section 1710(a)(1)(A) of this title) or subsection (c),22 So in original. Probably should be “section 1710(a)(1)(A) of this title or subsection (c)),”. as provided in regulations by the Secretary.


(b) Payment of partial claim(1) Establishment of programThe Secretary may establish a program for payment of a partial claim to a mortgagee that agrees to apply the claim amount to payment of a mortgage on a 1- to 4-family residence that is in default or faces imminent default, as defined by the Secretary.


(2) Payments and exceptionsAny payment of a partial claim under the program established in paragraph (1) to a mortgagee shall be made in the sole discretion of the Secretary and on terms and conditions acceptable to the Secretary, except that—(A) the amount of the payment shall be in an amount determined by the Secretary, not to exceed an amount equivalent to 30 percent of the unpaid principal balance of the mortgage and any costs that are approved by the Secretary;

(B) the amount of the partial claim payment shall first be applied to any arrearage on the mortgage, and may also be applied to achieve principal reduction;

(C) the mortgagor shall agree to repay the amount of the insurance claim to the Secretary upon terms and conditions acceptable to the Secretary;

(D) the Secretary may permit compensation to the mortgagee</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715u_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loss mitigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Loss mitigation Upon default or imminent default, as defined by the Secretary 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. of any mortgage insured under this subchapter, mortgagees shall engage in loss mitigation actions for the purpose of providing an alternative to foreclosure (including but not limited to actions such as special forbearance, loan modification, preforeclosure sale, support for borrower housing counseling, subordinate lien resolution, borrower incentives, and deeds in lieu of foreclosure, as required, but not including assignment of mortgages to the Secretary under section 1710(a)(1)(A) of this title) or subsection (c),22 So in original. Probably should be “section 1710(a)(1)(A) of this title or subsection (c)),”. as provided in regulations by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715u_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of partial claim</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment of partial claim</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715u_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment and loan modification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assignment and loan modification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715u_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition of judicial review No decision by the Secretary to exercise or forego exercising any authority under this section shall be subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715u_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101(e) [title II, § 221(b)(2)], Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 1321–257, 1321–291; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a), May 2, 1996, 110 Stat. 1327</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715u_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicability of other laws No provision of this chapter, or any other law, shall be construed to require the Secretary to provide an alternative to foreclosure for mortgagees with mortgages on 1- to 4-family residences insured by the Secretary under this chapter, or to accept assignments of such mortgages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>