<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715k"><akn:num>1715k</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation and neighborhood conservation housing insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715k. Rehabilitation and neighborhood conservation housing insurance(a) Purpose of sectionThe purpose of this section is to aid in the elimination of slums and blighted conditions and the prevention of the deterioration of residential property by supplementing the insurance of mortgages under sections 1709 and 1713 of this title with a system of loan and mortgage insurance designed to assist the financing required for the rehabilitation of existing dwelling accommodations and the construction of new dwelling accommodations where such dwelling accommodations are located in an area referred to in paragraph (1) of subsection (d) of this section.


(b) AuthorizationThe Secretary is authorized, upon application by the mortgagee, to insure, as hereinafter provided, any mortgage (including advances during construction on mortgages covering property of the character described in paragraph (3)(B) of subsection (d) of this section) which is eligible for insurance as hereinafter provided, and, upon such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, to make commitments for the insurance of such mortgages prior to the date of their execution or disbursement thereon.


(c) DefinitionsAs used in this section, the terms “mortgage”, “first mortgage”, “mortgagee”, “mortgagor”, “maturity date”, and “State” shall have the same meaning as in section 1707 of this title.


(d) Eligibility for insurance; conditions; limitsTo be eligible for insurance under this section a mortgage shall meet the following conditions:(1) The mortgaged property shall—(A) be located in (i) the area of a slum clearance and urban redevelopment project covered by a Federal-aid contract executed or a prior approval granted, pursuant to title I of the Housing Act of 1949 [42 U.S.C. 1450 et seq.] before August 2, 1954, or (ii) an urban renewal area (as defined in title I of the Housing Act of 1949, as amended), or (iii) the area of an urban renewal project assisted under section 111 of the Housing Act of 1949 [42 U.S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose of section The purpose of this section is to aid in the elimination of slums and blighted conditions and the prevention of the deterioration of residential property by supplementing the insurance of mortgages under sections 1709 and 1713 of this title with a system of loan and mortgage insurance designed to assist the financing required for the rehabilitation of existing dwelling accommodations and the construction of new dwelling accommodations where such dwelling accommodations are located in an area referred to in paragraph (1) of subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization The Secretary is authorized, upon application by the mortgagee, to insure, as hereinafter provided, any mortgage (including advances during construction on mortgages covering property of the character described in paragraph (3)(B) of subsection (d) of this section) which is eligible for insurance as hereinafter provided, and, upon such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, to make commitments for the insurance of such mortgages prior to the date of their execution or disbursement thereon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions As used in this section, the terms “mortgage”, “first mortgage”, “mortgagee”, “mortgagor”, “maturity date”, and “State” shall have the same meaning as in section 1707 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for insurance; conditions; limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility for insurance; conditions; limits To be eligible for insurance under this section a mortgage shall meet the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715k_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of mortgagor or part of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Release of mortgagor or part of property The Secretary may at any time, under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, consent to the release of the mortgagor from his liability under the mortgage or the credit instrument secured thereby, or consent to the release of parts of the mortgaged property from the lien of the mortgage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715k_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement of mortgagee to benefits; payment in cash or debentures; acquisition of mortgages; applicability of other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Entitlement of mortgagee to benefits; payment in cash or debentures; acquisition of mortgages; applicability of other provisions The mortgagee shall be entitled to receive the benefits of the insurance as hereinafter provided—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715k_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 89–117, title XI, § 1108(h)(3), Aug. 10, 1965, 79 Stat. 505</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715k_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Home improvement loans; eligibility; conditions; refinancing; premium charge; defaults; debentures; exception; limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Home improvement loans; eligibility; conditions; refinancing; premium charge; defaults; debentures; exception; limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>