<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–1b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–1b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–1b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715z_1b"><akn:num>1715z–1b</akn:num><akn:heading>Tenant participation in multifamily housing projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715z–1b. Tenant participation in multifamily housing projects(a) Purpose; definitionsThe purpose of this section is to recognize the importance and benefits of cooperation and participation of tenants in creating a suitable living environment in multifamily housing proj­ects and in contributing to the successful operation of such projects, including their good physical condition, proper maintenance, security, energy efficiency, and control of operating costs. For the purpose of this section, the term “multifamily housing project” means a project which is eligible for assistance as described in section 1715z–1a(c) of this title or section 1701q of this title, or a project which receives project-based assistance under section 1437f of title 42 or enhanced vouchers under the Low-Income Housing Preservation and Resident Homeownership Act of 1990 [12 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.], the provisions of the Emergency Low Income Housing Preservation Act of 1987, or the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997.


(b) Rights of tenantsThe Secretary shall assure that—(1) where the Secretary’s written approval is required with respect to an owner’s request for rent increase, conversion of residential rental units to any other use (including commercial use or use as a unit in any condominium or cooperative project), partial release of security, or major physical alterations or where the Secretary proposes to sell a mortgage secured by a multifamily housing project, tenants have adequate notice of, reasonable access to relevant information about, and an opportunity to comment on such actions (and in the case of a project owned by the Secretary, any proposed disposition of the project) and that such comments are taken into consideration by the Secretary;

(2) project owners not interfere with the efforts of tenants to obtain rent subsidies or other public assistance;

(3) leases approved by the Secretary provide that tenants may not be evicted without good cause or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose; definitions The purpose of this section is to recognize the importance and benefits of cooperation and participation of tenants in creating a suitable living environment in multifamily housing proj­ects and in contributing to the successful operation of such projects, including their good physical condition, proper maintenance, security, energy efficiency, and control of operating costs. For the purpose of this section, the term “multifamily housing project” means a project which is eligible for assistance as described in section 1715z–1a(c) of this title or section 1701q of this title, or a project which receives project-based assistance under section 1437f of title 42 or enhanced vouchers under the Low-Income Housing Preservation and Resident Homeownership Act of 1990 [12 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.], the provisions of the Emergency Low Income Housing Preservation Act of 1987, or the Multifamily Assisted Housing Reform and Affordability Act of 1997.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of tenants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rights of tenants The Secretary shall assure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out the provisions of this section not later than 90 days after October 31, 1978.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>