<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–1a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–1a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–1a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715z_1a"><akn:num>1715z–1a</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance for troubled multifamily housing projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715z–1a. Assistance for troubled multifamily housing projects(a) PurposeThe purposes of this section are to provide assistance to restore or maintain the financial soundness, to assist in the improvement of the management, to permit capital improvements to be made to maintain certain projects as decent, safe, and sanitary housing, and to maintain the low- to moderate-income character of certain projects assisted or approved for assistance under the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.], the United States Housing Act of 1937 [42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.], the Housing Act of 1959, or the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965, without regard to whether such projects are insured under the National Housing Act.


(b) Availability of financial assistanceThe Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) may make available, and contract to make available, to such extent and in such amounts as may be approved in appropriation Acts, financial assistance to owners of rental or cooperative housing projects meeting the requirements of this section. Such assistance shall be made on an annual basis and in accordance with the provisions of this section, without regard to whether such projects are insured under the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.].


(c) Eligibility for financial assistanceA rental or cooperative housing project is eligible for assistance under this section only if such project—(1)(A) is assisted under section 236 [12 U.S.C. 1715z–1] or the proviso of section 221(d)(5) of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1715l(d)(5)], or under section 101 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965 [12 U.S.C. 1701s], or received a loan under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 [12 U.S.C. 1701q] more than 15 years before the date on which assistance is made available under this section;

(B) is assisted under section 23 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [42 U.S.C. 1421b], as in effect i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purposes of this section are to provide assistance to restore or maintain the financial soundness, to assist in the improvement of the management, to permit capital improvements to be made to maintain certain projects as decent, safe, and sanitary housing, and to maintain the low- to moderate-income character of certain projects assisted or approved for assistance under the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.], the United States Housing Act of 1937 [42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.], the Housing Act of 1959, or the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965, without regard to whether such projects are insured under the National Housing Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of financial assistance The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) may make available, and contract to make available, to such extent and in such amounts as may be approved in appropriation Acts, financial assistance to owners of rental or cooperative housing projects meeting the requirements of this section. Such assistance shall be made on an annual basis and in accordance with the provisions of this section, without regard to whether such projects are insured under the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility for financial assistance A rental or cooperative housing project is eligible for assistance under this section only if such project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for granting financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criteria for granting financial assistance No assistance may be made available under this section unless the Secretary has determined that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with local officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation with local officials Prior to making assistance available to a proj­ect, the Secretary shall consult with the appropriate officials of the unit of local government in which such project is located and seek assurances that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Amount of financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rules and regulations The Secretary is authorized to issue such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions and purposes of this section, including regulations requiring the establishment of a project reserve or such other safeguards as the Secretary determines to be necessary for the financial soundness of any project for which assistance payments are provided, to the extent applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitation on use of financial assistance The Secretary may not use any of the assistance available under this section during any fiscal year beginning on or after October 1, 1981, to supplement any contract to make rental assistance payments which was made pursuant to section 101 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965 [12 U.S.C. 1701s].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 103–233, title I, § 103(b)(1), Apr. 11, 1994, 108 Stat. 359</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexible Subsidy Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Flexible Subsidy Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>