<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715z_1"><akn:num>1715z–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Rental and cooperative housing for lower income families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715z–1. Rental and cooperative housing for lower income families(a) Authorization for periodic interest reduction payments on behalf of owner of rental housing projectFor the purpose of reducing rentals for lower income families, the Secretary is authorized to make, and to contract to make, periodic interest reduction payments on behalf of the owner of a rental housing project designed for occupancy by lower income families, which shall be accomplished through payments to morgagees 11 So in original. Probably should be “mortgagees”. holding mortgages meeting the special requirements specified in this section.


(b) Restrictions on payments; payments with respect to projects financed under State or local programs; mortgage insurance premiumInterest reduction payments with respect to a project shall only be made during such time as the project is operated as a rental housing proj­ect and is subject to a mortgage which meets the requirements of, and is insured under, subsection (j) of this section: Provided, That the Secretary is authorized to continue making such interest reduction payments where the mortgage has been assigned to the Secretary: Provided further, That interest reduction payments may be made with respect to a mortgage or part thereof on a rental or cooperative housing project owned by a private nonprofit corporation or other private nonprofit entity, a limited dividend corporation or other limited dividend entity, public 22 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “a”. entity, or a cooperative housing corporation, which is financed under a State or local program providing assistance through loans, loan insurance, or tax abatements, and which may involve either new or existing construction and which is approved for receiving the benefits of this section. The term “mortgage insurance premium”, when used in this section in relation to a project financed by a loan under a State or local program, means such fees and charges, approved by the Secretar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for periodic interest reduction payments on behalf of owner of rental housing project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization for periodic interest reduction payments on behalf of owner of rental housing project For the purpose of reducing rentals for lower income families, the Secretary is authorized to make, and to contract to make, periodic interest reduction payments on behalf of the owner of a rental housing project designed for occupancy by lower income families, which shall be accomplished through payments to morgagees 11 So in original. Probably should be “mortgagees”. holding mortgages meeting the special requirements specified in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on payments; payments with respect to projects financed under State or local programs; mortgage insurance premium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Restrictions on payments; payments with respect to projects financed under State or local programs; mortgage insurance premium Interest reduction payments with respect to a project shall only be made during such time as the project is operated as a rental housing proj­ect and is subject to a mortgage which meets the requirements of, and is insured under, subsection (j) of this section: Provided, That the Secretary is authorized to continue making such interest reduction payments where the mortgage has been assigned to the Secretary: Provided further, That interest reduction payments may be made with respect to a mortgage or part thereof on a rental or cooperative housing project owned by a private nonprofit corporation or other private nonprofit entity, a limited dividend corporation or other limited dividend entity, public 22 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “a”. entity, or a cooperative housing corporation, which is financed under a State or local program providing </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amount of payments The interest reduction payments to a mortgagee by the Secretary on behalf of a project owner shall be in an amount not exceeding the difference between the monthly payment for principal, interest, and mortgage insurance premium which the project owner as a mortgagor is obligated to pay under the mortgage and the monthly payment for principal and interest such project owner would be obligated to pay if the mortgage were to bear interest at the rate of 1 per centum per annum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage handling expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mortgage handling expenses The Secretary may include in the payment to the mortgagee such amount, in addition to the amount computed under subsection (c), as he deems appropriate to reimburse the mortgagee for its expenses in handling the mortgage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of project in accordance with requirements respecting tenant eligibility and rents prescribed by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Operation of project in accordance with requirements respecting tenant eligibility and rents prescribed by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of basic and fair market rental charges; rental for dwelling units; separate utility metering; additional assistance payments for low-income tenants; limitations; amounts; approval of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Establishment of basic and fair market rental charges; rental for dwelling units; separate utility metering; additional assistance payments for low-income tenants; limitations; amounts; approval of payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of excess rental charges; credit to reserve for additional assistance payments; retention by project owner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Collection of excess rental charges; credit to reserve for additional assistance payments; retention by project owner</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rules and regulations In addition to establishing the requirements specified in subsection (e), the Secretary is authorized to make such rules and regulations, to enter into such agreements, and to adopt such procedures as he may deem necessary or desirable to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations; aggregate amount of contracts; contracts for assistance payments; income limitations; availability of amounts for projects approved prior to rehabilitation and projects for occupancy by elderly or handicapped families; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations; aggregate amount of contracts; contracts for assistance payments; income limitations; availability of amounts for projects approved prior to rehabilitation and projects for occupancy by elderly or handicapped families; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance of mortgages; definitions; eligibility for insurance; mortgage requirements; property or project requirements; sale of individual dwelling units; release of mortgagor from liability or release of property from lien of mortgage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Insurance of mortgages; definitions; eligibility for insurance; mortgage requirements; property or project requirements; sale of individual dwelling units; release of mortgagor from liability or release of property from lien of mortgage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>