<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–14" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–14/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–14/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715z_14"><akn:num>1715z–14</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk-sharing demonstration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715z–14. Risk-sharing demonstration(a) Demonstration mortgage risk-sharing program; areas; number of mortgagesThe purpose of this section is to authorize a demonstration mortgage risk-sharing program designed to test the feasibility of entering into risk-sharing contracts with private mortgage insurers and with insured community development financial institutions in order to reduce Government risk and administrative costs, and to speed mortgage processing. The Secretary shall limit the demonstration under this section to not more than four administrative regions of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and shall assure that the program is in the financial interest of the Government and will not result in loss of employment by any employees of the Department of Housing and Urban Development before the expiration of the 5-year period beginning on December 21, 2000. The aggregate number of mortgages for which risk of nonpayment is shared under this section in any administrative region of the Department of Housing and Urban Development in any fiscal year may not exceed 20 percent of the aggregate number of mortgages and loans insured by the Secretary under this subchapter in such region during the preceding fiscal year.


(b) One- to four-family dwellings; requirements for private mortgage insurance companiesNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter inconsistent with this section, the Secretary is authorized, in providing mortgage insurance with respect to one- to four-family dwellings under sections 1709(b), 1715y, and 1715z–10 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, to enter into risk-sharing contracts with private mortgage insurance companies which have been determined to be qualified insurers under section 1717(b)(2)(C) of this title and with insured community development financial institutions. Such contracts shall require private mortgage insurance companies and insured community development financial institutions to—(1) assume</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_14_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration mortgage risk-sharing program; areas; number of mortgages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Demonstration mortgage risk-sharing program; areas; number of mortgages The purpose of this section is to authorize a demonstration mortgage risk-sharing program designed to test the feasibility of entering into risk-sharing contracts with private mortgage insurers and with insured community development financial institutions in order to reduce Government risk and administrative costs, and to speed mortgage processing. The Secretary shall limit the demonstration under this section to not more than four administrative regions of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and shall assure that the program is in the financial interest of the Government and will not result in loss of employment by any employees of the Department of Housing and Urban Development before the expiration of the 5-year period beginning on December 21, 2000. The aggregate number of mortgages for which risk of nonpayment is shared under this section in any administrative region of the Department of Housi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_14_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>One- to four-family dwellings; requirements for private mortgage insurance companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) One- to four-family dwellings; requirements for private mortgage insurance companies Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter inconsistent with this section, the Secretary is authorized, in providing mortgage insurance with respect to one- to four-family dwellings under sections 1709(b), 1715y, and 1715z–10 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, to enter into risk-sharing contracts with private mortgage insurance companies which have been determined to be qualified insurers under section 1717(b)(2)(C) of this title and with insured community development financial institutions. Such contracts shall require private mortgage insurance companies and insured community development financial institutions to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_14_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required contract provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Required contract provisions Any contract for risk-sharing under this section shall contain such provisions relating to the sharing of premiums received by the Secretary with a private mortgage insurer or insured community development financial institution on a sound actuarial basis, establishment of loss reserves, manner of calculating claims on such risk-sharing contract, conditions with respect to foreclosure, handling and disposition of property prior to claim or settlement, rights of assignees, and other similar matters as the Secretary may prescribe pursuant to regulations. Pursuant to a contract under this section, a private mortgage insurance company or insured community development financial institution shall endorse loans for risk-sharing and take such other actions on behalf of the Secretary and in the Secretary’s name as the Secretary may authorize.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_14_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgages offered for inclusion by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mortgages offered for inclusion by Secretary The Secretary shall require any private mortgage insurance company or insured community development financial institution participating in the program under this section to provide risk-sharing for those mortgages offered by the Secretary for inclusion in the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_14_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insured community development financial institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Insured community development financial institution For purposes of this section, the term “insured community development financial institution” means a community development financial institution, as such term is defined in section 4702 of this title that is an insured depository institution (as such term is defined in section 1813 of this title) or an insured credit union (as such term is defined in section 1752 of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>