<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–22" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–22/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–22/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715z_22"><akn:num>1715z–22</akn:num><akn:heading>Multifamily mortgage credit programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715z–22. Multifamily mortgage credit programs(a) In generalThe Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall carry out programs through the Federal Housing Administration to provide new forms of Federal credit enhancement for multifamily loans. In carrying out the programs, the Secretary shall include an evaluation of the effectiveness of entering into partnerships or other contractual arrangements including reinsurance and risk-sharing agreements with State or local housing finance agencies, the Federal Housing Finance Board, the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, qualified financial institutions, and other State or local mortgage insurance companies or bank lending consortia.


(b) Risk-sharing program(1) In generalThe Secretary shall carry out a program in conjunction with qualified participating entities to provide Federal credit enhancement for loans for affordable multifamily housing through a system of risk-sharing agreements with such entities.


(2) Program requirements(A) In generalIn carrying out the program under this subsection, the Secretary shall enter into risk-sharing agreements with qualified participating entities.


(B) Mortgage insurance and reinsuranceAgreements under subparagraph (A) may provide for (i) mortgage insurance through the Federal Housing Administration of loans for affordable multifamily housing originated by or through, or purchased by, qualified participating entities, and (ii) reinsurance, including reinsurance of pools of loans, on affordable multifamily housing. In entering into risk-sharing agreements under this subsection covering mortgages, the Secretary may give preference to mortgages that are not already in the portfolios of qualified participating entities.


(C) Risk apportionmentAgreements entered into under this subsection between the Secretary and a qualified participating entity shall specify the percentage of loss th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_22_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (hereinafter referred to as the “Secretary”) shall carry out programs through the Federal Housing Administration to provide new forms of Federal credit enhancement for multifamily loans. In carrying out the programs, the Secretary shall include an evaluation of the effectiveness of entering into partnerships or other contractual arrangements including reinsurance and risk-sharing agreements with State or local housing finance agencies, the Federal Housing Finance Board, the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, qualified financial institutions, and other State or local mortgage insurance companies or bank lending consortia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_22_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk-sharing program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Risk-sharing program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_22_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing finance agency program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Housing finance agency program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>