<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715y" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715y/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715y/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715y"><akn:num>1715y</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage insurance for condominiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715y. Mortgage insurance for condominiums(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to provide an additional means of increasing the supply of privately owned dwelling units where, under the laws of the State in which the property is located, real property title and ownership are established with respect to a one-family unit which is part of a multifamily project.


(b) DefinitionsThe terms “mortgage”, “mortgagee”, “mortgagor”, “maturity date”, and “State” shall have the meanings respectively set forth in section 1707 of this title, except that the term “mortgage” for the purposes of subsection (c) may include a first mortgage given to secure the unpaid purchase price of a fee interest in, or a long-term leasehold interest in, a one-family unit in a multifamily project, including a project in which the dwelling units are attached, semi-attached, or detached, and an undivided interest in the common areas and facilities which serve the project where the mortgage is determined by the Secretary to be eligible for insurance under this section. The term “common areas and facilities” as used in this section shall be deemed to include the land and such commercial, community, and other facilities as are approved by the Secretary.


(c) Authorization; eligibility for insurance; conditions; limitsThe Secretary is authorized, in his discretion and under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe (including the minimum number of family units in the project which shall be offered for sale and provisions for the protection of the consumer and the public interest), to insure any mortgage covering a one-family unit in a multifamily project and an undivided interest in the common areas and facilities which serve the project, if (1) the mortgage meets the requirements of this subsection and of section 1709(b) of this title, except as that section is modified by this subsection, (2) at least 80 percent of the units in the project covered by mortgages insured under this subchapter </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to provide an additional means of increasing the supply of privately owned dwelling units where, under the laws of the State in which the property is located, real property title and ownership are established with respect to a one-family unit which is part of a multifamily project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions The terms “mortgage”, “mortgagee”, “mortgagor”, “maturity date”, and “State” shall have the meanings respectively set forth in section 1707 of this title, except that the term “mortgage” for the purposes of subsection (c) may include a first mortgage given to secure the unpaid purchase price of a fee interest in, or a long-term leasehold interest in, a one-family unit in a multifamily project, including a project in which the dwelling units are attached, semi-attached, or detached, and an undivided interest in the common areas and facilities which serve the project where the mortgage is determined by the Secretary to be eligible for insurance under this section. The term “common areas and facilities” as used in this section shall be deemed to include the land and such commercial, community, and other facilities as are approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization; eligibility for insurance; conditions; limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization; eligibility for insurance; conditions; limits The Secretary is authorized, in his discretion and under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe (including the minimum number of family units in the project which shall be offered for sale and provisions for the protection of the consumer and the public interest), to insure any mortgage covering a one-family unit in a multifamily project and an undivided interest in the common areas and facilities which serve the project, if (1) the mortgage meets the requirements of this subsection and of section 1709(b) of this title, except as that section is modified by this subsection, (2) at least 80 percent of the units in the project covered by mortgages insured under this subchapter are occupied by the mortgagors or comortgagors, and (3) the project has a blanket mortgage insured by the Secretary under subsection (d). Any project proposed to be constructed or rehabilitated after June 30, 1961, with the assistance of mortga</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Blanket mortgages of multifamily projects; plan of family unit ownership; regulations; stock purchase and redemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Blanket mortgages of multifamily projects; plan of family unit ownership; regulations; stock purchase and redemption In addition to individual mortgages insured under subsection (c), the Secretary is authorized, in his discretion and under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, to insure blanket mortgages (including advances on such mortgages during construction) which cover multifamily projects to be constructed or rehabilitated in cases where the mortgage is held by a mortgagor, approved by the Secretary, which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for insurance of blanket mortgages of multifamily projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligibility for insurance of blanket mortgages of multifamily projects To be eligible for insurance, a blanket mortgage on any multifamily project of a mortgagor of the character described in subsection (d) shall involve a principal obligation in an amount—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amortization of blanket mortgages of multifamily projects; interest; releases; extent of project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Amortization of blanket mortgages of multifamily projects; interest; releases; extent of project Any blanket mortgage insured under subsection (d) shall provide for complete amortization by periodic payments within such terms as the Secretary may prescribe but not to exceed 40 years from the beginning of amortization of the mortgage, and shall bear interest at such rate as may be agreed upon by the mortgagor and the mortgagee. The Secretary may consent to the release of a part or parts of the mortgaged property from the lien of the blanket mortgage upon such terms and conditions as he may prescribe and the blanket mortgage may provide for such release. The project covered by the blanket mortgage may include four or more family units and such commercial and community facilities as the Secretary deems adequate to serve the occupants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement to insurance benefits as provided in section 1710(a) of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Entitlement to insurance benefits as provided in Any mortgagee under a mortgage insured under subsection (c) of this section is entitled to receive the benefits of the insurance as provided in section 1710(a) of this title with respect to mortgages insured under section 1709 of this title, and the provisions of subsections (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h),1 (j), and (k) 1 of section 1710 of this title shall be applicable to the mortgages insured under subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Applicability of other provisions The provisions of subsections (d), (e), (g), (h), (i), (j), (k), (l), and (n) of section 1713 of this title shall be applicable to mortgages insured under subsection (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Applicability of other provisions The provisions of sections 1715p and 1715u of this title shall be applicable to the mortgages insured under subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715y_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increase in maximum insurance amounts for costs incurred from solar energy systems and energy conservation measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Increase in maximum insurance amounts for costs incurred from solar energy systems and energy conservation measures The Secretary may further increase the dollar amount limitations which would otherwise apply under subsection (e) by not to exceed 20 per centum if such increase is necessary to account for the increased cost of a project due to the installation therein of a solar energy system (as defined in subparagraph (3) of the last paragraph of section 1703(a) of this title) or residential energy conservation measures (as defined in section 8211(11)(A) through (G) and (I) of title 42) 1 in cases where the Secretary determines that such measures are in addition to those required under the minimum property standards and will be cost-effective over the life of the measure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>