<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–23" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–23/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–23/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715z_23"><akn:num>1715z–23</akn:num><akn:heading>HOPE for Homeowners Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715z–23. HOPE for Homeowners Program(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Federal Housing Administration a HOPE for Homeowners Program.


(b) PurposeThe purpose of the HOPE for Homeowners Program is—(1) to create an FHA program, participation in which is voluntary on the part of homeowners and existing loan holders to insure refinanced loans for distressed borrowers to support long-term, sustainable homeownership;

(2) to allow homeowners to avoid foreclosure by reducing the principle 11 So in original. Probably should be “principal”. balance outstanding, and interest rate charged, on their mortgages;

(3) to help stabilize and provide confidence in mortgage markets by bringing transparency to the value of assets based on mortgage assets;

(4) to target mortgage assistance under this section to homeowners for their principal residence;

(5) to enhance the administrative capacity of the FHA to carry out its expanded role under the HOPE for Homeowners Program;

(6) to ensure the HOPE for Homeowners Program remains in effect only for as long as is necessary to provide stability to the housing market; and

(7) to provide servicers of delinquent mortgages with additional methods and approaches to avoid foreclosure.


(c) Establishment and implementation of program requirements(1) Duties of SecretaryIn order to carry out the purposes of the HOPE for Homeowners Program, the Secretary, after consultation with the Board, shall—(A) establish requirements and standards for the program consistent with section 1709(b) of this title to the maximum extent possible; and

(B) prescribe such regulations and provide such guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to implement such requirements and standards.


(2) Duties of the SecretaryIn carrying out any of the program requirements or standards established under paragraph (1), the Secretary may issue such interim guidance and mortgagee letters as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate.


(3) Duties of BoardThe </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Federal Housing Administration a HOPE for Homeowners Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the HOPE for Homeowners Program is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and implementation of program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment and implementation of program requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance of mortgages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Insurance of mortgages The Secretary is authorized upon application of a mortgagee to make commitments to insure or to insure any eligible mortgage that has been refinanced in a manner meeting the requirements under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements of insured mortgages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirements of insured mortgages To be eligible for insurance under this section, a refinanced eligible mortgage shall comply with all of the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of auction or bulk refinance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Study of auction or bulk refinance program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal independence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Appraisal independence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards to protect against adverse selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Standards to protect against adverse selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Premiums</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_23_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Origination fees and interest rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Origination fees and interest rate The Secretary shall establish—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>