<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715d"><akn:num>1715d</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance of mortgages on property in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, and Virgin Islands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715d. Insurance of mortgages on property in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, and Virgin Islands
If the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development finds that, because of higher costs prevailing in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands, it is not feasible to construct dwellings or manufactured home courts or parks on property located in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands without sacrifice of sound standards of construction, design, or livability, within the limitations as to maximum or maxima mortgage amounts provided in this chapter, the Secretary may, by regulations or otherwise, prescribe, with respect to dollar amount, a higher maximum or maxima for the principal obligation of mortgages insured under this chapter covering property located in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands in such amounts as he shall find necessary to compensate for such higher costs but not to exceed, in any event, the maximum or maxima otherwise applicable (including increased mortgage amounts in geographical areas where cost levels so require) by more than one-half thereof. No mortgage with respect to a project or property in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands shall be accepted for insurance under this chapter unless the Secretary finds that the project or property is an acceptable risk giving consideration to the acute housing shortage in Alaska, Guam, Hawaii, or the Virgin Islands: Provided, That any such mortgage may be insured or accepted for insurance without regard to any requirement in any other section of this chapter that the Secretary find the project or property to be economically sound or an acceptable risk. Notwithstanding any of the provisions of this chapter or any other law, the Alaska Housing Authority or the Government of Guam, the Virgin Islands, or Hawaii or any agency or instrumentality thereof shall be eligible as mortgagor or mortgagee, as the case may be, for any of the purposes of mortgage insurance under the provisions of this chapter. Upon </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>