<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715z_8"><akn:num>1715z–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage assistance payments for middle-income families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715z–8. Mortgage assistance payments for middle-income families(a) Determination by Secretary of necessity; interest subsidy payments; effective dateWhenever he determines such action to be necessary in furtherance of the purposes set forth in section 501 of the Emergency Home Finance Act of 1970, the Secretary is authorized to make, and to contract to make, periodic assistance payments on behalf of families of middle income. The assistance shall be accomplished through interest subsidy payments to the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (hereinafter referred to as “the investor”) with respect to mortgages meeting the special requirements specified in this section and made after July 24, 1970.


(b) Qualifications of mortgagor for assistance paymentsTo qualify for assistance payments a middle-income family shall be a mortgagor under a mortgage which is (1) insured under subsection (j) of this section, (2) guaranteed under chapter 37 of title 38, or (3) a conventional mortgage meeting the requirements of subsection (j)(3) of this section. In addition to the foregoing requirement, the Secretary may require that the mortgagor have an income, at the time of acquisition of the property, of not more than the median income for the area in which the property is located, as determined by the Secretary, with appropriate adjustments for smaller and larger families.


(c) Termination of interest subsidy paymentsThe interest subsidy payments authorized by this section shall cease when (1) the mortgagor no longer occupies the property which secures the mortgage, (2) the mortgages are no longer held by the investor, or (3) the rate of interest paid by the mortgagor reaches the rate of interest specified on the mortgage.


(d) Monthly mortgage payments as determining eligibility for interest subsidy payments; mortgage assistance payments for middle-income cooperative members; interest subsidy payments; applicability of provisions t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination by Secretary of necessity; interest subsidy payments; effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination by Secretary of necessity; interest subsidy payments; effective date Whenever he determines such action to be necessary in furtherance of the purposes set forth in section 501 of the Emergency Home Finance Act of 1970, the Secretary is authorized to make, and to contract to make, periodic assistance payments on behalf of families of middle income. The assistance shall be accomplished through interest subsidy payments to the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (hereinafter referred to as “the investor”) with respect to mortgages meeting the special requirements specified in this section and made after July 24, 1970.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications of mortgagor for assistance payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualifications of mortgagor for assistance payments To qualify for assistance payments a middle-income family shall be a mortgagor under a mortgage which is (1) insured under subsection (j) of this section, (2) guaranteed under chapter 37 of title 38, or (3) a conventional mortgage meeting the requirements of subsection (j)(3) of this section. In addition to the foregoing requirement, the Secretary may require that the mortgagor have an income, at the time of acquisition of the property, of not more than the median income for the area in which the property is located, as determined by the Secretary, with appropriate adjustments for smaller and larger families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of interest subsidy payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Termination of interest subsidy payments The interest subsidy payments authorized by this section shall cease when (1) the mortgagor no longer occupies the property which secures the mortgage, (2) the mortgages are no longer held by the investor, or (3) the rate of interest paid by the mortgagor reaches the rate of interest specified on the mortgage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monthly mortgage payments as determining eligibility for interest subsidy payments; mortgage assistance payments for middle-income cooperative members; interest subsidy payments; applicability of provisions to cooperative mortgagors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Monthly mortgage payments as determining eligibility for interest subsidy payments; mortgage assistance payments for middle-income cooperative members; interest subsidy payments; applicability of provisions to cooperative mortgagors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of interest subsidy payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amount of interest subsidy payments The interest subsidy payments shall be in an amount equal to the difference, as determined by the Secretary, between the total amount of interest per calendar quarter received by the investor on mortgages assisted under this section and purchased by it and the total amount of interest which the investor would have received if the yield on such mortgages was equal to the sum of (1) the average costs (expressed as an annual percentage rate) to it of all borrowed funds outstanding in the immediately preceding calendar quarter, and (2) such per centum per annum as will provide for administrative and other expenses of the investor and a reasonable economic return, as determined by the Secretary to be necessary and appropriate taking into account the purpose of this section to provide additional mortgage credit at reasonable rates of interest to middle-income families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of procedures for recertifications of mortgagor’s income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Adoption of procedures for recertifications of mortgagor’s income Procedures shall be adopted by the Secretary for recertifications of the mortgagor’s income at intervals of two years (or at shorter intervals where the Secretary deems it desirable) for the purpose of adjusting the amount of the mortgagor’s payments pursuant to subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations to assure that sales price or other consideration paid is not increased above appraised value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations to assure that sales price or other consideration paid is not increased above appraised value The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as he deems necessary to assure that the sales price of, or other consideration paid in connection with, the purchase by a homeowner of the property with respect to which assistance payments are to be made is not increased above the appraised value on which the maximum mortgage which the Secretary will insure is computed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations; aggregate amount of assistance payment contracts; termination date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations; aggregate amount of assistance payment contracts; termination date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of family income; exclusion of income of minors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Determination of family income; exclusion of income of minors In determining the income of any family for the purposes of this section, income from all sources of each member of the family in the household shall be included, except that the Secretary shall exclude income earned by any minor person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_8_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance of mortgages executed by mortgagors meeting eligibility requirements for assistance payments; issuance of commitment; eligibility requirements for insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Insurance of mortgages executed by mortgagors meeting eligibility requirements for assistance payments; issuance of commitment; eligibility requirements for insurance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>