<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1715z–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715z_9"><akn:num>1715z–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Co-insurance of eligible mortgage, advance, or loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715z–9. Co-insurance of eligible mortgage, advance, or loan(a) Authority of Secretary; request of mortgagee; premium charges; provisions of contract of co-insurance; non-applicability of state insurance lawsIn addition to providing insurance as otherwise authorized under this chapter, and notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter inconsistent with this section, the Secretary, upon request of any mortgagee and for such mortgage insurance premium as he may prescribe (which premium, or other charges to be paid by the mortgagor, shall not exceed the premium, or other charges, that would otherwise be applicable), may insure and make a commitment to insure under any provision of this subchapter any mortgage, advance, or loan otherwise eligible under such provision, pursuant to a co-insurance contract providing that the mortgagee will—(1) assume a percentage of any loss on the insured mortgage, advance, or loan in direct proportion to the amount of the co-insurance, which co-insurance shall not be less than 10 per centum, subject to any reasonable limit or limits on the liability of the mortgagee that may be specified in the event of unusual or catastrophic losses that may be incurred by any one mortgagee; and

(2) carry out (under a delegation or otherwise and with or without compensation but subject to audit, exception, or review requirements) such credit approval, appraisal, inspection, commitment, property disposition, or other functions as the Secretary, pursuant to regulations, shall approve as consistent with the purposes of this chapter.


Any contract of co-insurance under this section shall contain such provisions relating to the sharing of premiums on a sound actuarial basis, establishment of mortgage reserves, manner of calculating insurance benefits, conditions with respect to foreclosure, handling and disposition of property prior to claim or settlement, rights of assignees (which may elect not to be subject to the loss sharing provisions), and o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary; request of mortgagee; premium charges; provisions of contract of co-insurance; non-applicability of state insurance laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary; request of mortgagee; premium charges; provisions of contract of co-insurance; non-applicability of state insurance laws In addition to providing insurance as otherwise authorized under this chapter, and notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter inconsistent with this section, the Secretary, upon request of any mortgagee and for such mortgage insurance premium as he may prescribe (which premium, or other charges to be paid by the mortgagor, shall not exceed the premium, or other charges, that would otherwise be applicable), may insure and make a commitment to insure under any provision of this subchapter any mortgage, advance, or loan otherwise eligible under such provision, pursuant to a co-insurance contract providing that the mortgagee will— Any contract of co-insurance under this section shall contain such provisions relating to the sharing of premiums on a sound actuarial basis, establishment of mortgage reserves, manner of calculating insuran</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection of construction of dwellings or projects as prerequisite; minimum standards or criteria applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inspection of construction of dwellings or projects as prerequisite; minimum standards or criteria applicable No insurance shall be granted pursuant to this section with respect to dwellings or projects approved for insurance prior to the beginning of construction unless the inspection of such construction is conducted in accordance with at least the minimum standards and criteria used with respect to dwellings or projects approved for mortgage insurance pursuant to other provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 100–242, title IV, § 414(a), Feb. 5, 1988, 101 Stat. 1907</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 100–242, title IV, § 401(a)(3), Feb. 5, 1988, 101 Stat. 1898</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability unaffecting insurance otherwise authorized; criteria for exercise of authority by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability unaffecting insurance otherwise authorized; criteria for exercise of authority by Secretary The Secretary shall not withdraw, deny, or delay insurance otherwise authorized under any other provision of this chapter by reason of the availability of insurance pursuant to this section. The Secretary shall exercise his authority under this section only to the extent that he finds that the continued exercise of such authority will not adversely affect the flow of mortgage credit to older and declining neighborhoods and to the purchasers of older and lower cost housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multifamily housing project; contract provisions; aggregate principal amount of all mortgages insured; loans on defaulted mortgages; insurance for state assisted projects and projects under construction; definitions; amount of reserves</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Multifamily housing project; contract provisions; aggregate principal amount of all mortgages insured; loans on defaulted mortgages; insurance for state assisted projects and projects under construction; definitions; amount of reserves</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redesignated (f)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Redesignated (f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptable co-insurance provisions for rental rehabilitation; termination date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Acceptable co-insurance provisions for rental rehabilitation; termination date Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in the case of a mortgage insured under section 1715n(f) of this title secured by property which is to be rehabilitated or developed under section 1437o 11 See References in Text note below. of title 42, such co-insurance may include provisions that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>22 So in original. Two subsecs. (i) have been enacted. Authority of mortgagee to assign its interest in any note or mortgage subject to a contract of co-insurance; terms and conditions respecting retention of co-insurance risk of such note or mortgage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Any mortgagee which enters into a contract of co-insurance under this section shall have the authority to assign its interest in any note or mortgage subject to a contract of co-insurance to a warehouse bank or other financial institution which provides interim funding for a loan co-insured under this section, and to retain the co-insurance risk of such note or mortgage, upon such terms and conditions as the Secretary shall prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1715z_9_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>2 Annual review of, and assessment of compliance with, requirements; report; adjustment of requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary shall, by January 15 and July 15 of each year (1) review the adequacy of capital and other requirements for mortgagees under this section, (2) assess the compliance by mortgagees with such requirements, and (3) make such adjustment to such requirements as the Secretary, after providing opportunity for hearing, determines to be appropriate to improve the long-term financial soundness of the Federal Housing Administration funds. Such requirements shall include the minimum capital or net worth of mortgagees; the ratio that mortgagees shall maintain between the mortgagee’s capital and the volume of mortgages co-insured by such mortgagee; and such other requirements as the Secretary determines to be appropriate to ensure the long-term financial soundness of the Federal Housing Administration funds. The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Represen</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>