<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1719" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1719/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1719/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1719"><akn:num>1719</akn:num><akn:heading>Secondary market operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1719. Secondary market operations(a) Purchase and sale of mortgages; secondary market operations; advance of funds or origination of loans; settlement or extinguishment of borrower’s rights(1) To carry out the purposes set forth in paragraph (a) 11 See References in Text note below. of section 1716 of this title, the operations of the corporation under this section shall be confined, so far as practicable, to mortgages which are deemed by the corporation to be of such quality, type, and class as to meet, generally, the purchase standards imposed by private institutional mortgage investors. In the interest of assuring sound operation, the prices to be paid by the corporation for mortgages purchased in its secondary market operations under this section, should be established, from time to time, within the range of market prices for the particular class of mortgages involved, as determined by the corporation. The volume of the corporation’s purchases and sales, and the establishment of the purchase prices, sale prices, and charges or fees, in its secondary market operations under this section, should be determined by the corporation from time to time, and such determinations should be consistent with the objectives that such purchases and sales should be effected only at such prices and on such terms as will reasonably prevent excessive use of the corporation’s facilities, and that the operations of the corporation under this section should be within its income derived from such operations and that such operations should be fully self-supporting. Nothing in this subchapter shall prohibit the corporation from purchasing, and making commitments to purchase, any mortgage with respect to which the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development has entered into a contract with the corporation to make interest subsidy payments under section 1715z–8 of this title.

(2) The volume of the corporation’s lending activities and the establishment of its loan ratios, interest rates, m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1719_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase and sale of mortgages; secondary market operations; advance of funds or origination of loans; settlement or extinguishment of borrower’s rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purchase and sale of mortgages; secondary market operations; advance of funds or origination of loans; settlement or extinguishment of borrower’s rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1719_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations of the Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Obligations of the Corporation For the purposes of this section, the corporation is authorized to issue, upon the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, and have outstanding at any one time obligations having such maturities and bearing such rate or rates of interest as may be determined by the corporation with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, to be redeemable at the option of the corporation before maturity in such manner as may be stipulated in such obligations. The corporation shall insert appropriate language in all of its obligations issued under this subsection clearly indicating that such obligations, together with the interest thereon, are not guaranteed by the United States and do not constitute a debt or obligation of the United States or any agency or instrumentality thereof other than the corporation. The corporation is authorized to purchase in the open market any of its obligations outstanding under this subsection at any time and at any price.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1719_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of obligations by Treasury; conditions and restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purchase of obligations by Treasury; conditions and restrictions The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized in the Secretary’s discretion to purchase any obligations issued pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, as now or hereafter in force, and for such purpose the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to use as a public debt transaction the proceeds of the sale of any securities hereafter issued under chapter 31 of title 31, and the purposes for which securities may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are extended to include such purchases. The Secretary of the Treasury shall not at any time purchase any obligations under this subsection if such purchase would increase the aggregate principal amount of the Secretary’s then outstanding holdings of such obligations under this subsection to an amount greater than $2,250,000,000. Each purchase of obligations by the Secretary of the Treasury under this subsection shall be upon such terms and conditions as to yield a return </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1719_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage-backed securities; issuance; maturities; rates of interest; exempt securities; adequacy of mortgages to permit principal and interest payments; statement in securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mortgage-backed securities; issuance; maturities; rates of interest; exempt securities; adequacy of mortgages to permit principal and interest payments; statement in securities To provide a greater degree of liquidity to the mortgage investment market and an additional means of financing its operations under this section, the corporation is authorized to set aside any mortgages held by it under this section, and, upon approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, to issue and sell securities based upon the mortgages so set aside. Securities issued under this subsection may be in the form of debt obligations or trust certificates of beneficial interest, or both. Securities issued under this subsection shall have such maturities and bear such rate or rates of interest as may be determined by the corporation with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury. Securities issued by the corporation under this subsection shall, to the same extent as securities which are direct obligations of</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1719_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subordinated or convertible obligations; issuance; maturities; rate of interest; redemption; exempt securities; debt or obligation of United States; purchases in open market</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subordinated or convertible obligations; issuance; maturities; rate of interest; redemption; exempt securities; debt or obligation of United States; purchases in open market For the purposes of this section, the corporation is authorized to issue, upon the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, obligations which are subordinated to any or all other obligations of the corporation, including subsequent obligations. The obligations issued under this subsection shall have such maturities and bear such rate or rates of interest as may be determined by the corporation with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury and may be made redeemable at the option of the corporation before maturity in such manner as may be stipulated in such obligations. Any of such obligations may be made convertible into shares of common stock in such manner, at such price or prices, and at such time or times as may be stipulated therein. Obligations issued by the corporation under this subsection shall,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1719_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on assessment or collection of fee or charge by United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition on assessment or collection of fee or charge by United States Except for fees paid pursuant to section 1723a(g) of this title and assessments pursuant to section 4516 of this title, no fee or charge may be assessed or collected by the United States (including any executive department, agency, or independent establishment of the United States) on or with regard to the purchase, acquisition, sale, pledge, issuance, guarantee, or redemption of any mortgage, asset, obligation, trust certificate of beneficial interest, or other security by the corporation. No provision of this subsection shall affect the purchase of any obligation by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1719_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary authority of Treasury to purchase obligations and securities; conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Temporary authority of Treasury to purchase obligations and securities; conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>