<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1723a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1723a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1723a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1723a"><akn:num>1723a</akn:num><akn:heading>General powers of Government National Mortgage Association and Federal National Mortgage Association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1723a. General powers of Government National Mortgage Association and Federal National Mortgage Association(a) Seal, and other matters incident to operationEach of the bodies corporate named in section 1717(a)(2) of this title shall have power to adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal, which shall be judicially noticed; to enter into and perform contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, or other transactions, on such terms as it may deem appropriate, with any agency or instrumentality of the United States, or with any State, Territory, or possession, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or with any political subdivision thereof, or with any person, firm, association, or corporation; to execute, in accordance with its bylaws, all instruments necessary or appropriate in the exercise of any of its powers; in its corporate name, to sue and to be sued, and to complain and to defend, in any court of competent jurisdiction, State or Federal, but no attachment, injunction, or other similar process, mesne or final, shall be issued against the property of the Association or against the Association with respect to its property; to conduct its business without regard to any qualification or similar statute in any State of the United States, including the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the Territories and possessions of the United States; to lease, purchase, or acquire any property, real, personal, or mixed, or any interest therein, to hold, rent, maintain, modernize, renovate, improve, use, and operate such property, and to sell, for cash or credit, lease, or otherwise dispose of the same, at such time and in such manner as and to the extent that it may deem necessary or appropriate; to prescribe, repeal, and amend or modify, rules, regulations, or requirements governing the manner in which its general business may be conducted; to accept gifts or donations of services, or of property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible, or intangible, in aid of an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seal, and other matters incident to operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Seal, and other matters incident to operation Each of the bodies corporate named in section 1717(a)(2) of this title shall have power to adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal, which shall be judicially noticed; to enter into and perform contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, or other transactions, on such terms as it may deem appropriate, with any agency or instrumentality of the United States, or with any State, Territory, or possession, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or with any political subdivision thereof, or with any person, firm, association, or corporation; to execute, in accordance with its bylaws, all instruments necessary or appropriate in the exercise of any of its powers; in its corporate name, to sue and to be sued, and to complain and to defend, in any court of competent jurisdiction, State or Federal, but no attachment, injunction, or other similar process, mesne or final, shall be issued against the property of the Association or against the Association w</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination with respect to obligations and expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination with respect to obligations and expenditures Except as may be otherwise provided in this subchapter, in chapter 91 of title 31, or in other laws specifically applicable to Government corporations, the Association shall determine the necessity for and the character and amount of its obligations and expenditures and the manner in which they shall be incurred, allowed, paid, and accounted for.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from taxation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exemption from taxation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and compensation of personnel; use of services of other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Appointment and compensation of personnel; use of services of other agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against use of names; injunction; damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition against use of names; injunction; damages No individual, association, partnership, or corporation, except the bodies corporate named in section 1717(a)(2) of this title, shall hereafter use the words “Federal National Mortgage Association,” “Government National Mortgage Association,” or any combination of such words, as the name or a part thereof under which the individual, association, partnership, or corporation shall do business. Violations of the foregoing sentence may be enjoined by any court of general jurisdiction at the suit of the proper body corporate. In any such suit, the plaintiff may recover any actual damages flowing from such violation, and, in addition, shall be entitled to punitive damages (regardless of the existence or nonexistence of actual damages) of not exceeding $100 for each day during which such violation is committed or repeated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation of forms of obligations and certificates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preparation of forms of obligations and certificates In order that the Association may be supplied with such forms of obligations or certificates as it may need for issuance under this subchapter, the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized, upon request of the Association, to prepare such forms as shall be suitable and approved by the Association, to be held in the Treasury subject to delivery, upon order of the Association. The engraved plates, dies, bed pieces, and other material executed in connection therewith shall remain in the custody of the Secretary of the Treasury. The Association shall reimburse the Secretary of the Treasury for any expenses incurred in the preparation, custody, and delivery of such forms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Depositaries, custodians, and fiscal agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Depositaries, custodians, and fiscal agents The Federal Reserve banks are authorized and directed to act as depositaries, custodians, and fiscal agents for each of the bodies corporate named in section 1717(a)(2) of this title, for its own account or as fiduciary, and such banks shall be reimbursed for such services in such manner as may be agreed upon; and each of such bodies corporate may itself act in such capacities, for its own account or as fiduciary, and for the account of others.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (i) Repealed. Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1381(k), Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 3997</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) , (i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit; access to books, etc.; report of audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Audit; access to books, etc.; report of audit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1723a_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial reports; submission to Director; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) Financial reports; submission to Director; contents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>