<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1757a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1757a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1757a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1757a"><akn:num>1757a</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on member business loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1757a. Limitation on member business loans(a) In generalOn and after August 7, 1998, no insured credit union may make any member business loan that would result in a total amount of such loans outstanding at that credit union at any one time equal to more than the lesser of—(1) 1.75 times the actual net worth of the credit union; or

(2) 1.75 times the minimum net worth required under section 1790d(c)(1)(A) of this title for a credit union to be well capitalized.


(b) ExceptionsSubsection (a) does not apply in the case of—(1) an insured credit union chartered for the purpose of making, or that has a history of primarily making, member business loans to its members, as determined by the Board; or

(2) an insured credit union that—(A) serves predominantly low-income members, as defined by the Board; or

(B) is a community development financial institution, as defined in section 4702 of this title.



(c) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) the term “member business loan”—(A) means any loan, line of credit, or letter of credit, the proceeds of which will be used for a commercial, corporate or other business investment property or venture, or agricultural purpose; and

(B) does not include an extension of credit—(i) that is fully secured by a lien on a 1- to 4-family dwelling;

(ii) that is fully secured by shares in the credit union making the extension of credit or deposits in other financial institutions;

(iii) that is described in subparagraph (A), if it was made to a borrower or an associated member that has a total of all such extensions of credit in an amount equal to less than $50,000;

(iv) the repayment of which is fully insured or fully guaranteed by, or where there is an advance commitment to purchase in full by, any agency of the Federal Government or of a State, or any political subdivision thereof; or

(v) that is granted by a corporate credit union (as that term is defined by the Board) to another credit union.



(2) the term “net worth”—(A) with</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1757a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general On and after August 7, 1998, no insured credit union may make any member business loan that would result in a total amount of such loans outstanding at that credit union at any one time equal to more than the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1757a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions Subsection (a) does not apply in the case of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1757a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1757a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on existing loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect on existing loans An insured credit union that has, on August 7, 1998, a total amount of outstanding member business loans that exceeds the amount permitted under subsection (a) shall, not later than 3 years after August 7, 1998, reduce the total amount of outstanding member business loans to an amount that is not greater than the amount permitted under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1757a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation and cooperation with State credit union supervisors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation and cooperation with State credit union supervisors In implementing this section, the Board shall consult and seek to work cooperatively with State officials having jurisdiction over State-chartered insured credit unions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>