<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1759" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1759/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1759/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1759"><akn:num>1759</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1759. Membership(a) In generalSubject to subsection (b), Federal credit union membership shall consist of the incorporators and such other persons and incorporated and unincorporated organizations, to the extent permitted by rules and regulations prescribed by the Board, as may be elected to membership and as such shall each, subscribe to at least one share of its stock and pay the initial installment thereon and a uniform entrance fee if required by the board of directors. Shares may be issued in joint tenancy with right of survivorship with any persons designated by the credit union member, but no joint tenant shall be permitted to vote, obtain loans, or hold office, unless he is within the field of membership and is a qualified member.


(b) Membership fieldSubject to the other provisions of this section, the membership of any Federal credit union shall be limited to the membership described in one of the following categories:(1) Single common-bond credit unionOne group that has a common bond of occupation or association.


(2) Multiple common-bond credit unionMore than one group—(A) each of which has (within the group) a common bond of occupation or association; and

(B) the number of members, each of which (at the time the group is first included within the field of membership of a credit union described in this paragraph) does not exceed any numerical limitation applicable under subsection (d).


(3) Community credit unionPersons or organizations within a well-defined local community, neighborhood, or rural district.



(c) Exceptions(1) Grandfathered members and groups(A) In generalNotwithstanding subsection (b)—(i) any person or organization that is a member of any Federal credit union as of August 7, 1998, may remain a member of the credit union after August 7, 1998; and

(ii) a member of any group whose members constituted a portion of the membership of any Federal credit union as of August 7, 1998, shall continue to be eligible to become a member of tha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1759_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to subsection (b), Federal credit union membership shall consist of the incorporators and such other persons and incorporated and unincorporated organizations, to the extent permitted by rules and regulations prescribed by the Board, as may be elected to membership and as such shall each, subscribe to at least one share of its stock and pay the initial installment thereon and a uniform entrance fee if required by the board of directors. Shares may be issued in joint tenancy with right of survivorship with any persons designated by the credit union member, but no joint tenant shall be permitted to vote, obtain loans, or hold office, unless he is within the field of membership and is a qualified member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1759_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership field</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership field Subject to the other provisions of this section, the membership of any Federal credit union shall be limited to the membership described in one of the following categories:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1759_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1759_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiple common-bond credit union group requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Multiple common-bond credit union group requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1759_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional membership eligibility provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional membership eligibility provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1759_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for approval of expansion of multiple common-bond credit unions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Criteria for approval of expansion of multiple common-bond credit unions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1759_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations required for community credit unions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations required for community credit unions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>