<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1764" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1764/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1764/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1764"><akn:num>1764</akn:num><akn:heading>Expulsion and withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1764. Expulsion and withdrawal(a) Expulsion by two-thirds voteExcept as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a member may be expelled by a two-thirds vote of the members of a Federal credit union present at a special meeting called for the purpose, but only after opportunity has been given to the member to be heard.


(b) Expulsion based on nonparticipationThe board of directors of a Federal credit union may, by majority vote of a quorum of directors, adopt and enforce a policy with respect to expulsion from membership based on nonparticipation by a member in the affairs of the credit union. In establishing its policy, the board should consider a member’s failure to vote in annual credit union elections or failure to purchase shares from, obtain a loan from, or lend to the Federal credit union. If such a policy is adopted, written notice of the policy as adopted and the effective date of such policy shall be mailed to each member of the credit union at the member’s current address appearing on the records of the credit union not less than thirty days prior to the effective date of such policy. In addition, each new member shall be provided written notice of any such policy prior to or upon applying for membership.


(c) Expulsion for cause(1) In generalExcept as provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, a member may be expelled for cause by a two-thirds vote of a quorum of the directors of the Federal credit union pursuant to a policy which the National Credit Union Administration Board shall adopt, pursuant to a rulemaking, not later than the end of the 18-month period following March 15, 2022.


(2) Distribution of policy to membersA Federal credit union may not expel a member pursuant to this subsection unless the Federal credit union has provided, in written or electronic form, a copy of the policy adopted by the National Credit Union Administration Board under paragraph (1) to each member of the Federal credit union.


(3) Procedure</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expulsion by two-thirds vote</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Expulsion by two-thirds vote Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c) of this section, a member may be expelled by a two-thirds vote of the members of a Federal credit union present at a special meeting called for the purpose, but only after opportunity has been given to the member to be heard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expulsion based on nonparticipation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expulsion based on nonparticipation The board of directors of a Federal credit union may, by majority vote of a quorum of directors, adopt and enforce a policy with respect to expulsion from membership based on nonparticipation by a member in the affairs of the credit union. In establishing its policy, the board should consider a member’s failure to vote in annual credit union elections or failure to purchase shares from, obtain a loan from, or lend to the Federal credit union. If such a policy is adopted, written notice of the policy as adopted and the effective date of such policy shall be mailed to each member of the credit union at the member’s current address appearing on the records of the credit union not less than thirty days prior to the effective date of such policy. In addition, each new member shall be provided written notice of any such policy prior to or upon applying for membership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expulsion for cause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expulsion for cause</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability to credit union</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Liability to credit union Withdrawal or expulsion of a member pursuant to subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this section shall not operate to relieve the member from liability to the Federal credit union. The amount to be paid a withdrawing or expelled member by a Federal credit union shall be determined and paid in a manner specified in the bylaws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1764_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No authority to expel classes of members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No authority to expel classes of members An expulsion of a member pursuant to this section shall be done individually, on a case-by-case basis, and neither the Board nor any Federal credit union may expel a class of members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>