<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1766" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1766/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1766/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1766"><akn:num>1766</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1766. Powers of Board(a) The Board may prescribe rules and regulations for the administration of this chapter (including, but not by way of limitation, the merger, consolidation, and dissolution of corporations organized under this chapter). Any central credit union chartered by the Board shall be subject to such rules, regulations, and orders as the Board deems appropriate and, except as otherwise specifically provided in such rules, regulations, or orders, shall be vested with or subject to the same rights, privileges, duties, restrictions, penalties, liabilities, conditions, and limitations that would apply to all Federal credit unions under this chapter.

(b)(1) The Board may suspend or revoke the charter of any Federal credit union, or place the same in involuntary liquidation and appoint a liquidating agent therefor, upon its finding that the organization is bankrupt or insolvent, or has violated any of the provisions of its charter, its bylaws, this chapter, or any regulations issued thereunder.

(2) The Board, through such persons as it shall designate, may examine any Federal credit union in voluntary liquidation and, upon its finding that such voluntary liquidation is not being conducted in an orderly or efficient manner or in the best interests of its members, may terminate such voluntary liquidation and place such organization in involuntary liquidation and appoint a liquidating agent therefor.

(3) Such liquidating agent shall have power and authority, subject to the control and supervision of the Board and under such rules and regulations as the Board may prescribe, (A) to receive and take possession of the books, rec­ords, assets, and property of every description of the Federal credit union in liquidation, to sell, enforce collection of, and liquidate all such assets and property, to compound all bad or doubtful debts, and to sue in his own name or in the name of the Federal credit union in liquidation, and defend such actions as may be brought aga</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Board may prescribe rules and regulations for the administration of this chapter (including, but not by way of limitation, the merger, consolidation, and dissolution of corporations organized under this chapter). Any central credit union chartered by the Board shall be subject to such rules, regulations, and orders as the Board deems appropriate and, except as otherwise specifically provided in such rules, regulations, or orders, shall be vested with or subject to the same rights, privileges, duties, restrictions, penalties, liabilities, conditions, and limitations that would apply to all Federal credit unions under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) After the expiration of five years from the date of cancellation of the charter of a Federal credit union the Board may, in its discretion, destroy any or all books and records of such Federal credit union in its possession or under its control.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Board is authorized and empowered to execute any and all functions and perform any and all duties vested in it hereby, through such persons as it shall designate or employ; and it may delegate to any person or persons, including any institution operating under the general supervision of the Administration, the performance and discharge of any authority, power, or function vested in it by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) All books and records of Federal credit unions shall be kept and reports shall be made in accordance with forms approved by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Any officer or employee of the Administration is authorized, when designated for the purpose by the Board, to administer oaths and affirmations and to take affidavits and depositions touching upon any matter within the jurisdiction of the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Board is authorized, empowered, and directed to require that every person appointed or elected by any Federal credit union to any position requiring the receipt, payment, or custody of money or other personal property owned by a Federal credit union, or in its custody or control as collateral or otherwise, give bond in a corporate surety company holding a certificate of authority from the Secretary of the Treasury under chapter 93 of title 31, as an acceptable surety on Federal bonds. Any such bond or bonds shall be in a form approved by the Board with a view to providing surety coverage to the Federal credit union with reference to loss by reason of acts of fraud or dishonesty including forgery, theft, embezzlement, wrongful abstraction, or misapplication on the part of the person, directly or through connivance with others, and such other surety coverages as the Board may determine to be reasonably appropriate or as elsewhere required by this chapter. Any such bond or bonds s</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In addition to the authority conferred upon it by other sections of this chapter, the Board is authorized in carrying out its functions under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1766_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>