<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1767" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1767/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1767/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1767"><akn:num>1767</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal agents and depositories; authorization to secure deposits by governmental bodies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1767. Fiscal agents and depositories; authorization to secure deposits by governmental bodies(a) Each Federal credit union organized under this chapter, when requested by the Secretary of the Treasury, shall act as fiscal agent of the United States and shall perform such services as the Secretary of the Treasury may require in connection with the collection of taxes and other obligations due the United States and the lending, borrowing, and repayment of money by the United States, including the issue, sale, redemption, or repurchase of bonds, notes, Treasury certificates of indebtedness, or other obligations of the United States; and to facilitate such purposes the Board shall furnish to the Secretary of the Treasury from time to time the names and addresses of all Federal credit unions with such other available information concerning them as may be requested by the Secretary of the Treasury. Any Federal credit union organized under this chapter, when designated for that purpose by the Secretary of the Treasury, shall be a depository of public money, except receipts from customs, under such regulations as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury.

(b) Any Federal credit union, upon the deposit with it of any funds by the Federal Government, an Indian tribe, or any State or local government or political subdivision thereof as otherwise authorized by this chapter, is authorized to pledge any of its assets securing the payment of the funds so deposited.

(June 26, 1934, ch. 750, title I, § 121, formerly § 17, 48 Stat. 1222; 1947, Reorg. Plan No. 1, § 401, eff. July 1, 1947, 12 F.R. 4534, 61 Stat. 952; June 29, 1948, ch. 711, §§ 1, 2, 62 Stat. 1091; renumbered § 22, Pub. L. 86–354, § 1, Sept. 22, 1959, 73 Stat. 637; amended Pub. L. 91–206, § 2(1), Mar. 10, 1970, 84 Stat. 49; renumbered title I, § 121, Pub. L. 91–468, § 1(2), Oct. 19, 1970, 84 Stat. 994; amended Pub. L. 95–630, title V, § 502(b), Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3681; Pub. L. 100–86, title VII, § 716,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1767_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each Federal credit union organized under this chapter, when requested by the Secretary of the Treasury, shall act as fiscal agent of the United States and shall perform such services as the Secretary of the Treasury may require in connection with the collection of taxes and other obligations due the United States and the lending, borrowing, and repayment of money by the United States, including the issue, sale, redemption, or repurchase of bonds, notes, Treasury certificates of indebtedness, or other obligations of the United States; and to facilitate such purposes the Board shall furnish to the Secretary of the Treasury from time to time the names and addresses of all Federal credit unions with such other available information concerning them as may be requested by the Secretary of the Treasury. Any Federal credit union organized under this chapter, when designated for that purpose by the Secretary of the Treasury, shall be a depository of public money, except receipts from custo</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1767_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any Federal credit union, upon the deposit with it of any funds by the Federal Government, an Indian tribe, or any State or local government or political subdivision thereof as otherwise authorized by this chapter, is authorized to pledge any of its assets securing the payment of the funds so deposited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>