<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1771" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1771/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1771/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1771"><akn:num>1771</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion from Federal to State credit union and from State to Federal credit union</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1771. Conversion from Federal to State credit union and from State to Federal credit union(a) A Federal credit union may be converted into a State credit union under the laws of any State, the District of Columbia, the several Territories and possessions of the United States, the Panama Canal Zone, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, by complying with the following requirements:(1) The proposition for such conversion shall first be approved, and a date set for a vote thereon by the members (either at a meeting to be held on such date or by written ballot to be filed on or before such date), by a majority of the directors of the Federal credit union. Written notice of the proposition and of the date set for the vote shall then be delivered in person to each member, or mailed to each member at the address for such member appearing on the records of the credit union, not more than thirty nor less than seven days prior to such date. Approval of the proposition for conversion shall be by the affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the credit union who vote on the proposal. The written notice of the proposition shall in boldface type state that the issue will be decided by a majority of the members who vote.

(2) A statement of the results of the vote, verified by the affidavits of the president or vice president and the secretary, shall be filed with the Administration within ten days after the vote is taken.

(3) Promptly after the vote is taken and in no event later than ninety days thereafter, if the proposition for conversion was approved by such vote, the credit union shall take such action as may be necessary under the applicable State law to make it a State credit union, and within ten days after receipt of the State credit union charter there shall be filed with the Administration a copy of the charter thus issued. Upon such filing the credit union shall cease to be a Federal credit union.

(4) Upon ceasing to be a Federal credit union, such credit uni</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1771_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A Federal credit union may be converted into a State credit union under the laws of any State, the District of Columbia, the several Territories and possessions of the United States, the Panama Canal Zone, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, by complying with the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1771_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>