<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1786" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1786/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1786/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1786"><akn:num>1786</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of insured credit union status; cease and desist orders; removal or suspension from offi</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1786. Termination of insured credit union status; cease and desist orders; removal or suspension from office; procedure(a) Termination of insurance(1) Any insured credit union other than a Federal credit union may, upon not less than ninety days’ written notice to the Board and upon the affirmative vote of a majority of its members within one year prior to the giving of such notice, terminate its status as an insured credit union.

(2) Any insured credit union, other than a Federal credit union, which has obtained a new certificate of insurance from a corporation authorized and duly licensed to insure member accounts may upon not less than ninety days’ written notice to the Board convert from status as an insured credit union under this chapter: Provided, That at the time of giving notice to the Board the provisions of paragraph (b)(1) of this section are not being invoked against the credit union.


(b) Unsound condition of credit union; notice to correct condition; hearing; judicial review(1) Whenever, in the opinion of the Board, any insured credit union is engaging or has engaged in unsafe or unsound practices in conducting the business of such credit union, or is in an unsafe or unsound condition to continue operations as an insured credit union, or is violating or has violated an applicable law, rule, regulation, order, or any condition imposed in writing by the Board in connection with any action on any application, notice, or other request by the credit union or institution-affiliated party,, 11 So in original. or is violating or has violated any written agreement entered into with the Board, the Board shall serve upon the credit union a statement with respect to such practices or conditions or violations for the purpose of securing the correction thereof. In the case of an insured State-chartered credit union, the Board shall send a copy of such statement to the commission, board, or authority, if any, having supervision of such credit union. Unless such </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Termination of insurance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unsound condition of credit union; notice to correct condition; hearing; judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Unsound condition of credit union; notice to correct condition; hearing; judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to members of termination of insured status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice to members of termination of insured status In the event of the termination of a credit union’s status as an insured credit union as provided under subsection (a)(1) or (b) of this section, the credit union shall give prompt and reasonable notice to all of its members whose accounts are insured that it has ceased to be an insured credit union. It may include in such notice a statement of the fact that member accounts insured on the effective date of such termination, to the extent not withdrawn, remain insured for one year from the date of such termination, but it shall not further represent itself in any manner as an insured credit union. In the event of failure to give the notice as herein provided to members whose accounts are insured, the Board is authorized to give reasonable notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation of insurance for one year; approval of conversion of status; procedure subsequent to approval; reduction of premium charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Continuation of insurance for one year; approval of conversion of status; procedure subsequent to approval; reduction of premium charges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opinion of Board as to unsound condition of credit union; notice of charges; hearing; order to cease and desist; judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Opinion of Board as to unsound condition of credit union; notice of charges; hearing; order to cease and desist; judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary cease and desist order; injunctive procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Temporary cease and desist order; injunctive procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal and prohibition authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Removal and prohibition authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board’s appointment of conservator; consultation with State; authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Board’s appointment of conservator; consultation with State; authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension, removal, and prohibition from participation orders in the case of certain criminal offenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Suspension, removal, and prohibition from participation orders in the case of certain criminal offenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of hearing; procedure; judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Jurisdiction of hearing; procedure; judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>