<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1787" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1787/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1787/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1787"><akn:num>1787</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1787. Payment of insurance(a) Liquidation by Board; bond; appointment of agent; fees to be fixed by Board(1)(A) Upon its finding that a Federal credit union insured under this subchapter is bankrupt or insolvent, the Board shall close such credit union for liquidation and appoint itself liquidating agent therefor.

(B) Not later than 10 days after the date on which the Board closes a credit union for liquidation pursuant to paragraph (1), or accepts appointment as liquidating agent pursuant to subsection (b), such insured credit union may apply to the United States district court for the judicial district in which the principal office of such insured credit union is located or the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, for an order requiring the Board to show cause why it should not be prohibited from continuing such liquidation. Except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph, no court may take any action for or toward the removal of any liquidating agent or, except at the instance of the Board, restrain or affect the exercise of powers or functions of a liquidating agent.


(2) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Board as liquidating agent of a closed Federal credit union insured under this subchapter shall not be required to furnish bond and shall have the right to appoint an agent or agents to assist it in its duties as such liquidating agent. All fees, compensation, and expenses of liquidation and administration thereof shall be fixed by the Board and may be paid by them out of funds coming into its possession as such liquidating agent.

(3) Liquidation to facilitate prompt corrective action.—The Board may close any credit union for liquidation, and appoint itself or another (including, in the case of a State-chartered insured credit union, the State official having jurisdiction over the credit union) as liquidating agent of that credit union, if—(A) the Board determines that—(i) the credit union is significantly undercapital</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation by Board; bond; appointment of agent; fees to be fixed by Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liquidation by Board; bond; appointment of agent; fees to be fixed by Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of Board as conservator or liquidating agent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Powers and duties of Board as conservator or liquidating agent</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to contracts entered into before appointment of conservator or liquidating agent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provisions relating to contracts entered into before appointment of conservator or liquidating agent</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of insured deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment of insured deposits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subrogation of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subrogation of Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation of claims in default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Valuation of claims in default</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on court action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on court action Except as provided in this section, no court may take any action, except at the request of the Board of Directors by regulation or order, to restrain or affect the exercise of powers or functions of the Board as a conservator or a liquidating agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of directors and officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Liability of directors and officers A director or officer of an insured credit union may be held personally liable for monetary damages in any civil action by, on behalf of, or at the request or direction of the Board, which action is prosecuted wholly or partially for the benefit of the Board— for gross negligence, including any similar conduct or conduct that demonstrates a greater disregard of a duty of care (than gross negligence) including intentional tortious conduct, as such terms are defined and determined under applicable State law. Nothing in this paragraph shall impair or affect any right, if any, of the Board under other applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Damages In any proceeding related to any claim against an insured credit union’s director, officer, employee, agent, attorney, accountant, appraiser, or any other party employed by or providing services to an insured credit union, recoverable damages determined to result from the improvident or otherwise improper use or investment of any insured credit union’s assets shall include principal losses and appropriate interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1787_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board as liquidating agent of State-chartered credit unions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Board as liquidating agent of State-chartered credit unions Whenever any insured State-chartered credit union shall have been closed by action of its board of directors or by the commission, board, or authority having supervision of such credit union, as the case may be, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, on account of bankruptcy or insolvency, the Board shall accept appointment as liquidating agent therefor, if such appointment is tendered by the commission, board, or authority having supervision of such credit union, or by a court of competent jurisdiction, and is authorized or permitted by State law. With respect to any such State-chartered credit union, the Board as such liquidating agent shall possess all the rights, powers, and privileges granted by State law to a liquidating agent of a State-chartered credit union. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “liquidating agent” includes a liquidating agent, receiver, conservator, commission, person, or other agency c</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>