<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1790d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1790d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1790d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1790d"><akn:num>1790d</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt corrective action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1790d. Prompt corrective action(a) Resolving problems to protect Fund(1) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to resolve the problems of insured credit unions at the least possible long-term loss to the Fund.


(2) Prompt corrective action requiredThe Board shall carry out the purpose of this section by taking prompt corrective action to resolve the problems of insured credit unions.



(b) Regulations required(1) Insured credit unions(A) In generalThe Board shall, by regulation, prescribe a system of prompt corrective action for insured credit unions that is—(i) consistent with this section; and

(ii) comparable to section 1831o of this title.


(B) Cooperative character of credit unionsThe Board shall design the system required under subparagraph (A) to take into account that credit unions are not-for-profit cooperatives that—(i) do not issue capital stock;

(ii) must rely on retained earnings to build net worth; and

(iii) have boards of directors that consist primarily of volunteers.



(2) New credit unions(A) In generalIn addition to regulations under paragraph (1), the Board shall, by regulation, prescribe a system of prompt corrective action that shall apply to new credit unions in lieu of this section and the regulations prescribed under paragraph (1).


(B) Criteria for alternative systemThe Board shall design the system prescribed under subparagraph (A)—(i) to carry out the purpose of this section;

(ii) to recognize that credit unions (as cooperatives that do not issue capital stock) initially have no net worth, and give new credit unions reasonable time to accumulate net worth;

(iii) to create adequate incentives for new credit unions to become adequately capitalized by the time that they either—(I) have been in operation for more than 10 years; or

(II) have more than $10,000,000 in total assets;


(iv) to impose appropriate restrictions and requirements on new credit unions that do not make sufficient progress toward becoming adequately capitalize</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolving problems to protect Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Resolving problems to protect Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net worth categories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Net worth categories</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk-based net worth requirement for complex credit unions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Risk-based net worth requirement for complex credit unions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Earnings-retention requirement applicable to credit unions that are not well capitalized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Earnings-retention requirement applicable to credit unions that are not well capitalized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net worth restoration plan required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Net worth restoration plan required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on undercapitalized credit unions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Restrictions on undercapitalized credit unions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>More stringent treatment based on other supervisory criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) More stringent treatment based on other supervisory criteria With respect to the exercise of authority by the Board under regulations comparable to section 1831o(g) of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action required regarding critically undercapitalized credit unions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Action required regarding critically undercapitalized credit unions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1790d_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reviews required when share insurance fund experiences losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reviews required when share insurance fund experiences losses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>