<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1815" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1815/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1815/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1815"><akn:num>1815</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1815. Deposit insurance(a) Application to Corporation required(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), any depository institution which is engaged in the business of receiving deposits other than trust funds (as defined in section 1813(p) of this title), upon application to and examination by the Corporation and approval by the Board of Directors, may become an insured depository institution.


(2) Interim depository institutionsIn the case of any interim Federal depository institution that is chartered by the appropriate Federal banking agency and will not open for business, the depository institution shall be an insured depository institution upon the issuance of the institution’s charter by the agency.


(3) Application and approval not required in cases of continued insuranceParagraph (1) shall not apply in the case of any depository institution whose insured status is continued pursuant to section 1814 of this title.


(4) Review requirementsIn reviewing any application under this subsection, the Board of Directors shall consider the factors described in section 1816 of this title in determining whether to approve the application for insurance.


(5) Notice of denial of application for insuranceIf the Board of Directors votes to deny any application for insurance by any depository institution, the Board of Directors shall promptly notify the appropriate Federal banking agency and, in the case of any State depository institution, the appropriate State banking supervisor of the denial of such application, giving specific reasons in writing for the Board of Directors’ determination with reference to the factors described in section 1816 of this title.


(6) Nondelegation requirementThe authority of the Board of Directors to make any determination to deny any application under this subsection may not be delegated by the Board of Directors.



(b) Foreign branch nonmember banks; matters consideredSubject to the provisions of this chapter and to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1815_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to Corporation required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application to Corporation required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1815_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign branch nonmember banks; matters considered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Foreign branch nonmember banks; matters considered Subject to the provisions of this chapter and to such terms and conditions as the Board of Directors may impose, any branch of a foreign bank, upon application by the bank to the Corporation, and examination by the Corporation of the branch, and approval by the Board of Directors, may become an insured branch. Before approving any such application, the Board of Directors shall give consideration to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1815_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection to Deposit Insurance Fund; surety bond, pledge of assets, etc.; injunction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Protection to Deposit Insurance Fund; surety bond, pledge of assets, etc.; injunction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1815_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Insurance fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1815_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of commonly controlled depository institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Liability of commonly controlled depository institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>