<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1817" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1817/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1817/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1817"><akn:num>1817</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1817. Assessments(a) Reports of condition; access to reports(1) Each insured State nonmember bank and each foreign bank having an insured branch which is not a Federal branch shall make to the Corporation reports of condition which shall be in such form and shall contain such information as the Board of Directors may require. Such reports shall be made to the Corporation on the dates selected as provided in paragraph (3) of this subsection and the deposit liabilities shall be reported therein in accordance with and pursuant to paragraphs (4) and (5) of this subsection. The Board of Directors may call for additional reports of condition on dates to be fixed by it and may call for such other reports as the Board may from time to time require. Any such bank which (A) maintains procedures reasonably adapted to avoid any inadvertent error and, unintentionally and as a result of such an error, fails to make or publish any report required under this paragraph, within the period of time specified by the Corporation, or submits or publishes any false or misleading report or information, or (B) inadvertently transmits or publishes any report which is minimally late, shall be subject to a penalty of not more than $2,000 for each day during which such failure continues or such false or misleading information is not corrected. Such bank shall have the burden of proving that an error was inadvertent and that a report was inadvertently transmitted or published late. Any such bank which fails to make or publish any report required under this paragraph, within the period of time specified by the Corporation, or submits or publishes any false or misleading report or information, in a manner not described in the 2nd preceding sentence shall be subject to a penalty of not more than $20,000 for each day during which such failure continues or such false or misleading information is not corrected. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, if any such bank knowingly or with reckless disreg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports of condition; access to reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports of condition; access to reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certified statements; payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certified statements; payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporation exempt from apportionment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Corporation exempt from apportionment Notwithstanding any other provision of law, amounts received pursuant to any assessment under this section and any other amounts received by the Corporation shall not be subject to apportionment for the purposes of chapter 15 of title 31 or under any other authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refunds, dividends, and credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Refunds, dividends, and credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action against depository institutions failing to file certified statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Action against depository institutions failing to file certified statements Any insured depository institution which fails to make any report of condition under subsection (a) of this section or to file any certified statement required to be filed by it in connection with determining the amount of any assessment payable by the depository institution to the Corporation may be compelled to make such report or file such statement by mandatory injunction or other appropriate remedy in a suit brought for such purpose by the Corporation against the depository institution and any officer or officers thereof in any court of the United States of competent jurisdiction in the District or Territory in which such depository institution is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assessment actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeiture of rights for failure to comply with law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Forfeiture of rights for failure to comply with law Should any national member bank or any insured national nonmember bank fail to make any report of condition under subsection (a) of this section or to file any certified statement required to be filed by such bank under any provision of this section, or fail to pay any assessment required to be paid by such bank under any provision of this chapter, and should the bank not correct such failure within thirty days after written notice has been given by the Corporation to an officer of the bank, citing this subsection, and stating that the bank has failed to make any report of condition under subsection (a) of this section or to file or pay as required by law, all the rights, privileges, and franchises of the bank granted to it under the National Bank Act, as amended [12 U.S.C. 21 et seq.], the Federal Reserve Act, as amended [12 U.S.C. 221 et seq.], or this chapter, shall be thereby forfeited. Whether or not the penalty provided in t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance of trust funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Insurance of trust funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1817_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change in control of insured depository institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Change in control of insured depository institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>