<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1821a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1821a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1821a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1821a"><akn:num>1821a</akn:num><akn:heading>FSLIC Resolution Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1821a. FSLIC Resolution Fund(a) Established(1) In generalThere is established a separate fund to be designated as the FSLIC Resolution Fund which shall be managed by the Corporation and separately maintained and not commingled.


(2) Transfer of FSLIC assets and liabilitiesExcept as provided in section 1441a 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, all assets and liabilities of the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation on the day before August 9, 1989, shall be transferred to the FSLIC Resolution Fund.


(3) Separate holdingAssets and liabilities transferred to the FSLIC Resolution Fund shall be the assets and liabilities of the Fund and not of the Corporation and shall not be consolidated with the assets and liabilities of the Deposit Insurance Fund or the Corporation for accounting, reporting, or any other purpose.


(4) Rights, powers, and dutiesEffective August 10, 1989, the Corporation shall have all rights, powers, and duties to carry out the Corporation’s duties with respect to the assets and liabilities of the FSLIC Resolution Fund that the Corporation otherwise has under this chapter.


(5) Corporation as conservator or receiver(A) In generalEffective August 10, 1989, the Corporation shall succeed the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation as conservator or receiver with respect to any depository institution—(i) the accounts of which were insured before August 10, 1989 by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation; and

(ii) for which a conservator or receiver was appointed before January 1, 1989.


(B) Rights, powers, and dutiesWhen acting as conservator or receiver with respect to any depository institution described in subparagraph (A), the Corporation shall have all rights, powers, and duties that the Corporation otherwise has as conservator or receiver under this chapter.




(b) Source of fundsThe FSLIC Resolution Fund shall be funded from the following sources to the extent funds are needed in the listed priorit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Established</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Established</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Source of funds The FSLIC Resolution Fund shall be funded from the following sources to the extent funds are needed in the listed priority:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treasury backup</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treasury backup</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Legal proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Legal proceedings Any judgment resulting from a proceeding to which the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation was a party prior to its dissolution or which is initiated against the Corporation with respect to the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation or with respect to the FSLIC Resolution Fund shall be limited to the assets of the FSLIC Resolution Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of net proceeds from sale of RTC assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transfer of net proceeds from sale of RTC assets The FSLIC Resolution Fund shall transfer to the Resolution Funding Corporation any net proceeds from the sale of assets acquired from the Resolution Trust Corporation upon the termination of such Corporation pursuant to section 1441a 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Dissolution The FSLIC Resolution Fund shall be dissolved upon satisfaction of all debts and liabilities and sale of all assets. Upon dissolution any remaining funds shall be paid into the Treasury. Any administrative facilities and supplies, including offices and office supplies, shall be transferred to the Corporation for use by and to be held as assets of the Deposit Insurance Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>