<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1821" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1821/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1821/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1821"><akn:num>1821</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1821. Insurance Funds(a) Deposit insurance(1) Insured amounts payable(A) In generalThe Corporation shall insure the deposits of all insured depository institutions as provided in this chapter.


(B) Net amount of insured depositThe net amount due to any depositor at an insured depository institution shall not exceed the standard maximum deposit insurance amount as determined in accordance with subparagraphs (C), (D), (E) and (F) and paragraph (3).


(C) Aggregation of depositsFor the purpose of determining the net amount due to any depositor under subparagraph (B), the Corporation shall aggregate the amounts of all deposits in the insured depository institution which are maintained by a depositor in the same capacity and the same right for the benefit of the depositor either in the name of the depositor or in the name of any other person, other than any amount in a trust fund described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 1817(i) of this title or any funds described in section 1817(i)(3) of this title.


(D) Coverage for certain employee benefit plan deposits(i) Pass-through insuranceThe Corporation shall provide pass-through deposit insurance for the deposits of any employee benefit plan.


(ii) Prohibition on acceptance of benefit plan depositsAn insured depository institution that is not well capitalized or adequately capitalized may not accept employee benefit plan deposits.


(iii) DefinitionsFor purposes of this subparagraph, the following definitions shall apply:(I) Capital standardsThe terms “well capitalized” and “adequately capitalized” have the same meanings as in section 1831o of this title.


(II) Employee benefit planThe term “employee benefit plan” has the same meaning as in paragraph (5)(B)(ii), and includes any eligible deferred compensation plan described in section 457 of title 26.


(III) Pass-through deposit insuranceThe term “pass-through deposit insurance” means, with respect to an employee benefit plan, deposit insurance coverage based on the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deposit insurance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation as closing of depository institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Liquidation as closing of depository institution For the purposes of this chapter an insured depository institution shall be deemed to have been closed on account of inability to meet the demands of its depositors in any case in which it has been closed for the purpose of liquidation without adequate provision being made for payment of its depositors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Corporation as conservator or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appointment of Corporation as conservator or receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of Corporation as conservator or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Powers and duties of Corporation as conservator or receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to contracts entered into before appointment of conservator or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Provisions relating to contracts entered into before appointment of conservator or receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of insured deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Payment of insured deposits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subrogation of Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subrogation of Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions applicable to resolution proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Conditions applicable to resolution proceedings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation of claims in default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Valuation of claims in default</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on court action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Limitation on court action Except as provided in this section, no court may take any action, except at the request of the Board of Directors by regulation or order, to restrain or affect the exercise of powers or functions of the Corporation as a conservator or a receiver.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>