<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1823" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1823/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1823/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1823"><akn:num>1823</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporation monies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1823. Corporation monies(a) Investment of Corporation’s funds(1) AuthorityFunds held in the Deposit Insurance Fund or the FSLIC Resolution Fund, that are not otherwise employed shall be invested in obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States.


(2) LimitationThe Corporation shall not sell or purchase any obligations described in paragraph (1) for its own account, at any one time aggregating in excess of $100,000, without the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury. The Secretary may approve a transaction or class of transactions subject to the provisions of this paragraph under such conditions as the Secretary may determine.



(b) Depository accountsThe depository accounts of the Corporation shall be kept with the Treasurer of the United States, or, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, with a Federal Reserve bank, or with a depository institution designated as a depository or fiscal agent of the United States: Provided, That the Secretary of the Treasury may waive the requirements of this subsection under such conditions as he may determine: And provided further, That this subsection shall not apply to the establishment and maintenance in any depository institution for temporary purposes of depository accounts not in excess of $50,000 in any one depository institution, or to the establishment and maintenance in any depository institution of any depository accounts to facilitate the payment of insured deposits, or the making of loans to, or the purchase of assets of, insured depository institutions. When designated for that purpose by the Secretary of the Treasury, the Corporation shall be a depositary of public moneys, except receipts from customs, under such regulations as may be prescribed by the said Secretary, and may also be employed as a financial agent of the Government. It shall perform all such reasonable duties as depositary of public moneys and financial agent of the G</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of Corporation’s funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Investment of Corporation’s funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Depository accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Depository accounts The depository accounts of the Corporation shall be kept with the Treasurer of the United States, or, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury, with a Federal Reserve bank, or with a depository institution designated as a depository or fiscal agent of the United States: Provided, That the Secretary of the Treasury may waive the requirements of this subsection under such conditions as he may determine: And provided further, That this subsection shall not apply to the establishment and maintenance in any depository institution for temporary purposes of depository accounts not in excess of $50,000 in any one depository institution, or to the establishment and maintenance in any depository institution of any depository accounts to facilitate the payment of insured deposits, or the making of loans to, or the purchase of assets of, insured depository institutions. When designated for that purpose by the Secretary of the Treasury, the Corporation shall be a d</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to insured depository institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance to insured depository institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of assets to Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Sale of assets to Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements against interests of Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Agreements against interests of Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assisted emergency interstate acquisitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Assisted emergency interstate acquisitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of interest on stock subscriptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payment of interest on stock subscriptions Prior to July 1, 1951, the Corporation shall pay out of its capital account to the Secretary of the Treasury an amount equal to 2 per centum simple interest per annum on amounts advanced to the Corporation on stock subscriptions by the Secretary of the Treasury and the Federal Reserve banks, from the time of such advances until the amounts thereof were repaid. The amount payable hereunder shall be paid in two equal installments, the first installment to be paid prior to December 31, 1950.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reopening or aversion of closing of insured branch of foreign bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reopening or aversion of closing of insured branch of foreign bank The powers conferred on the Board of Directors and the Corporation by this section to take action to reopen an insured depository institution in default or to avert the default of an insured depository institution may be used with respect to an insured branch of a foreign bank if, in the judgment of the Board of Directors, the public interest in avoiding the default of such branch substantially outweighs any additional risk of loss to the Deposit Insurance Fund which the exercise of such powers would entail.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 97–320, title II, § 206, Oct. 15, 1982, 96 Stat. 1496</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1823_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan loss amortization for certain banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Loan loss amortization for certain banks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>