<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1827" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1827/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1827/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1827"><akn:num>1827</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by Corporation; audit of financial transactions; report on audits; employment of certified p</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1827. Reports by Corporation; audit of financial transactions; report on audits; employment of certified public accountants for audits(a) Annual reports on the Deposit Insurance Fund and the FSLIC Resolution Fund(1) In generalThe Corporation shall annually submit a full report of its operations, activities, budget, receipts, and expenditures for the preceding 12-month period. The report shall include, with respect to the Deposit Insurance Fund and the FSLIC Resolution Fund, an analysis by the Corporation of—(A) the current financial condition of each such fund;

(B) the purpose, effect, and estimated cost of each resolution action taken for an insured depository institution during the preceding year;

(C) the extent to which the actual costs of assistance provided to, or for the benefit of, an insured depository institution during the preceding year exceeded the estimated costs of such assistance reported in a previous year under paragraph (A);

(D) the exposure of the Deposit Insurance Fund to changes in those economic factors most likely to affect the condition of that fund;

(E) a current estimate of the resources needed for the Deposit Insurance Fund or the FSLIC Resolution Fund to achieve the purposes of this chapter; and

(F) any findings, conclusions, and recommendations for legislative and administrative actions considered appropriate to future resolution activities by the Corporation.


(2) Manner of submissionSuch report shall be submitted to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, who shall cause the same to be printed for the information of Congress, and the President as soon as practicable after the first day of January each year.


(3) Coordination with other report requirementsThe report required under this subsection shall include the report required under section 57a(f)(7) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 15.



(b) Quarterly reports to Treasury(1) Financial operating plans and forecastsBefore the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1827_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports on the Deposit Insurance Fund and the FSLIC Resolution Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual reports on the Deposit Insurance Fund and the FSLIC Resolution Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1827_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quarterly reports to Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Quarterly reports to Treasury</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1827_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to OMB</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports to OMB</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1827_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Audit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1827_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit of Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Audit of Corporation The financial transactions of the Corporation shall be audited by the Government Accountability Office in accordance with the principles and procedures applicable to commercial corporate transactions and under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Comptroller General of the United States. The audit shall be conducted at the place or places where accounts of the Corporation are normally kept. The representatives of the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all books, accounts, records, reports, files, and all other papers, things, or property belonging to or in use by the Corporation pertaining to its financial transactions and necessary to facilitate the audit, and they shall be afforded full facilities for verifying transactions with the balances or securities held by depositaries, fiscal agents, and custodians. All such books, accounts, rec­ords, reports, files, papers, and property of the Corporation shall remain in possessio</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1827_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report of audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report of audit A report of each audit conducted under subsection (b) of this section shall be made by the Comptroller General to the Congress not later than six and one-half months following the close of the last year covered by such audit. The report to the Congress shall set forth the scope of the audit and shall include a statement of assets and liabilities and surplus or deficit; a statement of surplus or deficit analysis; a statement of income and expenses; a statement of sources and application of funds and such comments and information as may be deemed necessary to inform Congress of the financial operations and condition of the Corporation, together with such recommendations with respect thereto as the Comptroller General may deem advisable. The report shall also show specifically any program, expenditure, or other financial transaction or undertaking observed in the course of the audit, which, in the opinion of the Comptroller General, has been carried on or made without </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1827_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance in audit; costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistance in audit; costs For the purpose of conducting such audit the Comptroller General is authorized in his discretion to employ by contract, without regard to section 6101 of title 41, professional services of firms and organizations of certified public accountants, with the concurrence of the Corporation, for temporary periods or for special purposes. The Corporation shall reimburse the Government Accountability Office for the cost of any such audit as billed therefor by the Comptroller General, and the Government Accountability Office shall deposit the sums so reimbursed into the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>