<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1829b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1829b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1829b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1829b"><akn:num>1829b</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of records by insured depository institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1829b. Retention of records by insured depository institutions(a) Congressional findings and declaration of purpose(1) FindingsCongress finds that—(A) adequate records maintained by insured depository institutions have a high degree of usefulness in criminal, tax, and regulatory investigations or proceedings, and that, given the threat posed to the security of the Nation on and after the terrorist attacks against the United States on September 11, 2001, such records may also have a high degree of usefulness in the conduct of intelligence or counterintelligence activities, including analysis, to protect against domestic and international terrorism; and

(B) microfilm or other reproductions and other records made by insured depository institutions of checks, as well as records kept by such institutions, of the identity of persons maintaining or authorized to act with respect to accounts therein, have been of particular value in proceedings described in subparagraph (A).


(2) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section to require the maintenance of appropriate types of records by insured depository institutions in the United States where such records have a high degree of usefulness in criminal, tax, or regulatory investigations or proceedings, recognizing that, given the threat posed to the security of the Nation on and after the terrorist attacks against the United States on September 11, 2001, such records may also have a high degree of usefulness in the conduct of intelligence or counterintelligence activities, including analysis, to protect against international terrorism.



(b) Recordkeeping regulations(1) In generalWhere the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) determines that the maintenance of appropriate types of records and other evidence by insured depository institutions has a high degree of usefulness in criminal, tax, or regulatory investigations or proceedings, he shall prescribe regulations to carry out the purpos</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recordkeeping regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identity of persons having accounts and persons authorized to act with respect to such accounts; exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Identity of persons having accounts and persons authorized to act with respect to such accounts; exemptions Subject to the requirements of any regulations prescribed jointly by the Secretary and the Board under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (b), each insured depository institution shall maintain such rec­ords and other evidence, in such form as the Secretary shall require, of the identity of each person having an account in the United States with the insured depository institution and of each individual authorized to sign checks, make withdrawals, or otherwise act with respect to any such account. The Secretary may make such exemptions from any requirement otherwise imposed under this subsection as are consistent with the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reproduction of checks, drafts, and other instruments; record of transactions; identity of party</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reproduction of checks, drafts, and other instruments; record of transactions; identity of party Each insured depository institution shall make, to the extent that the regulations of the Secretary so require—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identity of persons making reportable currency and foreign transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Identity of persons making reportable currency and foreign transactions Subject to the requirements of any regulations prescribed jointly by the Secretary and the Board under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (b), whenever any individual engages (whether as principal, agent, or bailee) in any transaction with an insured depository institution which is required to be reported or recorded under subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31, the insured depository institution shall require and retain such evidence of the identity of that individual as the Secretary may prescribe as appropriate under the circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additions to or substitutes for required records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additions to or substitutes for required records Subject to the requirements of any regulations prescribed jointly by the Secretary and the Board under paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (b) and in addition to or in lieu of the records and evidence otherwise referred to in this section, each insured depository institution shall maintain such records and evidence as the Secretary may prescribe to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Retention period Any type of record or evidence required under this section shall be retained for such period as the Secretary may prescribe for the type in question. Any period so prescribed shall not exceed six years unless the Secretary determines, having regard for the purposes of this section, that a longer period is necessary in the case of a particular type of record or evidence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress by Secretary of the Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report to Congress by Secretary of the Treasury The Secretary shall include in his annual report to the Congress information on his implementation of the authority conferred by this section and any similar authority with respect to recordkeeping or reporting requirements conferred by other provisions of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of provisions to foreign banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Application of provisions to foreign banks The provisions of this section shall not apply to any foreign bank except with respect to the transactions and records of any insured branch of such a bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Civil penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>