<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1829c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1829c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1829c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1829c"><akn:num>1829c</akn:num><akn:heading>Making online banking initiation legal and easy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1829c. Making online banking initiation legal and easy(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) AffiliateThe term “affiliate” has the meaning given the term in section 1841 of this title.


(2) Driver’s licenseThe term “driver’s license” means a license issued by a State to an individual that authorizes the individual to operate a motor vehicle on public streets, roads, or highways.


(3) Federal bank secrecy lawsThe term “Federal bank secrecy laws” means—(A) section 1829b of this title;

(B) section 1953 of this title; and

(C) subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 31.


(4) Financial institutionThe term “financial institution” means—(A) an insured depository institution;

(B) an insured credit union; or

(C) any affiliate of an insured depository institution or insured credit union.


(5) Financial product or serviceThe term “financial product or service” has the meaning given the term in section 5481 of this title.


(6) Insured credit unionThe term “insured credit union” has the meaning given the term in section 1752 of this title.


(7) Insured depository institutionThe term “insured depository institution” has the meaning given the term in section 1813 of this title.


(8) Online serviceThe term “online service” means any Internet-based service, such as a website or mobile application.


(9) Personal identification cardThe term “personal identification card” means an identification document issued by a State or local government to an individual solely for the purpose of identification of that individual.


(10) Personal informationThe term “personal information” means the information displayed on or electronically encoded on a driver’s license or personal identification card that is reasonably necessary to fulfill the purpose and uses permitted by subsection (b).


(11) ScanThe term “scan” means the act of using a device or software to decipher, in an electronically readable format, personal information displayed on or electronically encoded on a driver’s license or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of a driver’s license or personal identification card</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of a driver’s license or personal identification card</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Relation to State law The provisions of this section shall preempt and supersede any State law that conflicts with a provision of this section, but only to the extent of such conflict.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>