<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1829" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1829/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1829/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1829"><akn:num>1829</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for unauthorized participation by convicted individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1829. Penalty for unauthorized participation by convicted individual(a) Prohibition(1) In generalExcept with the prior written consent of the Corporation—(A) any person who has been convicted of any criminal offense involving dishonesty or a breach of trust or money laundering, or has agreed to enter into a pretrial diversion or similar program in connection with a prosecution for such offense, may not—(i) become, or continue as, an institution-affiliated party with respect to any insured depository institution;

(ii) own or control, directly or indirectly, any insured depository institution; or

(iii) otherwise participate, directly or indirectly, in the conduct of the affairs of any insured depository institution; and


(B) any insured depository institution may not permit any person referred to in subparagraph (A) to engage in any conduct or continue any relationship prohibited under such subparagraph.


(2) Minimum 10-year prohibition period for certain offenses(A) In generalIf the offense referred to in paragraph (1)(A) in connection with any person referred to in such paragraph is—(i) an offense under—(I) section 215, 656, 657, 1005, 1006, 1007, 1008,11 See References in Text note below. 1014, 1032, 1344, 1517, 1956, or 1957 of title 18; or

(II) section 1341 or 1343 of such title which affects any financial institution (as defined in section 20 of such title); or


(ii) the offense of conspiring to commit any such offense,


the Corporation may not consent to any exception to the application of paragraph (1) to such person during the 10-year period beginning on the date the conviction or the agreement of the person becomes final.

(B) Exception by order of sentencing court(i) In generalOn motion of the Corporation, the court in which the conviction or the agreement of a person referred to in subparagraph (A) has been entered may grant an exception to the application of paragraph (1) to such person if granting the exception is in the interest of justice.


(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalty Whoever knowingly violates subsection (a) shall be fined not more than $1,000,000 for each day such prohibition is violated or imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bank holding companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Bank holding companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings and loan holding companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Savings and loan holding companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consent applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consent applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1829_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>