<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831x" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831x/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831x/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1831x"><akn:num>1831x</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance customer protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1831x. Insurance customer protections(a) Regulations required(1) In generalThe Federal banking agencies shall prescribe and publish in final form, before the end of the 1-year period beginning on November 12, 1999, customer protection regulations (which the agencies jointly determine to be appropriate) that—(A) apply to retail sales practices, solicitations, advertising, or offers of any insurance product by any depository institution or any person that is engaged in such activities at an office of the institution or on behalf of the institution; and

(B) are consistent with the requirements of this chapter and provide such additional protections for customers to whom such sales, solicitations, advertising, or offers are directed.


(2) Applicability to subsidiariesThe regulations prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall extend such protections to any subsidiary of a depository institution, as deemed appropriate by the regulators referred to in paragraph (3), where such extension is determined to be necessary to ensure the consumer protections provided by this section.


(3) Consultation and joint regulationsThe Federal banking agencies shall consult with each other and prescribe joint regulations pursuant to paragraph (1), after consultation with the State insurance regulators, as appropriate.



(b) Sales practicesThe regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) shall include antitying and anticoercion rules applicable to the sale of insurance products that prohibit a depository institution from engaging in any practice that would lead a customer to believe an extension of credit, in violation of section 1972 of this title, is conditional upon—(1) the purchase of an insurance product from the institution or any of its affiliates; or

(2) an agreement by the consumer not to obtain, or a prohibition on the consumer from obtaining, an insurance product from an unaffiliated entity.


(c) Disclosures and advertisingThe regulations prescribed pursuant to subsec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831x_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831x_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sales practices The regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) shall include antitying and anticoercion rules applicable to the sale of insurance products that prohibit a depository institution from engaging in any practice that would lead a customer to believe an extension of credit, in violation of section 1972 of this title, is conditional upon—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831x_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosures and advertising</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disclosures and advertising The regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) shall include the following provisions relating to disclosures and advertising in connection with the initial purchase of an insurance product:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831x_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation of banking and nonbanking activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Separation of banking and nonbanking activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831x_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic violence discrimination prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Domestic violence discrimination prohibition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831x_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer grievance process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consumer grievance process The Federal banking agencies shall jointly establish a consumer complaint mechanism, for receiving and expeditiously addressing consumer complaints alleging a violation of regulations issued under the section, which shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831x_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect on other authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831x_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-discrimination against non-affiliated agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Non-discrimination against non-affiliated agents The Federal banking agencies shall ensure that the regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (a) shall not have the effect of discriminating, either intentionally or unintentionally, against any person engaged in insurance sales or solicitations that is not affiliated with a depository institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>