<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1831o"><akn:num>1831o</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt corrective action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1831o. Prompt corrective action(a) Resolving problems to protect Deposit Insurance Fund(1) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to resolve the problems of insured depository institutions at the least possible long-term loss to the Deposit Insurance Fund.


(2) Prompt corrective action requiredEach appropriate Federal banking agency and the Corporation (acting in the Corporation’s capacity as the insurer of depository institutions under this chapter) shall carry out the purpose of this section by taking prompt corrective action to resolve the problems of insured depository institutions.



(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) Capital categories(A) Well capitalizedAn insured depository institution is “well capitalized” if it significantly exceeds the required minimum level for each relevant capital measure.


(B) Adequately capitalizedAn insured depository institution is “adequately capitalized” if it meets the required minimum level for each relevant capital measure.


(C) UndercapitalizedAn insured depository institution is “undercapitalized” if it fails to meet the required minimum level for any relevant capital measure.


(D) Significantly undercapitalizedAn insured depository institution is “significantly undercapitalized” if it is significantly below the required minimum level for any relevant capital measure.


(E) Critically undercapitalizedAn insured depository institution is “critically undercapitalized” if it fails to meet any level specified under subsection (c)(3)(A).



(2) Other definitions(A) Average(i) In generalThe “average” of an accounting item (such as total assets or tangible equity) during a given period means the sum of that item at the close of business on each business day during that period divided by the total number of business days in that period.


(ii) Agency may permit weekly averaging for certain institutionsIn the case of insured depository institutions that have total assets of less than $300,000,000 and normally file </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolving problems to protect Deposit Insurance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Resolving problems to protect Deposit Insurance Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Capital standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions applicable to all institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provisions applicable to all institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions applicable to undercapitalized institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Provisions applicable to undercapitalized institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions applicable to significantly undercapitalized institutions and undercapitalized institutions that fail to submit and implement capital restoration plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Provisions applicable to significantly undercapitalized institutions and undercapitalized institutions that fail to submit and implement capital restoration plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>More stringent treatment based on other supervisory criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) More stringent treatment based on other supervisory criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions applicable to critically undercapitalized institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Provisions applicable to critically undercapitalized institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restricting activities of critically undercapitalized institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Restricting activities of critically undercapitalized institutions To carry out the purpose of this section, the Corporation shall, by regulation or order—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831o_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Government-controlled institutions exempted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Certain Government-controlled institutions exempted Subsections (e) through (i) (other than paragraph (3) of subsection (e)) shall not apply—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>