<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1831r"><akn:num>1831r</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments on foreign deposits prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1831r. Payments on foreign deposits prohibited(a) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Corporation, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Resolution Trust Corporation, any other agency, department, and instrumentality of the United States, and any corporation owned or controlled by the United States may not, directly or indirectly, make any payment or provide any assistance, guarantee, or transfer under this chapter or any other provision of law in connection with any insured depository institution which would have the direct or indirect effect of satisfying, in whole or in part, any claim against the institution for obligations of the institution which would constitute deposits as defined in section 1813(l) of this title but for subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 1813(l)(5) of this title.


(b) ExceptionSubsection (a) shall not apply to any payment, assistance, guarantee, or transfer made or provided by the Corporation if the Board of Directors determines in writing that such action is not inconsistent with any requirement of section 1823(c) of this title.


(c) Discount window lendingNo provision of this section shall be construed as prohibiting any Federal Reserve bank from making advances or otherwise extending credit pursuant to the Federal Reserve Act [12 U.S.C. 221 et seq.] to any insured depository institution to the extent that such advance or extension of credit is consistent with the conditions and limitations imposed under section 10B of such Act [12 U.S.C. 347b].


(Sept. 21, 1950, ch. 967, § 2[41], as added Pub. L. 102–242, title III, § 312, Dec. 19, 1991, 105 Stat. 2367.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Reserve Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is act Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, 38 Stat. 251, which is classified principally to chapter 3 (§ 221 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see References in Text note set out under section 226 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Corporation, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Resolution Trust Corporation, any other agency, department, and instrumentality of the United States, and any corporation owned or controlled by the United States may not, directly or indirectly, make any payment or provide any assistance, guarantee, or transfer under this chapter or any other provision of law in connection with any insured depository institution which would have the direct or indirect effect of satisfying, in whole or in part, any claim against the institution for obligations of the institution which would constitute deposits as defined in section 1813(l) of this title but for subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 1813(l)(5) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception Subsection (a) shall not apply to any payment, assistance, guarantee, or transfer made or provided by the Corporation if the Board of Directors determines in writing that such action is not inconsistent with any requirement of section 1823(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discount window lending</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Discount window lending No provision of this section shall be construed as prohibiting any Federal Reserve bank from making advances or otherwise extending credit pursuant to the Federal Reserve Act [12 U.S.C. 221 et seq.] to any insured depository institution to the extent that such advance or extension of credit is consistent with the conditions and limitations imposed under section 10B of such Act [12 U.S.C. 347b].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>