<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831bb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831bb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831bb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1831bb"><akn:num>1831bb</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital requirements for certain acquisition, development, or construction loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1831bb. Capital requirements for certain acquisition, development, or construction loans(a) In generalThe appropriate Federal banking agencies may only require a depository institution to assign a heightened risk weight to a high volatility commercial real estate (HVCRE) exposure (as such term is defined under section 324.2 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, as of October 11, 2017, or if a successor regulation is in effect as of May 24, 2018, such term or any successor term contained in such successor regulation) under any risk-based capital requirement if such exposure is an HVCRE ADC loan.


(b) HVCRE ADC loan definedFor purposes of this section and with respect to a depository institution, the term “HVCRE ADC loan”—(1) means a credit facility secured by land or improved real property that, prior to being reclassified by the depository institution as a non-HVCRE ADC loan pursuant to subsection (d)—(A) primarily finances, has financed, or refinances the acquisition, development, or construction of real property;

(B) has the purpose of providing financing to acquire, develop, or improve such real property into income-producing real property; and

(C) is dependent upon future income or sales proceeds from, or refinancing of, such real property for the repayment of such credit facility;


(2) does not include a credit facility financing—(A) the acquisition, development, or construction of properties that are—(i) one- to four-family residential properties;

(ii) real property that would qualify as an investment in community development; or

(iii) agricultural land;


(B) the acquisition or refinance of existing income-producing real property secured by a mortgage on such property, if the cash flow being generated by the real property is sufficient to support the debt service and expenses of the real property, in accordance with the institution’s applicable loan underwriting criteria for permanent financings;

(C) improvements to existing income-producing impr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831bb_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The appropriate Federal banking agencies may only require a depository institution to assign a heightened risk weight to a high volatility commercial real estate (HVCRE) exposure (as such term is defined under section 324.2 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, as of October 11, 2017, or if a successor regulation is in effect as of May 24, 2018, such term or any successor term contained in such successor regulation) under any risk-based capital requirement if such exposure is an HVCRE ADC loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831bb_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>HVCRE ADC loan defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) HVCRE ADC loan defined For purposes of this section and with respect to a depository institution, the term “HVCRE ADC loan”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831bb_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value of contributed real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Value of contributed real property For purposes of this section, the value of any real property contributed by a borrower as a capital contribution shall be the appraised value of the property as determined under standards prescribed pursuant to section 3339 of this title, in connection with the extension of the credit facility or loan to such borrower.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831bb_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reclassification as a Non-HVRCE ADC loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reclassification as a Non-HVRCE ADC loan For purposes of this section and with respect to a credit facility and a depository institution, upon— in accordance with the institution’s applicable loan underwriting criteria for permanent financings, the credit facility may be reclassified by the depository institution as a Non-HVCRE ADC loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831bb_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Existing authorities Nothing in this section shall limit the supervisory, regulatory, or enforcement authority of an appropriate Federal banking agency to further the safe and sound operation of an institution under the supervision of the appropriate Federal banking agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>