<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1831q"><akn:num>1831q</akn:num><akn:heading>FDIC affordable housing program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1831q. FDIC affordable housing program(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to provide homeownership and rental housing opportunities for very low-income, low-income, and moderate-income families.


(b) Funding and limitations of program(1) Duration of programThe provisions of this section shall be effective, subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), only during the 3-year period beginning upon the commencement of the first fiscal year for which amounts are provided pursuant to paragraph (2)(A).


(2) Annual fiscal limitations(A) In generalIn each fiscal year during the 3-year period referred to in paragraph (1), the provisions of this section shall apply only—(i) to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in appropriations Acts for any losses resulting during the fiscal year from the sale of properties under this section, except that such amounts for losses may not exceed $30,000,000 in any fiscal year; and

(ii) to the extent that amounts are provided in appropriations Acts pursuant to subparagraph (C) for any other costs relating to the program under this section.


(B) Definition of lossesFor purposes of this paragraph, the amount of losses resulting from the sale of properties under this section during any fiscal year shall be the amount equal to the sum of any affordable housing discounts reasonably anticipated to accrue during the fiscal year.


(C) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated, for each fiscal year during the 3-year period referred to in paragraph (1), such sums as may be necessary for any costs of the program under this section other than losses resulting from the sale of properties under this section.


(D) Other definitionsFor purposes of this paragraph:(i) Affordable housing discountThe term “affordable housing discount” means, with respect to any eligible residential or eligible condominium property transferred under this section by the Corporation, the difference (if any) between the realizable d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to provide homeownership and rental housing opportunities for very low-income, low-income, and moderate-income families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding and limitations of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding and limitations of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules governing disposition of eligible single family properties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rules governing disposition of eligible single family properties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules governing disposition of eligible multifamily housing properties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rules governing disposition of eligible multifamily housing properties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rent limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rent limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferences for sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preferences for sales</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financing sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Financing sales</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Coordination with other programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for certain transactions with insured depository institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Exemption for certain transactions with insured depository institutions The provisions of this section shall not apply with respect to any eligible residential property after the date the Corporation enters into a contract to sell such property to an insured depository institution (as defined in section 1813 of this title), including any sale in connection with a transfer of all or substantially all of the assets of a closed insured depository institution (including such property) to another insured depository institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831q_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain eligible residential properties to State housing agencies for disposition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Transfer of certain eligible residential properties to State housing agencies for disposition Notwithstanding subsections (c), (d), (f), and (g), the Corporation may transfer eligible residential properties to the State housing finance agency or any other State housing agency for the State in which the property is located, or to any local housing agency in whose jurisdiction the property is located. Transfers of eligible residential properties under this subsection may be conducted by direct sale, consignment sale, or any other method the Corporation considers appropriate and shall be subject to the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>