<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1831m"><akn:num>1831m</akn:num><akn:heading>Early identification of needed improvements in financial management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1831m. Early identification of needed improvements in financial management(a) Annual report on financial condition and management(1) Report requiredEach insured depository institution shall submit an annual report to the Corporation, the appropriate Federal banking agency, and any appropriate State bank supervisor (including any State bank supervisor of a host State).


(2) Contents of reportAny annual report required under paragraph (1) shall contain—(A) the information required to be provided by—(i) the institution’s management under subsection (b); and

(ii) an independent public accountant under subsections (c) and (d); and


(B) such other information as the Corporation and the appropriate Federal banking agency may determine to be necessary to assess the financial condition and management of the institution.


(3) Public availabilityAny annual report required under paragraph (1) shall be available for public inspection. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, the Corporation and the appropriate Federal banking agencies may designate certain information as privileged and confidential and not available to the public.



(b) Management responsibility for financial statements and internal controlsEach insured depository institution shall prepare—(1) annual financial statements in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and such other disclosure requirements as the Corporation and the appropriate Federal banking agency may prescribe; and

(2) a report signed by the chief executive officer and the chief accounting or financial officer of the institution which contains—(A) a statement of the management’s responsibilities for—(i) preparing financial statements;

(ii) establishing and maintaining an adequate internal control structure and procedures for financial reporting; and

(iii) complying with the laws and regulations relating to safety and soundness which are designated by the Corporation and the appropriate Federal banking agency; and


(B) a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report on financial condition and management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report on financial condition and management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management responsibility for financial statements and internal controls</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management responsibility for financial statements and internal controls Each insured depository institution shall prepare—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Internal control evaluation and reporting requirements for independent public accountants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Internal control evaluation and reporting requirements for independent public accountants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual independent audits of financial statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual independent audits of financial statements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II, § 2301(a), Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–419</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and content of reports and auditing standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Form and content of reports and auditing standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Improved accountability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange of reports and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exchange of reports and information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for insured subsidiaries of holding companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Requirements for insured subsidiaries of holding companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831m_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for small depository institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exemption for small depository institutions This section shall not apply with respect to any fiscal year of any insured depository institution the total assets of which, as of the beginning of such fiscal year, are less than the greater of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>