<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831u" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831u/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831u/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1831u"><akn:num>1831u</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate bank mergers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1831u. Interstate bank mergers(a) Approval of interstate merger transactions authorized(1) In generalBeginning on June 1, 1997, the responsible agency may approve a merger transaction under section 1828(c) of this title between insured banks with different home States, without regard to whether such transaction is prohibited under the law of any State.


(2) State election to prohibit interstate merger transactions(A) In generalNotwithstanding paragraph (1), a merger transaction may not be approved pursuant to paragraph (1) if the transaction involves a bank the home State of which has enacted a law after September 29, 1994, and before June 1, 1997, that—(i) applies equally to all out-of-State banks; and

(ii) expressly prohibits merger transactions involving out-of-State banks.


(B) No effect on prior approvals of merger transactionsA law enacted by a State pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall have no effect on merger transactions that were approved before the effective date of such law.



(3) State election to permit early interstate merger transactions(A) In generalA merger transaction may be approved pursuant to paragraph (1) before June 1, 1997, if the home State of each bank involved in the transaction has in effect, as of the date of the approval of such transaction, a law that—(i) applies equally to all out-of-State banks; and

(ii) expressly permits interstate merger transactions with all out-of-State banks.


(B) Certain conditions allowedA host State may impose conditions on a branch within such State of a bank resulting from an interstate merger transaction if—(i) the conditions do not have the effect of discriminating against out-of-State banks, out-of-State bank holding companies, or any subsidiary of such bank or company (other than on the basis of a nationwide reciprocal treatment requirement);

(ii) the imposition of the conditions is not preempted by Federal law; and

(iii) the conditions do not apply or require performance after May 31, 1997.


</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831u_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of interstate merger transactions authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Approval of interstate merger transactions authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831u_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to application and approval process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Provisions relating to application and approval process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831u_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of certain laws to interstate banking operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicability of certain laws to interstate banking operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831u_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operations of the resulting bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Operations of the resulting bank</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831u_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for banks in default or in danger of default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exception for banks in default or in danger of default If an application under subsection (a)(1) for approval of a merger transaction which involves 1 or more banks in default or in danger of default or with respect to which the Corporation provides assistance under section 1823(c) of this title, the responsible agency may approve such application without regard to subsection (b), or paragraph (2), (4), or (5) of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831u_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable rate and other charge limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicable rate and other charge limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831u_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>