<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831y" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831y/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831y/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1831y"><akn:num>1831y</akn:num><akn:heading>CRA sunshine requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1831y. CRA sunshine requirements(a) Public disclosure of agreementsAny agreement (as defined in subsection (e)) entered into after November 12, 1999, by an insured depository institution or affiliate with a nongovernmental entity or person made pursuant to or in connection with the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 [12 U.S.C. 2901 et seq.] involving funds or other resources of such insured depository institution or affiliate—(1) shall be in its entirety fully disclosed, and the full text thereof made available to the appropriate Federal banking agency with supervisory responsibility over the insured depository institution and to the public by each party to the agreement; and

(2) shall obligate each party to comply with this section.


(b) Annual report of activity by insured depository institutionEach insured depository institution or affiliate that is a party to an agreement described in subsection (a) shall report to the appropriate Federal banking agency with supervisory responsibility over the insured depository institution, not less frequently than once each year, such information as the Federal banking agency may by rule require relating to the following actions taken by the party pursuant to the agreement during the preceding 12-month period:(1) Payments, fees, or loans made to any party to the agreement or received from any party to the agreement and the terms and conditions of the same.

(2) Aggregate data on loans, investments, and services provided by each party in its community or communities pursuant to the agreement.

(3) Such other pertinent matters as determined by regulation by the appropriate Federal banking agency with supervisory responsibility over the insured depository institution.


(c) Annual report of activity by nongovernmental entities(1) In generalEach nongovernmental entity or person that is not an affiliate of an insured depository institution and that is a party to an agreement described in subsection (a) shall report to the appro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831y_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public disclosure of agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Public disclosure of agreements Any agreement (as defined in subsection (e)) entered into after November 12, 1999, by an insured depository institution or affiliate with a nongovernmental entity or person made pursuant to or in connection with the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 [12 U.S.C. 2901 et seq.] involving funds or other resources of such insured depository institution or affiliate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831y_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report of activity by insured depository institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual report of activity by insured depository institution Each insured depository institution or affiliate that is a party to an agreement described in subsection (a) shall report to the appropriate Federal banking agency with supervisory responsibility over the insured depository institution, not less frequently than once each year, such information as the Federal banking agency may by rule require relating to the following actions taken by the party pursuant to the agreement during the preceding 12-month period:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831y_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report of activity by nongovernmental entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual report of activity by nongovernmental entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831y_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability Subsections (b) and (c) shall not apply with respect to any agreement entered into before the end of the 6-month period beginning on November 12, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831y_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831y_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831y_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rule of construction No provision of this section shall be construed as authorizing any appropriate Federal banking agency to enforce the provisions of any agreement described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831y_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>