<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1831n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1831n"><akn:num>1831n</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounting objectives, standards, and requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1831n. Accounting objectives, standards, and requirements(a) In general(1) ObjectivesAccounting principles applicable to reports or statements required to be filed with Federal banking agencies by insured depository institutions should—(A) result in financial statements and reports of condition that accurately reflect the capital of such institutions;

(B) facilitate effective supervision of the institutions; and

(C) facilitate prompt corrective action to resolve the institutions at the least cost to the Deposit Insurance Fund.


(2) Standards(A) Uniform accounting principles consistent with GAAPSubject to the requirements of this chapter and any other provision of Federal law, the accounting principles applicable to reports or statements required to be filed with Federal banking agencies by all insured depository institutions shall be uniform and consistent with generally accepted accounting principles.


(B) StringencyIf the appropriate Federal banking agency or the Corporation determines that the application of any generally accepted accounting principle to any insured depository institution is inconsistent with the objectives described in paragraph (1), the agency or the Corporation may, with respect to reports or statements required to be filed with such agency or Corporation, prescribe an accounting principle which is applicable to such institutions which is no less stringent than generally accepted accounting principles.



(3) Review and implementation of accounting principles requiredBefore the end of the 1-year period beginning on December 19, 1991, each appropriate Federal banking agency shall take the following actions:(A) Review of accounting principlesReview—(i) all accounting principles used by depository institutions with respect to reports or statements required to be filed with a Federal banking agency;

(ii) all requirements established by the agency with respect to such accounting procedures; and

(iii) the procedures and format for reports to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniform accounting of capital standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uniform accounting of capital standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1831n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to banking committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports to banking committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>