<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1833b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1833b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1833b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1833b"><akn:num>1833b</akn:num><akn:heading>Comparability in compensation schedules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1833b. Comparability in compensation schedules(a) In generalThe Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Comptroller of the Currency, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Office of Financial Research, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the 11 So in original. Probably should be “Research, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and the”. Farm Credit Administration, in establishing and adjusting schedules of compensation and benefits which are to be determined solely by each agency under applicable provisions of law, shall inform the heads of the other agencies and the Congress of such compensation and benefits and shall seek to maintain comparability regarding compensation and benefits.


(b) Commodity Futures Trading CommissionIn establishing and adjusting schedules of compensation and benefits for employees of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission under applicable provisions of law, the Commission shall—(1) inform the heads of the agencies referred to in subsection (a) and Congress of such compensation and benefits; and

(2) seek to maintain comparability with those agencies regarding compensation and benefits.


(Pub. L. 101–73, title XII, § 1206, Aug. 9, 1989, 103 Stat. 523; Pub. L. 102–233, title III, § 302(a), Dec. 12, 1991, 105 Stat. 1767; Pub. L. 107–123, § 8(d)(3), Jan. 16, 2002, 115 Stat. 2400; Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10702(b), May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 516; Pub. L. 111–203, title I, § 152(d)(3), title III, § 367(8), July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 1414, 1557.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989, and not as part of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act which comprises this chapter.

Amendments2010—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 111–203, § 367(8)(B), which directed striking out “, and the Office of Thrift Supervision” could not be executed because those words did not appear subsequent to amendment by Pub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1833b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Comptroller of the Currency, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Office of Financial Research, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the 11 So in original. Probably should be “Research, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, and the”. Farm Credit Administration, in establishing and adjusting schedules of compensation and benefits which are to be determined solely by each agency under applicable provisions of law, shall inform the heads of the other agencies and the Congress of such compensation and benefits and shall seek to maintain comparability regarding compensation and benefits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1833b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodity Futures Trading Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commodity Futures Trading Commission In establishing and adjusting schedules of compensation and benefits for employees of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission under applicable provisions of law, the Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>