<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1834" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1834/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1834/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1834"><akn:num>1834</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduced assessment rate for deposits attributable to lifeline accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1834. Reduced assessment rate for deposits attributable to lifeline accounts(a) Qualification of lifeline accounts(1) In generalThe Comptroller of the Currency and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall establish minimum requirements for accounts providing basic transaction services for consumers at insured depository institutions in order for such accounts to qualify as lifeline accounts for purposes of this section and section 1817(b)(2)(E) of this title.


(2) Factors to be consideredIn determining the minimum requirements under paragraph (1) for lifeline accounts at insured depository institutions, the Corporation shall consider the following factors:(A) Whether the account is available to provide basic transaction services for individuals who maintain a balance of less than $1,000 or such other amount which the Comptroller may determine to be appropriate.

(B) Whether any service charges or fees to which the account is subject, if any, for routine transactions do not exceed a minimal amount.

(C) Whether any minimum balance or minimum opening requirement to which the account is subject, if any, is not more than a minimal amount.

(D) Whether checks, negotiable orders of withdrawal, or similar instruments for making payments or other transfers to third parties may be drawn on the account.

(E) Whether the depositor is permitted to make more than a minimal number of withdrawals from the account each month by any means described in subparagraph (D) or any other means.

(F) Whether a monthly statement itemizing all transactions for the monthly reporting period is made available to the depositor with respect to such account or a passbook is provided in which all transactions with respect to such account are recorded.

(G) Whether depositors are permitted access to tellers at the institution for conducting transactions with respect to such account.

(H) Whether other account relationships with the institution are required in order to open any such account.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualification of lifeline accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Qualification of lifeline accounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of funds The provisions of this section shall not take effect until appropriations are specifically provided in advance. There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>