<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1834a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1834a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1834a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1834a"><akn:num>1834a</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment credits for qualifying activities relating to distressed communities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1834a. Assessment credits for qualifying activities relating to distressed communities(a) Determination of credits for increases in community enterprise activities(1) In generalThe Community Enterprise Assessment Credit Board established under subsection (d) shall issue guidelines for insured depository institutions eligible under this subsection for any community enterprise assessment credit with respect to any semiannual period. Such guidelines shall—(A) designate the eligibility requirements for any institution meeting applicable capital standards to receive an assessment credit under section 1817(b)(7) of this title; and

(B) determine the community enterprise assessment credit available to any eligible institution under paragraph (3).


(2) Qualifying activitiesAn insured depository institution may apply for for 11 So in original. any community enterprise assessment credit for any semiannual period for—(A) the amount, during such period, of new originations of qualified loans and other assistance provided for low- and moderate-income persons in distressed communities, or enterprises integrally involved with such neighborhoods, which the Board determines are qualified to be taken into account for purposes of this subsection;

(B) the amount, during such period, of deposits accepted from persons domiciled in the distressed community, at any office of the institution (including any branch) located in any qualified distressed community, and new originations of any loans and other financial assistance made within that community, except that in no case shall the credit for deposits at any institution or branch exceed the credit for loans and other financial assistance by the bank or branch in the distressed community; and

(C) any increase during the period in the amount of new equity investments in community development financial institutions.


(3) Amount of assessment creditThe amount of any community enterprise assessment credit available under section 1817(b)(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of credits for increases in community enterprise activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination of credits for increases in community enterprise activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Qualified distressed community” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Qualified distressed community” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community Enterprise Assessment Credit Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Community Enterprise Assessment Credit Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duties of Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Availability of funds The provisions of this section shall not take effect until appropriations are specifically provided in advance. There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on double funding for same activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prohibition on double funding for same activities No community development financial institution may receive a community enterprise assessment credit if such institution, either directly or through a community partnership—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority of awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Priority of awards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of amount of assessment credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Determination of amount of assessment credit Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the determination of the amount of any community enterprise assessment credit under subsection (a)(3) for any insured depository institution for any semiannual period shall be made solely at the discretion of the Board. No insured depository institution shall be awarded community enterprise assessment credits for any semiannual period in excess of an amount determined by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>