<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1867" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1867/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/1867/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1867"><akn:num>1867</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation and examination of bank service companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1867. Regulation and examination of bank service companies(a) Principal investorA bank service company shall be subject to examination and regulation by the appropriate Federal banking agency of its principal investor to the same extent as its principal investor. The appropriate Federal banking agency of the principal shareholder or principal member of such a bank service company may authorize any other Federal banking agency that supervises any other shareholder or member of the bank service company to make such an examination.


(b) Applicability of section 1818 of this titleA bank service company shall be subject to the provisions of section 1818 of this title as if the bank service company were an insured depository institution. For this purpose, the appropriate Federal banking agency shall be the appropriate Federal banking agency of the principal investor of the bank service company.


(c) Services performed by contract or otherwiseNotwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, whenever a depository institution that is regularly examined by an appropriate Federal banking agency, or any subsidiary or affiliate of such a depository institution that is subject to examination by that agency, causes to be performed for itself, by contract or otherwise, any services authorized under this chapter, whether on or off its premises—(1) such performance shall be subject to regulation and examination by such agency to the same extent as if such services were being performed by the depository institution itself on its own premises, and

(2) the depository institution shall notify each such agency of the existence of the service relationship within thirty days after the making of such service contract or the performance of the service, whichever occurs first.


(d) Issuance of regulations and ordersThe Board and the appropriate Federal banking agencies are authorized to issue such regulations and orders as may be necessary to enable them to administer and to carry out the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1867_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal investor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Principal investor A bank service company shall be subject to examination and regulation by the appropriate Federal banking agency of its principal investor to the same extent as its principal investor. The appropriate Federal banking agency of the principal shareholder or principal member of such a bank service company may authorize any other Federal banking agency that supervises any other shareholder or member of the bank service company to make such an examination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1867_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of section 1818 of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicability of A bank service company shall be subject to the provisions of section 1818 of this title as if the bank service company were an insured depository institution. For this purpose, the appropriate Federal banking agency shall be the appropriate Federal banking agency of the principal investor of the bank service company.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1867_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services performed by contract or otherwise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Services performed by contract or otherwise Notwithstanding subsection (a) of this section, whenever a depository institution that is regularly examined by an appropriate Federal banking agency, or any subsidiary or affiliate of such a depository institution that is subject to examination by that agency, causes to be performed for itself, by contract or otherwise, any services authorized under this chapter, whether on or off its premises—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1867_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of regulations and orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Issuance of regulations and orders The Board and the appropriate Federal banking agencies are authorized to issue such regulations and orders as may be necessary to enable them to administer and to carry out the purposes of this chapter and to prevent evasions thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>