<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/202" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/202/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/202/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_202"><akn:num>202</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 202. Definitions
As used in this subchapter, the term “bank” means any national banking association or any other financial institution chartered or licensed under Federal law and subject to the supervision of the Comptroller of the Currency; the term “voluntary dissolution and liquidation” means a transaction pursuant to section 181 of this title that involves the assumption of the bank’s insured deposit liabilities and the sale of the bank, or of control of the bank, as a going concern; and the term “State” means any State, Territory, or possession of the United States, and the Canal Zone.
(Mar. 9, 1933, ch. 1, title II, § 202, 48 Stat. 2; Pub. L. 101–73, title VIII, § 801, Aug. 9, 1989, 103 Stat. 441; Pub. L. 109–351, title VII, § 725(b), Oct. 13, 2006, 120 Stat. 2001; Pub. L. 109–356, title I, § 123(b), Oct. 16, 2006, 120 Stat. 2028.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextFor definition of Canal Zone, referred to in text, see section 3602(b) of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.

Amendments2006—Pub. L. 109–351 and 109–356 amended section identically, substituting “means any national” for “means (1) any national” and striking out “, and (2) any bank or trust company located in the District of Columbia and operating under the supervision of the Comptroller of the Currency” before first semicolon.
1989—Pub. L. 101–73, § 801(1), in cl. (1), extended term “bank” to include any financial institution chartered or licensed under Federal law and subject to supervision of Comptroller of the Currency.
Pub. L. 101–73, § 801(2), in cl. (2), inserted definition of term “voluntary dissolution and liquidation”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>