<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2021"><akn:num>2021</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans through associations or agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2021. Loans through associations or agents(a) In generalThe Farm Credit Banks shall, except as otherwise herein provided, make loans of the type authorized under section 2015(a) of this title through a Federal land bank association chartered to serve the territory in which the real estate of the borrower is located.


(b) No active associationIf there is no active association chartered to serve territory where the real estate is located, the bank may make the loan directly or through such bank or trust company or savings or other financial institution as such bank may designate.


(c) Purchase of stock requiredWhen the loan is not made through a Federal land bank association, the applicant shall purchase stock in the bank in accordance with the capitalization requirements provided for in the bylaws of the bank.


(Pub. L. 92–181, title I, § 1.13, as added Pub. L. 100–233, title IV, § 401, Jan. 6, 1988, 101 Stat. 1628.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1.13 of Pub. L. 92–181 was classified to section 2031 of this title prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by Pub. L. 100–233, § 401.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 100–233, title IV, § 401, Jan. 6, 1988, 101 Stat. 1622, provided that this section is effective 6 months after Jan. 6, 1988.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Farm Credit Banks shall, except as otherwise herein provided, make loans of the type authorized under section 2015(a) of this title through a Federal land bank association chartered to serve the territory in which the real estate of the borrower is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>No active association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No active association If there is no active association chartered to serve territory where the real estate is located, the bank may make the loan directly or through such bank or trust company or savings or other financial institution as such bank may designate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of stock required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purchase of stock required When the loan is not made through a Federal land bank association, the applicant shall purchase stock in the bank in accordance with the capitalization requirements provided for in the bylaws of the bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>