<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/206" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/206/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/206/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_206"><akn:num>206</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservator; powers and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 206. Conservator; powers and duties(a) General powersA conservator shall have all the powers of the shareholders, directors, and officers of the bank and may operate the bank in its own name unless the Comptroller 11 So in original. Probably should be “Comptroller of the Currency”. in the order of appointment limits the conservator’s authority.


(b) Subject to rules of ComptrollerThe conservator shall be subject to such rules, regulations, and orders as the Comptroller from time to time deems appropriate; and, except as otherwise specifically provided in such rules, regulations, or orders or in section 209 of this title, shall have the same rights and privileges and be subject to the same duties, restrictions, penalties, conditions, and limitations as apply to directors, officers, or employees of a national bank.


(c) Payment of depositors and creditorsThe Comptroller may require the conservator to set aside and make available for withdrawal by depositors and payment to other creditors such amounts as in the opinion of the Comptroller may safely be used for that purpose. All depositors and creditors who are similarly situated shall be treated in the same manner.


(d) Compensation of conservator and employeesThe conservator and professional employees appointed to represent or assist the conservator shall not be paid amounts greater than are payable to employees of the Federal Government for similar services, except that the Comptroller of the Currency may authorize payment at higher rates (but not in excess of rates prevailing in the private sector), if the Comptroller determines that paying such higher rates is necessary in order to recruit and retain competent personnel.


(e) ExpensesAll expenses of any such conservatorship shall be paid by the bank and shall be a lien upon the bank which shall be prior to any other lien.


(Mar. 9, 1933, ch. 1, title II, § 206, 48 Stat. 3; Pub. L. 101–73, title VIII, § 805, Aug. 9, 1989, 103 Stat. 445.)

Editorial Notes
Amen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General powers A conservator shall have all the powers of the shareholders, directors, and officers of the bank and may operate the bank in its own name unless the Comptroller 11 So in original. Probably should be “Comptroller of the Currency”. in the order of appointment limits the conservator’s authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subject to rules of Comptroller</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to rules of Comptroller The conservator shall be subject to such rules, regulations, and orders as the Comptroller from time to time deems appropriate; and, except as otherwise specifically provided in such rules, regulations, or orders or in section 209 of this title, shall have the same rights and privileges and be subject to the same duties, restrictions, penalties, conditions, and limitations as apply to directors, officers, or employees of a national bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of depositors and creditors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of depositors and creditors The Comptroller may require the conservator to set aside and make available for withdrawal by depositors and payment to other creditors such amounts as in the opinion of the Comptroller may safely be used for that purpose. All depositors and creditors who are similarly situated shall be treated in the same manner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of conservator and employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation of conservator and employees The conservator and professional employees appointed to represent or assist the conservator shall not be paid amounts greater than are payable to employees of the Federal Government for similar services, except that the Comptroller of the Currency may authorize payment at higher rates (but not in excess of rates prevailing in the private sector), if the Comptroller determines that paying such higher rates is necessary in order to recruit and retain competent personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Expenses All expenses of any such conservatorship shall be paid by the bank and shall be a lien upon the bank which shall be prior to any other lien.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>