<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2071" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2071/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2071/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2071"><akn:num>2071</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization and charters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2071. Organization and charters(a) CharterEach production credit association shall continue as a Federally chartered instrumentality of the United States.


(b) Organization(1) In generalProduction credit associations may be organized by 10 or more farmers or ranchers or producers or harvesters of aquatic products desiring to borrow money under the provisions of this part.


(2) Articles of associationThe proposed articles of association shall be forwarded to the Farm Credit Bank for the district accompanied by an agreement to subscribe on behalf of the association for stock in the bank in such amounts as may be required by the bank.


(3) Contents of articlesThe articles shall specify in general terms the—(A) objects for which the association is formed;

(B) powers to be exercised by the association in carrying out the functions authorized by this part; and

(C) territory the association proposes to serve.


(4) SignaturesThe articles shall be signed by persons desiring to form such an association and shall be accompanied by a statement signed by each such person establishing eligibility to borrow from the association in which such person will become a stockholder.


(5) Copy to FCAA copy of the articles of association shall be forwarded to the Farm Credit Administration with the recommendations of the bank concerning the need for such an association in order to adequately serve the credit needs of eligible persons in the proposed territory and whether that territory includes any area described in the charter of another production credit association.


(6) Denial of charterThe Farm Credit Administration for good cause shown may deny the charter.


(7) Approval of articlesOn approval of the proposed articles by the Farm Credit Administration, and on the issuance of a charter, the association shall become as of such date a federally chartered body corporate and an instrumentality of the United States.


(8) Powers of FCAThe Farm Credit Administration shall have the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2071_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Charter Each production credit association shall continue as a Federally chartered instrumentality of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2071_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>