<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2154a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2154a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2154a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2154a"><akn:num>2154a</akn:num><akn:heading>Capitalization of System institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2154a. Capitalization of System institutions(a) DefinitionsAs used in this section:(1) Permanent capitalThe term “permanent capital” means—(A) current year retained earnings;

(B) allocated and unallocated earnings (which, in the case of earnings allocated in any form by a System bank to any association or other recipient and retained by the bank, shall be considered, in whole or in part, permanent capital of the bank or of any such association or other recipient as provided under an agreement between the bank and each such association or other recipient);

(C) all surplus (less allowances for losses);

(D) stock issued by a System institution, except—(i) stock that may be retired by the holder of the stock on repayment of the holder’s loan, or otherwise at the option or request of the holder; or

(ii) stock that is protected under section 2162 of this title or is otherwise not at risk; and


(E) any other debt or equity instruments or other accounts that the Farm Credit Administration determines appropriate to be considered permanent capital.


(2) StockThe term “stock” means voting and nonvoting stock (including preferred stock), equivalent contributions to a guaranty fund, participation certificates, allocated equities, and other forms and types of equities.



(b) Adoption of bylawsSubject to approval by shareholders under subsection (c)(2), each bank and association shall adopt bylaws, developed by its board of directors, that provide for the capitalization of the institution in accordance with subsection (c)(1).


(c) Requirements of bylaws(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the bylaws adopted under subsection (b)—(A) shall provide for such classes, par value, and amounts of the stock of the institution, the manner in which such stock shall be issued, transferred, and retired, and the payment of dividends and patronage refunds, as determined appropriate by the Board of Directors, subject to this section;

(B) may provide for th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of bylaws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adoption of bylaws Subject to approval by shareholders under subsection (c)(2), each bank and association shall adopt bylaws, developed by its board of directors, that provide for the capitalization of the institution in accordance with subsection (c)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements of bylaws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements of bylaws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of capital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reduction of capital</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Compliance The Farm Credit Administration may issue a directive that requires compliance with subsection (d), to the board of directors of any System institution that fails to comply therewith.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans designated for sale or sold into secondary market</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Loans designated for sale or sold into secondary market</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Construction This section shall not be construed to affect the provisions of this chapter that confer on System institutions a lien on borrower stock or other equities and the privilege to retire or cancel such stock or other equities for application against the indebtedness on a defaulted or restructured loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2154a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Controlling authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Controlling authority To the extent that any provision of this section is inconsistent with any other provision of this chapter (other than section 2162 of this title), the provision of this section shall control.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>