<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/216b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/216b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/216b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_216b"><akn:num>216b</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of unclaimed property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 216b. Disposition of unclaimed property(a) Limitations for filing claims; publication of notice in Federal Register; contents of notice; disclosure of descriptive information; inspection of specific property(1) Within twelve months following October 15, 1982, the Comptroller shall publish formal notice in the Federal Register that all claims to rights of any claimant to obtain title to, or custody or possession of, any unclaimed property in the possession, custody, or control of the Comptroller must be filed within twelve months following the last date of publication of such formal notice in the Federal Register or shall thereafter be barred.

(2) Such notice shall contain the names of last known owners, if any, names and locations of affected closed banks, and a general description of the types of unclaimed property held by the Comptroller. The Comptroller may provide additional notice in local communities as it deems appropriate.

(3)(A) The Comptroller shall not disclose, by publication, inspection or otherwise, information relating to the ownership or description of any specific unclaimed property prior to publication of formal notice under this section.

(B) Thereafter, the Comptroller shall disclose descriptive information of specific unclaimed property only to a claimant thereof. The Comptroller may recoup expenses associated with any publication or other provision of notice from any sale of property authorized by this subchapter. Reasonable opportunity for inspection of specific property by a claimant thereof shall be provided in Washington, District of Columbia.



(b) Delivery of property to claimant upon proof of entitlement; determination of validity of claims; recoupment of expenses; liability for losses; insurance requirements(1) The Comptroller shall deliver such property to any claimant or his or her legally authorized representative upon receiving proof deemed adequate by the Comptroller that such claimant is entitled to the property, but only if </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_216b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations for filing claims; publication of notice in Federal Register; contents of notice; disclosure of descriptive information; inspection of specific property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitations for filing claims; publication of notice in Federal Register; contents of notice; disclosure of descriptive information; inspection of specific property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_216b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of property to claimant upon proof of entitlement; determination of validity of claims; recoupment of expenses; liability for losses; insurance requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Delivery of property to claimant upon proof of entitlement; determination of validity of claims; recoupment of expenses; liability for losses; insurance requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_216b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vesting of rights, title and interest in unclaimed property in United States; sale, use, destruction or disposition of property; proceeds of sale as miscellaneous receipts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Vesting of rights, title and interest in unclaimed property in United States; sale, use, destruction or disposition of property; proceeds of sale as miscellaneous receipts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_216b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for determination of validity of claims; liability for delivery, sale, etc., of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Liability for determination of validity of claims; liability for delivery, sale, etc., of property The United States, the Comptroller, or any officer, employee, or agent thereof shall not be subject to personal or legal liability for any determination as to the validity of any claim or claims filed under this subchapter or for any delivery, sale, destruction, or other disposition of unclaimed property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_216b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court action for determination of ownership, etc., in State or Federal court of competent jurisdiction; de novo nature of action; parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Court action for determination of ownership, etc., in State or Federal court of competent jurisdiction; de novo nature of action; parties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_216b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of United States Court of Federal Claims of actions against United States, Comptroller, officer, etc.; scope of review of actions of Comptroller; limitations; claims against Comptroller, officer, etc., as claim against United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Jurisdiction of United States Court of Federal Claims of actions against United States, Comptroller, officer, etc.; scope of review of actions of Comptroller; limitations; claims against Comptroller, officer, etc., as claim against United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>