<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2202a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2202a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2202a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2202a"><akn:num>2202a</akn:num><akn:heading>Restructuring distressed loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2202a. Restructuring distressed loans(a) DefinitionsAs used in this part and section 2219a of this title:(1) Application for restructuringThe term “application for restructuring” means a written request—(A) from a borrower for the restructuring of a distressed loan in accordance with a preliminary restructuring plan proposed by the borrower as a part of the application;

(B) submitted on the appropriate forms prescribed by the qualified lender; and

(C) accompanied by sufficient financial information and repayment projections, where appropriate, as required by the qualified lender to support a sound credit decision.


(2) Cost of foreclosureThe term “cost of foreclosure” includes—(A) the difference between the outstanding balance due on a loan made by a qualified lender and the liquidation value of the loan, taking into consideration the borrower’s repayment capacity and the liquidation value of the collateral used to secure the loan;

(B) the estimated cost of maintaining a loan as a nonperforming asset;

(C) the estimated cost of administrative and legal actions necessary to foreclose a loan and dispose of property acquired as the result of the foreclosure, including attorneys’ fees and court costs;

(D) the estimated cost of changes in the value of collateral used to secure a loan during the period beginning on the date of the initiation of an action to foreclose or liquidate the loan and ending on the date of the disposition of the collateral; and

(E) all other costs incurred as the result of the foreclosure or liquidation of a loan.


(3) Distressed loanThe term “distressed loan” means a loan that the borrower does not have the financial capacity to pay according to its terms and that exhibits one or more of the following characteristics:(A) The borrower is demonstrating adverse financial and repayment trends.

(B) The loan is delinquent or past due under the terms of the loan contract.

(C) One or both of the factors listed in subparagraphs (A) and (B), tog</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this part and section 2219a of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Meetings On determination by a qualified lender that a loan made by the lender is or has become a distressed loan, the lender shall provide a reasonable opportunity for the borrower thereof to personally meet with a representative of the lender—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consideration of applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restructuring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restructuring</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Least cost alternative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Least cost alternative If two or more restructuring alternatives are available to a qualified lender under this section with respect to a distressed loan, the lender shall restructure the loan in conformity with the alternative that results in the least cost to the lender.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restructuring policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Restructuring policy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Compliance The Farm Credit Administration may issue a directive requiring compliance with any provision of this section to any qualified lender that fails to comply with such provision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permitted foreclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Permitted foreclosures This section shall not be construed to prevent any qualified lender from enforcing any contractual provision that allows the lender to foreclose a loan, or from taking such other lawful action as the lender deems appropriate, if the lender has reasonable grounds to believe that the loan collateral will be destroyed, dissipated, consumed, concealed, or permanently removed from the State in which the collateral is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2202a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Application of section The time limitation prescribed in subsection (b)(2), and the requirements of subsection (c), shall not apply to a loan that became a distressed loan before January 6, 1988, if the borrower and lender of the loan are in the process of negotiating loan restructuring with respect to the loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>