<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2251" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2251/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2251/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2251"><akn:num>2251</akn:num><akn:heading>Quarters and facilities for the Farm Credit Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2251. Quarters and facilities for the Farm Credit Administration(a) Location of principal officeThe Farm Credit Administration shall maintain its principal office within the Washington D.C.-Maryland-Virginia standard metropolitan statistical area, and such other offices within the United States as in its judgment are necessary.


(b) Alternate property authorizations for System banksAs an alternate to the rental of quarters under section 2249 of this title, and without regard to any other provision of law, the banks of the System, with the concurrence of two-thirds of the bank boards, are hereby authorized—(1) To lease or acquire real property in the District of Columbia or elsewhere for quarters of the Farm Credit Administration.

(2) To construct, develop, furnish, and equip such building thereon and such facilities appurtenant thereto as in their judgment may be appropriate to provide, to the extent the Board may deem advisable, suitable, and adequate quarters and facilities for the Farm Credit Administration.

(3) To enlarge, remodel, or reconstruct the same.

(4) To make or enter into contracts for any of the foregoing.

(5) To sell or otherwise dispose of any interest in property leased or acquired under the foregoing if authorized by the Board.


(c) Financing(1) In generalThe Board may require of the respective banks of the System, and they shall make to the Farm Credit Administration, such advances of funds for the purposes set out in this section as in the sole judgment of the Board may from time to time be advisable for the purposes of this section.


(2) AdvancesThe advances of funds described in paragraph (1) shall be in addition to and kept in a separate fund from the assessments authorized in section 2250 of this title and shall be apportioned by the Board among the banks in proportion to the total assets of the respective banks, and determined in such manner and at such times as the Board may prescribe.


(3) Powers of banksThe powers of the banks </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2251_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location of principal office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Location of principal office The Farm Credit Administration shall maintain its principal office within the Washington D.C.-Maryland-Virginia standard metropolitan statistical area, and such other offices within the United States as in its judgment are necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2251_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternate property authorizations for System banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Alternate property authorizations for System banks As an alternate to the rental of quarters under section 2249 of this title, and without regard to any other provision of law, the banks of the System, with the concurrence of two-thirds of the bank boards, are hereby authorized—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2251_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Financing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>