<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2265a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2265a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2265a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2265a"><akn:num>2265a</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal and prohibition authority; industry-wide prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2265a. Removal and prohibition authority; industry-wide prohibition(a) Definition of personIn this section, the term “person” means—(1) an individual; and

(2) in the case of a specific determination by the Farm Credit Administration, a legal entity.


(b) Industry-wide prohibitionExcept as provided in subsection (c), any person who, pursuant to an order issued under section 2264 or 2265 of this title, has been removed or suspended from office at a System institution or prohibited from participating in the conduct of the affairs of a System institution shall not, during the period of effectiveness of the order, continue or commence to hold any office in, or participate in any manner in the conduct of the affairs of—(1) any insured depository institution subject to section 1818(e)(7)(A)(i) of this title;

(2) any institution subject to section 1818(e)(7)(A)(ii) of this title;

(3) any insured credit union under the Federal Credit Union Act (12 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.);

(4) any Federal home loan bank;

(5) any institution chartered under this chapter;

(6) any appropriate Federal financial institutions regulatory agency (as defined in section 1818(e)(7)(D) of this title);

(7) the Federal Housing Finance Agency; or

(8) the Farm Credit Administration.


(c) Exception for institution-affiliated party that receives written consent(1) In general(A) Affiliated partiesIf, on or after the date on which an order described in subsection (b) is issued that removes or suspends an institution-affiliated party from office at a System institution or prohibits an institution-affiliated party from participating in the conduct of the affairs of a System institution, that party receives written consent described in subparagraph (B), subsection (b) shall not apply to that party—(i) to the extent provided in the written consent received; and

(ii) with respect to the institution described in each written consent.


(B) Written consent describedThe written consent referred to in subparagr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2265a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of person In this section, the term “person” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2265a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry-wide prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Industry-wide prohibition Except as provided in subsection (c), any person who, pursuant to an order issued under section 2264 or 2265 of this title, has been removed or suspended from office at a System institution or prohibited from participating in the conduct of the affairs of a System institution shall not, during the period of effectiveness of the order, continue or commence to hold any office in, or participate in any manner in the conduct of the affairs of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2265a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for institution-affiliated party that receives written consent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception for institution-affiliated party that receives written consent</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2265a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Violations A violation of subsection (b) by any person who is subject to an order described in that subsection shall be treated as violation 22 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “a”. of that order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>