<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2275a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2275a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2275a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2275a"><akn:num>2275a</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition rules relating to amendment of certain FCA approval authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2275a. Transition rules relating to amendment of certain FCA approval authorities(a) In generalAny approvals granted by the Farm Credit Administration before January 6, 1988, shall remain in effect on and after such date.


(b) Authority to issue regulations(1) In generalAny approval authority of the Farm Credit Administration that, under the amendments made by section 802 of the Agricultural Credit Act of 1987, became an authority to issue regulations may be exercised only until the earlier of the date the Farm Credit Administration issues final regulations under such authority, or 1 year after January 6, 1988.


(2) Enforcement actionsAt the close of the 1-year period referred to in paragraph (1), the Farm Credit Administration shall not take any enforcement action against any System institution with respect to any provision so amended, until the Farm Credit Administration issues final regulations under such provision.



(c) Effect of sectionThis section shall not affect the authority of the Farm Credit Administration to exercise any other approval authority either on a case-by-case basis or through regulation, as provided in section 2252(a)(5) of this title.


(Pub. L. 92–181, title V, § 5.45, as added Pub. L. 100–233, title VIII, § 802(w), Jan. 6, 1988, 101 Stat. 1713.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe amendments made by section 802 of the Agricultural Credit Act of 1987, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), are the amendments made by section 802 of Pub. L. 100–233, title VIII, Jan. 6, 1988, 101 Stat. 1710, which enacted section 2275a of this title and amended sections 2011 to 2013, 2017, 2031, 2051, 2052, 2071 to 2073, 2077, 2091, 2121, 2122, 2124, 2126, 2130, 2132, 2212, 2213, 2223, and 2252 of this title. For complete classification of section 802 to the Code, see Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2275a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Any approvals granted by the Farm Credit Administration before January 6, 1988, shall remain in effect on and after such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2275a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to issue regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to issue regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2275a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effect of section This section shall not affect the authority of the Farm Credit Administration to exercise any other approval authority either on a case-by-case basis or through regulation, as provided in section 2252(a)(5) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>