<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2277a–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2277a–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2277a–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2277a_2"><akn:num>2277a–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2277a–2. Board of Directors(a) EstablishmentThe Corporation shall be managed by a Board of Directors that shall consist of the members of the Farm Credit Administration Board.


(b) ChairmanThe Board of Directors shall be chaired by any Board member other than the Chairman of the Farm Credit Administration Board.


(Pub. L. 92–181, title V, § 5.53, as added Pub. L. 100–233, title III, § 302, Jan. 6, 1988, 101 Stat. 1611; amended Pub. L. 102–552, title II, § 201(a), Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 4104; Pub. L. 104–105, title II, § 219(a), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 184.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–105 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section related to Board of Directors, including provisions relating to establishment, appointment, chairperson, postemployment prohibition, terms of office, succession, vacancies, oath, quorum, meetings, rules and records, compensation, and expenses.
1992—Pub. L. 102–552 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows:
“(a) Establishment.—The Corporation shall be managed by a Board of Directors that shall consist of the members of the Farm Credit Administration Board.
“(b) Chairman.—The Board of Directors shall be chaired by any Board member other than the Chairman of the Farm Credit Administration Board.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1992 Amendment; Transition ProvisionPub. L. 102–552, title II, § 201(c), Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 4105, provided that:
“(1) In general.—The amendments made by this section [amending this section and sections 5314 and 5315 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees] shall become effective on January 1, 1996.

“(2) Transitional provision.—The Board of Directors of the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation as established by section 5.53 of the Farm Credit Act of 1971 (12 U.S.C. 2277a–2) (as it existed before the amendments made by subsection (a) of this section) shall continue in existence and continue to manage the Farm </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Corporation shall be managed by a Board of Directors that shall consist of the members of the Farm Credit Administration Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Chairman The Board of Directors shall be chaired by any Board member other than the Chairman of the Farm Credit Administration Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>