<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279cc" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279cc/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279cc/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2279cc"><akn:num>2279cc</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservatorship; liquidation; receivership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2279cc. Conservatorship; liquidation; receivership(a) Voluntary liquidationThe Corporation may voluntarily liquidate only with the consent of, and in accordance with a plan of liquidation approved by, the Farm Credit Administration Board.


(b) Involuntary liquidation(1) In generalThe Farm Credit Administration Board may appoint a conservator or receiver for the Corporation under the circumstances specified in section 2183(b) of this title.


(2) ApplicationIn applying section 2183(b) of this title to the Corporation under paragraph (1)—(A) the Corporation shall also be considered insolvent if the Corporation is unable to pay its debts as they fall due in the ordinary course of business;

(B) a conservator may also be appointed for the Corporation if the authority of the Corporation to purchase qualified loans or issue or guarantee loan-backed securities is suspended; and

(C) a receiver may also be appointed for the Corporation if—(i)(I) the authority of the Corporation to purchase qualified loans or issue or guarantee loan-backed securities is suspended; or

(II) the Corporation is classified under section 2279bb–4 of this title as within level III or IV and the alternative actions available under part B are not satisfactory; and


(ii) the Farm Credit Administration determines that the appointment of a conservator would not be appropriate.



(3) No effect on supervisory actionsThe grounds for appointment of a conservator for the Corporation under this subsection shall be in addition to those in section 2279bb–6 of this title.



(c) Appointment of conservator or receiver(1) QualificationsNotwithstanding section 2183(b) of this title, if a conservator or receiver is appointed for the Corporation, the conservator or receiver shall be—(A) the Farm Credit Administration or any other governmental entity or employee, including the Farm Credit System Insurance Corporation; or

(B) any person that—(i) has no claim against, or financial interest in, the Corporation or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279cc_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Voluntary liquidation The Corporation may voluntarily liquidate only with the consent of, and in accordance with a plan of liquidation approved by, the Farm Credit Administration Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279cc_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Involuntary liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Involuntary liquidation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279cc_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of conservator or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appointment of conservator or receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279cc_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Judicial review of appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279cc_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>General powers of conservator or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) General powers of conservator or receiver The conservator or receiver for the Corporation shall have such powers to conduct the conservatorship or receivership as shall be provided pursuant to regulations adopted by the Farm Credit Administration Board. Such powers shall be comparable to the powers available to a conservator or receiver appointed pursuant to section 2183(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279cc_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Borrowings for working capital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Borrowings for working capital</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279cc_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements against interests of conservator or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Agreements against interests of conservator or receiver No agreement that tends to diminish or defeat the right, title, or interest of the conservator or receiver for the Corporation in any asset acquired by the conservator or receiver as conservator or receiver for the Corporation shall be valid against the conservator or receiver unless the agreement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279cc_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report to Congress On a determination by the receiver for the Corporation that there are insufficient assets of the receivership to pay all valid claims against the receivership, the receiver shall submit to the Secretary of the Treasury, the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report on the financial condition of the receivership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279cc_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination of authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>