<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa–11" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa–11/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa–11/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2279aa_11"><akn:num>2279aa–11</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision, examination, and report of condition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2279aa–11. Supervision, examination, and report of condition(a) Regulation(1) AuthorityNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the Farm Credit Administration shall have the authority to provide, acting through the Office of Secondary Market Oversight—(A) for the examination of the Corporation and its affiliates; and

(B) for the general supervision of the safe and sound performance of the powers, functions, and duties vested in the Corporation and its affiliates by this subchapter, including through the use of the authorities granted to the Farm Credit Administration under—(i) part C of subchapter V; and

(ii) beginning 6 months after December 13, 1991, section 2252(a)(9) of this title.



(2) ConsiderationsIn exercising its authority pursuant to this section, the Farm Credit Administration shall consider—(A) the purposes for which the Corporation was created;

(B) the practices appropriate to the conduct of secondary markets in agricultural loans; and

(C) the reduced levels of risk associated with appropriately structured secondary market transactions.


(3) Office of Secondary Market Oversight(A) Not later than 180 days after December 13, 1991, the Farm Credit Administration Board shall establish within the Farm Credit Administration the Office of Secondary Market Oversight.

(B) The Farm Credit Administration Board shall carry out the authority set forth in this section through the Office of Secondary Market Oversight.

(C) The Office of Secondary Market Oversight shall be managed by a full-time Director who shall be selected by and report to the Farm Credit Administration Board.



(b) Examinations and audits(1) In generalThe financial transactions of the Corporation shall be examined by examiners of the Farm Credit Administration in accordance with the principles and procedures applicable to commercial corporate transactions under such rules and regulations as may be prescribed by the Administration.


(2) FrequencyThe examinations shall occur a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_11_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_11_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examinations and audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Examinations and audits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_11_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report of condition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual report of condition The Corporation shall make and publish an annual report of condition as prescribed by the Farm Credit Administration. Each report shall contain financial statements prepared in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles and contain such additional information as the Farm Credit Administration may by regulation prescribe. The financial statements of the Corporation shall be audited by an independent public accountant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_11_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>FCA assessments to cover costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) FCA assessments to cover costs The Farm Credit Administration shall assess the Corporation for the cost to the Administration of any regulatory activities conducted under this section, including the cost of any examination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_11_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Affiliate” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Affiliate” defined As used in this subchapter, the term “affiliate” shall mean an entity effectively controlled or owned by the Corporation, except that such term shall not include an originator (as defined in section 2279aa of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_11_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees and personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employees and personnel The Farm Credit Administration Board shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>