<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2279c"><akn:num>2279c</akn:num><akn:heading>Equalization of loan-making powers of certain district associations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2279c. Equalization of loan-making powers of certain district associations(a) Equalization of loan-making powers(1) In general(A) Federal land bank associationsSubject to paragraph (2), any association that owns a Federal land bank association authorized as of January 1, 2007, to make long-term loans under subchapter I in its chartered territory within the geographic area described in subsection (b) may make short- and intermediate-term loans and otherwise operate as a production credit association under subchapter II within that same chartered territory.


(B) Production credit associationsSubject to paragraph (2), any association that under its charter has subchapter I lending authority and that owns a production credit association authorized as of January 1, 2007, to make short- and intermediate-term loans under subchapter II in the geographic area described in subsection (b) may make long-term loans and otherwise operate, directly or through a subsidiary association, as a Federal land bank association or Federal land credit association under subchapter I in the geographic area.


(C) Farm Credit BankNotwithstanding section 2252(a) of this title, the Farm Credit Bank with which any association had a written financing agreement as of January 1, 2007, may make loans and extend other comparable financial assistance with respect to, and may purchase, any loans made under the new authority provided under subparagraph (A) or (B) by an association exercising such authority.



(2) Required approvalsAn association may exercise the additional authority provided for in paragraph (1) only after the exercise of the authority is approved by—(A) the board of directors of the association; and

(B) a majority of the voting stockholders of the association (or, if the association is a subsidiary of another association, the voting stockholders of the parent association) voting, in person or by proxy, at a duly authorized meeting of stockholders in accordance with the process desc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equalization of loan-making powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Equalization of loan-making powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicability This section applies only to associations the chartered territory of which was within the geographic area served by the Federal intermediate credit bank immediately prior to its merger with a Farm Credit Bank under section 410(e)(1) of the Agricultural Credit Act of 1987 (12 U.S.C. 2011 note; Public Law 100–233).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>