<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2279aa_2"><akn:num>2279aa–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2279aa–2. Board of directors(a) In general(1) EstablishmentThe Corporation shall be under the management of the board of directors.


(2) CompositionThe Board shall consist of 15 members, of which—(A) 5 members shall be elected by holders of common stock that are insurance companies, banks, or other financial institutions or entities;

(B) 5 members shall be elected by holders of common stock that are Farm Credit System institutions; and

(C) 5 members shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate—(i) which members shall not be, or have been, officers or directors of any financial institutions or entities;

(ii) which members shall be representatives of the general public;

(iii) of which members not more than 3 shall be members of the same political party; and

(iv) of which members at least 2 shall be experienced in farming or ranching.



(3) Vacancy(A) Elected membersSubject to paragraph (5), a vacancy among the members elected to the Board in the manner described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (2) shall be filled by the Board from among persons eligible for election to the position for which the vacancy exists.


(B) Appointed membersA vacancy among the members appointed to the Board under paragraph (2)(C) shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.



(4) Continuation of membershipIf—(A) any member of the Board who was appointed or elected to the Board from among persons who are representatives of banks, other financial institutions or entities, insurance companies, or Farm Credit System institutions ceases to be such a representative; or

(B) any member who was appointed from persons who are not or have not been directors or officers of any financial institution or entity becomes a director or an officer of any financial institution or entity;


such member may continue as a member for not longer than the 45-day period beginning on the date such member ceases to be such a represe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers and staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Officers and staff The Board may appoint, employ, fix the pay of, and provide other allowances and benefits for such officers and employees of the Corporation as the Board determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>