<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa–13" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa–13/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa–13/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2279aa_13"><akn:num>2279aa–13</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to issue obligations to cover guarantee losses of Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2279aa–13. Authority to issue obligations to cover guarantee losses of Corporation(a) Sale of obligations to Treasury(1) In generalSubject to the limitations contained in section 2279aa–10(c) of this title and the requirement of paragraph (2), the Corporation may issue obligations to the Secretary of the Treasury the proceeds of which may be used by the Corporation solely for the purpose of fulfilling the obligations of the Corporation under any guarantee provided by the Corporation under this subchapter.


(2) CertificationThe Secretary of the Treasury may purchase obligations of the Corporation under paragraph (1) only if the Corporation certifies to the Secretary that—(A) the requirements of section 2279aa–10(c) of this title have been fulfilled; and

(B) the proceeds of the sale of such obligations are needed to fulfill the obligations of the Corporation under any guarantee provided by the Corporation under this subchapter.



(b) Expeditious transaction requiredNot later than 10 business days after receipt by the Secretary of the Treasury of any certification by the Corporation under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary of the Treasury shall purchase obligations issued by the Corporation in an amount determined by the Corporation to be sufficient to meet the guarantee liabilities of the Corporation.


(c) Limitation on amount of outstanding obligationsThe aggregate amount of obligations issued by the Corporation under subsection (a)(1) which may be held by the Secretary of the Treasury at any time (as determined by the Secretary) shall not exceed $1,500,000,000.


(d) Terms of obligation(1) InterestEach obligation purchased by the Secretary of the Treasury shall bear interest at a rate determined by the Secretary, taking into consideration the average rate on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States as of the last day of the last calendar month ending before the date of the purchase of such obligation.


(2) RedemptionThe Secretary of the Treasury </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_13_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of obligations to Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sale of obligations to Treasury</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_13_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expeditious transaction required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expeditious transaction required Not later than 10 business days after receipt by the Secretary of the Treasury of any certification by the Corporation under subsection (a)(2), the Secretary of the Treasury shall purchase obligations issued by the Corporation in an amount determined by the Corporation to be sufficient to meet the guarantee liabilities of the Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_13_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on amount of outstanding obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on amount of outstanding obligations The aggregate amount of obligations issued by the Corporation under subsection (a)(1) which may be held by the Secretary of the Treasury at any time (as determined by the Secretary) shall not exceed $1,500,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_13_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of obligation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms of obligation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_13_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with title 31</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination with title 31</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_13_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Treasury $1,500,000,000, without fiscal year limitation, to carry out the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>