<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2279aa/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2279aa"><akn:num>2279aa</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2279aa. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter:(1) Agricultural real estateThe term “agricultural real estate” means—(A) a parcel or parcels of land, or a building or structure affixed to the parcel or parcels, that—(i) is used for the production of one or more agricultural commodities or products; and

(ii) consists of a minimum acreage or is used in producing minimum annual receipts, as determined by the Corporation; or


(B) a principal residence that is a single family, moderate-priced residential dwelling located in a rural area, excluding—(i) any community having a population in excess of 2,500 inhabitants; and

(ii) any dwelling, excluding the land to which the dwelling is affixed, with a value exceeding $100,000 (as adjusted for inflation).



(2) BoardThe term “Board” means the board of directors established under section 2279aa–2 of this title.


(3) Certified facilityThe term “certified facility” means—(A) an agricultural mortgage marketing facility that is certified under section 2279aa–5 of this title; or

(B) the Corporation and any affiliate thereof.


(4) CorporationThe term “Corporation” means the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation established in section 2279aa–1 of this title.


(5) GuaranteeThe term “guarantee” means the guarantee of timely payment of the principal and interest on securities representing interests in, or obligations backed by, pools of qualified loans, in accordance with this subchapter.


(6) OriginatorThe term “originator” means any Farm Credit System institution, bank, insurance company, business and industrial development company, savings and loan association, association of agricultural producers, agricultural cooperative, commercial finance company, trust company, credit union, or other entity that originates and services agricultural mortgage loans.


(7) Qualified loanThe term “qualified loan” means an obligation—(A)(i) that is secured by a fee-simple or leasehold mortgage with status as a first lien, on agri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural real estate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agricultural real estate The term “agricultural real estate” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Board The term “Board” means the board of directors established under section 2279aa–2 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certified facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Certified facility The term “certified facility” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Corporation The term “Corporation” means the Federal Agricultural Mortgage Corporation established in section 2279aa–1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Guarantee The term “guarantee” means the guarantee of timely payment of the principal and interest on securities representing interests in, or obligations backed by, pools of qualified loans, in accordance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Originator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Originator The term “originator” means any Farm Credit System institution, bank, insurance company, business and industrial development company, savings and loan association, association of agricultural producers, agricultural cooperative, commercial finance company, trust company, credit union, or other entity that originates and services agricultural mortgage loans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Qualified loan The term “qualified loan” means an obligation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279aa_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) State The term “State” has the meaning given such term in section 2277a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>