<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/247" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/247/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/247/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247"><akn:num>247</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247. Reports to Congress
The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall annually make a full report of its operations to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, who shall cause the same to be printed for the information of the Congress. The report required under this paragraph shall include the reports required under section 1691f of title 15, section 57a(f)(7) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 15, section 1613 of title 15, and section 247a of this title.
(Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 10 (par.), 38 Stat. 261; June 3, 1922, ch. 205, 42 Stat. 621; Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614, title II, § 203(a), 49 Stat. 704; Pub. L. 106–569, title XI, § 1103(b), Dec. 27, 2000, 114 Stat. 3030.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 57a(f)(7) of title 15, referred to in text, was repealed by Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1092(3), July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 2095.

Codification
Section is comprised of seventh par. of section 10 of act Dec. 23, 1913. For classification to this title of other pars. of section 10, see Codification note set out under section 241 of this title.

Amendments2000—Pub. L. 106–569 inserted at end “The report required under this paragraph shall include the reports required under section 1691f of title 15, section 57a(f)(7) of title 15, section 1613 of title 15, and section 247a of this title.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Section 203(a) of act Aug. 23, 1935, changed name of Federal Reserve Board to Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.

Membership of International Banks in Federal Reserve System; Report to CongressPub. L. 95–369, § 3(g), Sept. 17, 1978, 92 Stat. 610, provided that the Board report to Congress not later than 270 days after Sept. 17, 1978 recommendations with respect to permitting corporations organized or operating under section 25 or 25(a) of the Federal Reserve Act to become members of Federal Reserve Banks.

Effect of International Banking Act of 1978 on International Banks; Report </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>