<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/248" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/248/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/248/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_248"><akn:num>248</akn:num><akn:heading>Enumerated powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 248. Enumerated powers
The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall be authorized and empowered:(a) Examination of accounts and affairs of banks; publication of weekly statements; reports of liabilities and assets of depository institutions; covered institutions(1) To examine at its discretion the accounts, books, and affairs of each Federal reserve bank and of each member bank and to require such statements and reports as it may deem necessary. The said board shall publish once each week a statement showing the condition of each Federal reserve bank and a consolidated statement for all Federal reserve banks. Such statements shall show in detail the assets and liabilities of the Federal reserve banks, single and combined, and shall furnish full information regarding the character of the money held as reserve and the amount, nature, and maturities of the paper and other investments owned or held by Federal reserve banks.

(2) To require any depository institution specified in this paragraph to make, at such intervals as the Board may prescribe, such reports of its liabilities and assets as the Board may determine to be necessary or desirable to enable the Board to discharge its responsibility to monitor and control monetary and credit aggregates. Such reports shall be made (A) directly to the Board in the case of member banks and in the case of other depository institutions whose reserve requirements under sections 461, 463, 464, 465, and 466 of this title exceed zero, and (B) for all other reports to the Board through the (i) Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation in the case of insured State savings associations that are insured depository institutions (as defined in section 1813 of this title), State nonmember banks, savings banks, and mutual savings banks, (ii) National Credit Union Administration Board in the case of insured credit unions, (iii) the Comptroller of the Currency in the case of any Federal savings association which is an insured depo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of accounts and affairs of banks; publication of weekly statements; reports of liabilities and assets of depository institutions; covered institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Examination of accounts and affairs of banks; publication of weekly statements; reports of liabilities and assets of depository institutions; covered institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permitting or requiring rediscounting of paper at specified rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Permitting or requiring rediscounting of paper at specified rate To permit, or, on the affirmative vote of at least five members of the Board of Governors, to require Federal reserve banks to rediscount the discounted paper of other Federal reserve banks at rates of interest to be fixed by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspending reserve requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Suspending reserve requirements To suspend for a period not exceeding thirty days, and from time to time to renew such suspension for periods not exceeding fifteen days, any reserve requirements specified in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervising and regulating issue and retirement of notes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Supervising and regulating issue and retirement of notes To supervise and regulate through the Secretary of the Treasury the issue and retirement of Federal Reserve notes, except for the cancellation and destruction, and accounting with respect to such cancellation and destruction, of notes unfit for circulation, and to prescribe rules and regulations under which such notes may be delivered by the Secretary of the Treasury to the Federal Reserve agents applying therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adding to or reclassifying reserve cities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Adding to or reclassifying reserve cities To add to the number of cities classified as reserve cities under existing law in which national banking associations are subject to the reserve requirements set forth in section 20 of this Act, or to reclassify existing reserve cities or to terminate their designation as such.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspending or removing officers or directors of reserve banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Suspending or removing officers or directors of reserve banks To suspend or remove any officer or director of any Federal reserve bank, the cause of such removal to be forthwith communicated in writing by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to the removed officer or director and to said bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requiring writing off of doubtful or worthless assets of banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Requiring writing off of doubtful or worthless assets of banks To require the writing off of doubtful or worthless assets upon the books and balance sheets of Federal reserve banks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspending operations of or liquidating or reorganizing banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Suspending operations of or liquidating or reorganizing banks To suspend, for the violation of any of the provisions of this chapter, the operations of any Federal reserve bank, to take possession thereof, administer the same during the period of suspension, and, when deemed advisable, to liquidate or reorganize such bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requiring bonds of agents; safeguarding property in hands of agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Requiring bonds of agents; safeguarding property in hands of agents To require bonds of Federal reserve agents, to make regulations for the safeguarding of all collateral, bonds, Federal reserve notes, money, or property of any kind deposited in the hands of such agents, and said board shall perform the duties, functions, or services specified in this chapter, and make all rules and regulations necessary to enable said board effectively to perform the same.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_248_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exercising supervision over reserve banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exercising supervision over reserve banks To exercise general supervision over said Federal reserve banks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>