<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/24a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/24a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/24a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_24a"><akn:num>24a</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial subsidiaries of national banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 24a. Financial subsidiaries of national banks(a) Authorization to conduct in subsidiaries certain activities that are financial in nature(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), a national bank may control a financial subsidiary, or hold an interest in a financial subsidiary.


(2) Conditions and requirementsA national bank may control a financial subsidiary, or hold an interest in a financial subsidiary, only if—(A) the financial subsidiary engages only in—(i) activities that are financial in nature or incidental to a financial activity pursuant to subsection (b); and

(ii) activities that are permitted for national banks to engage in directly (subject to the same terms and conditions that govern the conduct of the activities by a national bank);


(B) the activities engaged in by the financial subsidiary as a principal do not include—(i) insuring, guaranteeing, or indemnifying against loss, harm, damage, illness, disability, or death (except to the extent permitted under section 302 or 303(c) of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act [15 U.S.C. 6712 or 6713(c)]) or providing or issuing annuities the income of which is subject to tax treatment under section 72 of title 26;

(ii) real estate development or real estate investment activities, unless otherwise expressly authorized by law; or

(iii) any activity permitted in subparagraph (H) or (I) of section 1843(k)(4) of this title, except activities described in section 1843(k)(4)(H) of this title that may be permitted in accordance with section 122 of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act;


(C) the national bank and each depository institution affiliate of the national bank are well capitalized and well managed;

(D) the aggregate consolidated total assets of all financial subsidiaries of the national bank do not exceed the lesser of—(i) 45 percent of the consolidated total assets of the parent bank; or

(ii) $50,000,000,000;


(E) except as provided in paragraph (4), the national bank meets standards of credit-worthiness established by</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization to conduct in subsidiaries certain activities that are financial in nature</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization to conduct in subsidiaries certain activities that are financial in nature</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities that are financial in nature</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities that are financial in nature</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital deduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Capital deduction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safeguards for the bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Safeguards for the bank A national bank that establishes or maintains a financial subsidiary shall assure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions applicable to national banks that fail to continue to meet certain requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Provisions applicable to national banks that fail to continue to meet certain requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to meet standards of credit-worthiness meet 22 So in original. Probably should be “or meet”. applicable criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Failure to meet standards of credit-worthiness meet</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>