<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/250" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/250/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/250/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_250"><akn:num>250</akn:num><akn:heading>Independence of financial regulatory agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 250. Independence of financial regulatory agencies
No officer or agency of the United States shall have any authority to require the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, or the National Credit Union Administration to submit legislative recommendations, or testimony, or comments on legislation, to any officer or agency of the United States for approval, comments, or review, prior to the submission of such recommendations, testimony, or comments to the Congress if such recommendations, testimony, or comments to the Congress include a statement indicating that the views expressed therein are those of the agency submitting them and do not necessarily represent the views of the President.
(Pub. L. 93–495, title I, § 111, Oct. 28, 1974, 88 Stat. 1506; Pub. L. 103–325, title III, § 331(a), Sept. 23, 1994, 108 Stat. 2232; Pub. L. 106–102, title VI, § 606(e)(2), Nov. 12, 1999, 113 Stat. 1455; Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title I, § 1102(b), July 30, 2008, 122 Stat. 2664.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was not enacted as part of the Federal Reserve Act which comprises this chapter.

Amendments2008—Pub. L. 110–289 substituted “the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency” for “the Federal Housing Finance Board”.
1999—Pub. L. 106–102 substituted “Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the Federal Housing Finance Board,” for “Federal Home Loan Bank Board,”.
1994—Pub. L. 103–325 inserted “the Comptroller of the Currency,” after “Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation,”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>