<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/25b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/25b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/25b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_25b"><akn:num>25b</akn:num><akn:heading>State law preemption standards for national banks and subsidiaries clarified</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 25b. State law preemption standards for national banks and subsidiaries clarified(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) National bankThe term “national bank” includes—(A) any bank organized under the laws of the United States; and

(B) any Federal branch established in accordance with the International Banking Act of 1978 [12 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.].


(2) State consumer financial lawsThe term “State consumer financial law” means a State law that does not directly or indirectly discriminate against national banks and that directly and specifically regulates the manner, content, or terms and conditions of any financial transaction (as may be authorized for national banks to engage in), or any account related thereto, with respect to a consumer.


(3) Other definitionsThe terms “affiliate”, “subsidiary”, “includes”, and “including” have the same meanings as in section 1813 of this title.



(b) Preemption standard(1) In generalState consumer financial laws are preempted, only if—(A) application of a State consumer financial law would have a discriminatory effect on national banks, in comparison with the effect of the law on a bank chartered by that State;

(B) in accordance with the legal standard for preemption in the decision of the Supreme Court of the United States in Barnett Bank of Marion County, N. A. v. Nelson, Florida Insurance Commissioner, et al., 517 U.S. 25 (1996), the State consumer financial law prevents or significantly interferes with the exercise by the national bank of its powers; and any preemption determination under this subparagraph may be made by a court, or by regulation or order of the Comptroller of the Currency on a case-by-case basis, in accordance with applicable law; or

(C) the State consumer financial law is preempted by a provision of Federal law other than title 62 of the Revised Statutes.


(2) Savings clauseTitle 62 of the Revised Statutes and section 371 of this title do not preempt, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preemption standard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantial evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Substantial evidence No regulation or order of the Comptroller of the Currency prescribed under subsection (b)(1)(B), shall be interpreted or applied so as to invalidate, or otherwise declare inapplicable to a national bank, the provision of the State consumer financial law, unless substantial evidence, made on the record of the proceeding, supports the specific finding regarding the preemption of such provision in accordance with the legal standard of the decision of the Supreme Court of the United States in Barnett Bank of Marion County, N.A. v. Nelson, Florida Insurance Commissioner, et al., 517 U.S. 25 (1996).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review of preemption determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Periodic review of preemption determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of State consumer financial law to subsidiaries and affiliates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application of State consumer financial law to subsidiaries and affiliates Notwithstanding any provision of title 62 of the Revised Statutes or section 371 of this title, a State consumer financial law shall apply to a subsidiary or affiliate of a national bank (other than a subsidiary or affiliate that is chartered as a national bank) to the same extent that the State consumer financial law applies to any person, corporation, or other entity subject to such State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of powers related to charging interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preservation of powers related to charging interest No provision of title 62 of the Revised Statutes shall be construed as altering or otherwise affecting the authority conferred by section 85 of this title for the charging of interest by a national bank at the rate allowed by the laws of the State, territory, or district where the bank is located, including with respect to the meaning of “interest” under such provision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transparency of OCC preemption determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transparency of OCC preemption determinations The Comptroller of the Currency shall publish and update no less frequently than quarterly, a list of preemption determinations by the Comptroller of the Currency then in effect that identifies the activities and practices covered by each determination and the requirements and constraints determined to be preempted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification of law applicable to nondepository institution subsidiaries and affiliates of national banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Clarification of law applicable to nondepository institution subsidiaries and affiliates of national banks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Visitorial powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Visitorial powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Enforcement actions The ability of the Comptroller of the Currency to bring an enforcement action under title 62 of the Revised Statutes or section 45 of title 15 does not preclude any private party from enforcing rights granted under Federal or State law in the courts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>