<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2604" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2604/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2604/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2604"><akn:num>2604</akn:num><akn:heading>Home buying information booklets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2604. Home buying information booklets(a) Preparation and distributionThe Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Director”) shall prepare, at least once every 5 years, a booklet to help consumers applying for federally related mortgage loans to understand the nature and costs of real estate settlement services. The Director shall prepare the booklet in various languages and cultural styles, as the Director determines to be appropriate, so that the booklet is understandable and accessible to homebuyers of different ethnic and cultural backgrounds. The Director shall distribute such booklets to all lenders that make federally related mortgage loans. The Director shall also distribute to such lenders lists, organized by location, of homeownership counselors certified under section 1701x(e) of this title for use in complying with the requirement under subsection (c) of this section.


(b) ContentsEach booklet shall be in such form and detail as the Director shall prescribe and, in addition to such other information as the Director may provide, shall include in plain and understandable language the following information:(1) A description and explanation of the nature and purpose of the costs incident to a real estate settlement or a federally related mortgage loan. The description and explanation shall provide general information about the mortgage process as well as specific information concerning, at a minimum—(A) balloon payments;

(B) prepayment penalties;

(C) the advantages of prepayment; and

(D) the trade-off between closing costs and the interest rate over the life of the loan.


(2) An explanation and sample of the uniform settlement statement required by section 2603 of this title.

(3) A list and explanation of lending practices, including those prohibited by the Truth in Lending Act or other applicable Federal law, and of other unfair practices and unreasonable or unnecessary charges to be avo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation and distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preparation and distribution The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Director”) shall prepare, at least once every 5 years, a booklet to help consumers applying for federally related mortgage loans to understand the nature and costs of real estate settlement services. The Director shall prepare the booklet in various languages and cultural styles, as the Director determines to be appropriate, so that the booklet is understandable and accessible to homebuyers of different ethnic and cultural backgrounds. The Director shall distribute such booklets to all lenders that make federally related mortgage loans. The Director shall also distribute to such lenders lists, organized by location, of homeownership counselors certified under section 1701x(e) of this title for use in complying with the requirement under subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents Each booklet shall be in such form and detail as the Director shall prescribe and, in addition to such other information as the Director may provide, shall include in plain and understandable language the following information: The booklet prepared pursuant to this section shall take into consideration differences in real estate settlement procedures that may exist among the several States and territories of the United States and among separate political subdivisions within the same State and territory.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estimate of charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Estimate of charges Each lender shall include with the booklet a good faith estimate of the amount or range of charges for specific settlement services the borrower is likely to incur in connection with the settlement as prescribed by the Bureau. Each lender shall also include with the booklet a reasonably complete or updated list of homeownership counselors who are certified pursuant to section 1701x(e) of this title and located in the area of the lender.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution by lenders to loan applicants at time of receipt or preparation of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Distribution by lenders to loan applicants at time of receipt or preparation of applications Each lender referred to in subsection (a) shall provide the booklet described in such subsection to each person from whom it receives or for whom it prepares a written application to borrow money to finance the purchase of residential real estate. The lender shall provide the booklet in the version that is most appropriate for the person receiving it. Such booklet shall be provided by delivering it or placing it in the mail not later than 3 business days after the lender receives the application, but no booklet need be provided if the lender denies the application for credit before the end of the 3-day period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2604_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Printing and distribution by lenders of booklets approved by Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Printing and distribution by lenders of booklets approved by Bureau Booklets may be printed and distributed by lenders if their form and content are approved by the Bureau as meeting the requirements of subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>