<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2617" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2617/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2617/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2617"><akn:num>2617</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2617. Authority of Bureau(a) Issuance of regulations; exemptionsThe Bureau is authorized to prescribe such rules and regulations, to make such interpretations, and to grant such reasonable exemptions for classes of transactions, as may be necessary to achieve the purposes of this chapter.


(b) Liability for acts done in good faith in conformity with rule, regulation, or interpretationNo provision of this chapter or the laws of any State imposing any liability shall apply to any act done or omitted in good faith in conformity with any rule, regulation, or interpretation thereof by the Bureau or the Attorney General, notwithstanding that after such act or omission has occurred, such rule, regulation, or interpretation is amended, rescinded, or determined by judicial or other authority to be invalid for any reason.


(c) Investigations; hearings; failure to obey order; contempt(1) The Secretary 11 Probably should be “The Bureau”. may investigate any facts, conditions, practices, or matters that may be deemed necessary or proper to aid in the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter, in prescribing of rules and regulations thereunder, or in securing information to serve as a basis for recommending further legislation concerning real estate settlement practices. To aid in the investigations, the Bureau is authorized to hold such hearings, administer such oaths, and require by subpena the attendance and testimony of such witnesses and production of such documents as the Bureau deems advisable.

(2) Any district court of the United States within the jurisdiction of which an inquiry is carried on may, in the case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpena of the Bureau issued under this section, issue an order requiring compliance therewith; and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof.


(d) Delay of effectiveness of recent final regulation relating to payments to employees(1) In generalThe amendment to part 350</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of regulations; exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Issuance of regulations; exemptions The Bureau is authorized to prescribe such rules and regulations, to make such interpretations, and to grant such reasonable exemptions for classes of transactions, as may be necessary to achieve the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for acts done in good faith in conformity with rule, regulation, or interpretation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Liability for acts done in good faith in conformity with rule, regulation, or interpretation No provision of this chapter or the laws of any State imposing any liability shall apply to any act done or omitted in good faith in conformity with any rule, regulation, or interpretation thereof by the Bureau or the Attorney General, notwithstanding that after such act or omission has occurred, such rule, regulation, or interpretation is amended, rescinded, or determined by judicial or other authority to be invalid for any reason.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations; hearings; failure to obey order; contempt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Investigations; hearings; failure to obey order; contempt</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2617_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delay of effectiveness of recent final regulation relating to payments to employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Delay of effectiveness of recent final regulation relating to payments to employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>