<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2707" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2707/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2707/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2707"><akn:num>2707</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2707. Authority of Secretary(a) Rules and regulationsThe Secretary is authorized to make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.


(b) Payment of expenses and charges relating to acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of real and personal propertyNotwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of real or other property by the United States, the Secretary shall have power, for the protection of the interest of the fund authorized under this chapter, to pay out of such fund all expenses or charges in connection with the acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of any property, real or personal, acquired by the Secretary as a result of recoveries under security, subrogation, or other rights.


(c) Powers with respect to property rights held by SecretaryIn the performance of, with respect to, the functions, powers, and duties vested in the Secretary by this chapter, the Secretary shall—(1) have the power, notwithstanding any other provision of law, whether before or after default, to provide by contract or otherwise for the extinguishment upon default of any redemption, equitable, legal, or other right, title in any mortgage, deed, trust, or other instrument held by or held on behalf of the Secretary under the provisions of this chapter; and

(2) have the power to foreclose on any property or commence any action to protect or enforce any right conferred upon the Secretary by law, contract, or other agreement, and bid for and purchase at any foreclosure or other sale any property in connection with which assistance has been provided pursuant to this chapter. In the event of any such acquisition, the Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, or disposal of real property by the United States, complete, remodel and convert, dispose of, lease, and otherwise deal with, such property. Notwithstan</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules and regulations The Secretary is authorized to make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of expenses and charges relating to acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of real and personal property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment of expenses and charges relating to acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of real and personal property Notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of real or other property by the United States, the Secretary shall have power, for the protection of the interest of the fund authorized under this chapter, to pay out of such fund all expenses or charges in connection with the acquisition, handling, improvement, or disposal of any property, real or personal, acquired by the Secretary as a result of recoveries under security, subrogation, or other rights.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers with respect to property rights held by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Powers with respect to property rights held by Secretary In the performance of, with respect to, the functions, powers, and duties vested in the Secretary by this chapter, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage of existing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coverage of existing programs The Secretary shall allow funds to be administered by a State that has an existing program that is determined by the Secretary to provide substantially similar assistance to homeowners. After such determination is made such State shall not be required to modify such program to comply with the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>