<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/2906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2906"><akn:num>2906</akn:num><akn:heading>Written evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2906. Written evaluations(a) Required(1) In generalUpon the conclusion of each examination of an insured depository institution under section 2903 of this title, the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency shall prepare a written evaluation of the institution’s record of meeting the credit needs of its entire community, including low- and moderate-income neighborhoods.


(2) Public and confidential sectionsEach written evaluation required under paragraph (1) shall have a public section and a confidential section.



(b) Public section of report(1) Findings and conclusions(A) Contents of written evaluationThe public section of the written evaluation shall—(i) state the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency’s conclusions for each assessment factor identified in the regulations prescribed by the Federal financial supervisory agencies to implement this chapter;

(ii) discuss the facts and data supporting such conclusions; and

(iii) contain the institution’s rating and a statement describing the basis for the rating.


(B) Metropolitan area distinctionsThe information required by clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall be presented separately for each metropolitan area in which a regulated depository institution maintains one or more domestic branch offices.



(2) Assigned ratingThe institution’s rating referred to in paragraph (1)(C) 11 So in original. Probably should be paragraph “(1)(A)(iii)”. shall be 1 of the following:(A) “Outstanding record of meeting community credit needs”.

(B) “Satisfactory record of meeting community credit needs”.

(C) “Needs to improve record of meeting community credit needs”.

(D) “Substantial noncompliance in meeting community credit needs”.


Such ratings shall be disclosed to the public on and after July 1, 1990.


(c) Confidential section of report(1) Privacy of named individualsThe confidential section of the written evaluation shall contain all references that identify any customer of the institution, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public section of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public section of report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2906_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidential section of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Confidential section of report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2906_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institutions with interstate branches</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Institutions with interstate branches</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2906_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>