<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3014" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3014/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3014/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3014"><akn:num>3014</akn:num><akn:heading>Capitalization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3014. Capitalization(a) Subscriptions for capital; authorization of appropriationsThe capital of the Bank shall consist of capital subscribed by borrowers from the Bank, by cooperatives eligible to become borrowers, by organizations owned and controlled by such borrowers, by foundations, trust or charitable funds, by public bodies, by other public or private investors, and by the United States. There are authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $47,000,000 for fiscal year 1982 for purposes of purchasing class A stock.


(b) Classes of stock; general requirements respecting rights, powers, privileges, and preferencesThe capital stock of the Bank shall include class B and class C stock and such other classes with such rights, powers, privileges, and preferences of the separate classes as may be specified, not inconsistent with law, in the bylaws of the Bank. Class A notes which are held by the United States shall have first preference with respect to assets and interest payments over all classes of stock issued by the Bank. So long as any class A notes are outstanding, the Bank shall not pay any dividend on any class of stock at a rate greater than the statutory interest rate payable on class A notes. Class B and class C stock shall be common stock with voting rights as provided for herein and shall be issued only to eligible borrowers and organizations controlled by such borrowers or organizations eligible to borrow, and shall be transferable only on the books of the Bank and then only to another eligible borrower. No holder of voting stock of the Bank shall be entitled to more than one vote regardless of the number of shares of stock of other classes held, except as provided in subsection (g) of this section.


(c) Class A notes; interest payments; redemption, etc.The holder of class A notes shall be entitled to interest at a rate or rates determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the current average yield on outstanding marketable </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3014_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subscriptions for capital; authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subscriptions for capital; authorization of appropriations The capital of the Bank shall consist of capital subscribed by borrowers from the Bank, by cooperatives eligible to become borrowers, by organizations owned and controlled by such borrowers, by foundations, trust or charitable funds, by public bodies, by other public or private investors, and by the United States. There are authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $47,000,000 for fiscal year 1982 for purposes of purchasing class A stock.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3014_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classes of stock; general requirements respecting rights, powers, privileges, and preferences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Classes of stock; general requirements respecting rights, powers, privileges, and preferences The capital stock of the Bank shall include class B and class C stock and such other classes with such rights, powers, privileges, and preferences of the separate classes as may be specified, not inconsistent with law, in the bylaws of the Bank. Class A notes which are held by the United States shall have first preference with respect to assets and interest payments over all classes of stock issued by the Bank. So long as any class A notes are outstanding, the Bank shall not pay any dividend on any class of stock at a rate greater than the statutory interest rate payable on class A notes. Class B and class C stock shall be common stock with voting rights as provided for herein and shall be issued only to eligible borrowers and organizations controlled by such borrowers or organizations eligible to borrow, and shall be transferable only on the books of the Bank and then only to another elig</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3014_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Class A notes; interest payments; redemption, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Class A notes; interest payments; redemption, etc. The holder of class A notes shall be entitled to interest at a rate or rates determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the current average yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable terms and conditions as of the last day of the month preceding each issuance of such class A notes to the Secretary of the Treasury, except that, until October 1, 1990, interest payments shall not exceed 25 percent of gross revenues for the year, less necessary operating expenses including a reserve for possible losses. From time to time, the Bank may, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury and consistent with the terms of this chapter, issue replacement class A notes upon terms and conditions to be agreed upon by the Bank and the Secretary, bearing interest as provided in this subsection, in substitution for those class A notes previously issued. Any such interest payment may </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3014_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Class B stock; ownership requirements, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Class B stock; ownership requirements, etc. Class B stock shall be held only by recipients of loans under section 3015 of this title, and such borrowers shall be required to own class B stock in an amount not less than 1 per centum of the face amount of the loan at the time the loan is made. Such borrowers may be required by the Bank to own additional class B or class C stock at the time the loan is made, but not to exceed an amount equal to 10 per centum of the face amount of the loan, or from time to time, as the Bank may determine. Such additional stock ownership requirements may be on the basis of the face amount of the loan, the outstanding balances, or on a percentage of interest payable during any year or any quarter thereof, as the Bank may determine will provide adequate capital for the operation of the Bank and equitable ownership thereof among borrowers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3014_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Class C stock; purchase, dividends, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Class C stock; purchase, dividends, etc. Class C stock shall be available for purchase and shall be held only by borrowers or by organizations eligible to borrow under section 3015 of this title or by organizations controlled by such borrowers, and shall be entitled to dividends in the manner specified in the bylaws of the Bank. Such dividends shall be payable only from income, and, until all class A notes has 11 So in original. Probably should be “have”. been retired, the rate of such dividends shall not exceed the rate of the statutory interest payment on class A notes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3014_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonvoting stock of other classifications and priorities; issuance, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nonvoting stock of other classifications and priorities; issuance, etc. Nonvoting stock of other classifications and other priorities may be issued at the discretion of the Board, to other investors, except that so long as any class A notes are outstanding, the Board shall not authorize or issue any class of stock, whether voting or nonvoting, that would rank prior or equal to the class A notes as to dividends, interest payments, or upon liquidation or dissolution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3014_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting requirements of bylaws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Voting requirements of bylaws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3014_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance by Bank of nonreturnable capital contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Acceptance by Bank of nonreturnable capital contributions The Bank may accept nonreturnable capital contributions on which no interest, dividend, or patronage refund shall be payable from associations, foundations, or funds or public bodies or agencies at the discretion of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3014_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Patronage refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Patronage refunds After payment of all operating expenses of the Bank, including interest on its obligations, and after setting aside appropriate funds for reserves for losses, for interest payments on class A notes and dividends on class C stock and for any redemption of class A notes in accordance with subsection (c), the Bank shall annually set aside the remaining earnings of the Bank for patronage refunds in the form of class B or C stock or allocated surplus in accordance with the bylaws of the Bank. After ten years from the date of issue of any such stock, or at such earlier time as all the Government-held stock is retired, patronage refunds may be made in cash, or partly in stock and partly in cash.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>