<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3105"><akn:num>3105</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Federal Reserve System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3105. Authority of Federal Reserve System(a) Bank reserves(1)(A) Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, sections 371a,11 See References in Text note below. 371b, 371b–1,1 374, 374a, 461, 464, and 465 of this title shall apply to every Federal branch and Federal agency of a foreign bank in the same manner and to the same extent as if the Federal branch or Federal agency were a member bank as that term is defined in section 221 of this title; but the Board either by general or specific regulation or ruling may waive the minimum and maximum reserve ratios prescribed under sections 461, 463, 464, 465, and 466 of this title and may prescribe any ratio, not more than 22 per centum, for any obligation of any such Federal branch or Federal agency that the Board may deem reasonable and appropriate, taking into consideration the character of business conducted by such institutions and the need to maintain vigorous and fair competition between and among such institutions and member banks. The Board may impose reserve requirements on Federal branches and Federal agencies in such graduated manner as it deems reasonable and appropriate.

(B) After consultation and in cooperation with the State bank supervisory authorities, the Board may make applicable to any State branch or State agency any requirement made applicable to, or which the Board has authority to impose upon, any Federal branch or agency under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph.


(2) A branch or agency shall be subject to this subsection only if (A) its parent foreign bank has total worldwide consolidated bank assets in excess of $1,000,000,000; (B) its parent foreign bank is controlled by a foreign company which owns or controls foreign banks that in the aggregate have total worldwide consolidated bank assets in excess of $1,000,000,000; or (C) its parent foreign bank is controlled by a group of foreign companies that own or control foreign banks that in the aggregate have total worldwide consolid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bank reserves</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Bank reserves</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign bank examinations and reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Foreign bank examinations and reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of foreign bank offices in United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Establishment of foreign bank offices in United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of foreign bank offices in United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of foreign bank offices in United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with State bank supervisor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Consultation with State bank supervisor The Board shall request and consider any views of the appropriate State bank supervisor with respect to any application or action under subsection (d) or (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on powers of State branches and agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations on powers of State branches and agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings related to conviction for money laundering offenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Proceedings related to conviction for money laundering offenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3105_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study on equivalence of foreign bank capital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Study on equivalence of foreign bank capital Not later than 180 days after December 19, 1991, the Board and the Secretary of the Treasury shall jointly submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives a report— An update shall be prepared annually explaining any changes in the analysis under paragraph (1) and resulting changes in the guidelines pursuant to paragraph (2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>