<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3108"><akn:num>3108</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3108. Regulation and enforcement(a) Rules, regulations and ordersThe Comptroller, the Board, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, are authorized and empowered to issue such rules, regulations, and orders as each of them may deem necessary in order to perform their respective duties and functions under this chapter and to administer and carry out the provisions and purposes of this chapter and prevent evasions thereof.


(b) Enforcement(1) In generalIn addition to any powers, remedies, or sanctions otherwise provided by law, compliance with the requirements imposed under this chapter or any amendment made by this chapter may be enforced under section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1818] by any appropriate Federal banking agency as defined in that Act [12 U.S.C. 1811 et seq.].


(2) Authority to administer oaths; subpoena powerIn the course of, or in connection with, an application, examination, investigation, or other proceeding under this chapter, the Board, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, as the case may be, any member of the Board or of the Board of Directors of the Corporation, and any designated representative of the Board, Comptroller, or Corporation (including any person designated to conduct any hearing under this chapter) may—(A) administer oaths and affirmations and take or cause to be taken depositions; and

(B) issue, revoke, quash, or modify any subpoena, including any subpoena requiring the attendance and testimony of a witness or any subpoenas duces tecum.


(3) Administrative aspects of subpoenas(A) Attendance and production at designated siteThe attendance of any witness and the production of any document pursuant to a subpoena under paragraph (2) may be required at the place designated in the subpoena from any place in any State (as defined in section 3(a)(3) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1813(a)(3)]) or other place subject to the jurisdiction of the Uni</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules, regulations and orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules, regulations and orders The Comptroller, the Board, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, are authorized and empowered to issue such rules, regulations, and orders as each of them may deem necessary in order to perform their respective duties and functions under this chapter and to administer and carry out the provisions and purposes of this chapter and prevent evasions thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of Federal Reserve Board and Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Powers of Federal Reserve Board and Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation In the case of any provision of the Federal Reserve Act [12 U.S.C. 221 et seq.] to which a foreign bank or branch thereof is subject under this chapter, and which is made applicable to nonmember insured banks by the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1811 et seq.], whether by cross-reference to the Federal Reserve Act or by a provision in substantially the same terms in the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, the administration, interpretation, and enforcement of such provision, insofar as it relates to any foreign bank or branch thereof as to which the Board is an appropriate Federal banking agency, are vested in the Board, but where the making of any report to the Board or a Federal Reserve bank is required under any such provision, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation may require that a duplicate of any such report be sent directly to it. This subsection shall not be construed to impair any power of </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>