<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3109" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3109/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3109/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3109"><akn:num>3109</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with foreign supervisors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3109. Cooperation with foreign supervisors(a) Disclosure of supervisory information to foreign supervisorsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Board, Comptroller of the Currency, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision may disclose information obtained in the course of exercising supervisory or examination authority to any foreign bank regulatory or supervisory authority if the Board, Comptroller, Corporation, or Director determines that such disclosure is appropriate and will not prejudice the interests of the United States.


(b) Requirement of confidentialityBefore making any disclosure of any information to a foreign authority, the Board, Comptroller of the Currency, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision shall obtain, to the extent necessary, the agreement of such foreign authority to maintain the confidentiality of such information to the extent possible under applicable law.


(c) Confidential information received from foreign supervisors(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (3), a Federal banking agency may not be compelled to disclose information received from a foreign regulatory or supervisory authority if—(A) the Federal banking agency determines that the foreign regulatory or supervisory authority has, in good faith, determined and represented in writing to such Federal banking agency that public disclosure of the information would violate the laws applicable to that foreign regulatory or supervisory authority; and

(B) the relevant Federal banking agency obtained such information pursuant to—(i) such procedures as the Federal banking agency may establish for use in connection with the administration and enforcement of Federal banking laws; or

(ii) a memorandum of understanding or other similar arrangement between the Federal banking agency and the foreign regulatory or supervisory authority.



(2) Treatment under title 5For purposes o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3109_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of supervisory information to foreign supervisors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disclosure of supervisory information to foreign supervisors Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Board, Comptroller of the Currency, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision may disclose information obtained in the course of exercising supervisory or examination authority to any foreign bank regulatory or supervisory authority if the Board, Comptroller, Corporation, or Director determines that such disclosure is appropriate and will not prejudice the interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3109_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement of confidentiality Before making any disclosure of any information to a foreign authority, the Board, Comptroller of the Currency, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision shall obtain, to the extent necessary, the agreement of such foreign authority to maintain the confidentiality of such information to the extent possible under applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3109_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidential information received from foreign supervisors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Confidential information received from foreign supervisors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>