<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3203" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3203/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3203/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3203"><akn:num>3203</akn:num><akn:heading>Dual service of management official of $2,500,000,000 institution or holding company as management o</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3203. Dual service of management official of $2,500,000,000 institution or holding company as management official of unaffiliated $1,500,000,000 institution or holding company prohibited
If a depository institution or a depository holding company has total assets exceeding $2,500,000,000, a management official of such institution or any affiliate thereof may not serve as a management official of any other nonaffiliated depository institution or depository holding company having total assets exceeding $1,500,000,000 or as a management official of any affiliate of such other institution. In order to allow for inflation or market changes, the appropriate Federal depository institutions regulatory agencies may, by regulation, adjust, as necessary, the amount of total assets required for depository institutions or depository holding companies under this section.
(Pub. L. 95–630, title II, § 204, Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3673; Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II, § 2210(a), Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–409.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–208 substituted “$2,500,000,000” for “$1,000,000,000” and “$1,500,000,000” for “$500,000,000” and inserted at end “In order to allow for inflation or market changes, the appropriate Federal depository institutions regulatory agencies may, by regulation, adjust, as necessary, the amount of total assets required for depository institutions or depository holding companies under this section.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective upon the expiration of 120 days after Nov. 10, 1978, see section 2101 of Pub. L. 95–630, set out as a note under section 375b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>