<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3307"><akn:num>3307</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3307. Administration(a) Authority of Chairman of CouncilThe Chairman of the Council is authorized to carry out and to delegate the authority to carry out the internal administration of the Council, including the appointment and supervision of employees and the distribution of business among members, employees, and administrative units.


(b) Use of personnel, services, and facilities of Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, Federal Reserve banks, and Federal Home Loan Banksin 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. addition to any other authority conferred upon it by this chapter, in carrying out its functions under this chapter, the Council may utilize, with their consent and to the extent practical, the personnel, services, and facilities of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, Federal Reserve banks, and Federal Home Loan Banks, with or without reimbursement therefor.


(c) Compensation, authority, and duties of officers and employees; experts and consultantsIn addition, the Council may—(1) subject to the provisions of title 5 relating to the competitive service, classification, and General Schedule pay rates, appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter, and to prescribe the authority and duties of such officers and employees; and

(2) obtain the services of such experts and consultants as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.


(Pub. L. 95–630, title X, § 1008, Nov. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 3696.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe provisions of title 5 relating to the competitive service, referred to in subsec. (c), are classified generally to section 3301 et seq. of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.
The provisions of title 5 relating to classification, referred to in subsec. (c), are classified generally to chapter 51 (§ 5101 et seq.) and to subchapter III (§ 5331 et seq.) of chapter 53 of Title 5.
The </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Chairman of Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Chairman of Council The Chairman of the Council is authorized to carry out and to delegate the authority to carry out the internal administration of the Council, including the appointment and supervision of employees and the distribution of business among members, employees, and administrative units.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of personnel, services, and facilities of Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, Federal Reserve banks, and Federal Home Loan Banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of personnel, services, and facilities of Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, Federal Reserve banks, and Federal Home Loan Banks in 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. addition to any other authority conferred upon it by this chapter, in carrying out its functions under this chapter, the Council may utilize, with their consent and to the extent practical, the personnel, services, and facilities of the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, Federal Reserve banks, and Federal Home Loan Banks, with or without reimbursement therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation, authority, and duties of officers and employees; experts and consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation, authority, and duties of officers and employees; experts and consultants In addition, the Council may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>