<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3345" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3345/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3345/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3345"><akn:num>3345</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification and licensing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3345. Certification and licensing requirements(a) In generalFor purposes of this chapter, the term “State certified real estate appraiser” means any individual who has satisfied the requirements for State certification in a State or territory whose criteria for certification as a real estate appraiser currently meets the minimum criteria for certification issued by the Appraiser Qualification Board of the Appraisal Foundation.


(b) RestrictionNo individual shall be a State certified real estate appraiser under this section unless such individual has achieved a passing grade upon a suitable examination administered by a State or territory that is consistent with and equivalent to the Uniform State Certification Examination issued or endorsed by the Appraiser Qualification Board of the Appraisal Foundation.


(c) “State licensed appraiser” definedAs used in this section, the term “State licensed appraiser” means an individual who has satisfied the requirements for State licensing in a State or territory whose criteria for the licensing of a real estate appraiser currently meet or exceed the minimum criteria issued by the Appraisal Qualifications Board of The Appraisal Foundation for the licensing of real estate appraisers.


(d) Additional qualification criteriaNothing in this chapter shall be construed to prevent any Federal agency or instrumentality under this chapter from establishing such additional qualification criteria as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the statutory responsibilities of such department, agency, or instrumentality.


(e) Minimum qualification requirementsAny requirements established for individuals in the position of “Trainee Appraiser” and “Supervisory Appraiser” shall meet or exceed the minimum qualification requirements of the Appraiser Qualifications Board of The Appraisal Foundation. The Appraisal Subcommittee shall have the authority to enforce these requirements.


(Pub. L. 101–73, title XI, § 1116, Aug. 9, 1989, 103 Stat.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For purposes of this chapter, the term “State certified real estate appraiser” means any individual who has satisfied the requirements for State certification in a State or territory whose criteria for certification as a real estate appraiser currently meets the minimum criteria for certification issued by the Appraiser Qualification Board of the Appraisal Foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Restriction No individual shall be a State certified real estate appraiser under this section unless such individual has achieved a passing grade upon a suitable examination administered by a State or territory that is consistent with and equivalent to the Uniform State Certification Examination issued or endorsed by the Appraiser Qualification Board of the Appraisal Foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“State licensed appraiser” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “State licensed appraiser” defined As used in this section, the term “State licensed appraiser” means an individual who has satisfied the requirements for State licensing in a State or territory whose criteria for the licensing of a real estate appraiser currently meet or exceed the minimum criteria issued by the Appraisal Qualifications Board of The Appraisal Foundation for the licensing of real estate appraisers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional qualification criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional qualification criteria Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prevent any Federal agency or instrumentality under this chapter from establishing such additional qualification criteria as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the statutory responsibilities of such department, agency, or instrumentality.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3345_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum qualification requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Minimum qualification requirements Any requirements established for individuals in the position of “Trainee Appraiser” and “Supervisory Appraiser” shall meet or exceed the minimum qualification requirements of the Appraiser Qualifications Board of The Appraisal Foundation. The Appraisal Subcommittee shall have the authority to enforce these requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>