<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3349" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3349/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3349/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3349"><akn:num>3349</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations in obtaining and performing appraisals in federally related transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3349. Violations in obtaining and performing appraisals in federally related transactions(a) ViolationsExcept as authorized by the Appraisal Subcommittee in exercising its waiver authority pursuant to section 3348(b) of this title, it shall be a violation of this section—(1) for a financial institution to seek, obtain, or give money or any other thing of value in exchange for the performance of an appraisal by a person who the institution knows is not a State certified or licensed appraiser in connection with a federally related transaction; and

(2) for the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, or the Resolution Trust Corporation to knowingly contract for the performance of any appraisal by a person who is not a State certified or licensed appraiser in connection with a real estate related financial transaction defined in section 3350(5) of this title to which such association or corporation is a party.


(b) PenaltiesA financial institution that violates subsection (a)(1) shall be subject to civil penalties under section 1818(i)(2) of this title or section 1786(k)(2) of this title, as appropriate.


(c) ProceedingA proceeding with respect to a violation of this section shall be an administrative proceeding which may be conducted by a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency in accordance with the procedures set forth in subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.


(Pub. L. 101–73, title XI, § 1120, Aug. 9, 1989, 103 Stat. 517.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3349_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Violations Except as authorized by the Appraisal Subcommittee in exercising its waiver authority pursuant to section 3348(b) of this title, it shall be a violation of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3349_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalties A financial institution that violates subsection (a)(1) shall be subject to civil penalties under section 1818(i)(2) of this title or section 1786(k)(2) of this title, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3349_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Proceeding A proceeding with respect to a violation of this section shall be an administrative proceeding which may be conducted by a Federal financial institutions regulatory agency in accordance with the procedures set forth in subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>