<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3351"><akn:num>3351</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3351. Miscellaneous provisions(a) Temporary practice(1) In generalA State appraiser certifying or licensing agency shall recognize on a temporary basis the certification or license of an appraiser issued by another State if—(A) the property to be appraised is part of a federally related transaction,

(B) the appraiser’s business is of a temporary nature, and

(C) the appraiser registers with the appraiser certifying or licensing agency in the State of temporary practice.


(2) Fees for temporary practiceA State appraiser certifying or licensing agency shall not impose excessive fees or burdensome requirements, as determined by the Appraisal Subcommittee, for temporary practice under this subsection.



(b) ReciprocityNotwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, a federally related transaction shall not be appraised by a certified or licensed appraiser unless the State appraiser certifying or licensing agency of the State certifying or licensing such appraiser has in place a policy of issuing a reciprocal certification or license for an individual from another State when—(1) the appraiser licensing and certification program of such other State is in compliance with the provisions of this chapter; and

(2) the appraiser holds a valid certification from a State whose requirements for certification or licensing meet or exceed the licensure standards established by the State where an individual seeks appraisal licensure.


(c) Supplemental fundingFunds available to the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies may be made available to the Financial Institutions Examination Council to support the Council’s functions under this chapter.


(d) Prohibition against discriminationCriteria established by the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, and the Resolution Trust Corporation for appraiser qualifications in addition to State certification or licensing m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Temporary practice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reciprocity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reciprocity Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, a federally related transaction shall not be appraised by a certified or licensed appraiser unless the State appraiser certifying or licensing agency of the State certifying or licensing such appraiser has in place a policy of issuing a reciprocal certification or license for an individual from another State when—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Supplemental funding Funds available to the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies may be made available to the Financial Institutions Examination Council to support the Council’s functions under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against discrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition against discrimination Criteria established by the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies, the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, and the Resolution Trust Corporation for appraiser qualifications in addition to State certification or licensing may include education achieved, experience, sample appraisals, and references from prior clients. Membership in a nationally recognized professional appraisal organization may be a criteria considered, though lack of membership therein shall not be the sole bar against consideration for an assignment under these criteria.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other requirements A corporation, partnership, or other business entity may provide appraisal services in connection with federally related transactions if such appraisal is prepared by individuals certified or licensed in accordance with the requirements of this chapter. An individual who is not a State certified or licensed appraiser may assist in the preparation of an appraisal if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Studies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraiser independence monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Appraiser independence monitoring The Appraisal Subcommittee shall monitor each State appraiser certifying and licensing agency for the purpose of determining whether such agency’s policies, practices, and procedures are consistent with the purposes of maintaining appraiser independence and whether such State has adopted and maintains effective laws, regulations, and policies aimed at maintaining appraiser independence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approved education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Approved education The Appraisal Subcommittee shall encourage the States to accept courses approved by the Appraiser Qualification Board’s Course Approval Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal complaint national hotline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Appraisal complaint national hotline If, 6 months after July 21, 2010, the Appraisal Subcommittee determines that no national hotline exists to receive complaints of non-compliance with appraisal independence standards and Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice, including complaints from appraisers, individuals, or other entities concerning the improper influencing or attempted improper influencing of appraisers or the appraisal process, the Appraisal Subcommittee shall establish and operate such a national hotline, which shall include a toll-free telephone number and an email address. If the Appraisal Subcommittee operates such a national hotline, the Appraisal Subcommittee shall refer complaints for further action to appropriate governmental bodies, including a State appraiser certifying and licensing agency, a financial institution regulator, or other appropriate legal authorities. For complaints referred to State appraiser certifying and licensing agencies or to F</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>