<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3353" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3353/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3353/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3353"><akn:num>3353</akn:num><akn:heading>Appraisal management company minimum requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3353. Appraisal management company minimum requirements(a) In generalThe Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall jointly, by rule, establish minimum requirements to be applied by a State in the registration of appraisal management companies. Such requirements shall include a requirement that such companies—(1) register with and be subject to supervision by a State appraiser certifying and licensing agency in each State in which such company operates;

(2) verify that only licensed or certified appraisers are used for federally related transactions;

(3) require that appraisals coordinated by an appraisal management company comply with the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice; and

(4) require that appraisals are conducted independently and free from inappropriate influence and coercion pursuant to the appraisal independence standards established under section 1639e of title 15.


(b) Relation to State lawNothing in this section shall be construed to prevent States from establishing requirements in addition to any rules promulgated under subsection (a).


(c) Federally regulated financial institutionsThe requirements of subsection (a) shall apply to an appraisal management company that is a subsidiary owned and controlled by a financial institution and regulated by a Federal financial institution regulatory agency. An appraisal management company that is a subsidiary owned and controlled by a financial institution regulated by a Federal financial institution regulatory agency shall not be required to register with a State.


(d) Registration limitationsAn appraisal management company shall not be registered by a State or included on the national registry if such company, in whole or in part, directly or indirectly, is owned by an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3353_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall jointly, by rule, establish minimum requirements to be applied by a State in the registration of appraisal management companies. Such requirements shall include a requirement that such companies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3353_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relation to State law Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent States from establishing requirements in addition to any rules promulgated under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3353_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federally regulated financial institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federally regulated financial institutions The requirements of subsection (a) shall apply to an appraisal management company that is a subsidiary owned and controlled by a financial institution and regulated by a Federal financial institution regulatory agency. An appraisal management company that is a subsidiary owned and controlled by a financial institution regulated by a Federal financial institution regulatory agency shall not be required to register with a State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3353_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Registration limitations An appraisal management company shall not be registered by a State or included on the national registry if such company, in whole or in part, directly or indirectly, is owned by any person who has had an appraiser license or certificate refused, denied, cancelled, surrendered in lieu of revocation, or revoked in any State. Additionally, each person that owns more than 10 percent of an appraisal management company shall be of good moral character, as determined by the State appraiser certifying and licensing agency, and shall submit to a background investigation carried out by the State appraiser certifying and licensing agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3353_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporting The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall jointly promulgate regulations for the reporting of the activities of appraisal management companies to the Appraisal Subcommittee in determining the payment of the annual registry fee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3353_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>