<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/339" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/339/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/339/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_339"><akn:num>339</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation by State member banks in lotteries and related activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 339. Participation by State member banks in lotteries and related activities(a) Prohibited activitiesA State member bank may not—(1) deal in lottery tickets;

(2) deal in bets used as a means or substitute for participation in a lottery;

(3) announce, advertise, or publicize the existence of any lottery; 11 So in original. The word “or” probably should appear.

(4) announce, advertise, or publicize the existence or identity of any participant or winner, as such, in a lottery.


(b) Use of banking premises prohibitedA State member bank may not permit—(1) the use of any part of any of its banking offices by any person for any purpose forbidden to the bank under subsection (a), or

(2) direct access by the public from any of its banking offices to any premises used by any person for any purpose forbidden to the bank under subsection (a).


(c) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) The term “deal in” includes making, taking, buying, selling, redeeming, or collecting.

(2) The term “lottery” includes any arrangement, other than a savings promotion raffle, whereby three or more persons (the “participants”) advance money or credit to another in exchange for the possibility or expectation that one or more but not all of the participants (the “winners”) will receive by reason of their advances more than the amounts they have advanced, the identity of the winners being determined by any means which includes—(A) a random selection;

(B) a game, race, or contest; or

(C) any record or tabulation of the result of one or more events in which any participant has no interest except for its bearing upon the possibility that he may become a winner.


(3) The term “lottery ticket” includes any right, privilege, or possibility (and any ticket, receipt, record, or other evidence of any such right, privilege, or possibility) of becoming a winner in a lottery.

(4) The term “savings promotion raffle” means a contest in which the sole consideration required for a chance of winning desi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_339_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibited activities A State member bank may not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_339_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of banking premises prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of banking premises prohibited A State member bank may not permit—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_339_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_339_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lawful banking services connected with operation of lottery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Lawful banking services connected with operation of lottery Nothing contained in this section prohibits a State member bank from accepting deposits or cashing or otherwise handling checks or other negotiable instruments, or performing other lawful banking services for a State operating a lottery, or for an officer or employee of that State who is charged with the administration of the lottery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_339_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations; enforcement The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall issue such regulations as may be necessary to the strict enforcement of this section and the prevention of evasions thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>