<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3412" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3412/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3412/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3412"><akn:num>3412</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3412. Use of information(a) Transfer of financial records to other agencies or departments; certificationFinancial records originally obtained pursuant to this chapter shall not be transferred to another agency or department unless the transferring agency or department certifies in writing that there is reason to believe that the rec­ords are relevant to a legitimate law enforcement inquiry, or intelligence or counterintelligence activity, investigation or analysis related to international terrorism within the jurisdiction of the receiving agency or department.


(b) Mailing of copy of certification and notice to customerWhen financial records subject to this chapter are transferred pursuant to subsection (a), the transferring agency or department shall, within fourteen days, send to the customer a copy of the certification made pursuant to subsection (a) and the following notice, which shall state the nature of the law enforcement inquiry with reasonable specificity: “Copies of, or information contained in, your financial records lawfully in possession of                    have been furnished to              pursuant to the Right of Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [12 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.] for the following purpose:             . If you believe that this transfer has not been made to further a legitimate law enforcement inquiry, you may have legal rights under the Financial Privacy Act of 1978 or the Privacy Act of 1974 [5 U.S.C. 552a].”


(c) Court-ordered delays in mailingNotwithstanding subsection (b), notice to the customer may be delayed if the transferring agency or department has obtained a court order delaying notice pursuant to section 3409(a) and (b) of this title and that order is still in effect, or if the receiving agency or department obtains a court order authorizing a delay in notice pursuant to section 3409(a) and (b) of this title. Upon the expiration of any such period of delay, the transferring agency or department shall serve to the customer th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3412_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of financial records to other agencies or departments; certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer of financial records to other agencies or departments; certification Financial records originally obtained pursuant to this chapter shall not be transferred to another agency or department unless the transferring agency or department certifies in writing that there is reason to believe that the rec­ords are relevant to a legitimate law enforcement inquiry, or intelligence or counterintelligence activity, investigation or analysis related to international terrorism within the jurisdiction of the receiving agency or department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3412_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mailing of copy of certification and notice to customer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mailing of copy of certification and notice to customer When financial records subject to this chapter are transferred pursuant to subsection (a), the transferring agency or department shall, within fourteen days, send to the customer a copy of the certification made pursuant to subsection (a) and the following notice, which shall state the nature of the law enforcement inquiry with reasonable specificity: “Copies of, or information contained in, your financial records lawfully in possession of                    have been furnished to              pursuant to the Right of Financial Privacy Act of 1978 [12 U.S.C. 3401 et seq.] for the following purpose:             . If you believe that this transfer has not been made to further a legitimate law enforcement inquiry, you may have legal rights under the Financial Privacy Act of 1978 or the Privacy Act of 1974 [5 U.S.C. 552a].”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3412_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court-ordered delays in mailing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Court-ordered delays in mailing Notwithstanding subsection (b), notice to the customer may be delayed if the transferring agency or department has obtained a court order delaying notice pursuant to section 3409(a) and (b) of this title and that order is still in effect, or if the receiving agency or department obtains a court order authorizing a delay in notice pursuant to section 3409(a) and (b) of this title. Upon the expiration of any such period of delay, the transferring agency or department shall serve to the customer the notice specified in subsection (b) and the agency or department that obtained the court order authorizing a delay in notice pursuant to section 3409(a) and (b) of this title shall serve to the customer the notice specified in section 3409(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3412_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchanges of examination reports by supervisory agencies; transfer of financial records to defend customer action; withholding of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exchanges of examination reports by supervisory agencies; transfer of financial records to defend customer action; withholding of information Nothing in this chapter prohibits any supervisory agency from exchanging examination reports or other information with another supervisory agency. Nothing in this chapter prohibits the transfer of a customer’s financial records needed by counsel for a Government authority to defend an action brought by the customer. Nothing in this chapter shall authorize the withholding of information by any officer or employee of a supervisory agency from a duly authorized committee or subcommittee of the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3412_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange of records, reports, or other information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exchange of records, reports, or other information Notwithstanding section 3401(6) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title or any other provision of law, the exchange of financial records, examination reports or other information with respect to a financial institution, holding company, or any subsidiary of a depository institution or holding company, among and between the five member supervisory agencies of the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Federal Trade Commission, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection is permitted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3412_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to Attorney General or Secretary of the Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer to Attorney General or Secretary of the Treasury</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>