<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3413" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3413/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3413/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3413"><akn:num>3413</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3413. Exceptions(a) Disclosure of financial records not identified with particular customersNothing in this chapter prohibits the disclosure of any financial records or information which is not identified with or identifiable as being derived from the financial records of a particular customer.


(b) Disclosure to, or examination by, supervisory agency pursuant to exercise of supervisory, regulatory, or monetary functions with respect to financial institutions, holding companies, subsidiaries, institution-affiliated parties, or other personsThis chapter shall not apply to the examination by or disclosure to any supervisory agency of financial records or information in the exercise of its supervisory, regulatory, or monetary functions, including conservatorship or receivership functions, with respect to any financial institution, holding company, subsidiary of a financial institution or holding company, institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to a financial institution, holding company, or subsidiary, or other person participating in the conduct of the affairs thereof.


(c) Disclosure pursuant to title 26Nothing in this chapter prohibits the disclosure of financial records in accordance with procedures authorized by title 26.


(d) Disclosure pursuant to Federal statute or rule promulgated thereunderNothing in this chapter shall authorize the withholding of financial records or information required to be reported in accordance with any Federal statute or rule promulgated thereunder.


(e) Disclosure pursuant to Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure or comparable rules of other courtsNothing in this chapter shall apply when financial records are sought by a Government authority under the Federal Rules of Civil or Criminal Procedure or comparable rules of other courts in connection with litigation to which the Government authority and the customer are parties.


(f) Disclosure pursuant to administrative subpena i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of financial records not identified with particular customers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disclosure of financial records not identified with particular customers Nothing in this chapter prohibits the disclosure of any financial records or information which is not identified with or identifiable as being derived from the financial records of a particular customer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to, or examination by, supervisory agency pursuant to exercise of supervisory, regulatory, or monetary functions with respect to financial institutions, holding companies, subsidiaries, institution-affiliated parties, or other persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosure to, or examination by, supervisory agency pursuant to exercise of supervisory, regulatory, or monetary functions with respect to financial institutions, holding companies, subsidiaries, institution-affiliated parties, or other persons This chapter shall not apply to the examination by or disclosure to any supervisory agency of financial records or information in the exercise of its supervisory, regulatory, or monetary functions, including conservatorship or receivership functions, with respect to any financial institution, holding company, subsidiary of a financial institution or holding company, institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to a financial institution, holding company, or subsidiary, or other person participating in the conduct of the affairs thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure pursuant to title 26</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disclosure pursuant to title 26 Nothing in this chapter prohibits the disclosure of financial records in accordance with procedures authorized by title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure pursuant to Federal statute or rule promulgated thereunder</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disclosure pursuant to Federal statute or rule promulgated thereunder Nothing in this chapter shall authorize the withholding of financial records or information required to be reported in accordance with any Federal statute or rule promulgated thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure pursuant to Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure or comparable rules of other courts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disclosure pursuant to Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure or comparable rules of other courts Nothing in this chapter shall apply when financial records are sought by a Government authority under the Federal Rules of Civil or Criminal Procedure or comparable rules of other courts in connection with litigation to which the Government authority and the customer are parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure pursuant to administrative subpena issued by administrative law judge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosure pursuant to administrative subpena issued by administrative law judge Nothing in this chapter shall apply when financial records are sought by a Government authority pursuant to an administrative subpena issued by an administrative law judge in an adjudicatory proceeding subject to section 554 of title 5 and to which the Government authority and the customer are parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure pursuant to legitimate law enforcement inquiry respecting name, address, account number, and type of account of particular customers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Disclosure pursuant to legitimate law enforcement inquiry respecting name, address, account number, and type of account of particular customers The notice requirements of this chapter and sections 3410 and 3412 of this title shall not apply when a Government authority by a means described in section 3402 of this title and for a legitimate law enforcement inquiry is seeking only the name, address, account number, and type of account of any customer or ascertainable group of customers associated (1) with a financial transaction or class of financial transactions, or (2) with a foreign country or subdivision thereof in the case of a Government authority exercising financial controls over foreign accounts in the United States under section 4305(b) of title 50; the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (title II, Public Law 95–223) [50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.]; or section 287c of title 22.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure pursuant to lawful proceeding, investigation, etc., directed at financial institution or legal entity or consideration or administration respecting Government loans, loan guarantees, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Disclosure pursuant to lawful proceeding, investigation, etc., directed at financial institution or legal entity or consideration or administration respecting Government loans, loan guarantees, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure pursuant to issuance of subpena or court order respecting grand jury proceeding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Disclosure pursuant to issuance of subpena or court order respecting grand jury proceeding Nothing in this chapter (except sections 3415 and 3420 of this title) shall apply to any subpena or court order issued in connection with proceedings before a grand jury, except that a court shall have authority to order a financial institution, on which a grand jury subpoena for customer records has been served, not to notify the customer of the existence of the subpoena or information that has been furnished to the grand jury, under the circumstances and for the period specified and pursuant to the procedures established in section 3409 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3413_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure pursuant to proceeding, investigation, etc., instituted by Government Accountability Office and directed at a government authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Disclosure pursuant to proceeding, investigation, etc., instituted by Government Accountability Office and directed at a government authority This chapter shall not apply when financial records are sought by the Government Accountability Office pursuant to an authorized proceeding, investigation, examination or audit directed at a government authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>