<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3414" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3414/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3414/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3414"><akn:num>3414</akn:num><akn:heading>Special procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3414. Special procedures(a) Access to financial records for certain intelligence and protective purposes(1) Nothing in this chapter (except sections 3415, 3417, 3418, and 3421 11 See References in Text note below. of this title) shall apply to the production and disclosure of financial records pursuant to requests from—(A) a Government authority authorized to conduct foreign counter- or foreign positive-intelligence activities for purposes of conducting such activities;

(B) the Secret Service for the purpose of conducting its protective functions (18 U.S.C. 3056; 18 U.S.C. 3056A, Public Law 90–331,1 as amended); or

(C) a Government authority authorized to conduct investigations of, or intelligence or counterintelligence analyses related to, international terrorism for the purpose of conducting such investigations or analyses.


(2) In the instances specified in paragraph (1), the Government authority shall submit to the financial institution the certificate required in section 3403(b) of this title signed by a supervisory official of a rank designated by the head of the Government authority and a term that specifically identifies a customer, entity, or account to be used as the basis for the production and disclosure of financial records.

(3)(A) If the Government authority described in paragraph (1) or the Secret Service, as the case may be, certifies that otherwise there may result a danger to the national security of the United States, interference with a criminal, counterterrorism, or counterintelligence investigation, interference with diplomatic relations, or danger to the life or physical safety of any person, no financial institution, or officer, employee, or agent of such institution, shall disclose to any person (other than those to whom such disclosure is necessary to comply with the request or an attorney to obtain legal advice or legal assistance with respect to the request) that the Government authority or the Secret Service has sought or obtained </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3414_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to financial records for certain intelligence and protective purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Access to financial records for certain intelligence and protective purposes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3414_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency access to financial records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Emergency access to financial records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3414_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of certain disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition of certain disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3414_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3414_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of “financial institution”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definition of “financial institution” For purposes of this section, and sections 3415 and 3417 of this title insofar as they relate to the operation of this section, the term “financial institution” has the same meaning as in subsections (a)(2) and (c)(1) of section 5312 of title 31, except that, for purposes of this section, such term shall include only such a financial institution any part of which is located inside any State or territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the United States Virgin Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>