<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/36" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/36/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/36/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_36"><akn:num>36</akn:num><akn:heading>Branch banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 36. Branch banks
The conditions upon which a national banking association may retain or establish and operate a branch or branches are the following:(a) Lawful and continuous operationA national banking association may retain and operate such branch or branches as it may have had in lawful operation on February 25, 1927, and any national banking association which continuously maintained and operated not more than one branch for a period of more than twenty-five years immediately preceding February 25, 1927, may continue to maintain and operate such branch.


(b) Converted State banks(1) A national bank resulting from the conversion of a State bank may retain and operate as a branch any office which was a branch of the State bank immediately prior to conversion if such office—(A) might be established under subsection (c) of this section as a new branch of the resulting national bank, and is approved by the Comptroller of the Currency for continued operation as a branch of the resulting national bank;

(B) was a branch of any bank on February 25, 1927; or

(C) is approved by the Comptroller of the Currency for continued operation as a branch of the resulting national bank.


The Comptroller of the Currency may not grant approval under clause (C) of this paragraph if a State bank (in a situation identical to that of the national bank) resulting from the conversion of a national bank would be prohibited by the law of such State from retaining and operating as a branch an identically situated office which was a branch of the national bank immediately prior to conversion.

(2) A national bank (referred to in this paragraph as the “resulting bank”), resulting from the consolidation of a national bank (referred to in this paragraph as the “national bank”) under whose charter the consolidation is effected with another bank or banks, may retain and operate as a branch any office which, immediately prior to such consolidation, was in operation as—(A) a main office or branch </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lawful and continuous operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Lawful and continuous operation A national banking association may retain and operate such branch or branches as it may have had in lawful operation on February 25, 1927, and any national banking association which continuously maintained and operated not more than one branch for a period of more than twenty-five years immediately preceding February 25, 1927, may continue to maintain and operate such branch.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Converted State banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Converted State banks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>New branches</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) New branches A national banking association may, with the approval of the Comptroller of the Currency, establish and operate new branches: (1) Within the limits of the city, town or village in which said association is situated, if such establishment and operation are at the time expressly authorized to State banks by the law of the State in question; and (2) at any point within the State in which said association is situated, if such establishment and operation are at the time authorized to State banks by the statute law of the State in question by language specifically granting such authority affirmatively and not merely by implication or recognition, and subject to the restrictions as to location imposed by the law of the State on State banks. In any State in which State banks are permitted by statute law to maintain branches within county or greater limits, if no bank is located and doing business in the place where the proposed agency is to be located, any national banking ass</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Branches resulting from interstate merger transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Branches resulting from interstate merger transactions A national bank resulting from an interstate merger transaction (as defined in section 1831u(f)(6) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title) may maintain and operate a branch in a State other than the home State (as defined in subsection (g)(3)(B)) of such bank in accordance with section 1831u of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive authority for additional branches</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusive authority for additional branches</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law applicable to interstate branching operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Law applicable to interstate branching operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>State “opt-in” election to permit interstate branching through de novo branches</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) State “opt-in” election to permit interstate branching through de novo branches</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title II, § 2204, Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–405</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior approval of branch locations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Prior approval of branch locations No branch of any national banking association shall be established or moved from one location to another without first obtaining the consent and approval of the Comptroller of the Currency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_36_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Branch” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) “Branch” defined The term “branch” as used in this section shall be held to include any branch bank, branch office, branch agency, additional office, or any branch place of business located in any State or Territory of the United States or in the District of Columbia at which deposits are received, or checks paid, or money lent. The term “branch”, as used in this section, does not include an automated teller machine or a remote service unit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>