<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3702"><akn:num>3702</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3702. Definitions
As used in this chapter—(1) “mortgage” means a deed of trust, mortgage, deed to secure debt, security agreement, or any other form of instrument under which any interest in property, real, personal or mixed, or any interest in property including leaseholds, life estates, reversionary interests, and any other estates under applicable State law, is conveyed in trust, mortgaged, encumbered, pledged, or otherwise rendered subject to a lien, for the purpose of securing the payment of money or the performance of an obligation;

(2) “multifamily mortgage” means a mortgage held by the Secretary pursuant to—(A) section 608 or 801, or title II or X, of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1743, 1748, 1707 et seq., 1749aa et seq.];

(B) section 312 of the Housing Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 1452b], as it existed immediately before its repeal by section 289 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act;

(C) section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 [12 U.S.C. 1701q], as it existed immediately before its amendment by section 801 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act;

(D) section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 [12 U.S.C. 1701q], as amended by section 801 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act;

(E) section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act [42 U.S.C. 8013]; and

(F) section 514 or 515 of the Housing Act of 1949 (42 U.S.C. 1484, 1485).


(3) “mortgage agreement” means the note or debt instrument and the mortgage instrument, deed of trust instrument, trust deed, or instrument or instruments creating the mortgage, including any instrument incorporated by reference therein (including any applicable regulatory agreement), and any instrument or agreement amending or modifying any of the foregoing;

(4) “mortgagor” means the obligor, grantor, or trustor named in the mortgage agreement and, unless the context otherwise indicates, includes the current owner of record of the security property whether or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) “mortgage” means a deed of trust, mortgage, deed to secure debt, security agreement, or any other form of instrument under which any interest in property, real, personal or mixed, or any interest in property including leaseholds, life estates, reversionary interests, and any other estates under applicable State law, is conveyed in trust, mortgaged, encumbered, pledged, or otherwise rendered subject to a lien, for the purpose of securing the payment of money or the performance of an obligation;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) “multifamily mortgage” means a mortgage held by the Secretary pursuant to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) “mortgage agreement” means the note or debt instrument and the mortgage instrument, deed of trust instrument, trust deed, or instrument or instruments creating the mortgage, including any instrument incorporated by reference therein (including any applicable regulatory agreement), and any instrument or agreement amending or modifying any of the foregoing;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) “mortgagor” means the obligor, grantor, or trustor named in the mortgage agreement and, unless the context otherwise indicates, includes the current owner of record of the security property whether or not personally liable on the mortgage debt;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) “person” includes any individual, group of individuals, association, partnership, corporation, or organization;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) “record” and “recorded” include “register” and “registered” in the instance of registered land;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) “security property” means the property, real, personal or mixed, or an interest in property, including leaseholds, life estates, reversionary interests, and any other estates under applicable State law, together with fixtures and other interests subject to the lien of the mortgage under applicable State law;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) “State” means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the territories and possessions of the United States, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and Indian tribes as defined by the Secretary;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) “county” means county as defined in section 2 of title 1; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>