<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/371c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/371c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/371c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_371c"><akn:num>371c</akn:num><akn:heading>Banking affiliates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 371c. Banking affiliates(a) Restrictions on transactions with affiliates(1) A member bank and its subsidiaries may engage in a covered transaction with an affiliate only if—(A) in the case of any affiliate, the aggregate amount of covered transactions of the member bank and its subsidiaries will not exceed 10 per centum of the capital stock and surplus of the member bank; and

(B) in the case of all affiliates, the aggregate amount of covered transactions of the member bank and its subsidiaries will not exceed 20 per centum of the capital stock and surplus of the member bank.


(2) For the purpose of this section, any transaction by a member bank with any person shall be deemed to be a transaction with an affiliate to the extent that the proceeds of the transaction are used for the benefit of, or transferred to, that affiliate.

(3) A member bank and its subsidiaries may not purchase a low-quality asset from an affiliate unless the bank or such subsidiary, pursuant to an independent credit evaluation, committed itself to purchase such asset prior to the time such asset was acquired by the affiliate.

(4) Any covered transactions and any transactions exempt under subsection (d) between a member bank and an affiliate shall be on terms and conditions that are consistent with safe and sound banking practices.


(b) DefinitionsFor the purpose of this section—(1) the term “affiliate” with respect to a member bank means—(A) any company that controls the member bank and any other company that is controlled by the company that controls the member bank;

(B) a bank subsidiary of the member bank;

(C) any company—(i) that is controlled directly or indirectly, by a trust or otherwise, by or for the benefit of shareholders who beneficially or otherwise control, directly or indirectly, by trust or otherwise, the member bank or any company that controls the member bank; or

(ii) in which a majority of its directors or trustees constitute a majority of the persons holding any suc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_371c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on transactions with affiliates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Restrictions on transactions with affiliates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_371c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_371c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collateral for certain transactions with affiliates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Collateral for certain transactions with affiliates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_371c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemptions The provisions of this section, except paragraph (a)(4),11 So in original. Probably should read “subsection (a)(4),”. shall not be applicable to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_371c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules relating to banks with financial subsidiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rules relating to banks with financial subsidiaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_371c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking and additional exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rulemaking and additional exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>