<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/375b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/375b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/375b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_375b"><akn:num>375b</akn:num><akn:heading>Extensions of credit to executive officers, directors, and principal shareholders of member banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 375b. Extensions of credit to executive officers, directors, and principal shareholders of member banks(1) In generalNo member bank may extend credit to any of its executive officers, directors, or principal shareholders, or to any related interest of such a person, except to the extent permitted under paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6).


(2) Preferential terms prohibited(A) In generalA member bank may extend credit to its executive officers, directors, or principal shareholders, or to any related interest of such a person, only if the extension of credit—(i) is made on substantially the same terms, including interest rates and collateral, as those prevailing at the time for comparable transactions by the bank with persons who are not executive officers, directors, principal shareholders, or employees of the bank;

(ii) does not involve more than the normal risk of repayment or present other unfavorable features; and

(iii) the bank follows credit underwriting procedures that are not less stringent than those applicable to comparable transactions by the bank with persons who are not executive officers, directors, principal shareholders, or employees of the bank.


(B) ExceptionNothing in this paragraph shall prohibit any extension of credit made pursuant to a benefit or compensation program—(i) that is widely available to employees of the member bank; and

(ii) that does not give preference to any officer, director, or principal shareholder of the member bank, or to any related interest of such person, over other employees of the member bank.



(3) Prior approval requiredA member bank may extend credit to a person described in paragraph (1) in an amount that, when aggregated with the amount of all other outstanding extensions of credit by that bank to each such person and that person’s related interests, would exceed an amount prescribed by regulation of the appropriate Federal banking agency (as defined in section 1813 of this title) only if—(A) the extensi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) In general No member bank may extend credit to any of its executive officers, directors, or principal shareholders, or to any related interest of such a person, except to the extent permitted under paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferential terms prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Preferential terms prohibited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior approval required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Prior approval required A member bank may extend credit to a person described in paragraph (1) in an amount that, when aggregated with the amount of all other outstanding extensions of credit by that bank to each such person and that person’s related interests, would exceed an amount prescribed by regulation of the appropriate Federal banking agency (as defined in section 1813 of this title) only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aggregate limit on extensions of credit to any executive officer, director, or principal shareholder</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Aggregate limit on extensions of credit to any executive officer, director, or principal shareholder A member bank may extend credit to any executive officer, director, or principal shareholder, or to any related interest of such a person, only if the extension of credit is in an amount that, when aggregated with the amount of all outstanding extensions of credit by that bank to that person and that person’s related interests, would not exceed the limits on loans to a single borrower established by section 84 of this title. For purposes of this paragraph, section 84 of this title shall be deemed to apply to a State member bank as if the State member bank were a national banking association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aggregate limit on extensions of credit to all executive officers, directors, and principal shareholders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Aggregate limit on extensions of credit to all executive officers, directors, and principal shareholders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overdrafts by executive officers and directors prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Overdrafts by executive officers and directors prohibited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on knowingly receiving unauthorized extension of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Prohibition on knowingly receiving unauthorized extension of credit No executive officer, director, or principal shareholder shall knowingly receive (or knowingly permit any of that person’s related interests to receive) from a member bank, directly or indirectly, any extension of credit not authorized under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive officer, director, or principal shareholder of certain affiliates treated as executive officer, director, or principal shareholder of member bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Executive officer, director, or principal shareholder of certain affiliates treated as executive officer, director, or principal shareholder of member bank</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_375b_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board’s rulemaking authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Board’s rulemaking authority The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System may prescribe such regulations, including definitions of terms, as it determines to be necessary to effectuate the purposes and prevent evasions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>