<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/3906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3906"><akn:num>3906</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection and disclosure of international lending data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3906. Collection and disclosure of international lending data(a) Submission of information to Federal banking agenciesEach appropriate Federal banking agency shall require, by regulation, each banking institution with foreign country exposure to submit, no fewer than four times each calendar year, information regarding such exposure in a format prescribed by such regulations.


(b) Disclosure of information to the publicEach appropriate Federal banking agency shall require, by regulation, banking institutions to disclose to the public information regarding material foreign country exposure in relation to assets and to capital.


(c) Regulations and orders of Federal banking agenciesThe appropriate Federal banking agencies shall promulgate regulations or orders necessary to implement this section within one hundred and twenty days after November 30, 1983.


(Pub. L. 98–181, title I [title IX, § 907], Nov. 30, 1983, 97 Stat. 1280.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of information to Federal banking agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission of information to Federal banking agencies Each appropriate Federal banking agency shall require, by regulation, each banking institution with foreign country exposure to submit, no fewer than four times each calendar year, information regarding such exposure in a format prescribed by such regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of information to the public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosure of information to the public Each appropriate Federal banking agency shall require, by regulation, banking institutions to disclose to the public information regarding material foreign country exposure in relation to assets and to capital.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3906_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and orders of Federal banking agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations and orders of Federal banking agencies The appropriate Federal banking agencies shall promulgate regulations or orders necessary to implement this section within one hundred and twenty days after November 30, 1983.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>