<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4003" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4003/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4003/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4003"><akn:num>4003</akn:num><akn:heading>Safeguard exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4003. Safeguard exceptions(a) New accountsNotwithstanding section 4002 of this title, in the case of any account established at a depository institution by a new depositor, the following provisions shall apply with respect to any deposit in such account during the 30-day period (or such shorter period as the Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, may establish) beginning on the date such account is established—(1) Next business day availability of cash and certain itemsExcept as provided in paragraph (3), in the case of—(A) any cash deposited in such account;

(B) any funds received by such depository institution by wire transfer for deposit in such account;

(C) any funds deposited in such account by cashier’s check, certified check, teller’s check, depository check, or traveler’s check; and

(D) any funds deposited by a government check which is described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 4002(a)(2) of this title,


such cash or funds shall be available for withdrawal on the business day after the business day on which such cash or funds are deposited or, in the case of a wire transfer, on the business day after the business day on which such funds are received for deposit.

(2) Availability of other itemsIn the case of any funds deposited in such account by a check (other than a check described in subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1)), the availability for withdrawal of such funds shall not be subject to the provisions of section 4002(b), 4002(c), or paragraphs 11 So in original. Probably should be “paragraph”. (1) of section 4002(e) of this title.


(3) Limitation relating to certain checks in excess of $5,000In the case of funds deposited in such account during such period by checks described in subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) the aggregate amount of which exceeds $5,000—(A) paragraph (1) shall apply only with respect to the first $5,000 of such aggregate amount; and

(B) not more than 8 busines</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>New accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) New accounts Notwithstanding section 4002 of this title, in the case of any account established at a depository institution by a new depositor, the following provisions shall apply with respect to any deposit in such account during the 30-day period (or such shorter period as the Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, may establish) beginning on the date such account is established—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Large or redeposited checks; repeated overdrafts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Large or redeposited checks; repeated overdrafts The Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, may, by regulation, establish reasonable exceptions to any time limitation established under subsection (a)(2), (b), (c), or (e) of section 4002 of this title for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable cause exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reasonable cause exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Emergency conditions Subject to such regulations as the Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, may prescribe, subsections (a)(2), (b), (c), and (e) of section 4002 of this title shall not apply to funds deposited by check in any receiving depository institution in the case of— if the receiving depository institution exercises such diligence as the circumstances require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of fraud losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prevention of fraud losses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4003_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of exception; availability within reasonable time</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notice of exception; availability within reasonable time</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>