<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4004" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4004/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4004/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4004"><akn:num>4004</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of funds availability policies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4004. Disclosure of funds availability policies(a) Notice for new accountsBefore an account is opened at a depository institution, the depository institution shall provide written notice to the potential customer of the specific policy of such depository institution with respect to when a customer may withdraw funds deposited into the customer’s account.


(b) Preprinted deposit slipsAll preprinted deposit slips that a depository institution furnishes to its customers shall contain a summary notice, as prescribed by the Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in regulations, that deposited items may not be available for immediate withdrawal.


(c) Mailing of notice(1) First mailing after enactmentIn the first regularly scheduled mailing to customers occurring after September 1, 1988, but not more than 60 days after September 1, 1988, each depository institution shall send a written notice containing the specific policy of such depository institution with respect to when a customer may withdraw funds deposited into such customer’s account, unless the depository institution has provided a disclosure which meets the requirements of this section before September 1, 1988.


(2) Subsequent changesA depository institution shall send a written notice to customers at least 30 days before implementing any change to the depository institution’s policy with respect to when customers may withdraw funds deposited into consumer accounts, except that any change which expedites the availability of such funds shall be disclosed not later than 30 days after implementation.


(3) Upon requestUpon the request of any person, a depository institution shall provide or send such person a written notice containing the specific policy of such depository institution with respect to when a customer may withdraw funds deposited into a customer’s account.



(d) Posting of notice(1) Specific notice at manned teller stationsEach depository institution sha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4004_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice for new accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice for new accounts Before an account is opened at a depository institution, the depository institution shall provide written notice to the potential customer of the specific policy of such depository institution with respect to when a customer may withdraw funds deposited into the customer’s account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4004_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preprinted deposit slips</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preprinted deposit slips All preprinted deposit slips that a depository institution furnishes to its customers shall contain a summary notice, as prescribed by the Board, jointly with the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, in regulations, that deposited items may not be available for immediate withdrawal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4004_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mailing of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mailing of notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4004_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Posting of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Posting of notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4004_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of interest payment policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice of interest payment policy If a depository institution described in section 4005(b) of this title begins the accrual of interest or dividends at a later date than the date described in section 4005(a) of this title with respect to all funds, including cash, deposited in an interest-bearing account at such depository institution, any notice required to be provided under subsections (a) and (c) shall contain a written description of the time at which such depository institution begins to accrue interest or dividends on such funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4004_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Model disclosure forms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Model disclosure forms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>