<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4009" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4009/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4009/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4009"><akn:num>4009</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4009. Administrative enforcement(a) Administrative enforcementCompliance with the requirements imposed under this chapter, including regulations prescribed by and orders issued by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System under this chapter, shall be enforced under—(1) section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1818] in the case of—(A) national banks, and Federal branches and Federal agencies of foreign banks, by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency;

(B) member banks of the Federal Reserve System (other than national banks), and offices, branches, and agencies of foreign banks located in the United States (other than Federal branches, Federal agencies, and insured State branches of foreign banks), by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System; and

(C) banks insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (other than members of the Federal Reserve System) and insured State branches of foreign banks, by the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation;


(2) section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1818], by the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision in the case of savings associations the deposits of which are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; and

(3) the Federal Credit Union Act [12 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.], by the National Credit Union Administration Board with respect to any Federal credit union or insured credit union.


The terms used in paragraph (1) that are not defined in this chapter or otherwise defined in section 3(s) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (12 U.S.C. 1813(s)) shall have the meaning given to them in section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978 (12 U.S.C. 3101).

(b) Additional powers(1) Violation of this chapter treated as violation of other ActsFor purposes of the exercise by any agency referred to in subsection (a) of this section of its powers under any Act referred to in that subsection, a violation of any requirement </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administrative enforcement Compliance with the requirements imposed under this chapter, including regulations prescribed by and orders issued by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System under this chapter, shall be enforced under— The terms used in paragraph (1) that are not defined in this chapter or otherwise defined in section 3(s) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (12 U.S.C. 1813(s)) shall have the meaning given to them in section 1(b) of the International Banking Act of 1978 (12 U.S.C. 3101).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement by Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4009_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedural rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Procedural rules The authority of the Board to prescribe regulations under this chapter does not impair the authority of any other agency designated in this section to make rules regarding its own procedures in enforcing compliance with requirements imposed under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>