<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4101"><akn:num>4101</akn:num><akn:heading>General prepayment limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4101. General prepayment limitation(a) Prepayment and terminationAn owner of eligible low-income housing may prepay, and a mortgagee may accept prepayment of, a mortgage on such housing only in accordance with a plan of action approved by the Secretary under this subchapter or in accordance with section 4114 of this title. An insurance contract with respect to eligible low-income housing may be terminated pursuant to section 1715t of this title only in accordance with a plan of action approved by the Secretary under this subchapter or in accordance with section 4114 of this title.


(b) ForeclosureA mortgagee may foreclose the mortgage on, or acquire by deed in lieu of foreclosure, any eligible low-income housing project only if the mortgagee also conveys title to the project to the Secretary in connection with a claim for insurance benefits.


(c) Effect of unauthorized prepaymentAny prepayment of a mortgage on eligible low-income housing or termination of the mortgage insurance on such housing not in compliance with the provisions of this subchapter shall be null and void and any low-income affordability restrictions on the housing shall continue to apply to the housing.


(Pub. L. 100–242, title II, § 211, as added Pub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 601(a), Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4249.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 605, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4278, provided that: “This subtitle [subtitle A (§§ 601–605) of title VI of Pub. L. 101–625, enacting this chapter, amending sections 1715z–6 and 1715z–15 of this title and section 1437f of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare, and enacting provisions set out below] shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [Nov. 28, 1990].”


Short TitlePub. L. 100–242, title II, § 201, as added by Pub. L. 101–625, title VI, § 601(a), Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4249, provided that: “This title [enacting this chapter, amending section 1715z–15 of this title and section</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prepayment and termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prepayment and termination An owner of eligible low-income housing may prepay, and a mortgagee may accept prepayment of, a mortgage on such housing only in accordance with a plan of action approved by the Secretary under this subchapter or in accordance with section 4114 of this title. An insurance contract with respect to eligible low-income housing may be terminated pursuant to section 1715t of this title only in accordance with a plan of action approved by the Secretary under this subchapter or in accordance with section 4114 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Foreclosure A mortgagee may foreclose the mortgage on, or acquire by deed in lieu of foreclosure, any eligible low-income housing project only if the mortgagee also conveys title to the project to the Secretary in connection with a claim for insurance benefits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of unauthorized prepayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effect of unauthorized prepayment Any prepayment of a mortgage on eligible low-income housing or termination of the mortgage insurance on such housing not in compliance with the provisions of this subchapter shall be null and void and any low-income affordability restrictions on the housing shall continue to apply to the housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>