<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4105"><akn:num>4105</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal cost limits and limitations on plans of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4105. Federal cost limits and limitations on plans of action(a) Determination of relationship to Federal cost limits(1) Initial determinationFor each eligible low-income housing project appraised under section 4103(a) of this title, the Secretary shall determine whether the aggregate preservation rents for the project determined under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 4104(b) of this title exceed the amount determined by multiplying 120 percent of the fair market rental (established under section 1437f(c) of title 42) for the market area in which the housing is located by the number of dwelling units in the project (according to appropriate unit sizes).


(2) Relevant local marketsIf the aggregate preservation rents for a project exceeds the amount determined under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall determine whether such aggregate rents exceed the amount determined by multiplying 120 percent of the prevailing rents in the relevant local market area in which the housing is located by the number of units in the project (according to the appropriate unit sizes). A relevant local market area shall be an area geographically smaller than a market area established by the Secretary under section 1437f(c)(1) of title 42 that is identifiable as a distinct rental market area. The Secretary may rely on the appraisal to determine the relevant local market areas and prevailing rents in such local areas and any other information the Secretary determines is appropriate.


(3) EffectFor purposes of this subchapter, the aggregate preservation rents shall be considered to exceed the Federal cost limits under this subsection only if the aggregate preservation rents exceed the amount determined under paragraph (1) and the amount determined under paragraph (2).



(b) Limitations on action pursuant to Federal cost limits(1) Housing within Federal cost limitsIf the aggregate preservation rents for an eligible low-income housing project do not exceed the Federal cost limit, the owner may </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of relationship to Federal cost limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination of relationship to Federal cost limits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on action pursuant to Federal cost limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations on action pursuant to Federal cost limits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>