<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4111"><akn:num>4111</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory sale for housing exceeding Federal cost limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4111. Mandatory sale for housing exceeding Federal cost limits(a) In generalWith respect to any eligible low-income housing for which the aggregate preservation rents determined under section 4104(b) of this title exceed the Federal cost limit, the owner shall offer the housing for sale to qualified purchasers as provided in this section.


(b) Right of first refusal to priority purchasers(1) Duration and required saleFor the 12-month period beginning upon the receipt by the Secretary of the second notice of intent under section 4106(d) of this title with respect to such housing, the owner of the housing may offer to sell and may sell the housing only to priority purchasers. If, during such period, a priority purchaser makes a bona fide offer to purchase the housing for a sale price not less than the preservation value of the housing determined under section 4103(b)(2) of this title, the Secretary shall require the owner to sell the housing pursuant to such offer.


(2) Expression of interestDuring the period under paragraph (1), priority purchasers shall have the opportunity to submit written notice to the owner and the Secretary stating their interest in acquiring the housing. Such written notice shall be in such form and include such information as the Secretary may prescribe.


(3) Information from SecretaryNot later than 30 days after receipt of any notice under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall provide such purchaser with information on the assistance available from the Federal Government to facilitate a transfer and the owner shall provide such purchaser with appropriate information on the housing, as determined by the Secretary.



(c) Right of refusal for other qualified purchasersIf no bona fide offer to purchase any eligible low-income housing subject to this section that meets the requirements of subsection (b) is made during the period under such subsection, during the 3-month period beginning upon the expiration of the 12-month period under subsecti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general With respect to any eligible low-income housing for which the aggregate preservation rents determined under section 4104(b) of this title exceed the Federal cost limit, the owner shall offer the housing for sale to qualified purchasers as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of first refusal to priority purchasers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Right of first refusal to priority purchasers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4111_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of refusal for other qualified purchasers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Right of refusal for other qualified purchasers If no bona fide offer to purchase any eligible low-income housing subject to this section that meets the requirements of subsection (b) is made during the period under such subsection, during the 3-month period beginning upon the expiration of the 12-month period under subsection (b)(1), the owner of the housing may offer to sell and may sell the housing only to qualified purchasers. If, during such period, a qualified purchaser makes a bona fide offer to purchase the housing for a sale price not less than the preservation value of the housing determined under section 4103(b)(2) of this title, the Secretary shall require the owner to sell the housing pursuant to such offer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4111_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>