<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4113"><akn:num>4113</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance for displaced tenants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4113. Assistance for displaced tenants(a) Section 1437f assistanceEach low-income family that is displaced as a result of the prepayment of the mortgage or voluntary termination of an insurance contract on eligible low income housing shall, subject to the availability or 11 So in original. Probably should be “of”. amounts provided under appropriations Acts, receive tenant-based assistance under section 1437f of title 42. To the extent sufficient amounts are made available under appropriations Acts, in each fiscal year the Secretary shall reserve from amounts made available under section 4124(a) of this title or, if necessary, under section 1437c(c) of title 42, such amounts as the Secretary determines are necessary to provide assistance payments for low-income families displaced during the fiscal year.


(b) Relocation assistanceThe Secretary shall coordinate with public housing agencies to ensure that any very low- or low-income family displaced from eligible low-income housing as the result of the prepayment of the mortgage (or termination of the mortgage insurance contract) on such housing is able to acquire a suitable, affordable dwelling unit in the area of the housing from which the family is displaced. The Secretary shall require the owner of such housing to pay 50 percent of the moving expenses of each family relocated, except that such percentage shall be increased to the extent that State or local law of general applicability requires a higher payment by the owner.


(c) Continued occupancy(1) In generalEach owner that prepays the mortgage (or terminates the mortgage insurance contract) on eligible low-income housing shall, as provided in paragraph (3), allow the tenants occupying units in such housing on the date of the submission of notice of intent under section 4102 of this title to remain in the housing for a period of 3 years, at rent levels (except for increases necessary for increased operating costs) existing at the time of prepayment.


(2) Pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section 1437f assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Section 1437f assistance Each low-income family that is displaced as a result of the prepayment of the mortgage or voluntary termination of an insurance contract on eligible low income housing shall, subject to the availability or 11 So in original. Probably should be “of”. amounts provided under appropriations Acts, receive tenant-based assistance under section 1437f of title 42. To the extent sufficient amounts are made available under appropriations Acts, in each fiscal year the Secretary shall reserve from amounts made available under section 4124(a) of this title or, if necessary, under section 1437c(c) of title 42, such amounts as the Secretary determines are necessary to provide assistance payments for low-income families displaced during the fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relocation assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relocation assistance The Secretary shall coordinate with public housing agencies to ensure that any very low- or low-income family displaced from eligible low-income housing as the result of the prepayment of the mortgage (or termination of the mortgage insurance contract) on such housing is able to acquire a suitable, affordable dwelling unit in the area of the housing from which the family is displaced. The Secretary shall require the owner of such housing to pay 50 percent of the moving expenses of each family relocated, except that such percentage shall be increased to the extent that State or local law of general applicability requires a higher payment by the owner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued occupancy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Continued occupancy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required acceptance of section 1437f assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Required acceptance of section 1437f assistance An owner who prepays the mortgage (or terminates the mortgage insurance contract) on eligible low-income housing and maintains the housing for residential rental occupancy may not refuse to rent, refuse to negotiate for the rental of, or otherwise make unavailable or deny the rent of a dwelling unit in such property to any person, or discriminate against any person in the terms, conditions, or privileges of rental of a dwelling (or in the provision of services or facilities in connection therewith), because the person receives assistance under section 1437f of title 42.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional pools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regional pools In providing assistance under this section, the Secretary shall allocate the assistance on a regional basis through the regional offices of the Department of Housing and Urban Development. The Secretary shall allocate assistance under this section in a manner so that the total number of assisted units in each such region available for occupancy by, and affordable to, lower income families and persons does not decrease because of the prepayment or payment of a mortgage on eligible low-income housing or the termination of an insurance contract on such housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced voucher assistance for certain tenants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Enhanced voucher assistance for certain tenants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>