<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4143" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4143/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4143/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4143"><akn:num>4143</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for building resident capacity and funding predevelopment costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4143. Grants for building resident capacity and funding predevelopment costs(a) In generalAssistance made available under this section shall be used for direct assistance grants to resident organizations and community-based nonprofit housing developers and resident councils to assist the acquisition of specific projects (including the payment of reasonable administrative expenses to participating intermediaries).


(b) Allocation30 percent of the assistance made available under this section shall be used for resident capacity grants in accordance with subsection (d). The remainder shall be used for predevelopment grants in connection with specific projects in accordance with subsection (e).


(c) Limitation on grant amountsA resident capacity grant under subsection (d) may not exceed $30,000 per project and a grant under subsection (e) for predevelopment costs may not exceed $200,000 per project, exclusive of any fees paid to a participating intermediary by the Secretary for administering the program.


(d) Resident capacity grants(1) UseResident capacity grants under this subsection shall be available to eligible applicants to cover expenses for resident outreach, incorporation of a resident organization or council, conducting democratic elections, training, leadership development, legal and other technical assistance to the board of directors, staff and members of the resident organization or council.


(2) Eligible housingGrants under this subsection may be provided with respect to eligible low-income housing for which the owner has filed a notice of intent under subchapter I of this chapter or title II of the Emergency Low Income Housing Preservation Act of 1987 (pursuant to section 604 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act).



(e) Predevelopment grants(1) UsePredevelopment grants under this subsection shall be made available to community-based nonprofit housing developers and resident councils to cover the cost of organizing a purchasing e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4143_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Assistance made available under this section shall be used for direct assistance grants to resident organizations and community-based nonprofit housing developers and resident councils to assist the acquisition of specific projects (including the payment of reasonable administrative expenses to participating intermediaries).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4143_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocation 30 percent of the assistance made available under this section shall be used for resident capacity grants in accordance with subsection (d). The remainder shall be used for predevelopment grants in connection with specific projects in accordance with subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4143_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on grant amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on grant amounts A resident capacity grant under subsection (d) may not exceed $30,000 per project and a grant under subsection (e) for predevelopment costs may not exceed $200,000 per project, exclusive of any fees paid to a participating intermediary by the Secretary for administering the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4143_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resident capacity grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Resident capacity grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4143_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Predevelopment grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Predevelopment grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4143_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grant applications Grant applications for assistance under subsections (d) and (e) shall be received monthly on a rolling basis and approved or rejected on at least a quarterly basis by intermediaries selected under section 4145(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4143_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Appeal If an application for assistance under subsections 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (d) or (e) is denied, the applicant shall have the right to appeal the denial to the Secretary and receive a binding determination within 30 days of the appeal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>