<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4145" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4145/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4145/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4145"><akn:num>4145</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of assistance through intermediaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4145. Delivery of assistance through intermediaries(a) In generalThe Secretary shall approve and disburse assistance under section 4143 of this title through eligible intermediaries selected by the Secretary under subsection (b). If the Secretary does not receive an acceptable proposal from an intermediary offering to administer assistance under this section in a given State, the Secretary shall administer the program in such State directly.


(b) Selection of eligible intermediaries(1) In generalThe Secretary shall develop criteria to select eligible intermediaries, through a competitive process, to administer assistance under this subchapter. The process shall include provision for a reasonable administrative fee.


(2) PriorityWith respect to all forms of grants available under section 4143 of this title, such criteria shall give priority to applications from eligible intermediaries with demonstrated expertise or experience with the program established under this title 11 See References in Text note below. or under the Emergency Low Income Housing Preservation Act of 1987.


(3) CriteriaThe criteria developed under this subsection shall—(A) not assign any preference or priority to applications from eligible intermediaries based on their previous participation in administering or receiving Federal grants or loans (but may exclude applicants who have failed to perform under prior contracts of a similar nature);

(B) require an applicant to prepare a proposal that demonstrates adequate staffing, qualifications, prior experience, and a plan for participation; and

(C) permit an applicant to serve as the administrator of assistance made available under section 4143(d) or (e) of this title, based on the applicant’s suitability and interest.


(4) Geographic coverageThe Secretary may select more than 1 State or regional intermediary for a single State or region. The number of intermediaries chosen for each State or region may be based on the number of eligible low-inc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4145_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall approve and disburse assistance under section 4143 of this title through eligible intermediaries selected by the Secretary under subsection (b). If the Secretary does not receive an acceptable proposal from an intermediary offering to administer assistance under this section in a given State, the Secretary shall administer the program in such State directly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4145_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of eligible intermediaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection of eligible intermediaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4145_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflicts of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Conflicts of interest Eligible intermediaries selected under subsection (b) to disburse assistance under section 4143 of this title shall certify that they will serve only as delegated program administrators, charged with the responsibility for reviewing and approving grant applications on behalf of the Secretary. Selected intermediaries shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4145_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Eligible intermediary” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Eligible intermediary” defined For purposes of this section, the term “eligible intermediary” means a State, regional, or national organization (including a quasi-public organization) or a State or local housing agency that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>