<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4403" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4403/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4403/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4403"><akn:num>4403</akn:num><akn:heading>Bilateral netting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4403. Bilateral netting(a) General ruleNotwithstanding any other provision of State or Federal law (other than section 1821(e) of this title, section 5390(c) of this title, section 4617 of this title, section 1787(c) of this title, or any order authorized under section 78eee(b)(2) of title 15), the covered contractual payment obligations and the covered contractual payment entitlements between any 2 financial institutions shall be terminated, liquidated, accelerated, and netted in accordance with, and subject to the conditions of, the terms of any applicable netting contract (except as provided in section 561(b)(2) of title 11).


(b) Limitation on obligation to make paymentThe only obligation, if any, of a financial institution to make payment with respect to covered contractual payment obligations to another financial institution shall be equal to its net obligation to such other financial institution, and no such obligation shall exist if there is no net obligation.


(c) Limitation on right to receive paymentThe only right, if any, of a financial institution to receive payments with respect to covered contractual payment entitlements from another financial institution shall be equal to its net entitlement with respect to such other financial institution, and no such right shall exist if there is no net entitlement.


(d) Payment of net entitlement of failed financial institutionThe net entitlement of any failed financial institution, if any, shall be paid to the failed financial institution in accordance with, and subject to the conditions of, the applicable netting contract.


(e) Effectiveness notwithstanding status as financial institutionThis section shall be given effect notwithstanding that a financial institution is a failed financial institution.


(f) Enforceability of security agreementsThe provisions of any security agreement or arrangement or other credit enhancement related to one or more netting contracts between any 2 financial institutions shal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4403_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Notwithstanding any other provision of State or Federal law (other than section 1821(e) of this title, section 5390(c) of this title, section 4617 of this title, section 1787(c) of this title, or any order authorized under section 78eee(b)(2) of title 15), the covered contractual payment obligations and the covered contractual payment entitlements between any 2 financial institutions shall be terminated, liquidated, accelerated, and netted in accordance with, and subject to the conditions of, the terms of any applicable netting contract (except as provided in section 561(b)(2) of title 11).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4403_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on obligation to make payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on obligation to make payment The only obligation, if any, of a financial institution to make payment with respect to covered contractual payment obligations to another financial institution shall be equal to its net obligation to such other financial institution, and no such obligation shall exist if there is no net obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4403_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on right to receive payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on right to receive payment The only right, if any, of a financial institution to receive payments with respect to covered contractual payment entitlements from another financial institution shall be equal to its net entitlement with respect to such other financial institution, and no such right shall exist if there is no net entitlement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4403_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of net entitlement of failed financial institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment of net entitlement of failed financial institution The net entitlement of any failed financial institution, if any, shall be paid to the failed financial institution in accordance with, and subject to the conditions of, the applicable netting contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4403_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effectiveness notwithstanding status as financial institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effectiveness notwithstanding status as financial institution This section shall be given effect notwithstanding that a financial institution is a failed financial institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4403_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforceability of security agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Enforceability of security agreements The provisions of any security agreement or arrangement or other credit enhancement related to one or more netting contracts between any 2 financial institutions shall be enforceable in accordance with their terms (except as provided in section 561(b)(2) of title 11), and shall not be stayed, avoided, or otherwise limited by any State or Federal law (other than section 1821(e) of this title, section 1787(c) of this title, and section 78eee(b)(2) of title 15).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>