<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4404" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4404/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4404/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4404"><akn:num>4404</akn:num><akn:heading>Clearing organization netting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4404. Clearing organization netting(a) General ruleNotwithstanding any other provision of State or Federal law (other than section 1821(e) of this title, section 1787(c) of this title, and any order authorized under section 78eee(b)(2) of title 15), the covered contractual payment obligations and the covered contractual payment entitlements of a member of a clearing organization to and from all other members of a clearing organization shall be terminated, liquidated, accelerated, and netted in accordance with and subject to the conditions of any applicable netting contract (except as provided in section 561(b)(2) of title 11).


(b) Limitation of obligation to make paymentThe only obligation, if any, of a member of a clearing organization to make payment with respect to covered contractual payment obligations arising under a single netting contract to any other member of a clearing organization shall be equal to its net obligation arising under that netting contract, and no such obligation shall exist if there is no net obligation.


(c) Limitation on right to receive paymentThe only right, if any, of a member of a clearing organization to receive payment with respect to a covered contractual payment entitlement arising under a single netting contract from other members of a clearing organization shall be equal to its net entitlement arising under that netting contract, and no such right shall exist if there is no net entitlement.


(d) Entitlement of failed membersThe net entitlement, if any, of any failed member of a clearing organization shall be paid to the failed member in accordance with, and subject to the conditions of, the applicable netting contract.


(e) Obligations of failed membersThe net obligation, if any, of any failed member of a clearing organization shall be determined in accordance with, and subject to the conditions of, the applicable netting contract.


(f) Limitation on claims for entitlementA failed member of a clearing organization shall </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4404_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Notwithstanding any other provision of State or Federal law (other than section 1821(e) of this title, section 1787(c) of this title, and any order authorized under section 78eee(b)(2) of title 15), the covered contractual payment obligations and the covered contractual payment entitlements of a member of a clearing organization to and from all other members of a clearing organization shall be terminated, liquidated, accelerated, and netted in accordance with and subject to the conditions of any applicable netting contract (except as provided in section 561(b)(2) of title 11).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4404_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of obligation to make payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation of obligation to make payment The only obligation, if any, of a member of a clearing organization to make payment with respect to covered contractual payment obligations arising under a single netting contract to any other member of a clearing organization shall be equal to its net obligation arising under that netting contract, and no such obligation shall exist if there is no net obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4404_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on right to receive payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on right to receive payment The only right, if any, of a member of a clearing organization to receive payment with respect to a covered contractual payment entitlement arising under a single netting contract from other members of a clearing organization shall be equal to its net entitlement arising under that netting contract, and no such right shall exist if there is no net entitlement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4404_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement of failed members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Entitlement of failed members The net entitlement, if any, of any failed member of a clearing organization shall be paid to the failed member in accordance with, and subject to the conditions of, the applicable netting contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4404_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligations of failed members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Obligations of failed members The net obligation, if any, of any failed member of a clearing organization shall be determined in accordance with, and subject to the conditions of, the applicable netting contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4404_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on claims for entitlement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on claims for entitlement A failed member of a clearing organization shall have no recognizable claim against any member of a clearing organization for any amount based on such covered contractual payment entitlements other than its net entitlement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4404_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effectiveness notwithstanding status as member</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effectiveness notwithstanding status as member This section shall be given effect notwithstanding that a member is a failed member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4404_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforceability of security agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Enforceability of security agreements The provisions of any security agreement or arrangement or other credit enhancement related to one or more netting contracts between any 2 members of a clearing organization shall be enforceable in accordance with their terms (except as provided in section 561(b)(2) of title 11), and shall not be stayed, avoided, or otherwise limited by any State or Federal law (other than section 1821(e) of this title, section 1787(c) of this title, and section 78eee(b)(2) of title 15).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>