<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4512" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4512/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4512/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4512"><akn:num>4512</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4512. Director(a) Establishment of positionThere is established the position of the Director of the Agency, who shall be the head of the Agency.


(b) Appointment; term(1) AppointmentThe Director shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from among individuals who are citizens of the United States, have a demonstrated understanding of financial management or oversight, and have a demonstrated understanding of capital markets, including the mortgage securities markets and housing finance.


(2) TermThe Director shall be appointed for a term of 5 years, unless removed before the end of such term for cause by the President.


(3) VacancyA vacancy in the position of Director that occurs before the expiration of the term for which a Director was appointed shall be filled in the manner established under paragraph (1), and the Director appointed to fill such vacancy shall be appointed only for the remainder of such term.


(4) Service after end of termAn individual may serve as the Director after the expiration of the term for which appointed until a successor has been appointed.


(5) Transitional provisionNotwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), during the period beginning on the effective date of the Federal Housing Finance Regulatory Reform Act of 2008, and ending on the date on which the Director is appointed and confirmed, the person serving as the Director of the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight of the Department of Housing and Urban Development on that effective date shall act for all purposes as, and with the full powers of, the Director.



(c) Deputy Director of the Division of Enterprise Regulation(1) In generalThe Agency shall have a Deputy Director of the Division of Enterprise Regulation, who shall be designated by the Director from among individuals who are citizens of the United States, have a demonstrated understanding of financial management or oversight, and have a demonstrated understanding of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4512_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of position</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of position There is established the position of the Director of the Agency, who shall be the head of the Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4512_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment; term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment; term</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4512_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Director of the Division of Enterprise Regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deputy Director of the Division of Enterprise Regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4512_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Director of the Division of Federal Home Loan Bank Regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deputy Director of the Division of Federal Home Loan Bank Regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4512_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Director for Housing Mission and Goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deputy Director for Housing Mission and Goals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4512_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acting Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Acting Director In the event of the death, resignation, sickness, or absence of the Director, the President shall designate either the Deputy Director of the Division of Enterprise Regulation, the Deputy Director of the Division of Federal Home Loan Bank Regulation, or the Deputy Director for Housing Mission and Goals, to serve as acting Director until the return of the Director, or the appointment of a successor pursuant to subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4512_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitations The Director and each of the Deputy Directors may not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>