<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4513a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4513a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4513a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4513a"><akn:num>4513a</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Housing Finance Oversight Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4513a. Federal Housing Finance Oversight Board(a) In generalThere is established the Federal Housing Finance Oversight Board, which shall advise the Director with respect to overall strategies and policies in carrying out the duties of the Director under this chapter.


(b) LimitationsThe Board may not exercise any executive authority, and the Director may not delegate to the Board any of the functions, powers, or duties of the Director.


(c) CompositionThe Board shall be comprised of 4 members, of whom—(1) 1 member shall be the Secretary of the Treasury;

(2) 1 member shall be the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development;

(3) 1 member shall be the Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission; and

(4) 1 member shall be the Director, who shall serve as the Chairperson of the Board.


(d) Meetings(1) In generalThe Board shall meet upon notice by the Director, but in no event shall the Board meet less frequently than once every 3 months.


(2) Special meetingsEither the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, or the Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission may, upon giving written notice to the Director, require a special meeting of the Board.



(e) TestimonyOn an annual basis, the Board shall testify before Congress regarding—(1) the safety and soundness of the regulated entities;

(2) any material deficiencies in the conduct of the operations of the regulated entities;

(3) the overall operational status of the regulated entities;

(4) an evaluation of the performance of the regulated entities in carrying out their respective missions;

(5) operations, resources, and performance of the Agency; and

(6) such other matters relating to the Agency and its fulfillment of its mission, as the Board determines appropriate.


(Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1313A, as added Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title I, § 1103(a), July 30, 2008, 122 Stat. 2665.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subse</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4513a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established the Federal Housing Finance Oversight Board, which shall advise the Director with respect to overall strategies and policies in carrying out the duties of the Director under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4513a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations The Board may not exercise any executive authority, and the Director may not delegate to the Board any of the functions, powers, or duties of the Director.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4513a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Composition The Board shall be comprised of 4 members, of whom—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4513a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Meetings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4513a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testimony</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Testimony On an annual basis, the Board shall testify before Congress regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>