<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4515" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4515/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4515/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4515"><akn:num>4515</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4515. Personnel(a) In generalSubject to title III of the Federal Housing Finance Regulatory Reform Act of 2008, the Director may appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees of the Agency as the Director considers necessary to carry out the functions of the Director and the Agency. Officers and employees may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.


(b) Comparability of compensation with Federal banking agenciesIn fixing and directing compensation under subsection (a), the Director shall consult with, and maintain comparability with compensation of officers and employees of the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.


(c) Personnel of other Federal agenciesIn carrying out the duties of the Agency, the Director may use information, services, staff, and facilities of any executive agency, independent agency, or department on a reimbursable basis, with the consent of such agency or department.


(d) Outside experts and consultantsNotwithstanding any provision of law limiting pay or compensation, the Director may appoint and compensate such outside experts and consultants as the Director determines necessary to assist the work of the Agency.


(Pub. L. 102–550, title XIII, § 1315, Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 3947; Pub. L. 110–289, div. A, title I, § 1161(a)(1), July 30, 2008, 122 Stat. 2778; Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 365(1), July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 1555.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Housing Finance Regulatory Reform Act of 2008, referred to in subsec. (a), is div. A of Pub. L. 110–289, July 30, 2008, 122 Stat. 2659. Title III of div. A of the Pub. L. 110–289 is set out as a note under section 4511 of this title. For complete classification of Pub. L. 110–289 to the Code, see Short Title note under section 450</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4515_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to title III of the Federal Housing Finance Regulatory Reform Act of 2008, the Director may appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees of the Agency as the Director considers necessary to carry out the functions of the Director and the Agency. Officers and employees may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4515_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comparability of compensation with Federal banking agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Comparability of compensation with Federal banking agencies In fixing and directing compensation under subsection (a), the Director shall consult with, and maintain comparability with compensation of officers and employees of the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4515_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel of other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Personnel of other Federal agencies In carrying out the duties of the Agency, the Director may use information, services, staff, and facilities of any executive agency, independent agency, or department on a reimbursable basis, with the consent of such agency or department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4515_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outside experts and consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Outside experts and consultants Notwithstanding any provision of law limiting pay or compensation, the Director may appoint and compensate such outside experts and consultants as the Director determines necessary to assist the work of the Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>