<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4516" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4516/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4516/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4516"><akn:num>4516</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4516. Funding(a) Annual assessmentsThe Director shall establish and collect from the regulated entities annual assessments in an amount not exceeding the amount sufficient to provide for reasonable costs (including administrative costs) and expenses of the Agency, including—(1) the expenses of any examinations under section 4517 of this title and under section 1440 of this title;

(2) the expenses of obtaining any reviews and credit assessments under section 4519 of this title;

(3) such amounts in excess of actual expenses for any given year as deemed necessary by the Director to maintain a working capital fund in accordance with subsection (e); and

(4) the windup of the affairs of the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight and the Federal Housing Finance Board under title III of the Federal Housing Finance Regulatory Reform Act of 2008.


(b) Allocation of annual assessment to enterprises(1) Amount of paymentEach enterprise shall pay to the Director a proportion of the annual assessment made pursuant to subsection (a) that bears the same ratio to the total annual assessment that the total assets of each enterprise bears 11 So in original. Probably should be “bear”. to the total assets of both enterprises.


(2) Separate treatment of Federal home loan bank and enterprise assessmentsAssessments collected from the enterprises shall not exceed the amounts sufficient to provide for the costs and expenses described in subsection (a) relating to the enterprises. Assessments collected from the Federal Home Loan Banks shall not exceed the amounts sufficient to provide for the costs and expenses described in subsection (a) relating to the Federal Home Loan Banks.


(3) Timing of paymentThe annual assessment shall be payable semiannually for each fiscal year, on October 1 and April 1.


(4) “Total assets” definedFor the purpose of this section, the term “total assets” means, with respect to an enterprise, the sum of—(A) on-balance-sheet assets of the enterprise, a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4516_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual assessments The Director shall establish and collect from the regulated entities annual assessments in an amount not exceeding the amount sufficient to provide for reasonable costs (including administrative costs) and expenses of the Agency, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4516_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of annual assessment to enterprises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocation of annual assessment to enterprises</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4516_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased costs of regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Increased costs of regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4516_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surplus</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Surplus Except with respect to amounts collected pursuant to subsection (a)(3), if any amount from any annual assessment collected from an enterprise remains unobligated at the end of the year for which the assessment was collected, such amount shall be credited to the assessment to be collected from the enterprise for the following year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4516_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Working capital fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Working capital fund At the end of each year for which an assessment under this section is made, the Director shall remit to each regulated entity any amount of assessment collected from such regulated entity that is attributable to subsection (a)(3) and is in excess of the amount the Director deems necessary to maintain a working capital fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4516_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4516_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget and financial management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Budget and financial management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4516_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit of Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Audit of Agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>