<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4518" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4518/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4518/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4518"><akn:num>4518</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition and withholding of executive compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4518. Prohibition and withholding of executive compensation(a) In generalThe Director shall prohibit the regulated entities from providing compensation to any executive officer of the regulated entity that is not reasonable and comparable with compensation for employment in other similar businesses (including other publicly held financial institutions or major financial services companies) involving similar duties and responsibilities.


(b) FactorsIn making any determination under subsection (a), the Director may take into consideration any factors the Director considers relevant, including any wrongdoing on the part of the executive officer, and such wrongdoing shall include any fraudulent act or omission, breach of trust or fiduciary duty, violation of law, rule, regulation, order, or written agreement, and insider abuse with respect to the regulated entity. The approval of an agreement or contract pursuant to section 1723a(d)(3)(B) of this title or section 1452(h)(2) of this title shall not preclude the Director from making any subsequent determination under subsection (a).


(c) Withholding of compensationIn carrying out subsection (a), the Director may require a regulated entity to withhold any payment, transfer, or disbursement of compensation to an executive officer, or to place such compensation in an escrow account, during the review of the reasonableness and comparability of compensation.


(d) Prohibition of setting compensationIn carrying out subsection (a), the Director may not prescribe or set a specific level or range of compensation.


(e) Authority to regulate or prohibit certain forms of benefits to affiliated parties(1) Golden parachutes and indemnification paymentsThe Director may prohibit or limit, by regulation or order, any golden parachute payment or indemnification payment.


(2) Factors to be taken into accountThe Director shall prescribe, by regulation, the factors to be considered by the Director in taking any action pursuant to paragr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4518_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director shall prohibit the regulated entities from providing compensation to any executive officer of the regulated entity that is not reasonable and comparable with compensation for employment in other similar businesses (including other publicly held financial institutions or major financial services companies) involving similar duties and responsibilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4518_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Factors In making any determination under subsection (a), the Director may take into consideration any factors the Director considers relevant, including any wrongdoing on the part of the executive officer, and such wrongdoing shall include any fraudulent act or omission, breach of trust or fiduciary duty, violation of law, rule, regulation, order, or written agreement, and insider abuse with respect to the regulated entity. The approval of an agreement or contract pursuant to section 1723a(d)(3)(B) of this title or section 1452(h)(2) of this title shall not preclude the Director from making any subsequent determination under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4518_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding of compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Withholding of compensation In carrying out subsection (a), the Director may require a regulated entity to withhold any payment, transfer, or disbursement of compensation to an executive officer, or to place such compensation in an escrow account, during the review of the reasonableness and comparability of compensation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4518_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of setting compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition of setting compensation In carrying out subsection (a), the Director may not prescribe or set a specific level or range of compensation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4518_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to regulate or prohibit certain forms of benefits to affiliated parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authority to regulate or prohibit certain forms of benefits to affiliated parties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>