<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4541" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4541/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4541/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4541"><akn:num>4541</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior approval authority for products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4541. Prior approval authority for products(a) In generalThe Director shall require each enterprise to obtain the approval of the Director for any product of the enterprise before initially offering the product.


(b) Standard for approvalIn considering any request for approval of a product pursuant to subsection (a), the Director shall make a determination that—(1) in the case of a product of the Federal National Mortgage Association, the product is authorized under paragraph (2), (3), (4), or (5) of section 1717(b) or section 1719 of this title;

(2) in the case of a product of the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, the product is authorized under paragraph (1), (4), or (5) of section 1454(a) of this title;

(3) the product is in the public interest; and

(4) the product is consistent with the safety and soundness of the enterprise or the mortgage finance system.


(c) Procedure for approval(1) Submission of requestAn enterprise shall submit to the Director a written request for approval of a product that describes the product in such form as prescribed by order or regulation of the Director.


(2) Request for public commentImmediately upon receipt of a request for approval of a product, as required under paragraph (1), the Director shall publish notice of such request and of the period for public comment pursuant to paragraph (3) regarding the product, and a description of the product proposed by the request. The Director shall give interested parties the opportunity to respond in writing to the proposed product.


(3) Public comment periodDuring the 30-day period beginning on the date of publication pursuant to paragraph (2) of a request for approval of a product, the Director shall receive public comments regarding the proposed product.


(4) Offering of product(A) In generalNot later than 30 days after the close of the public comment period described in paragraph (3), the Director shall approve or deny the product, specifying the grounds for such decisi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4541_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director shall require each enterprise to obtain the approval of the Director for any product of the enterprise before initially offering the product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4541_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard for approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standard for approval In considering any request for approval of a product pursuant to subsection (a), the Director shall make a determination that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4541_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Procedure for approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4541_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditional approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conditional approval If the Director approves the offering of any product by an enterprise, the Director may establish terms, conditions, or limitations with respect to such product with which the enterprise must comply in order to offer such product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4541_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4541_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>No limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No limitation Nothing in this section may be construed to restrict—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>