<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4547" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4547/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4547/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4547"><akn:num>4547</akn:num><akn:heading>Enterprise guarantee fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4547. Enterprise guarantee fees(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Guarantee feeThe term “guarantee fee”—(A) means a fee described in subsection (b); and

(B) includes—(i) the guaranty fee charged by the Federal National Mortgage Association with respect to mortgage-backed securities; and

(ii) the management and guarantee fee charged by the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation with respect to participation certificates.



(2) Average feesThe term “average fees” means the average contractual fee rate of single-family guaranty arrangements by an enterprise entered into during 2011, plus the recognition of any up-front cash payments over an estimated average life, expressed in terms of basis points. Such definition shall be interpreted in a manner consistent with the annual report on guarantee fees by the Federal Housing Finance Agency.



(b) Increase(1) In general(A) Phased increase requiredSubject to subsection (c), the Director shall require each enterprise to charge a guarantee fee in connection with any guarantee of the timely payment of principal and interest on securities, notes, and other obligations based on or backed by mortgages on residential real properties designed principally for occupancy of from 1 to 4 families, consummated after December 23, 2011.


(B) AmountThe amount of the increase required under this section shall be determined by the Director to appropriately reflect the risk of loss, as well 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “as”. the cost of capital allocated to similar assets held by other fully private regulated financial institutions, but such amount shall be not less than an average increase of 10 basis points for each origination year or book year above the average fees imposed in 2011 for such guarantees. The Director shall prohibit an enterprise from offsetting the cost of the fee to mortgage originators, borrowers, and investors by decreasing other charges, fees,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4547_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4547_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increase</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Increase</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4547_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase-in</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Phase-in</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4547_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information collection and annual analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information collection and annual analysis The Director shall require each enterprise to provide to the Director, as part of its annual report submitted to Congress—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4547_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4547_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expiration The provisions of this section shall expire on October 1, 2032.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>