<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4561" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4561/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4561/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4561"><akn:num>4561</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of housing goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4561. Establishment of housing goals(a) In generalThe Director shall, by regulation, establish effective for 2010 and each year thereafter, annual housing goals, with respect to the mortgage purchases by the enterprises, as follows:(1) Single-family housing goalsFour single-family housing goals under section 4562 of this title.


(2) Multifamily special affordable housing goalOne multifamily special affordable housing goal under section 4563 of this title.



(b) TimingThe Director shall, by regulation, establish an annual deadline by which the Director shall establish the annual housing goals under this subpart for each year, taking into consideration the need for the enterprises to reasonably and sufficiently plan their operations and activities in advance, including operations and activities necessary to meet such annual goals.


(c) TransitionThe annual housing goals effective for 2008 pursuant to this subpart, as in effect before July 30, 2008, shall remain in effect for 2009, except that not later than the expiration of the 270-day period beginning on July 30, 2008, the Director shall review such goals applicable for 2009 to determine the feasibility of such goals given the market conditions current at such time and, after seeking public comment for a period not to exceed 30 days, may make appropriate adjustments consistent with such market conditions.


(d) Eliminating interest rate disparities(1) In generalUpon request by the Director, an enterprise shall provide to the Director, in a form determined by the Director, data the Director may review to determine whether there exist disparities in interest rates charged on mortgages to borrowers who are minorities as compared with comparable mortgages to borrowers of similar creditworthiness who are not minorities.


(2) Remedial actions upon preliminary findingUpon a preliminary finding by the Director that a pattern of disparities in interest rates with respect to any lender or lenders exists pursuant to the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4561_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director shall, by regulation, establish effective for 2010 and each year thereafter, annual housing goals, with respect to the mortgage purchases by the enterprises, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4561_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Timing The Director shall, by regulation, establish an annual deadline by which the Director shall establish the annual housing goals under this subpart for each year, taking into consideration the need for the enterprises to reasonably and sufficiently plan their operations and activities in advance, including operations and activities necessary to meet such annual goals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4561_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transition The annual housing goals effective for 2008 pursuant to this subpart, as in effect before July 30, 2008, shall remain in effect for 2009, except that not later than the expiration of the 270-day period beginning on July 30, 2008, the Director shall review such goals applicable for 2009 to determine the feasibility of such goals given the market conditions current at such time and, after seeking public comment for a period not to exceed 30 days, may make appropriate adjustments consistent with such market conditions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4561_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eliminating interest rate disparities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eliminating interest rate disparities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>