<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4562" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4562/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4562/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4562"><akn:num>4562</akn:num><akn:heading>Single-family housing goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4562. Single-family housing goals(a) In generalThe Director shall, by regulation, establish annual goals for the purchase by each enterprise of the following types of mortgages for the following categories of families:(1) Purchase-money mortgagesA goal for purchase of conventional, conforming, single-family, purchase money mortgages financing owner-occupied housing for each of the following categories of families:(A) Low-income families.

(B) Families that reside in low-income areas.

(C) Very low-income families.


(2) Refinancing mortgagesA goal for purchase of conventional, conforming mortgages on owner-occupied, single-family housing for low-income families that are given to pay off or prepay an existing loan secured by the same property.



(b) Goals as a percentage of total mortgage purchasesThe goals established under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) shall be established as a percentage of the total number of conventional, conforming, single-family, owner-occupied, purchase money mortgages purchased by the enterprise, or as percentage of the total number of conventional, single-family, owner-occupied refinance mortgages purchased by the enterprise, as applicable, that are mortgages for the types of families specified in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).


(c) Single-family, owner-occupied rental housing unitsThe Director shall require each enterprise to report the number of rental housing units affordable to low-income families each year which are contained in mortgages purchased by the enterprise financing 2- to 4-unit single-family, owner-occupied properties and may, by regulation, establish additional requirements relating to such units.


(d) Determination of compliance(1) In generalThe Director shall determine, for each year that the housing goals under this section are in effect pursuant to section 4561(a) of this title, whether each enterprise has complied with each such goal established under subsection (a) of this section and any ad</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4562_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director shall, by regulation, establish annual goals for the purchase by each enterprise of the following types of mortgages for the following categories of families:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4562_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals as a percentage of total mortgage purchases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Goals as a percentage of total mortgage purchases The goals established under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) shall be established as a percentage of the total number of conventional, conforming, single-family, owner-occupied, purchase money mortgages purchased by the enterprise, or as percentage of the total number of conventional, single-family, owner-occupied refinance mortgages purchased by the enterprise, as applicable, that are mortgages for the types of families specified in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4562_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Single-family, owner-occupied rental housing units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Single-family, owner-occupied rental housing units The Director shall require each enterprise to report the number of rental housing units affordable to low-income families each year which are contained in mortgages purchased by the enterprise financing 2- to 4-unit single-family, owner-occupied properties and may, by regulation, establish additional requirements relating to such units.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4562_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Determination of compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4562_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual targets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual targets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4562_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of determination and enterprise comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notice of determination and enterprise comment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4562_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of borrower income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Use of borrower income In monitoring the performance of each enterprise pursuant to the housing goals under this section and evaluating such performance (for purposes of section 4566 of this title), the Director shall consider a mortgagor’s income to be such income at the time of origination of the mortgage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4562_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of properties with rental units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Consideration of properties with rental units Mortgages financing two- to four-unit owner-occupied properties shall count toward the achievement of the single-family housing goals under this section, if such properties otherwise meet the requirements under this section, notwithstanding the use of one or more units for rental purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4562_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Goals credit The Director shall determine whether an enterprise shall receive full, partial, or no credit for a transaction toward achievement of any of the housing goals established pursuant to section 4562 and 4563 of this title. In making any such determination, the Director shall consider whether a transaction or activity of an enterprise is substantially equivalent to a mortgage purchase and either (1) creates a new market, or (2) adds liquidity to an existing market. No credit toward the achievement of the housing goals and subgoals established under this section may be given to the purchase of mortgages, including any transaction or activity of an enterprise determined to be substantially equivalent to a mortgage purchase, that is determined to be unacceptable or contrary to good lending practices, inconsistent with safety and soundness, or unauthorized for purchase by the enterprises, pursuant to regulations issued by the Director.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>