<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4565" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4565/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4565/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4565"><akn:num>4565</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty to serve underserved markets and other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4565. Duty to serve underserved markets and other requirements(a) Duty to serve underserved markets(1) 11 So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted. DutyTo increase the liquidity of mortgage investments and improve the distribution of investment capital available for mortgage financing for underserved markets, each enterprise shall provide leadership to the market in developing loan products and flexible underwriting guidelines to facilitate a secondary market for mortgages for very low-, low-, and moderate-income families with respect to the following underserved markets:(A) Manufactured housingThe enterprise shall develop loan products and flexible underwriting guidelines to facilitate a secondary market for mortgages on manufactured homes for very low-, low-, and moderate-income families.


(B) Affordable housing preservationThe enterprise shall develop loan products and flexible underwriting guidelines to facilitate a secondary market to preserve housing affordable to very low-, low-, and moderate-income families, including housing projects subsidized under_22 So in original.(i) the project-based and tenant-based rental assistance programs under section 1437f of title 42;

(ii) the program under section 1715z–1 of this title;

(iii) the below-market interest rate mortgage program under section 1715l(d)(4) of this title;

(iv) the supportive housing for the elderly program under section 1701q of this title;

(v) the supportive housing program for persons with disabilities under section 8013 of title 42;

(vi) the programs under title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act [42 U.S.C. 11360 et seq.], but only permanent supportive housing projects subsidized under such programs;

(vii) the rural rental housing program under section 1485 of title 42;

(viii) the low-income housing tax credit under section 42 of title 26; and

(ix) comparable state 33 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. and local affordable housing programs.


(C) Rural mark</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4565_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty to serve underserved markets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Duty to serve underserved markets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4565_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In general To meet the housing goals established under this subpart and to carry out the duty under subsection (a) of this section, each enterprise shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4565_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional categories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional categories The Director may submit recommendations to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate for the establishment of additional categories under subsection (a), provided that the Director makes a preliminary determination that any such category is important to the mission of the enterprises, that the category is an underserved market, and that the establishment of such category is warranted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4565_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and reporting of compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluation and reporting of compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>