<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4567" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4567/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4567/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4567"><akn:num>4567</akn:num><akn:heading>Affordable housing allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4567. Affordable housing allocations(a) Set aside and allocation of amounts by enterprisesSubject to subsection (b), in each fiscal year—(1) the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation shall—(A) set aside an amount equal to 4.2 basis points for each dollar of the unpaid principal balance of its total new business purchases; and

(B) allocate or otherwise transfer—(i) 65 percent of such amounts to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to fund the Housing Trust Fund established under section 4568 of this title; and

(ii) 35 percent of such amounts to fund the Capital Magnet Fund established pursuant to section 4569 of this title; and



(2) the Federal National Mortgage Association shall—(A) set aside an amount equal to 4.2 basis points for each dollar of unpaid principal balance of its total new business purchases; and

(B) allocate or otherwise transfer—(i) 65 percent of such amounts to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to fund the Housing Trust Fund established under section 4568 of this title; and

(ii) 35 percent of such amounts to fund the Capital Magnet Fund established pursuant to section 4569 of this title.




(b) Suspension of contributionsThe Director shall temporarily suspend allocations under subsection (a) by an enterprise upon a finding by the Director that such allocations—(1) are contributing, or would contribute, to the financial instability of the enterprise;

(2) are causing, or would cause, the enterprise to be classified as undercapitalized; or

(3) are preventing, or would prevent, the enterprise from successfully completing a capital restoration plan under section 4622 of this title.


(c) Prohibition of pass-through of cost of allocationsThe Director shall, by regulation, prohibit each enterprise from redirecting the costs of any allocation required under this section, through increased charges or fees, or decreased premiums, or in any other manner, to the originators of mortgages purchased or securitized by the enterpr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Set aside and allocation of amounts by enterprises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Set aside and allocation of amounts by enterprises Subject to subsection (b), in each fiscal year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Suspension of contributions The Director shall temporarily suspend allocations under subsection (a) by an enterprise upon a finding by the Director that such allocations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of pass-through of cost of allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition of pass-through of cost of allocations The Director shall, by regulation, prohibit each enterprise from redirecting the costs of any allocation required under this section, through increased charges or fees, or decreased premiums, or in any other manner, to the originators of mortgages purchased or securitized by the enterprise.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of requirements on enterprise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement of requirements on enterprise Compliance by the enterprises with the requirements under this section shall be enforceable under subpart 3. Any reference in such subpart to this part or to an order, rule, or regulation under this part specifically includes this section and any order, rule, or regulation under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required amount for HOPE reserve fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Required amount for HOPE reserve fund Of the aggregate amount allocated under subsection (a), 25 percent shall be deposited into a fund established in the Treasury of the United States by the Secretary of the Treasury for such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4567_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation No funds under this chapter may be used in conjunction with property taken by eminent domain, unless eminent domain is employed only for a public use, except that, for purposes of this section, public use shall not be construed to include economic development that primarily benefits any private entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>