<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4569" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4569/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4569/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4569"><akn:num>4569</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital Magnet Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4569. Capital Magnet Fund(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the Capital Magnet Fund, which shall be a special account within the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund.


(b) Deposits to Trust FundThe Capital Magnet Fund shall consist of—(1) any amounts transferred to the Fund pursuant to section 4567 of this title; and

(2) any amounts as are or may be appropriated, transferred, or credited to such Fund under any other provisions of law.


(c) Expenditures from Trust FundAmounts in the Capital Magnet Fund shall be available to the Secretary of the Treasury to carry out a competitive grant program to attract private capital for and increase investment in—(1) the development, preservation, rehabilitation, or purchase of affordable housing for primarily extremely low-, very low-, and low-income families; and

(2) economic development activities or community service facilities, such as day care centers, workforce development centers, and health care clinics, which in conjunction with affordable housing activities implement a concerted strategy to stabilize or revitalize a low-income area or underserved rural area.


(d) Federal assistanceFor purposes of the application of Federal civil rights laws, all assistance provided using amounts in the Capital Magnet Fund shall be considered Federal financial assistance.


(e) Eligible granteesA grant under this section may be made, pursuant to such requirements as the Secretary of the Treasury shall establish for experience and success in attracting private financing and carrying out the types of activities proposed under the application of the grantee, only to—(1) a Treasury certified community development financial institution; or

(2) a nonprofit organization having as 1 of its principal purposes the development or management of affordable housing.


(f) Eligible usesGrant amounts awarded from the Capital Magnet Fund pursuant to this section may</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the Capital Magnet Fund, which shall be a special account within the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits to Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deposits to Trust Fund The Capital Magnet Fund shall consist of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures from Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expenditures from Trust Fund Amounts in the Capital Magnet Fund shall be available to the Secretary of the Treasury to carry out a competitive grant program to attract private capital for and increase investment in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal assistance For purposes of the application of Federal civil rights laws, all assistance provided using amounts in the Capital Magnet Fund shall be considered Federal financial assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible grantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligible grantees A grant under this section may be made, pursuant to such requirements as the Secretary of the Treasury shall establish for experience and success in attracting private financing and carrying out the types of activities proposed under the application of the grantee, only to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligible uses Grant amounts awarded from the Capital Magnet Fund pursuant to this section may be used for the purposes described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c), including for the following uses:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Grant limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Periodic reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4569_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>