<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4617" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4617/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4617/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4617"><akn:num>4617</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority over critically undercapitalized regulated entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4617. Authority over critically undercapitalized regulated entities(a) Appointment of the Agency as conservator or receiver(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of Federal or State law, the Director may appoint the Agency as conservator or receiver for a regulated entity in the manner provided under paragraph (2) or (4). All references to the conservator or receiver under this section are references to the Agency acting as conservator or receiver.


(2) Discretionary appointmentThe Agency may, at the discretion of the Director, be appointed conservator or receiver for the purpose of reorganizing, rehabilitating, or winding up the affairs of a regulated entity.


(3) Grounds for discretionary appointment of conservator or receiverThe grounds for appointing conservator or receiver for any regulated entity under paragraph (2) are as follows:(A) Assets insufficient for obligationsThe assets of the regulated entity are less than the obligations of the regulated entity to its creditors and others.


(B) Substantial dissipationSubstantial dissipation of assets or earnings due to—(i) any violation of any provision of Federal or State law; or

(ii) any unsafe or unsound practice.


(C) Unsafe or unsound conditionAn unsafe or unsound condition to transact business.


(D) Cease and desist ordersAny willful violation of a cease and desist order that has become final.


(E) ConcealmentAny concealment of the books, papers, records, or assets of the regulated entity, or any refusal to submit the books, papers, records, or affairs of the regulated entity, for inspection to any examiner or to any lawful agent of the Director.


(F) Inability to meet obligationsThe regulated entity is likely to be unable to pay its obligations or meet the demands of its creditors in the normal course of business.


(G) LossesThe regulated entity has incurred or is likely to incur losses that will deplete all or substantially all of its capital, and there is no reasonable prospect for th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of the Agency as conservator or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment of the Agency as conservator or receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of the Agency as conservator or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Powers and duties of the Agency as conservator or receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority of expenses and unsecured claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority of expenses and unsecured claims</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to contracts entered into before appointment of conservator or receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provisions relating to contracts entered into before appointment of conservator or receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation of claims in default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Valuation of claims in default</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on court action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on court action Except as provided in this section or at the request of the Director, no court may take any action to restrain or affect the exercise of powers or functions of the Agency as a conservator or a receiver.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of directors and officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Liability of directors and officers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Damages In any proceeding related to any claim against a director, officer, employee, agent, attorney, accountant, appraiser, or any other party employed by or providing services to a regulated entity, recoverable damages determined to result from the improvident or otherwise improper use or investment of any assets of the regulated entity shall include principal losses and appropriate interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited-life regulated entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Limited-life regulated entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4617_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Agency exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Other Agency exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>