<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4618" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4618/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4618/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4618"><akn:num>4618</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of classification and enforcement action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4618. Notice of classification and enforcement action(a) NoticeBefore taking any action referred to in subsection (b), the Director shall provide to the regulated entity written notice of the proposed action, which states the reasons for the proposed action and the information on which the proposed action is based.


(b) ApplicabilityThe requirements of subsection (a) shall apply to the following actions:(1) Classification or reclassification of a regulated entity within a particular capital classification under section 4614 of this title.

(2) Any discretionary supervisory action pursuant to section 4615 of this title.

(3) Any discretionary supervisory action pursuant to section 4616 of this title except a decision to appoint a conservator under section 4616(b)(6) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


Notice of classification under paragraph (1) and notice of supervisory actions under paragraph (2) or (3) may be provided together in a single notice under subsection (a).

(c) Response period(1) In generalDuring the 30-day period beginning on the date that a regulated entity is provided notice under subsection (a) of a proposed action, the regulated entity may submit to the Director any information relevant to the action that the regulated entity considers appropriate for consideration by the Director in determining whether to take such action. The Director may, at the discretion of the Director, hold an informal administrative hearing to receive and discuss such information and the proposed determination.


(2) Extended periodThe Director may extend the period under paragraph (1) for good cause for not more than 30 additional days.


(3) Shortened periodThe Director may shorten the period under paragraph (1) if the Director determines that the condition of the regulated entity so requires or the regulated entity consents.


(4) Failure to respondThe failure of a regulated entity to provide information during the response period under this subsect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4618_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice Before taking any action referred to in subsection (b), the Director shall provide to the regulated entity written notice of the proposed action, which states the reasons for the proposed action and the information on which the proposed action is based.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4618_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicability The requirements of subsection (a) shall apply to the following actions: Notice of classification under paragraph (1) and notice of supervisory actions under paragraph (2) or (3) may be provided together in a single notice under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4618_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Response period</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4618_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of information and determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consideration of information and determination After the expiration of the response period under subsection (c) or upon receipt of information provided during such period by the regulated entity, whichever occurs earlier, the Director shall determine whether to take the action proposed, taking into consideration any relevant information submitted by the regulated entity during the response period. The Director shall provide written notice of a determination to take action and the reasons for such determination to the regulated entity, the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate. Such notice shall respond to any information submitted during the response period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4618_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date of actions An action referred to in subsection (b) shall take effect upon receipt by the regulated entity of notice of the determination of the Director under subsection (d), unless otherwise provided in such notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>