<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4631"><akn:num>4631</akn:num><akn:heading>Cease-and-desist proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4631. Cease-and-desist proceedings(a) Issuance for unsafe or unsound practices and violations(1) Authority of DirectorIf, in the opinion of the Director, a regulated entity or any entity-affiliated party is engaging or has engaged, or the Director has reasonable cause to believe that the regulated entity or any entity-affiliated party is about to engage, in an unsafe or unsound practice in conducting the business of the regulated entity or the Office of Finance, or is violating or has violated, or the Director has reasonable cause to believe is about to violate, a law, rule, regulation, or order, or any condition imposed in writing by the Director in connection with the granting of any application or other request by the regulated entity or the Office of Finance or any written agreement entered into with the Director, the Director may issue and serve upon the regulated entity or entity-affiliated party a notice of charges in respect thereof.


(2) LimitationThe Director may not, pursuant to this section, enforce compliance with any housing goal established under subpart 2 of part B of subchapter I of this chapter, with section 4566 or 4567 of this title, with subsection (m) or (n) of section 1723a of this title, with subsection (e) or (f) of section 1456 of this title, or with paragraph (5) of section 1430(j) of this title.



(b) Issuance for unsatisfactory ratingIf a regulated entity receives, in its most recent report of examination, a less-than-satisfactory rating for asset quality, management, earnings, or liquidity, the Director may (if the deficiency is not corrected) deem the regulated entity to be engaging in an unsafe or unsound practice for purposes of subsection (a).


(c) Procedure(1) Notice of chargesEach notice of charges under this section shall contain a statement of the facts constituting the alleged practice or violation and shall fix a time and place at which a hearing will be held to determine on the record whether an order to cease and desist</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance for unsafe or unsound practices and violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Issuance for unsafe or unsound practices and violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance for unsatisfactory rating</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Issuance for unsatisfactory rating If a regulated entity receives, in its most recent report of examination, a less-than-satisfactory rating for asset quality, management, earnings, or liquidity, the Director may (if the deficiency is not corrected) deem the regulated entity to be engaging in an unsafe or unsound practice for purposes of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4631_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affirmative action to correct conditions resulting from violations or activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Affirmative action to correct conditions resulting from violations or activities The authority under this section and section 4632 of this title to issue any order requiring a regulated entity, executive officer, director, or entity-affiliated party to take affirmative action to correct or remedy any condition resulting from any practice or violation with respect to which such order is issued includes the authority to require a regulated entity or entity-affiliated party—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4631_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to limit activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authority to limit activities The authority to issue an order under this section or section 4632 of this title includes the authority to place limitations on the activities or functions of the regulated entity or entity-affiliated party or any executive officer or director of the regulated entity or entity-affiliated party.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4631_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective date An order under this section shall become effective upon the expiration of the 30-day period beginning on the service of the order upon the regulated entity, finance facility,,22 So in original. executive officer, director, or entity-affiliated party concerned (except in the case of an order issued upon consent, which shall become effective at the time specified therein), and shall remain effective and enforceable as provided in the order, except to the extent that the order is stayed, modified, terminated, or set aside by action of the Director or otherwise, as provided in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>