<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4632" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4632/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4632/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4632"><akn:num>4632</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary cease-and-desist orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4632. Temporary cease-and-desist orders(a) Grounds for issuance(1) In generalIf the Director determines that the actions specified in the notice of charges served upon a regulated entity or any entity-affiliated party pursuant to section 4631(a) of this title, or the continuation thereof, is likely to cause insolvency or significant dissipation of assets or earnings of that entity, or is likely to weaken the condition of that entity prior to the completion of the proceedings conducted pursuant to sections 4631 and 4633 of this title, the Director may—(A) issue a temporary order requiring that regulated entity or entity-affiliated party to cease and desist from any such violation or practice; and

(B) require that regulated entity or entity-affiliated party to take affirmative action to prevent or remedy such insolvency, dissipation, condition, or prejudice pending completion of such proceedings.


(2) Additional requirementsAn order issued under paragraph (1) may include any requirement authorized under subsection 4631(d) of this title.



(b) Effective dateAn order issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall become effective upon service upon the regulated entity, executive officer, director, or entity-affiliated party and, unless set aside, limited, or suspended by a court in proceedings pursuant to subsection (d), shall remain in effect and enforceable pending the completion of the proceedings pursuant to such notice and shall remain effective until the Director dismisses the charges specified in the notice or until superseded by a cease-and-desist order issued pursuant to section 4631 of this title.


(c) Incomplete or inaccurate records(1) Temporary orderIf a notice of charges served under section 4631(a) or (b) of this title specifies on the basis of particular facts and circumstances that the books and records of the regulated entity served are so incomplete or inaccurate that the Director is unable, through the normal supervisory process, to determine the fina</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grounds for issuance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grounds for issuance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effective date An order issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall become effective upon service upon the regulated entity, executive officer, director, or entity-affiliated party and, unless set aside, limited, or suspended by a court in proceedings pursuant to subsection (d), shall remain in effect and enforceable pending the completion of the proceedings pursuant to such notice and shall remain effective until the Director dismisses the charges specified in the notice or until superseded by a cease-and-desist order issued pursuant to section 4631 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incomplete or inaccurate records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Incomplete or inaccurate records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Judicial review A regulated entity, executive officer, director, or entity-affiliated party that has been served with a temporary order pursuant to this section may apply to the United States District Court for the District of Columbia within 10 days after such service for an injunction setting aside, limiting, or suspending the enforcement, operation, or effectiveness of the order pending the completion of the administrative proceedings pursuant to the notice of charges served upon the enterprise, executive officer, director, or entity-affiliated party under section 4631(a) or (b) of this title. Such court shall have jurisdiction to issue such injunction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4632_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement by Attorney General In the case of violation or threatened violation of, or failure to obey, a temporary order issued pursuant to this section, the Director may bring an action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia for an injunction to enforce such order. If the court finds any such violation, threatened violation, or failure to obey, the court shall issue such injunction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>