<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4636a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4636a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4636a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4636a"><akn:num>4636a</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal and prohibition authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4636a. Removal and prohibition authority(a) Authority to issue order(1) In generalThe Director may serve upon a party described in paragraph (2), or any officer, director, or management of the Office of Finance a written notice of the intention of the Director to suspend or remove such party from office, or prohibit any further participation by such party, in any manner, in the conduct of the affairs of the regulated entity.


(2) ApplicabilityA party described in this paragraph is an entity-affiliated party or any officer, director, or management of the Office of Finance, if the Director determines that—(A) that party, officer, or director has, directly or indirectly—(i) violated—(I) any law or regulation;

(II) any cease and desist order which has become final;

(III) any condition imposed in writing by the Director in connection with the grant of any application or other request by such regulated entity; or

(IV) any written agreement between such regulated entity and the Director;


(ii) engaged or participated in any unsafe or unsound practice in connection with any regulated entity or business institution; or

(iii) committed or engaged in any act, omission, or practice which constitutes a breach of such party’s fiduciary duty;


(B) by reason of the violation, practice, or breach described in subparagraph (A)—(i) such regulated entity or business institution has suffered or will probably suffer financial loss or other damage; or

(ii) such party has received financial gain or other benefit; and


(C) the violation, practice, or breach described in subparagraph (A)—(i) involves personal dishonesty on the part of such party; or

(ii) demonstrates willful or continuing disregard by such party for the safety or soundness of such regulated entity or business institution.




(b) Suspension order(1) Suspension or prohibition authorityIf the Director serves written notice under subsection (a) upon a party subject to that subsection (a), the Director may, by order,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4636a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to issue order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to issue order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4636a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Suspension order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4636a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice, hearing, and order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice, hearing, and order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4636a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of certain specific activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition of certain specific activities Any person subject to an order issued under this section shall not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4636a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry-wide prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Industry-wide prohibition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4636a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicability This section shall only apply to a person who is an individual, unless the Director specifically finds that it should apply to a corporation, firm, or other business entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4636a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of suspension and prohibition of entity-affiliated party</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Stay of suspension and prohibition of entity-affiliated party Not later than 10 days after the date on which any entity-affiliated party has been suspended from office or prohibited from participation in the conduct of the affairs of a regulated entity under this section, such party may apply to the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, or the United States district court for the judicial district in which the headquarters of the regulated entity is located, for a stay of such suspension or prohibition pending the completion of the administrative proceedings pursuant to subsection (c). The court shall have jurisdiction to stay such suspension or prohibition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4636a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension or removal of entity-affiliated party charged with felony</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Suspension or removal of entity-affiliated party charged with felony</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>