<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4639" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4639/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4639/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4639"><akn:num>4639</akn:num><akn:heading>Public disclosure of final orders and agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4639. Public disclosure of final orders and agreements(a) In generalThe Director shall make available to the public—(1) any written agreement or other written statement for which a violation may be redressed by the Director or any modification to or termination thereof, unless the Director, in the Director’s discretion, determines that public disclosure would be contrary to the public interest;

(2) any order that is issued with respect to any administrative enforcement proceeding initiated by the Director under this subchapter and that has become final in accordance with sections 4633 and 4634 of this title; and

(3) any modification to or termination of any final order made public pursuant to this subsection.


(b) HearingsAll hearings on the record with respect to any notice of charges issued by the Director shall be open to the public, unless the Director, in the Director’s discretion, determines that holding an open hearing would be contrary to the public interest.


(c) Delay of public disclosure under exceptional circumstancesIf the Director makes a determination in writing that the public disclosure of any final order pursuant to subsection (a) would seriously threaten the financial health or security of the regulated entity, the Director may delay the public disclosure of such order for a reasonable time.


(d) Documents filed under seal in public enforcement hearingsThe Director may file any document or part thereof under seal in any hearing commenced by the Director if the Director determines in writing that disclosure thereof would be contrary to the public interest.


(e) Retention of documentsThe Director shall keep and maintain a record, for not less than 6 years, of all documents described in subsection (a) and all enforcement agreements and other supervisory actions and supporting documents issued with respect to or in connection with any enforcement proceeding initiated by the Director under this subchapter or any other law.


(f) Disclosures to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4639_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director shall make available to the public—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4639_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hearings All hearings on the record with respect to any notice of charges issued by the Director shall be open to the public, unless the Director, in the Director’s discretion, determines that holding an open hearing would be contrary to the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4639_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delay of public disclosure under exceptional circumstances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Delay of public disclosure under exceptional circumstances If the Director makes a determination in writing that the public disclosure of any final order pursuant to subsection (a) would seriously threaten the financial health or security of the regulated entity, the Director may delay the public disclosure of such order for a reasonable time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4639_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documents filed under seal in public enforcement hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Documents filed under seal in public enforcement hearings The Director may file any document or part thereof under seal in any hearing commenced by the Director if the Director determines in writing that disclosure thereof would be contrary to the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4639_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of documents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Retention of documents The Director shall keep and maintain a record, for not less than 6 years, of all documents described in subsection (a) and all enforcement agreements and other supervisory actions and supporting documents issued with respect to or in connection with any enforcement proceeding initiated by the Director under this subchapter or any other law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4639_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosures to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosures to Congress This section may not be construed to authorize the withholding, or to prohibit the disclosure, of any information to the Congress or any committee or subcommittee thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>