<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4703a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4703a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4703a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4703a"><akn:num>4703a</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital investments for neighborhoods disproportionately impacted by the COVID–19 pandemic</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4703a. Capital investments for neighborhoods disproportionately impacted by the COVID–19 pandemic(a) DefinitionsIn this section—(1) the term “bank holding company” has the meaning given the term in section 1841 of this title;

(2) the term “eligible institution” means any low- and moderate-income community financial institution that is eligible to participate in the Program;

(3) the term “Emergency Capital Investment Fund” means the Emergency Capital Investment Fund established under subsection (b);

(4) the term “low- and moderate-income community financial institution” means any financial institution that is—(A)(i) a community development financial institution; or

(ii) a minority depository institution; and


(B)(i) an insured depository institution that is not controlled by a bank holding company or savings and loan holding company that is also an eligible institution;

(ii) a bank holding company;

(iii) a savings and loan holding company; or

(iv) a federally insured credit union;



(5) the term “minority” means any Black American, Native American, Hispanic American, Asian American, Native Alaskan, Native Hawaiian, or Pacific Islander;

(6) the term “minority depository institution” means an entity that is—(A) a minority depository institution, as defined in section 308 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (12 U.S.C. 1463 note); or

(B) considered to be a minority depository institution by—(i) the appropriate Federal banking agency; or

(ii) the National Credit Union Administration, in the case of an insured credit union; or


(C) listed in the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation’s Minority Depository Institutions List published for the Third Quarter 2020.11 So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.


(7) the term “Program” means the Emergency Capital Investment Program established under subsection (b);

(8) the term “savings and loan holding company” has the meaning given the term under section 146</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purchases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of capital investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment of capital investments The Secretary shall seek to establish the terms of preferred stock issued under the Program to enable such preferred stock to receive Tier 1 capital treatment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach to minority communities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Outreach to minority communities The Secretary shall require low- and moderate-income community financial institutions receiving capital investments under the Program to provide community outreach and communication, where appropriate, describing the availability and application process of receiving loans made possible by the Program through organizations, trade associations, and individuals that represent or work within or are members of minority communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility of certain institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Ineligibility of certain institutions An institution shall be ineligible to participate in the Program if such institution is designated in Troubled Condition by the appropriate Federal banking agency or the National Credit Union Administration, as applicable, or is subject to a formal enforcement action with its primary Federal regulator that addresses unsafe or unsound lending practices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4703a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of investment authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Termination of investment authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>