<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4713a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4713a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4713a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4713a"><akn:num>4713a</akn:num><akn:heading>Guarantees for bonds and notes issued for community or economic development purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4713a. Guarantees for bonds and notes issued for community or economic development purposes(a) DefinitionsIn this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Eligible community development financial institutionThe term “eligible community development financial institution” means a community development financial institution (as described in section 1805.201 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto) certified by the Secretary that has applied to a qualified issuer for, or been granted by a qualified issuer, a loan under the Program.


(2) Eligible community or economic development purposeThe term “eligible community or economic development purpose”—(A) means any purpose described in section 4707(b) of this title; and

(B) includes the provision of community or economic development in low-income or underserved rural areas.


(3) GuaranteeThe term “guarantee” means a written agreement between the Secretary and a qualified issuer (or trustee), pursuant to which the Secretary ensures repayment of the verifiable losses of principal, interest, and call premium, if any, on notes or bonds issued by a qualified issuer to finance or refinance loans to eligible community development financial institutions.


(4) LoanThe term “loan” means any credit instrument that is extended under the Program for any eligible community or economic development purpose.


(5) Master servicer(A) In generalThe term “master servicer” means any entity approved by the Secretary in accordance with subparagraph (B) to oversee the activities of servicers, as provided in subsection (f)(4).


(B) Approval criteria for master servicersThe Secretary shall approve or deny any application to become a master servicer under the Program not later than 90 days after the date on which all required information is submitted to the Secretary, based on the capacity and experience of the applicant in—(i) loan administration, servicing, and loan monitoring;

(ii) managing regional or n</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guarantees authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Guarantees authorized The Secretary shall guarantee payments on bonds or notes issued by any qualified issuer, if the proceeds of the bonds or notes are used in accordance with this section to make loans to eligible community development financial institutions—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General program requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk-share pool</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Risk-share pool Each qualified issuer shall, during the term of a guarantee provided under the Program, establish a risk-share pool, capitalized by contributions from eligible community development financial institution participants an amount equal to 3 percent of the guaranteed amount outstanding on the subject notes and bonds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Guarantees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Servicing of transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Servicing of transactions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment in guaranteed bonds ineligible for Community Reinvestment Act purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Investment in guaranteed bonds ineligible for Community Reinvestment Act purposes Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any investment by a financial institution in bonds or notes guaranteed under the Program shall not be taken into account in assessing the record of such institution for purposes of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (12 U.S.C. 2901 [et seq.]).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4713a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>