<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4717" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4717/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4717/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4717"><akn:num>4717</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4717. Enforcement(a) Regulations(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after the appointment and qualification of the Administrator, the Fund shall promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter.


(2) Regulations requiredThe regulations promulgated under paragraph (1) shall include regulations applicable to community development financial institutions that are not insured depository institutions to—(A) prevent conflicts of interest on the part of directors, officers, and employees of community development financial institutions as the Fund determines to be appropriate; and

(B) establish such standards with respect to loans by a community development financial institution to any director, officer, or employee of such institution as the Fund determines to be appropriate, including loan amount limitations.



(b) Administrative enforcementThe provisions of this subchapter, and regulations prescribed and agreements entered into under this subchapter, shall be enforced under section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1818] by the appropriate Federal banking agency, in the case of an insured community development financial institution. A violation of this subchapter, or any regulation prescribed under or any agreement entered into under this subchapter, shall be treated as a violation of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1811 et seq.].


(Pub. L. 103–325, title I, § 119, Sept. 23, 1994, 108 Stat. 2188.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Deposit Insurance Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is act Sept. 21, 1950, ch. 967, § 2, 64 Stat. 873, which is classified generally to chapter 16 (§ 1811 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1811 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section is comprised of section 119 of Pub. L. 103–325. Subsec. (c) of section 119 of Pub. L. 103–325 amended section 657 of Title 18, Crimes and Crimina</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4717_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4717_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrative enforcement The provisions of this subchapter, and regulations prescribed and agreements entered into under this subchapter, shall be enforced under section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1818] by the appropriate Federal banking agency, in the case of an insured community development financial institution. A violation of this subchapter, or any regulation prescribed under or any agreement entered into under this subchapter, shall be treated as a violation of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act [12 U.S.C. 1811 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>