<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4745" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4745/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4745/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4745"><akn:num>4745</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of participation agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4745. Terms of participation agreements(a) In generalThe participation agreement to be entered into by a participating State and a participating financial institution shall include all provisions required by this section, and shall not include any provisions inconsistent with the provisions of this section.


(b) Establishment of separate reserve fundsA separate reserve fund shall be established by the participating State for each participating financial institution. All funds credited to a reserve fund shall be the exclusive property of the participating State. Each reserve fund shall be an administrative account for the purposes of—(1) receiving all required premium charges to be paid by the borrower and participating financial institution and contributions by the participating State; and

(2) disbursing funds, either to cover losses sustained by the participating financial institution in connection with loans made under the Program, or as contemplated by subsections (d) and (r).


(c) Investment authoritySubject to applicable State law, the participating State may invest, or cause to be invested, funds held in a reserve fund by establishing a deposit account at the participating financial institution in the name of the participating State. In the event that funds in the reserve fund are not deposited in such an account, such funds shall be invested in a form that the participating State determines is safe and liquid.


(d) Earned income and interestInterest or income earned on the funds credited to a reserve fund shall be deemed to be part of the reserve fund, except that a participating State may, as further specified in the participation agreement, provide authority for the participating State to withdraw some or all of such interest or income earned.


(e) Loan terms and conditions(1) In generalA loan to be filed for enrollment under the Program may be made with such interest rate, fees, and other terms and conditions as agreed upon by the participating fina</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The participation agreement to be entered into by a participating State and a participating financial institution shall include all provisions required by this section, and shall not include any provisions inconsistent with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of separate reserve funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of separate reserve funds A separate reserve fund shall be established by the participating State for each participating financial institution. All funds credited to a reserve fund shall be the exclusive property of the participating State. Each reserve fund shall be an administrative account for the purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Investment authority Subject to applicable State law, the participating State may invest, or cause to be invested, funds held in a reserve fund by establishing a deposit account at the participating financial institution in the name of the participating State. In the event that funds in the reserve fund are not deposited in such an account, such funds shall be invested in a form that the participating State determines is safe and liquid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Earned income and interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Earned income and interest Interest or income earned on the funds credited to a reserve fund shall be deemed to be part of the reserve fund, except that a participating State may, as further specified in the participation agreement, provide authority for the participating State to withdraw some or all of such interest or income earned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Loan terms and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Enrollment process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coverage amount In filing a loan for enrollment under the Program, the participating financial institution may specify an amount to be covered under the Program that is less than the full amount of the loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premium charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Premium charges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4745_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>State contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) State contributions In enrolling a loan under the Program, the participating State shall contribute to the reserve fund an amount, as provided for in the participation agreement, which shall not be less than the sum of the amount of premium charges paid by the borrower and the participating financial institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>