<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/4901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4901"><akn:num>4901</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4901. Definitions
In this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Adjustable rate mortgageThe term “adjustable rate mortgage” means a residential mortgage that has an interest rate that is subject to change. A residential mortgage that: (A) does not fully amortize over the term of the obligation; and (B) contains a conditional right to refinance or modify the unamortized principal at the maturity date of the term, shall be considered to be an adjustable rate mortgage for purposes of this chapter.


(2) Cancellation dateThe term “cancellation date” means—(A) with respect to a fixed rate mortgage, at the option of the mortgagor, the date on which the principal balance of the mortgage—(i) based solely on the initial amortization schedule for that mortgage, and irrespective of the outstanding balance for that mortgage on that date, is first scheduled to reach 80 percent of the original value of the property securing the loan; or

(ii) based solely on actual payments, reaches 80 percent of the original value of the property securing the loan; and


(B) with respect to an adjustable rate mortgage, at the option of the mortgagor, the date on which the principal balance of the mortgage—(i) based solely on the amortization schedule then in effect for that mortgage, and irrespective of the outstanding balance for that mortgage on that date, is first scheduled to reach 80 percent of the original value of the property securing the loan; or

(ii) based solely on actual payments, first reaches 80 percent of the original value of the property securing the loan.



(3) Fixed rate mortgageThe term “fixed rate mortgage” means a residential mortgage that has an interest rate that is not subject to change.


(4) Good payment historyThe term “good payment history” means, with respect to a mortgagor, that the mortgagor has not—(A) made a mortgage payment that was 60 days or longer past due during the 12-month period beginning 24 months before the later of (i) the date on whi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustable rate mortgage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Adjustable rate mortgage The term “adjustable rate mortgage” means a residential mortgage that has an interest rate that is subject to change. A residential mortgage that: (A) does not fully amortize over the term of the obligation; and (B) contains a conditional right to refinance or modify the unamortized principal at the maturity date of the term, shall be considered to be an adjustable rate mortgage for purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Cancellation date The term “cancellation date” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fixed rate mortgage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Fixed rate mortgage The term “fixed rate mortgage” means a residential mortgage that has an interest rate that is not subject to change.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Good payment history</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Good payment history The term “good payment history” means, with respect to a mortgagor, that the mortgagor has not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial amortization schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Initial amortization schedule The term “initial amortization schedule” means a schedule established at the time at which a residential mortgage transaction is consummated with respect to a fixed rate mortgage, showing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amortization schedule then in effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Amortization schedule then in effect The term “amortization schedule then in effect” means, with respect to an adjustable rate mortgage, a schedule established at the time at which the residential mortgage transaction is consummated or, if such schedule has been changed or recalculated, is the most recent schedule under the terms of the note or mortgage, which shows—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Midpoint of the amortization period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Midpoint of the amortization period The term “midpoint of the amortization period” means, with respect to a residential mortgage transaction, the point in time that is halfway through the period that begins upon the first day of the amortization period established at the time a residential mortgage transaction is consummated and ends upon the completion of the entire period over which the mortgage is scheduled to be amortized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Mortgage insurance The term “mortgage insurance” means insurance, including any mortgage guaranty insurance, against the nonpayment of, or default on, an individual mortgage or loan involved in a residential mortgage transaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage insurer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Mortgage insurer The term “mortgage insurer” means a provider of private mortgage insurance, as described in this chapter, that is authorized to transact such business in the State in which the provider is transacting such business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4901_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgagee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Mortgagee The term “mortgagee” means the holder of a residential mortgage at the time at which that mortgage transaction is consummated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>