<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_504"><akn:num>504</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil money penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 504. Civil money penalty(a) First tierAny member bank which, and any institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to such member bank who, violates any provision of section 371c, 371c–1, 375, 375a, 375b, 376, or 503 of this title, or any regulation issued pursuant thereto, shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each day during which such violation continues.


(b) Second tierNotwithstanding subsection (a), any member bank which, and any institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to such member bank who 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a dash.(1)(A) commits any violation described in subsection (a);

(B) recklessly engages in an unsafe or unsound practice in conducting the affairs of such member bank; or

(C) breaches any fiduciary duty;


(2) which violation, practice, or breach—(A) is part of a pattern of misconduct;

(B) causes or is likely to cause more than a minimal loss to such member bank; or

(C) results in pecuniary gain or other benefit to such party,



shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 for each day during which such violation, practice, or breach continues.

(c) Third tierNotwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), any member bank which, and any institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to such member bank who—(1) knowingly—(A) commits any violation described in subsection (a);

(B) engages in any unsafe or unsound practice in conducting the affairs of such credit union; 22 So in original. Probably should be “such member bank”. or

(C) breaches any fiduciary duty; and


(2) knowingly or recklessly causes a substantial loss to such credit union 2 or a substantial pecuniary gain or other benefit to such party by reason of such violation, practice, or breach,


shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed the ap</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>First tier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) First tier Any member bank which, and any institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to such member bank who, violates any provision of section 371c, 371c–1, 375, 375a, 375b, 376, or 503 of this title, or any regulation issued pursuant thereto, shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each day during which such violation continues.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Second tier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Second tier Notwithstanding subsection (a), any member bank which, and any institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to such member bank who 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a dash. shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 for each day during which such violation, practice, or breach continues.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Third tier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Third tier Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), any member bank which, and any institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to such member bank who— shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed the applicable maximum amount determined under subsection (d) for each day during which such violation, practice, or breach continues.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum amounts of penalties for any violation described in subsection (c)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Maximum amounts of penalties for any violation described in subsection (c) The maximum daily amount of any civil penalty which may be assessed pursuant to subsection (c) for any violation, practice, or breach described in such subsection is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment; etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assessment; etc. Any penalty imposed under subsection (a), (b), or (c) shall be assessed and collected 33 So in original. Probably should be followed by a dash rather than “by”. by in the manner provided in subparagraphs (E), (F), (G), and (I) of section 1818(i)(2) of this title for penalties imposed (under such section) and any such assessment shall be subject to the provisions of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Hearing The member bank or other person against whom any penalty is assessed under this section shall be afforded an agency hearing if such member bank or person submits a request for such hearing within 20 days after the issuance of the notice of assessment. Section 1818(h) of this title shall apply to any proceeding under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Disbursement All penalties collected under authority of this paragraph shall be deposited into the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Violate” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Violate” defined For purposes of this section, the term “violate” includes any action (alone or with another or others) for or toward causing, bringing about, participating in, counseling, or aiding or abetting a violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Comptroller of the Currency and the Board shall prescribe regulations establishing such procedures as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_504_m"><akn:num>(m)</akn:num><akn:heading>44 So in original. No subsecs. (j) to (l) have been enacted. Notice under this section after separation from service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(m) The resignation, termination of employment or participation, or separation of an institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to a member bank (including a separation caused by the closing of such a bank) shall not affect the jurisdiction and authority of the appropriate Federal banking agency to issue any notice and proceed under this section against any such party, if such notice is served before the end of the 6-year period beginning on the date such party ceased to be such a party with respect to such bank (whether such date occurs before, on, or after August 9, 1989).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>