<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5102"><akn:num>5102</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5102. Definitions
For purposes of this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) BureauThe term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.


(2) Federal banking agencyThe term “Federal banking agency” means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.


(3) Depository institutionThe term “depository institution” has the same meaning as in section 1813 of this title, and includes any credit union.


(4) Loan originator(A) In generalThe term “loan originator”—(i) means an individual who—(I) takes a residential mortgage loan application; and

(II) offers or negotiates terms of a residential mortgage loan for compensation or gain;


(ii) does not include any individual who is not otherwise described in clause (i) and who performs purely administrative or clerical tasks on behalf of a person who is described in any such clause;

(iii) does not include a person or entity that only performs real estate brokerage activities and is licensed or registered in accordance with applicable State law, unless the person or entity is compensated by a lender, a mortgage broker, or other loan originator or by any agent of such lender, mortgage broker, or other loan originator; and

(iv) does not include a person or entity solely involved in extensions of credit relating to timeshare plans, as that term is defined in section 101(53D) of title 11.


(B) Other definitions relating to loan originatorFor purposes of this subsection, an individual “assists a consumer in obtaining or applying to obtain a residential mortgage loan” by, among other things, advising on loan terms (including rates, fees, other costs), preparing loan packages, or collecting information on behalf of the consumer with regard to a residential mortgage loan.


(C) Administrative or clerical tasksThe term “administrative or clerical tasks” means the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Bureau The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal banking agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Federal banking agency The term “Federal banking agency” means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Depository institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Depository institution The term “depository institution” has the same meaning as in section 1813 of this title, and includes any credit union.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan originator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Loan originator</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan processor or underwriter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Loan processor or underwriter</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nationwide mortgage licensing system and registry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Nationwide mortgage licensing system and registry The term “Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry” means a mortgage licensing system developed and maintained by the Conference of State Bank Supervisors and the American Association of Residential Mortgage Regulators for the State licensing and registration of State-licensed loan originators and the registration of registered loan originators or any system established by the Director under section 5108 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nontraditional mortgage product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Nontraditional mortgage product The term “nontraditional mortgage product” means any mortgage product other than a 30-year fixed rate mortgage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registered loan originator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Registered loan originator The term “registered loan originator” means any individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Residential mortgage loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Residential mortgage loan The term “residential mortgage loan” means any loan primarily for personal, family, or household use that is secured by a mortgage, deed of trust, or other equivalent consensual security interest on a dwelling (as defined in section 1602(v) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 15) or residential real estate upon which is constructed or intended to be constructed a dwelling (as so defined).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Director The term “Director” means the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>