<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5104"><akn:num>5104</akn:num><akn:heading>State license and registration application and issuance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5104. State license and registration application and issuance(a) Background checksIn connection with an application to any State for licensing and registration as a State-licensed loan originator, the applicant shall, at a minimum, furnish to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry information concerning the applicant’s identity, including—(1) fingerprints for submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and any governmental agency or entity authorized to receive such information for a State and national criminal history background check; and

(2) personal history and experience, including authorization for the System to obtain—(A) an independent credit report obtained from a consumer reporting agency described in section 1681a(p) of title 15; and

(B) information related to any administrative, civil or criminal findings by any governmental jurisdiction.



(b) Issuance of licenseThe minimum standards for licensing and registration as a State-licensed loan originator shall include the following:(1) The applicant has never had a loan originator license revoked in any governmental jurisdiction.

(2) The applicant has not been convicted of, or pled guilty or nolo contendere to, a felony in a domestic, foreign, or military court—(A) during the 7-year period preceding the date of the application for licensing and registration; or

(B) at any time preceding such date of application, if such felony involved an act of fraud, dishonesty, or a breach of trust, or money laundering.


(3) The applicant has demonstrated financial responsibility, character, and general fitness such as to command the confidence of the community and to warrant a determination that the loan originator will operate honestly, fairly, and efficiently within the purposes of this chapter.

(4) The applicant has completed the pre-licensing education requirement described in subsection (c).

(5) The applicant has passed a written test that meets the test requirement described in subse</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Background checks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Background checks In connection with an application to any State for licensing and registration as a State-licensed loan originator, the applicant shall, at a minimum, furnish to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry information concerning the applicant’s identity, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of license</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Issuance of license The minimum standards for licensing and registration as a State-licensed loan originator shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pre-licensing education of loan originators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Pre-licensing education of loan originators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing of loan originators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Testing of loan originators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5104_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgage call reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Mortgage call reports Each mortgage licensee shall submit to the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry reports of condition, which shall be in such form and shall contain such information as the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>