<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5107" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5107/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5107/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5107"><akn:num>5107</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection backup authority to establish loan originator licensing syst</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5107. Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection backup authority to establish loan originator licensing system(a) Backup licensing systemIf, by the end of the 1-year period, or the 2-year period in the case of a State whose legislature meets only biennially, beginning on July 30, 2008, or at any time thereafter, the Director determines that a State does not have in place by law or regulation a system for licensing and registering loan originators that meets the requirements of sections 5104 and 5105 of this title and subsection (d) of this section, or does not participate in the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, the Director shall provide for the establishment and maintenance of a system for the licensing and registration by the Director of loan originators operating in such State as State-licensed loan originators.


(b) Licensing and registration requirementsThe system established by the Director under subsection (a) for any State shall meet the requirements of sections 5104 and 5105 of this title for State-licensed loan originators.


(c) Unique identifierThe Director shall coordinate with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry to establish protocols for assigning a unique identifier to each loan originator licensed by the Director as a State-licensed loan originator that will facilitate electronic tracking and uniform identification of, and public access to, the employment history of and the publicly adjudicated disciplinary and enforcement actions against loan originators.


(d) State licensing law requirementsFor purposes of this section, the law in effect in a State meets the requirements of this subsection if the Director determines the law satisfies the following minimum requirements:(1) A State loan originator supervisory authority is maintained to provide effective supervision and enforcement of such law, including the suspension, termination, or nonrenewal of a license for a violation of State or Federal law.

(2) The Stat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Backup licensing system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Backup licensing system If, by the end of the 1-year period, or the 2-year period in the case of a State whose legislature meets only biennially, beginning on July 30, 2008, or at any time thereafter, the Director determines that a State does not have in place by law or regulation a system for licensing and registering loan originators that meets the requirements of sections 5104 and 5105 of this title and subsection (d) of this section, or does not participate in the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, the Director shall provide for the establishment and maintenance of a system for the licensing and registration by the Director of loan originators operating in such State as State-licensed loan originators.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing and registration requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Licensing and registration requirements The system established by the Director under subsection (a) for any State shall meet the requirements of sections 5104 and 5105 of this title for State-licensed loan originators.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unique identifier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Unique identifier The Director shall coordinate with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry to establish protocols for assigning a unique identifier to each loan originator licensed by the Director as a State-licensed loan originator that will facilitate electronic tracking and uniform identification of, and public access to, the employment history of and the publicly adjudicated disciplinary and enforcement actions against loan originators.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State licensing law requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State licensing law requirements For purposes of this section, the law in effect in a State meets the requirements of this subsection if the Director determines the law satisfies the following minimum requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary extension of period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Temporary extension of period The Director may extend, by not more than 24 months, the 1-year or 2-year period, as the case may be, referred to in subsection (a) for the licensing of loan originators in any State under a State licensing law that meets the requirements of sections 5104 and 5105 of this title and subsection (d) if the Director determines that such State is making a good faith effort to establish a State licensing law that meets such requirements, license mortgage originators under such law, and register such originators with the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulation authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>