<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5113"><akn:num>5113</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by the Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5113. Enforcement by the Bureau(a) Summons authorityThe Director may—(1) examine any books, papers, records, or other data of any loan originator operating in any State which is subject to a licensing system established by the Director under section 5107 of this title; and

(2) summon any loan originator referred to in paragraph (1) or any person having possession, custody, or care of the reports and records relating to such loan originator, to appear before the Director or any delegate of the Director at a time and place named in the summons and to produce such books, papers, records, or other data, and to give testimony, under oath, as may be relevant or material to an investigation of such loan originator for compliance with the requirements of this chapter.


(b) Examination authority(1) In generalIf the Director establishes a licensing system under section 5107 of this title for any State, the Director shall appoint examiners for the purposes of administering such section.


(2) Power to examineAny examiner appointed under paragraph (1) shall have power, on behalf of the Director, to make any examination of any loan originator operating in any State which is subject to a licensing system established by the Director under section 5107 of this title whenever the Director determines an examination of any loan originator is necessary to determine the compliance by the originator with this chapter.


(3) Report of examinationEach examiner appointed under paragraph (1) shall make a full and detailed report of examination of any loan originator examined to the Director.


(4) Administration of oaths and affirmations; evidenceIn connection with examinations of loan originators operating in any State which is subject to a licensing system established by the Director under section 5107 of this title, or with other types of investigations to determine compliance with applicable law and regulations, the Director and examiners appointed by the Director may administer oath</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Summons authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Summons authority The Director may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Examination authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cease and desist proceeding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cease and desist proceeding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the Director to assess money penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority of the Director to assess money penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>