<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5211" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5211/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5211/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5211"><akn:num>5211</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchases of troubled assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5211. Purchases of troubled assets(a) Offices; authority(1) AuthorityThe Secretary is authorized to establish the Troubled Asset Relief Program (or “TARP”) to purchase, and to make and fund commitments to purchase, troubled assets from any financial institution, on such terms and conditions as are determined by the Secretary, and in accordance with this chapter and the policies and procedures developed and published by the Secretary.


(2) Commencement of programEstablishment of the policies and procedures and other similar administrative requirements imposed on the Secretary by this chapter are not intended to delay the commencement of the TARP.


(3) Establishment of Treasury office(A) In generalThe Secretary shall implement any program under paragraph (1) through an Office of Financial Stability, established for such purpose within the Office of Domestic Finance of the Department of the Treasury, which office shall be headed by an Assistant Secretary of the Treasury, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, except that an interim Assistant Secretary may be appointed by the Secretary.


(B) Omitted



(b) ConsultationIn exercising the authority under this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Board, the Corporation, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration Board, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.


(c) Necessary actionsThe Secretary is authorized to take such actions as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the authorities in this chapter, including, without limitation, the following:(1) The Secretary shall have direct hiring authority with respect to the appointment of employees to administer this chapter.

(2) Entering into contracts, including contracts for services authorized by section 3109 of title 5.

(3) Designating financial institutions as financial agents of the Federal Government, and s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5211_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offices; authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Offices; authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5211_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation In exercising the authority under this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Board, the Corporation, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision, the Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration Board, and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5211_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Necessary actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Necessary actions The Secretary is authorized to take such actions as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out the authorities in this chapter, including, without limitation, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5211_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Program guidelines Before the earlier of the end of the 2-business-day period beginning on the date of the first purchase of troubled assets pursuant to the authority under this section or the end of the 45-day period beginning on October 3, 2008, the Secretary shall publish program guidelines, including the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5211_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preventing unjust enrichment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preventing unjust enrichment In making purchases under the authority of this chapter, the Secretary shall take such steps as may be necessary to prevent unjust enrichment of financial institutions participating in a program established under this section, including by preventing the sale of a troubled asset to the Secretary at a higher price than what the seller paid to purchase the asset. This subsection does not apply to troubled assets acquired in a merger or acquisition, or a purchase of assets from a financial institution in conservatorship or receivership, or that has initiated bankruptcy proceedings under title 11.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>