<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5212"><akn:num>5212</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance of troubled assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5212. Insurance of troubled assets(a) Authority(1) In generalIf the Secretary establishes the program authorized under section 5211 of this title, then the Secretary shall establish a program to guarantee troubled assets originated or issued prior to March 14, 2008, including mortgage-backed securities.


(2) GuaranteesIn establishing any program under this subsection, the Secretary may develop guarantees of troubled assets and the associated premiums for such guarantees. Such guarantees and premiums may be determined by category or class of the troubled assets to be guaranteed.


(3) Extent of guaranteeUpon request of a financial institution, the Secretary may guarantee the timely payment of principal of, and interest on, troubled assets in amounts not to exceed 100 percent of such payments. Such guarantee may be on such terms and conditions as are determined by the Secretary, provided that such terms and conditions are consistent with the purposes of this chapter.



(b) ReportsNot later than 90 days after October 3, 2008, the Secretary shall report to the appropriate committees of Congress on the program established under subsection (a).


(c) Premiums(1) In generalThe Secretary shall collect premiums from any financial institution participating in the program established under subsection (a). Such premiums shall be in an amount that the Secretary determines necessary to meet the purposes of this chapter and to provide sufficient reserves pursuant to paragraph (3).


(2) Authority to base premiums on product riskIn establishing any premium under paragraph (1), the Secretary may provide for variations in such rates according to the credit risk associated with the particular troubled asset that is being guaranteed. The Secretary shall publish the methodology for setting the premium for a class of troubled assets together with an explanation of the appropriateness of the class of assets for participation in the program established under this section. The methodolo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports Not later than 90 days after October 3, 2008, the Secretary shall report to the appropriate committees of Congress on the program established under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5212_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Premiums</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5212_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Troubled Assets Insurance Financing Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Troubled Assets Insurance Financing Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>