<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5214" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5214/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5214/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5214"><akn:num>5214</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial Stability Oversight Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5214. Financial Stability Oversight Board(a) EstablishmentThere is established the Financial Stability Oversight Board, which shall be responsible for—(1) reviewing the exercise of authority under a program developed in accordance with this chapter, including—(A) policies implemented by the Secretary and the Office of Financial Stability created under sections 5211 and 5212 of this title, including the appointment of financial agents, the designation of asset classes to be purchased, and plans for the structure of vehicles used to purchase troubled assets; and

(B) the effect of such actions in assisting American families in preserving home ownership, stabilizing financial markets, and protecting taxpayers;


(2) making recommendations, as appropriate, to the Secretary regarding use of the authority under this chapter; and

(3) reporting any suspected fraud, misrepresentation, or malfeasance to the Special Inspector General for the Troubled Assets Relief Program or the Attorney General of the United States, consistent with section 535(b) of title 28.


(b) MembershipThe Financial Stability Oversight Board shall be comprised of—(1) the Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System;

(2) the Secretary;

(3) the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency;

(4) the Chairman of the Securities Exchange Commission; and

(5) the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.


(c) ChairpersonThe chairperson of the Financial Stability Oversight Board shall be elected by the members of the Board from among the members other than the Secretary.


(d) MeetingsThe Financial Stability Oversight Board shall meet 2 weeks after the first exercise of the purchase authority of the Secretary under this chapter, and monthly thereafter.


(e) Additional authoritiesIn addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the Financial Stability Oversight Board shall have the authority to ensure that the policies implemented by the Secretary are—(1) in accorda</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5214_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established the Financial Stability Oversight Board, which shall be responsible for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5214_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The Financial Stability Oversight Board shall be comprised of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5214_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Chairperson The chairperson of the Financial Stability Oversight Board shall be elected by the members of the Board from among the members other than the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5214_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Meetings The Financial Stability Oversight Board shall meet 2 weeks after the first exercise of the purchase authority of the Secretary under this chapter, and monthly thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5214_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional authorities In addition to the responsibilities described in subsection (a), the Financial Stability Oversight Board shall have the authority to ensure that the policies implemented by the Secretary are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5214_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit review committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Credit review committee The Financial Stability Oversight Board may appoint a credit review committee for the purpose of evaluating the exercise of the purchase authority provided under this chapter and the assets acquired through the exercise of such authority, as the Financial Stability Oversight Board determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5214_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports The Financial Stability Oversight Board shall report to the appropriate committees of Congress and the Congressional Oversight Panel established under section 5233 of this title, not less frequently than quarterly, on the matters described under subsection (a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5214_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Termination The Financial Stability Oversight Board, and its authority under this section, shall terminate on the expiration of the 15-day period beginning upon the later of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>