<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5216" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5216/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5216/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5216"><akn:num>5216</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights; management; sale of troubled assets; revenues and sale proceeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5216. Rights; management; sale of troubled assets; revenues and sale proceeds(a) Exercise of rightsThe Secretary may, at any time, exercise any rights received in connection with troubled assets purchased under this chapter.


(b) Management of troubled assetsThe Secretary shall have authority to manage troubled assets purchased under this chapter, including revenues and portfolio risks therefrom.


(c) Sale of troubled assetsThe Secretary may, at any time, upon terms and conditions and at a price determined by the Secretary, sell, or enter into securities loans, repurchase transactions, or other financial transactions in regard to, any troubled asset purchased under this chapter.


(d) Transfer to TreasuryRevenues of, and proceeds from the sale of troubled assets purchased under this chapter, or from the sale, exercise, or surrender of warrants or senior debt instruments acquired under section 5223 of this title shall be paid into the general fund of the Treasury for reduction of the public debt.


(e) Application of sunset to troubled assetsThe authority of the Secretary to hold any troubled asset purchased under this chapter before the termination date in section 5230 of this title, or to purchase or fund the purchase of a troubled asset under a commitment entered into before the termination date in section 5230 of this title, is not subject to the provisions of section 5230 of this title.


(f) ReportThe Secretary of the Treasury shall report to Congress every 6 months on amounts received and transferred to the general fund under subsection (d).


(Pub. L. 110–343, div. A, title I, § 106, Oct. 3, 2008, 122 Stat. 3773; Pub. L. 111–203, title XIII, § 1303, July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 2133.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act” and was translated as reading “this division”, meaning div. A of Pub. L. 110–343, Oct. 3, 2008, 122 Stat. 3765, known as the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008, to ref</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5216_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exercise of rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Exercise of rights The Secretary may, at any time, exercise any rights received in connection with troubled assets purchased under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5216_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of troubled assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Management of troubled assets The Secretary shall have authority to manage troubled assets purchased under this chapter, including revenues and portfolio risks therefrom.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5216_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of troubled assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sale of troubled assets The Secretary may, at any time, upon terms and conditions and at a price determined by the Secretary, sell, or enter into securities loans, repurchase transactions, or other financial transactions in regard to, any troubled asset purchased under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5216_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer to Treasury Revenues of, and proceeds from the sale of troubled assets purchased under this chapter, or from the sale, exercise, or surrender of warrants or senior debt instruments acquired under section 5223 of this title shall be paid into the general fund of the Treasury for reduction of the public debt.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5216_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of sunset to troubled assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application of sunset to troubled assets The authority of the Secretary to hold any troubled asset purchased under this chapter before the termination date in section 5230 of this title, or to purchase or fund the purchase of a troubled asset under a commitment entered into before the termination date in section 5230 of this title, is not subject to the provisions of section 5230 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5216_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report The Secretary of the Treasury shall report to Congress every 6 months on amounts received and transferred to the general fund under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>