<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5221" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5221/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5221/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5221"><akn:num>5221</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive compensation and corporate governance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5221. Executive compensation and corporate governance(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Senior executive officerThe term “senior executive officer” means an individual who is 1 of the top 5 most highly paid executives of a public company, whose compensation is required to be disclosed pursuant to the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.], and any regulations issued thereunder, and non-public company counterparts.


(2) Golden parachute paymentThe term “golden parachute payment” means any payment to a senior executive officer for departure from a company for any reason, except for payments for services performed or benefits accrued.


(3) TARP recipientThe term “TARP recipient” means any entity that has received or will receive financial assistance under the financial assistance provided under the TARP.


(4) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Securities and Exchange Commission.


(5) Period in which obligation is outstanding; rule of constructionFor purposes of this section, the period in which any obligation arising from financial assistance provided under the TARP remains outstanding does not include any period during which the Federal Government only holds warrants to purchase common stock of the TARP recipient.



(b) Executive compensation and corporate governance(1) Establishment of standardsDuring the period in which any obligation arising from financial assistance provided under the TARP remains outstanding, each TARP recipient shall be subject to—(A) the standards established by the Secretary under this section; and

(B) the provisions of section 162(m)(5) of title 26, as applicable.


(2) Standards requiredThe Secretary shall require each TARP recipient to meet appropriate standards for executive compensation and corporate governance.


(3) Specific requirementsThe standards established under paragraph (2) shall include the following:(A) Limits on compensation that exclude incen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5221_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5221_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive compensation and corporate governance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Executive compensation and corporate governance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5221_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board Compensation Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Board Compensation Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5221_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on luxury expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on luxury expenditures The board of directors of any TARP recipient shall have in place a company-wide policy regarding excessive or luxury expenditures, as identified by the Secretary, which may include excessive expenditures on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5221_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shareholder approval of executive compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Shareholder approval of executive compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5221_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of prior payments to executives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Review of prior payments to executives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5221_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No impediment to withdrawal by TARP recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No impediment to withdrawal by TARP recipients Subject to consultation with the appropriate Federal banking agency (as that term is defined in section 1813 of this title), if any, the Secretary shall permit a TARP recipient to repay any assistance previously provided under the TARP to such financial institution, without regard to whether the financial institution has replaced such funds from any other source or to any waiting period, and when such assistance is repaid, the Secretary, at the market price, may liquidate warrants associated with such assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5221_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>