<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5223" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5223/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5223/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5223"><akn:num>5223</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimization of long-term costs and maximization of benefits for taxpayers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5223. Minimization of long-term costs and maximization of benefits for taxpayers(a) Long-term costs and benefits(1) Minimizing negative impactThe Secretary shall use the authority under this chapter in a manner that will minimize any potential long-term negative impact on the taxpayer, taking into account the direct outlays, potential long-term returns on assets purchased, and the overall economic benefits of the program, including economic benefits due to improvements in economic activity and the availability of credit, the impact on the savings and pensions of individuals, and reductions in losses to the Federal Government.


(2) AuthorityIn carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—(A) hold the assets to maturity or for resale for and until such time as the Secretary determines that the market is optimal for selling such assets, in order to maximize the value for taxpayers; and

(B) sell such assets at a price that the Secretary determines, based on available financial analysis, will maximize return on investment for the Federal Government.


(3) Private sector participationThe Secretary shall encourage the private sector to participate in purchases of troubled assets, and to invest in financial institutions, consistent with the provisions of this section.



(b) Use of market mechanismsIn making purchases under this chapter, the Secretary shall—(1) make such purchases at the lowest price that the Secretary determines to be consistent with the purposes of this chapter; and

(2) maximize the efficiency of the use of taxpayer resources by using market mechanisms, including auctions or reverse auctions, where appropriate.


(c) Direct purchasesIf the Secretary determines that use of a market mechanism under subsection (b) is not feasible or appropriate, and the purposes of the chapter are best met through direct purchases from an individual financial institution, the Secretary shall pursue additional measures to ensure that prices paid for assets are reasona</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5223_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Long-term costs and benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Long-term costs and benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5223_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of market mechanisms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of market mechanisms In making purchases under this chapter, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5223_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct purchases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Direct purchases If the Secretary determines that use of a market mechanism under subsection (b) is not feasible or appropriate, and the purposes of the chapter are best met through direct purchases from an individual financial institution, the Secretary shall pursue additional measures to ensure that prices paid for assets are reasonable and reflect the underlying value of the asset.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5223_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions on purchase authority for warrants and debt instruments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conditions on purchase authority for warrants and debt instruments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>