<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5225" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5225/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5225/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5225"><akn:num>5225</akn:num><akn:heading>Graduated authorization to purchase</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5225. Graduated authorization to purchase(a) AuthorityThe authority of the Secretary to purchase troubled assets under this chapter shall be limited as follows:(1) Effective upon October 3, 2008, such authority shall be limited to $250,000,000,000 outstanding at any one time.

(2) If at any time, the President submits to the Congress a written certification that the Secretary needs to exercise the authority under this paragraph, effective upon such submission, such authority shall be limited to $350,000,000,000 outstanding at any one time.

(3) If, at any time after the certification in paragraph (2) has been made, the President transmits to the Congress a written report detailing the plan of the Secretary to exercise the authority under this paragraph, unless there is enacted, within 15 calendar days of such transmission, a joint resolution described in subsection (c), effective upon the expiration of such 15-day period, such authority shall be limited to $475,000,000,000.

(4) For purposes of this subsection, the amount of authority considered to be exercised by the Secretary shall not be reduced by—(A) any amounts received by the Secretary before, on, or after July 21, 2010, from repayment of the principal of financial assistance by an entity that has received financial assistance under the TARP or any other program enacted by the Secretary under the authorities granted to the Secretary under this chapter;

(B) any amounts committed for any guarantees pursuant to the TARP that became or become uncommitted; or

(C) any losses realized by the Secretary.


(5) No authority under this chapter may be used to incur any obligation for a program or initiative that was not initiated prior to June 25, 2010.


(b) Aggregation of purchase pricesThe amount of troubled assets purchased by the Secretary outstanding at any one time shall be determined for purposes of the dollar amount limitations under subsection (a) by aggregating the purchase prices of all troubled assets he</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5225_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority The authority of the Secretary to purchase troubled assets under this chapter shall be limited as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5225_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aggregation of purchase prices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Aggregation of purchase prices The amount of troubled assets purchased by the Secretary outstanding at any one time shall be determined for purposes of the dollar amount limitations under subsection (a) by aggregating the purchase prices of all troubled assets held.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5225_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint resolution of disapproval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Joint resolution of disapproval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5225_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fast track consideration in House of Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fast track consideration in House of Representatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5225_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fast track consideration in Senate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fast track consideration in Senate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5225_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules relating to Senate and House of Representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rules relating to Senate and House of Representatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>