<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5252" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5252/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5252/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5252"><akn:num>5252</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by the Office of Management and Budget and the Congressional Budget Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5252. Reports by the Office of Management and Budget and the Congressional Budget Office(a) Reports by the Office of Management and BudgetWithin 60 days of the first exercise of the authority granted in section 5211(a) of this title, but in no case later than December 31, 2008, and annually thereafter, the Office of Management and Budget shall report to the President and the Congress—(1) the estimate, notwithstanding section 661a(5)(F) of title 2, as of the first business day that is at least 30 days prior to the issuance of the report, of the cost of the troubled assets, and guarantees of the troubled assets, determined in accordance with section 5232 of this title;

(2) the information used to derive the estimate, including assets purchased or guaranteed, prices paid, revenues received, the impact on the deficit and debt, and a description of any outstanding commitments to purchase troubled assets; and

(3) a detailed analysis of how the estimate has changed from the previous report.


Beginning with the second report under subsection (a), the Office of Management and Budget shall explain the differences between the Congressional Budget Office estimates delivered in accordance with subsection (b) and prior Office of Management and Budget estimates.

(b) Reports by the Congressional Budget OfficeWithin 45 days of receipt by the Congress of each report from the Office of Management and Budget under subsection (a), the Congressional Budget Office shall report to the Congress the Congressional Budget Office’s assessment of the report submitted by the Office of Management and Budget, including—(1) the cost of the troubled assets and guarantees of the troubled assets,

(2) the information and valuation methods used to calculate such cost, and

(3) the impact on the deficit and the debt.


(c) Financial expertiseIn carrying out the duties in this subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. or performing analyses of activities under this chapter, the Dir</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5252_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by the Office of Management and Budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports by the Office of Management and Budget Within 60 days of the first exercise of the authority granted in section 5211(a) of this title, but in no case later than December 31, 2008, and annually thereafter, the Office of Management and Budget shall report to the President and the Congress— Beginning with the second report under subsection (a), the Office of Management and Budget shall explain the differences between the Congressional Budget Office estimates delivered in accordance with subsection (b) and prior Office of Management and Budget estimates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5252_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by the Congressional Budget Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports by the Congressional Budget Office Within 45 days of receipt by the Congress of each report from the Office of Management and Budget under subsection (a), the Congressional Budget Office shall report to the Congress the Congressional Budget Office’s assessment of the report submitted by the Office of Management and Budget, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5252_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial expertise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Financial expertise In carrying out the duties in this subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. or performing analyses of activities under this chapter, the Director of the Congressional Budget Office may employ personnel and procure the services of experts and consultants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5252_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to produce reports required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5252_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sunset Notwithstanding the previous provisions of this section, the reporting and comment requirements under this section shall terminate with the annual period on the last day of which all troubled assets acquired by the Secretary under section 5211 of this title have been sold or transferred out of the ownership or control of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>