<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5323"><akn:num>5323</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to require supervision and regulation of certain nonbank financial companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5323. Authority to require supervision and regulation of certain nonbank financial companies(a) U.S. nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors(1) DeterminationThe Council, on a nondelegable basis and by a vote of not fewer than ⅔ of the voting members then serving, including an affirmative vote by the Chairperson, may determine that a U.S. nonbank financial company shall be supervised by the Board of Governors and shall be subject to prudential standards, in accordance with this subchapter, if the Council determines that material financial distress at the U.S. nonbank financial company, or the nature, scope, size, scale, concentration, interconnectedness, or mix of the activities of the U.S. nonbank financial company, could pose a threat to the financial stability of the United States.


(2) ConsiderationsIn making a determination under paragraph (1), the Council shall consider—(A) the extent of the leverage of the company;

(B) the extent and nature of the off-balance-sheet exposures of the company;

(C) the extent and nature of the transactions and relationships of the company with other significant nonbank financial companies and significant bank holding companies;

(D) the importance of the company as a source of credit for households, businesses, and State and local governments and as a source of liquidity for the United States financial system;

(E) the importance of the company as a source of credit for low-income, minority, or underserved communities, and the impact that the failure of such company would have on the availability of credit in such communities;

(F) the extent to which assets are managed rather than owned by the company, and the extent to which ownership of assets under management is diffuse;

(G) the nature, scope, size, scale, concentration, interconnectedness, and mix of the activities of the company;

(H) the degree to which the company is already regulated by 1 or more primary financial regulatory agencies;

(I) t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>U.S. nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) U.S. nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Foreign nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antievasion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Antievasion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reevaluation and rescission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reevaluation and rescission The Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and opportunity for hearing and final determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice and opportunity for hearing and final determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Emergency exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Consultation The Council shall consult with the primary financial regulatory agency, if any, for each nonbank financial company or subsidiary of a nonbank financial company that is being considered for supervision by the Board of Governors under this section before the Council makes any final determination with respect to such nonbank financial company under subsection (a), (b), or (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Judicial review If the Council makes a final determination under this section with respect to a nonbank financial company, such nonbank financial company may, not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of the notice of final determination under subsection (d)(2), (e)(3), or (f)(5), bring an action in the United States district court for the judicial district in which the home office of such nonbank financial company is located, or in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, for an order requiring that the final determination be rescinded, and the court shall, upon review, dismiss such action or direct the final determination to be rescinded. Review of such an action shall be limited to whether the final determination made under this section was arbitrary and capricious.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5323_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>International coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) International coordination In exercising its duties under this subchapter with respect to foreign nonbank financial companies, foreign-based bank holding companies, and cross-border activities and markets, the Council shall consult with appropriate foreign regulatory authorities, to the extent appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>