<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5325" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5325/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5325/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5325"><akn:num>5325</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced supervision and prudential standards for nonbank financial companies supervised by the Boar</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5325. Enhanced supervision and prudential standards for nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors and certain bank holding companies(a) In general(1) PurposeIn order to prevent or mitigate risks to the financial stability of the United States that could arise from the material financial distress, failure, or ongoing activities of large, interconnected financial institutions, the Council may make recommendations to the Board of Governors concerning the establishment and refinement of prudential standards and reporting and disclosure requirements applicable to nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors and large, interconnected bank holding companies, that—(A) are more stringent than those applicable to other nonbank financial companies and bank holding companies that do not present similar risks to the financial stability of the United States; and

(B) increase in stringency, based on the considerations identified in subsection (b)(3).


(2) Recommended application of required standardsIn making recommendations under this section, the Council may—(A) differentiate among companies that are subject to heightened standards on an individual basis or by category, taking into consideration their capital structure, riskiness, complexity, financial activities (including the financial activities of their subsidiaries), size, and any other risk-related factors that the Council deems appropriate; or

(B) recommend an asset threshold that is higher than the applicable threshold for the application of any standard described in subsections (c) through (g).



(b) Development of prudential standards(1) In generalThe recommendations of the Council under subsection (a) may include—(A) risk-based capital requirements;

(B) leverage limits;

(C) liquidity requirements;

(D) resolution plan and credit exposure report requirements;

(E) concentration limits;

(F) a contingent capital requirement;

(G) enhanced public disclosures;

(H) short-</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of prudential standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development of prudential standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contingent capital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contingent capital</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolution plan and credit exposure reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Resolution plan and credit exposure reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concentration limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Concentration limits In order to limit the risks that the failure of any individual company could pose to nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors or bank holding companies described in subsection (a), the Council may make recommendations to the Board of Governors to prescribe standards to limit such risks, as set forth in section 5365 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced public disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Enhanced public disclosures The Council may make recommendations to the Board of Governors to require periodic public disclosures by bank holding companies described in subsection (a) and by nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors, in order to support market evaluation of the risk profile, capital adequacy, and risk management capabilities thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5325_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short-term debt limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Short-term debt limits The Council may make recommendations to the Board of Governors to require short-term debt limits to mitigate the risks that an over-accumulation of such debt could pose to bank holding companies described in subsection (a), nonbank financial companies supervised by the Board of Governors, or the financial system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>