<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5327" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5327/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5327/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5327"><akn:num>5327</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain companies that cease to be bank holding companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5327. Treatment of certain companies that cease to be bank holding companies(a) ApplicabilityThis section shall apply to—(1) any entity that—(A) was a bank holding company having total consolidated assets equal to or greater than $50,000,000,000 as of January 1, 2010; and

(B) received financial assistance under or participated in the Capital Purchase Program established under the Troubled Asset Relief Program authorized by the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 [12 U.S.C. 5201 et seq.]; and


(2) any successor entity (as defined by the Board of Governors, in consultation with the Council) to an entity described in paragraph (1).


(b) TreatmentIf an entity described in subsection (a) ceases to be a bank holding company at any time after January 1, 2010, then such entity shall be treated as a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors, as if the Council had made a determination under section 5323 of this title with respect to that entity.


(c) Appeal(1) Request for hearingAn entity may request, in writing, an opportunity for a written or oral hearing before the Council to appeal its treatment as a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors in accordance with this section. Upon receipt of the request, the Council shall fix a time (not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of the request) and place at which such entity may appear, personally or through counsel, to submit written materials (or, at the sole discretion of the Council, oral testimony and oral argument).


(2) Decision(A) Proposed decisionA Council decision to grant an appeal under this subsection shall be made by a vote of not fewer than ⅔ of the voting members then serving, including an affirmative vote by the Chairperson. Not later than 60 days after the date of a hearing under paragraph (1), the Council shall submit a report to, and may testify before, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Fina</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5327_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability This section shall apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5327_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treatment If an entity described in subsection (a) ceases to be a bank holding company at any time after January 1, 2010, then such entity shall be treated as a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors, as if the Council had made a determination under section 5323 of this title with respect to that entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5327_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appeal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>