<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5343" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5343/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5343/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5343"><akn:num>5343</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and duties of the Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5343. Purpose and duties of the Office(a) Purpose and dutiesThe purpose of the Office is to support the Council in fulfilling the purposes and duties of the Council, as set forth in part A, and to support member agencies, by—(1) collecting data on behalf of the Council, and providing such data to the Council and member agencies;

(2) standardizing the types and formats of data reported and collected;

(3) performing applied research and essential long-term research;

(4) developing tools for risk measurement and monitoring;

(5) performing other related services;

(6) making the results of the activities of the Office available to financial regulatory agencies; and

(7) assisting such member agencies in determining the types and formats of data authorized by this Act to be collected by such member agencies.


(b) Administrative authorityThe Office may—(1) share data and information, including software developed by the Office, with the Council, member agencies, and the Bureau of Economic Analysis, which shared data, information, and software—(A) shall be maintained with at least the same level of security as is used by the Office; and

(B) may not be shared with any individual or entity without the permission of the Council;


(2) sponsor and conduct research projects; and

(3) assist, on a reimbursable basis, with financial analyses undertaken at the request of other Federal agencies that are not member agencies.


(c) Rulemaking authority(1) ScopeThe Office, in consultation with the Chairperson, shall issue rules, regulations, and orders only to the extent necessary to carry out the purposes and duties described in paragraphs (1), (2), and (7) of subsection (a).


(2) StandardizationMember agencies, in consultation with the Office, shall implement regulations promulgated by the Office under paragraph (1) to standardize the types and formats of data reported and collected on behalf of the Council, as described in subsection (a)(2). If a member agency fails to impl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5343_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose and duties The purpose of the Office is to support the Council in fulfilling the purposes and duties of the Council, as set forth in part A, and to support member agencies, by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5343_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrative authority The Office may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5343_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rulemaking authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5343_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testimony</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Testimony</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5343_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional reports The Director may provide additional reports to Congress concerning the financial stability of the United States. The Director shall notify the Council of any such additional reports provided to Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5343_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoena</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Subpoena</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>