<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5346" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5346/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5346/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5346"><akn:num>5346</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5346. Transition oversight(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to ensure that the Office—(1) has an orderly and organized startup;

(2) attracts and retains a qualified workforce; and

(3) establishes comprehensive employee training and benefits programs.


(b) Reporting requirement(1) In generalThe Office shall submit an annual report to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives that includes the plans described in paragraph (2).


(2) PlansThe plans described in this paragraph are as follows:(A) Training and workforce development planThe Office shall submit a training and workforce development plan that includes, to the extent practicable—(i) identification of skill and technical expertise needs and actions taken to meet those requirements;

(ii) steps taken to foster innovation and creativity;

(iii) leadership development and succession planning; and

(iv) effective use of technology by employees.


(B) Workplace flexibility planThe Office shall submit a workforce flexibility plan that includes, to the extent practicable—(i) telework;

(ii) flexible work schedules;

(iii) phased retirement;

(iv) reemployed annuitants;

(v) part-time work;

(vi) job sharing;

(vii) parental leave benefits and childcare assistance;

(viii) domestic partner benefits;

(ix) other workplace flexibilities; or

(x) any combination of the items described in clauses (i) through (ix).


(C) Recruitment and retention planThe Office shall submit a recruitment and retention plan that includes, to the extent practicable, provisions relating to—(i) the steps necessary to target highly qualified applicant pools with diverse backgrounds;

(ii) streamlined employment application processes;

(iii) the provision of timely notification of the status of employment applications to applicants; and

(iv) the collection of information to measure indicators of hiring effectiveness.




(c) ExpirationTh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5346_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to ensure that the Office—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5346_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reporting requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5346_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expiration The reporting requirement under subsection (b) shall terminate 5 years after July 21, 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5346_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construed to affect—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>