<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5367" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5367/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5367/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5367"><akn:num>5367</akn:num><akn:heading>Affiliations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5367. Affiliations(a) AffiliationsNothing in this part shall be construed to require a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors, or a company that controls a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors, to conform the activities thereof to the requirements of section 1843 of this title.


(b) Requirement(1) In general(A) Board authorityIf a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors conducts activities other than those that are determined to be financial in nature or incidental thereto under section 1843(k) of this title, the Board of Governors may require such company to establish and conduct all or a portion of such activities that are determined to be financial in nature or incidental thereto in or through an intermediate holding company established pursuant to regulation of the Board of Governors, not later than 90 days (or such longer period as the Board of Governors may deem appropriate) after the date on which the nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors is notified of the determination of the Board of Governors under this section.


(B) Necessary actionsNotwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Board of Governors shall require a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors to establish an intermediate holding company if the Board of Governors makes a determination that the establishment of such intermediate holding company is necessary to—(i) appropriately supervise activities that are determined to be financial in nature or incidental thereto; or

(ii) to 11 So in original. The word “to” probably should not appear. ensure that supervision by the Board of Governors does not extend to the commercial activities of such nonbank financial company.



(2) Internal financial activitiesFor purposes of this subsection, activities that are determined to be financial in nature or incidental thereto under section 1843(k) of this title, as described in paragraph (1), shall</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5367_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affiliations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Affiliations Nothing in this part shall be construed to require a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors, or a company that controls a nonbank financial company supervised by the Board of Governors, to conform the activities thereof to the requirements of section 1843 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5367_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5367_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations The Board of Governors—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>