<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5381" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5381/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5381/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5381"><akn:num>5381</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5381. Definitions(a) In generalIn this subchapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Administrative expenses of the receiverThe term “administrative expenses of the receiver” includes—(A) the actual, necessary costs and expenses incurred by the Corporation as receiver for a covered financial company in liquidating a covered financial company; and

(B) any obligations that the Corporation as receiver for a covered financial company determines are necessary and appropriate to facilitate the smooth and orderly liquidation of the covered financial company.


(2) Bankruptcy CodeThe term “Bankruptcy Code” means title 11.


(3) Bridge financial companyThe term “bridge financial company” means a new financial company organized by the Corporation in accordance with section 5390(h) of this title for the purpose of resolving a covered financial company.


(4) ClaimThe term “claim” means any right to payment, whether or not such right is reduced to judgment, liquidated, unliquidated, fixed, contingent, matured, unmatured, disputed, undisputed, legal, equitable, secured, or unsecured.


(5) CompanyThe term “company” has the same meaning as in section 1841(b) of this title, except that such term includes any company described in paragraph (11), the majority of the securities of which are owned by the United States or any State.


(6) CourtThe term “Court” means the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, unless the context otherwise requires.


(7) Covered broker or dealerThe term “covered broker or dealer” means a covered financial company that is a broker or dealer that—(A) is registered with the Commission under section 78o(b) of title 15; and

(B) is a member of SIPC.


(8) Covered financial companyThe term “covered financial company”—(A) means a financial company for which a determination has been made under section 5383(b) of this title; and

(B) does not include an insured depository institution.


(9) Covered subsidiaryThe term “covered subsid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5381_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In this subchapter, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5381_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitional criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitional criteria For purpose of the definition of the term “financial company” under subsection (a)(11), no company shall be deemed to be predominantly engaged in activities that the Board of Governors has determined are financial in nature or incidental thereto for purposes of section 1843(k) of this title, if the consolidated revenues of such company from such activities constitute less than 85 percent of the total consolidated revenues of such company, as the Corporation, in consultation with the Secretary, shall establish by regulation. In determining whether a company is a financial company under this subchapter, the consolidated revenues derived from the ownership or control of a depository institution shall be included.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>