<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5382" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5382/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5382/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5382"><akn:num>5382</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5382. Judicial review(a) Commencement of orderly liquidation(1) Petition to District Court(A) District Court review(i) Petition to District CourtSubsequent to a determination by the Secretary under section 5383 of this title that a financial company satisfies the criteria in section 5383(b) of this title, the Secretary shall notify the Corporation and the covered financial company. If the board of directors (or body performing similar functions) of the covered financial company acquiesces or consents to the appointment of the Corporation as receiver, the Secretary shall appoint the Corporation as receiver. If the board of directors (or body performing similar functions) of the covered financial company does not acquiesce or consent to the appointment of the Corporation as receiver, the Secretary shall petition the United States District Court for the District of Columbia for an order authorizing the Secretary to appoint the Corporation as receiver.


(ii) Form and content of orderThe Secretary shall present all relevant findings and the recommendation made pursuant to section 5383(a) of this title to the Court. The petition shall be filed under seal.


(iii) DeterminationOn a strictly confidential basis, and without any prior public disclosure, the Court, after notice to the covered financial company and a hearing in which the covered financial company may oppose the petition, shall determine whether the determination of the Secretary that the covered financial company is in default or in danger of default and satisfies the definition of a financial company under section 5381(a)(11) of this title is arbitrary and capricious.


(iv) Issuance of orderIf the Court determines that the determination of the Secretary that the covered financial company is in default or in danger of default and satisfies the definition of a financial company under section 5381(a)(11) of this title—(I) is not arbitrary and capricious, the Court shall issue an order immediately authorizing </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5382_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of orderly liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Commencement of orderly liquidation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5382_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and transmittal of rules and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment and transmittal of rules and procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5382_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions applicable to financial companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provisions applicable to financial companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5382_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time limit on receivership authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time limit on receivership authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5382_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of bankruptcy and orderly liquidation process for financial companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Study of bankruptcy and orderly liquidation process for financial companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5382_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of international coordination relating to bankruptcy process for financial companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Study of international coordination relating to bankruptcy process for financial companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5382_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of prompt corrective action implementation by the appropriate Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Study of prompt corrective action implementation by the appropriate Federal agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>