<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5385" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5385/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5385/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5385"><akn:num>5385</akn:num><akn:heading>Orderly liquidation of covered brokers and dealers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5385. Orderly liquidation of covered brokers and dealers(a) Appointment of SIPC as trustee(1) AppointmentUpon the appointment of the Corporation as receiver for any covered broker or dealer, the Corporation shall appoint, without any need for court approval, the Securities Investor Protection Corporation to act as trustee for the liquidation under the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 78aaa et seq.) of the covered broker or dealer.


(2) Actions by SIPC(A) FilingUpon appointment of SIPC under paragraph (1), SIPC shall promptly file with any Federal district court of competent jurisdiction specified in section 78u or 78aa of title 15, an application for a protective decree under the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 78aaa et seq.) as to the covered broker or dealer. The Federal district court shall accept and approve the filing, including outside of normal business hours, and shall immediately issue the protective decree as to the covered broker or dealer.


(B) Administration by SIPCFollowing entry of the protective decree, and except as otherwise provided in this section, the determination of claims and the liquidation of assets retained in the receivership of the covered broker or dealer and not transferred to the bridge financial company shall be administered under the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 78aaa et seq.) by SIPC, as trustee for the covered broker or dealer.


(C) Definition of filing dateFor purposes of the liquidation proceeding, the term “filing date” means the date on which the Corporation is appointed as receiver of the covered broker or dealer.


(D) Determination of claimsAs trustee for the covered broker or dealer, SIPC shall determine and satisfy, consistent with this subchapter and with the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 78aaa et seq.), all claims against the covered broker or dealer arising on or before the filing date.




(b) Powers and duties of SIPC(1) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5385_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of SIPC as trustee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment of SIPC as trustee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5385_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of SIPC</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Powers and duties of SIPC</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5385_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on court action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on court action Except as otherwise provided in this subchapter, no court may take any action, including any action pursuant to the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 78aaa et seq.) or the Bankruptcy Code, to restrain or affect the exercise of powers or functions of the Corporation as receiver for a covered broker or dealer and any claims against the Corporation as such receiver shall be determined in accordance with subsection (e) and such claims shall be limited to money damages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5385_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by Corporation as receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Actions by Corporation as receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5385_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claims against the Corporation as receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Claims against the Corporation as receiver Any claim against the Corporation as receiver for a covered broker or dealer for assets transferred to a bridge financial company established with respect to such covered broker or dealer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5385_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Satisfaction of customer claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Satisfaction of customer claims</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5385_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Priorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5385_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rulemaking The Commission and the Corporation, after consultation with SIPC, shall jointly issue rules to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>