<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5388" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5388/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5388/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5388"><akn:num>5388</akn:num><akn:heading>Dismissal and exclusion of other actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5388. Dismissal and exclusion of other actions(a) In generalEffective as of the date of the appointment of the Corporation as receiver for the covered financial company under section 5382 of this title or the appointment of SIPC as trustee for a covered broker or dealer under section 5385 of this title, as applicable, any case or proceeding commenced with respect to the covered financial company under the Bankruptcy Code or the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 78aaa et seq.) shall be dismissed, upon notice to the bankruptcy court (with respect to a case commenced under the Bankruptcy Code), and upon notice to SIPC (with respect to a covered broker or dealer) and no such case or proceeding may be commenced with respect to a covered financial company at any time while the orderly liquidation is pending.


(b) Revesting of assetsEffective as of the date of appointment of the Corporation as receiver, the assets of a covered financial company shall, to the extent they have vested in any entity other than the covered financial company as a result of any case or proceeding commenced with respect to the covered financial company under the Bankruptcy Code, the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 78aaa et seq.), or any similar provision of State liquidation or insolvency law applicable to the covered financial company, revest in the covered financial company.


(c) LimitationNotwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), any order entered or other relief granted by a bankruptcy court prior to the date of appointment of the Corporation as receiver shall continue with the same validity as if an orderly liquidation had not been commenced.


(Pub. L. 111–203, title II, § 208, July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 1459.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is Pub. L. 91–598, Dec. 30, 1970, 84 Stat. 1636, which is classified generally to chapter 2B–1 (§ 78aaa et seq.) of Title</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5388_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Effective as of the date of the appointment of the Corporation as receiver for the covered financial company under section 5382 of this title or the appointment of SIPC as trustee for a covered broker or dealer under section 5385 of this title, as applicable, any case or proceeding commenced with respect to the covered financial company under the Bankruptcy Code or the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 78aaa et seq.) shall be dismissed, upon notice to the bankruptcy court (with respect to a case commenced under the Bankruptcy Code), and upon notice to SIPC (with respect to a covered broker or dealer) and no such case or proceeding may be commenced with respect to a covered financial company at any time while the orderly liquidation is pending.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5388_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revesting of assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Revesting of assets Effective as of the date of appointment of the Corporation as receiver, the assets of a covered financial company shall, to the extent they have vested in any entity other than the covered financial company as a result of any case or proceeding commenced with respect to the covered financial company under the Bankruptcy Code, the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (15 U.S.C. 78aaa et seq.), or any similar provision of State liquidation or insolvency law applicable to the covered financial company, revest in the covered financial company.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5388_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), any order entered or other relief granted by a bankruptcy court prior to the date of appointment of the Corporation as receiver shall continue with the same validity as if an orderly liquidation had not been commenced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>