<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5390" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5390/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5390/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5390"><akn:num>5390</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of the Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5390. Powers and duties of the Corporation(a) Powers and authorities(1) General powers(A) Successor to covered financial companyThe Corporation shall, upon appointment as receiver for a covered financial company under this subchapter, succeed to—(i) all rights, titles, powers, and privileges of the covered financial company and its assets, and of any stockholder, member, officer, or director of such company; and

(ii) title to the books, records, and assets of any previous receiver or other legal custodian of such covered financial company.


(B) Operation of the covered financial company during the period of orderly liquidationThe Corporation, as receiver for a covered financial company, may—(i) take over the assets of and operate the covered financial company with all of the powers of the members or shareholders, the directors, and the officers of the covered financial company, and conduct all business of the covered financial company;

(ii) collect all obligations and money owed to the covered financial company;

(iii) perform all functions of the covered financial company, in the name of the covered financial company;

(iv) manage the assets and property of the covered financial company, consistent with maximization of the value of the assets in the context of the orderly liquidation; and

(v) provide by contract for assistance in fulfilling any function, activity, action, or duty of the Corporation as receiver.


(C) Functions of covered financial company officers, directors, and shareholdersThe Corporation may provide for the exercise of any function by any member or stockholder, director, or officer of any covered financial company for which the Corporation has been appointed as receiver under this subchapter.


(D) Additional powers as receiverThe Corporation shall, as receiver for a covered financial company, and subject to all legally enforceable and perfected security interests and all legally enforceable security entitlements in respect of assets held </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Powers and authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority of expenses and unsecured claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority of expenses and unsecured claims</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to contracts entered into before appointment of receiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provisions relating to contracts entered into before appointment of receiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation of claims in default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Valuation of claims in default</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on court action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on court action Except as provided in this subchapter, no court may take any action to restrain or affect the exercise of powers or functions of the receiver hereunder, and any remedy against the Corporation or receiver shall be limited to money damages determined in accordance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of directors and officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Liability of directors and officers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Damages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Damages In any proceeding related to any claim against a director, officer, employee, agent, attorney, accountant, or appraiser of a covered financial company, or any other party employed by or providing services to a covered financial company, recoverable damages determined to result from the improvident or otherwise improper use or investment of any assets of the covered financial company shall include principal losses and appropriate interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bridge financial companies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Bridge financial companies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Sharing records If the Corporation has been appointed as receiver for a covered financial company, other Federal regulators shall make all records relating to the covered financial company available to the Corporation, which may be used by the Corporation in any manner that the Corporation determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5390_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited procedures for certain claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Expedited procedures for certain claims</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>