<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5435" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5435/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5435/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5435"><akn:num>5435</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of affairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5435. Disposition of affairs(a) Authority of DirectorDuring the 90-day period beginning on the transfer date, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision—(1) shall, solely for the purpose of winding up the affairs of the Office of Thrift Supervision relating to any function transferred to the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Corporation, or the Board of Governors under this title— 11 See References in Text note below.(A) manage the employees of the Office of Thrift Supervision who have not yet been transferred and provide for the payment of the compensation and benefits of the employees that accrue before the date on which the employees are transferred under this title; 1 and

(B) manage any property of the Office of Thrift Supervision, until the date on which the property is transferred under section 5433 of this title; and


(2) may take any other action necessary to wind up the affairs of the Office of Thrift Supervision.


(b) Status of Director(1) In generalNotwithstanding the transfer of functions under this part, during the 90-day period beginning on the transfer date, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision shall retain and may exercise any authority vested in the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision on the day before the transfer date, only to the extent necessary—(A) to wind up the Office of Thrift Supervision; and

(B) to carry out the transfer under this part during such 90-day period.


(2) Other provisionsFor purposes of paragraph (1), the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision shall, during the 90-day period beginning on the transfer date, continue to be—(A) treated as an officer of the United States; and

(B) entitled to receive compensation at the same annual rate of basic pay that the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision received on the day before the transfer date.



(Pub. L. 111–203, title III, § 325, July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 1536.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis title, where footnote</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5435_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Director During the 90-day period beginning on the transfer date, the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5435_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Status of Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>