<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5452" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5452/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5452/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5452"><akn:num>5452</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Minority and Women Inclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5452. Office of Minority and Women Inclusion(a) Office of Minority and Women Inclusion(1) Establishment(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), not later than 6 months after July 21, 2010, each agency shall establish an Office of Minority and Women Inclusion that shall be responsible for all matters of the agency relating to diversity in management, employment, and business activities.


(B) BureauThe Bureau shall establish an Office of Minority and Women Inclusion not later than 6 months after the designated transfer date established under section 5582 of this title.



(2) Transfer of responsibilitiesEach agency that, on the day before July 21, 2010, assigned the responsibilities described in paragraph (1) (or comparable responsibilities) to another office of the agency shall ensure that such responsibilities are transferred to the Office.


(3) Duties with respect to civil rights lawsThe responsibilities described in paragraph (1) do not include enforcement of statutes, regulations, or executive orders pertaining to civil rights, except each Director shall coordinate with the agency administrator, or the designee of the agency administrator, regarding the design and implementation of any remedies resulting from violations of such statutes, regulations, or executive orders.



(b) Director(1) In generalThe Director of each Office shall be appointed by, and shall report to, the agency administrator. The position of Director shall be a career reserved position in the Senior Executive Service, as that position is defined in section 3132 of title 5, or an equivalent designation.


(2) DutiesEach Director shall develop standards for—(A) equal employment opportunity and the racial, ethnic, and gender diversity of the workforce and senior management of the agency;

(B) increased participation of minority-owned and women-owned businesses in the programs and contracts of the agency, including standards for coordinating technical assistance to such businesses</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Minority and Women Inclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Office of Minority and Women Inclusion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion in all levels of business activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inclusion in all levels of business activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability This section shall apply to all contracts of an agency for services of any kind, including the services of financial institutions, investment banking firms, mortgage banking firms, asset management firms, brokers, dealers, financial services entities, underwriters, accountants, investment consultants, and providers of legal services. The contracts referred to in this subsection include all contracts for all business and activities of an agency, at all levels, including contracts for the issuance or guarantee of any debt, equity, or security, the sale of assets, the management of the assets of the agency, the making of equity investments by the agency, and the implementation by the agency of programs to address economic recovery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports Each Office shall submit to Congress an annual report regarding the actions taken by the agency and the Office pursuant to this section, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diversity in agency workforce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Diversity in agency workforce Each agency shall take affirmative steps to seek diversity in the workforce of the agency at all levels of the agency in a manner consistent with applicable law. Such steps shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>