<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5462" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5462/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5462/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5462"><akn:num>5462</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5462. Definitions
In this subchapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Appropriate financial regulatorThe term “appropriate financial regulator” means—(A) the primary financial regulatory agency, as defined in section 5301 of this title;

(B) the National Credit Union Administration, with respect to any insured credit union under the Federal Credit Union Act (12 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.); and

(C) the Board of Governors, with respect to organizations operating under section 25A of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 611), and any other financial institution engaged in a designated activity.


(2) Designated activityThe term “designated activity” means a payment, clearing, or settlement activity that the Council has designated as systemically important under section 5463 of this title.


(3) Designated clearing entityThe term “designated clearing entity” means a designated financial market utility that is a derivatives clearing organization registered under section 5b of the Commodity Exchange Act (7 U.S.C. 7a–1) or a clearing agency registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission under section 17A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78q–1).


(4) Designated financial market utilityThe term “designated financial market utility” means a financial market utility that the Council has designated as systemically important under section 5463 of this title.


(5) Financial institution(A) In generalThe term “financial institution” means—(i) a depository institution, as defined in section 1813 of this title;

(ii) a branch or agency of a foreign bank, as defined in section 3101 of this title;

(iii) an organization operating under section 25 or 25A of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 601–604a and 611 through 631);

(iv) a credit union, as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (12 U.S.C. 1752); 11 See References in Text note below.

(v) a broker or dealer, as defined in section 3 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5462_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate financial regulator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Appropriate financial regulator The term “appropriate financial regulator” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5462_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Designated activity The term “designated activity” means a payment, clearing, or settlement activity that the Council has designated as systemically important under section 5463 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5462_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated clearing entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Designated clearing entity The term “designated clearing entity” means a designated financial market utility that is a derivatives clearing organization registered under section 5b of the Commodity Exchange Act (7 U.S.C. 7a–1) or a clearing agency registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission under section 17A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78q–1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5462_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated financial market utility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Designated financial market utility The term “designated financial market utility” means a financial market utility that the Council has designated as systemically important under section 5463 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5462_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Financial institution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5462_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial market utility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Financial market utility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5462_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment, clearing, or settlement activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Payment, clearing, or settlement activity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5462_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervisory Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Supervisory Agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5462_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Systemically important and systemic importance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Systemically important and systemic importance The terms “systemically important” and “systemic importance” mean a situation where the failure of or a disruption to the functioning of a financial market utility or the conduct of a payment, clearing, or settlement activity could create, or increase, the risk of significant liquidity or credit problems spreading among financial institutions or markets and thereby threaten the stability of the financial system of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>