<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5465" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5465/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5465/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5465"><akn:num>5465</akn:num><akn:heading>Operations of designated financial market utilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5465. Operations of designated financial market utilities(a) Federal Reserve account and servicesThe Board of Governors may authorize a Federal Reserve Bank to establish and maintain an account for a designated financial market utility and provide the services listed in section 11A(b) of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 248a(b)) and deposit accounts under the first undesignated paragraph of section 13 of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 342) to the designated financial market utility that the Federal Reserve Bank is authorized under the Federal Reserve Act [12 U.S.C. 221 et seq.] to provide to a depository institution, subject to any applicable rules, orders, standards, or guidelines prescribed by the Board of Governors.


(b) AdvancesThe Board of Governors may authorize a Federal Reserve bank under section 10B of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 347b) to provide to a designated financial market utility discount and borrowing privileges only in unusual or exigent circumstances, upon the affirmative vote of a majority of the Board of Governors then serving (or such other number in accordance with the provisions of section 11(r)(2) of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 248(r)(2)) 11 So in original. Another closing parenthesis probably should appear. after consultation with the Secretary, and upon a showing by the designated financial market utility that it is unable to secure adequate credit accommodations from other banking institutions. All such discounts and borrowing privileges shall be subject to such other limitations, restrictions, and regulations as the Board of Governors may prescribe. Access to discount and borrowing privileges under section 10B of the Federal Reserve Act as authorized in this section does not require a designated financial market utility to be or become a bank or bank holding company.


(c) Earnings on Federal Reserve balancesA Federal Reserve Bank may pay earnings on balances maintained by or on behalf of a designated financial mar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5465_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Reserve account and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal Reserve account and services The Board of Governors may authorize a Federal Reserve Bank to establish and maintain an account for a designated financial market utility and provide the services listed in section 11A(b) of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 248a(b)) and deposit accounts under the first undesignated paragraph of section 13 of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 342) to the designated financial market utility that the Federal Reserve Bank is authorized under the Federal Reserve Act [12 U.S.C. 221 et seq.] to provide to a depository institution, subject to any applicable rules, orders, standards, or guidelines prescribed by the Board of Governors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5465_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advances The Board of Governors may authorize a Federal Reserve bank under section 10B of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 347b) to provide to a designated financial market utility discount and borrowing privileges only in unusual or exigent circumstances, upon the affirmative vote of a majority of the Board of Governors then serving (or such other number in accordance with the provisions of section 11(r)(2) of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 248(r)(2)) 11 So in original. Another closing parenthesis probably should appear. after consultation with the Secretary, and upon a showing by the designated financial market utility that it is unable to secure adequate credit accommodations from other banking institutions. All such discounts and borrowing privileges shall be subject to such other limitations, restrictions, and regulations as the Board of Governors may prescribe. Access to discount and borrowing privileges under section 10B of the Federal Reserve Act as authorized in this</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5465_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Earnings on Federal Reserve balances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Earnings on Federal Reserve balances A Federal Reserve Bank may pay earnings on balances maintained by or on behalf of a designated financial market utility in the same manner and to the same extent as the Federal Reserve Bank may pay earnings to a depository institution under the Federal Reserve Act [12 U.S.C. 221 et seq.], subject to any applicable rules, orders, standards, or guidelines prescribed by the Board of Governors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5465_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reserve requirements The Board of Governors may exempt a designated financial market utility from, or modify any, reserve requirements under section 19 of the Federal Reserve Act (12 U.S.C. 461) applicable to a designated financial market utility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5465_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes to rules, procedures, or operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Changes to rules, procedures, or operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>