<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5466" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5466/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5466/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5466"><akn:num>5466</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of and enforcement actions against designated financial market utilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5466. Examination of and enforcement actions against designated financial market utilities(a) ExaminationNotwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subsection (d), the Supervisory Agency shall conduct examinations of a designated financial market utility at least once annually in order to determine the following:(1) The nature of the operations of, and the risks borne by, the designated financial market utility.

(2) The financial and operational risks presented by the designated financial market utility to financial institutions, critical markets, or the broader financial system.

(3) The resources and capabilities of the designated financial market utility to monitor and control such risks.

(4) The safety and soundness of the designated financial market utility.

(5) The designated financial market utility’s compliance with—(A) this subchapter; and

(B) the rules and orders prescribed under this subchapter.



(b) Service providersWhenever a service integral to the operation of a designated financial market utility is performed for the designated financial market utility by another entity, whether an affiliate or non-affiliate and whether on or off the premises of the designated financial market utility, the Supervisory Agency may examine whether the provision of that service is in compliance with applicable law, rules, orders, and standards to the same extent as if the designated financial market utility were performing the service on its own premises.


(c) EnforcementFor purposes of enforcing the provisions of this subchapter, a designated financial market utility shall be subject to, and the appropriate Supervisory Agency shall have authority under the provisions of subsections (b) through (n) of section 1818 of this title in the same manner and to the same extent as if the designated financial market utility was an insured depository institution and the Supervisory Agency was the appropriate Federal banking agency for such insured depository</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5466_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Examination Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subsection (d), the Supervisory Agency shall conduct examinations of a designated financial market utility at least once annually in order to determine the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5466_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Service providers Whenever a service integral to the operation of a designated financial market utility is performed for the designated financial market utility by another entity, whether an affiliate or non-affiliate and whether on or off the premises of the designated financial market utility, the Supervisory Agency may examine whether the provision of that service is in compliance with applicable law, rules, orders, and standards to the same extent as if the designated financial market utility were performing the service on its own premises.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5466_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement For purposes of enforcing the provisions of this subchapter, a designated financial market utility shall be subject to, and the appropriate Supervisory Agency shall have authority under the provisions of subsections (b) through (n) of section 1818 of this title in the same manner and to the same extent as if the designated financial market utility was an insured depository institution and the Supervisory Agency was the appropriate Federal banking agency for such insured depository institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5466_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Governors involvement in examinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Board of Governors involvement in examinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5466_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Governors enforcement recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Board of Governors enforcement recommendations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5466_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency enforcement actions by the Board of Governors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Emergency enforcement actions by the Board of Governors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>