<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/548" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/548/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/548/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_548"><akn:num>548</akn:num><akn:heading>State taxation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 548. State taxation
For the purposes of any tax law enacted under authority of the United States or any State, a national bank shall be treated as a bank organized and existing under the laws of the State or other jurisdiction within which its principal office is located.
(R.S. § 5219; Mar. 4, 1923, ch. 267, 42 Stat. 1499; Mar. 25, 1926, ch. 88, 44 Stat. 223; Pub. L. 91–156, §§ 1(a), 2(a), Dec. 24, 1969, 83 Stat. 434.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
R.S. § 5219 derived from act June 3, 1864, ch. 106, § 41, 13 Stat. 111, which was the National Bank Act, and act Feb. 10, 1868, ch. 7, 15 Stat. 34. See section 38 of this title.

Amendments1969—Pub. L. 91–156, § 2(a), substituted provisions directing that national banks, for purposes of both Federal and State tax laws, be treated as banks organized and existing under the laws of the State or other jurisdiction within which each bank’s principal office is located for provisions placing restrictions on the taxation of national bank shares and, for the period until the effective date of such amendment, set out interim provisions regarding intangible personal property taxes of States and local governments on national banks.
Pub. L. 91–156, § 1(a), added par. 5.
1926—Act Mar. 25, 1926, among other changes inserted “on their net income” in cl. (3) of former opening par., and added cl. (4) thereto, and inserted proviso in former subsec. 1(c).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1969 AmendmentPub. L. 91–156, § 1(b), Dec. 24, 1969, 83 Stat. 434, provided that: “The amendment made by subsection (a) of this section [setting out interim provisions regarding intangible personal property taxes of State and local governments on national banks] shall be effective from the date of enactment of this Act [Dec. 24, 1969] until the effective date [Jan. 1, 1973] of the amendment made by section 2(a) of this Act [removing restrictions on the taxation of national bank shares and directing that national banks, for purpos</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>