<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5481" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5481/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5481/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5481"><akn:num>5481</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5481. Definitions
Except as otherwise provided in this title,11 See References in Text note below. for purposes of this title,1 the following definitions shall apply:(1) AffiliateThe term “affiliate” means any person that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another person.


(2) BureauThe term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.


(3) Business of insuranceThe term “business of insurance” means the writing of insurance or the reinsuring of risks by an insurer, including all acts necessary to such writing or reinsuring and the activities relating to the writing of insurance or the reinsuring of risks conducted by persons who act as, or are, officers, directors, agents, or employees of insurers or who are other persons authorized to act on behalf of such persons.


(4) ConsumerThe term “consumer” means an individual or an agent, trustee, or representative acting on behalf of an individual.


(5) Consumer financial product or serviceThe term “consumer financial product or service” means any financial product or service that is described in one or more categories under—(A) paragraph (15) and is offered or provided for use by consumers primarily for personal, family, or household purposes; or

(B) clause (i), (iii), (ix), or (x) of paragraph (15)(A), and is delivered, offered, or provided in connection with a consumer financial product or service referred to in subparagraph (A).


(6) Covered personThe term “covered person” means—(A) any person that engages in offering or providing a consumer financial product or service; and

(B) any affiliate of a person described in subparagraph (A) if such affiliate acts as a service provider to such person.


(7) CreditThe term “credit” means the right granted by a person to a consumer to defer payment of a debt, incur debt and defer its payment, or purchase property or services and defer payment for such purchase.


(8) Deposit-taking activityThe term “deposit-taking activity” means—</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affiliate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Affiliate The term “affiliate” means any person that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with another person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Bureau The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Business of insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Business of insurance The term “business of insurance” means the writing of insurance or the reinsuring of risks by an insurer, including all acts necessary to such writing or reinsuring and the activities relating to the writing of insurance or the reinsuring of risks conducted by persons who act as, or are, officers, directors, agents, or employees of insurers or who are other persons authorized to act on behalf of such persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Consumer The term “consumer” means an individual or an agent, trustee, or representative acting on behalf of an individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer financial product or service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Consumer financial product or service The term “consumer financial product or service” means any financial product or service that is described in one or more categories under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Covered person The term “covered person” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Credit The term “credit” means the right granted by a person to a consumer to defer payment of a debt, incur debt and defer its payment, or purchase property or services and defer payment for such purchase.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit-taking activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Deposit-taking activity The term “deposit-taking activity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated transfer date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Designated transfer date The term “designated transfer date” means the date established under section 5582 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5481_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Director The term “Director” means the Director of the Bureau.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>