<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5491" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5491/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5491/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5491"><akn:num>5491</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5491. Establishment of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection(a) Bureau establishedThere is established in the Federal Reserve System, an independent bureau to be known as the “Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection”, which shall regulate the offering and provision of consumer financial products or services under the Federal consumer financial laws. The Bureau shall be considered an Executive agency, as defined in section 105 of title 5. Except as otherwise provided expressly by law, all Federal laws dealing with public or Federal contracts, property, works, officers, employees, budgets, or funds, including the provisions of chapters 5 and 7 of title 5, shall apply to the exercise of the powers of the Bureau.


(b) Director and Deputy Director(1) In generalThere is established the position of the Director, who shall serve as the head of the Bureau.


(2) AppointmentSubject to paragraph (3), the Director shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(3) QualificationThe President shall nominate the Director from among individuals who are citizens of the United States.


(4) CompensationThe Director shall be compensated at the rate prescribed for level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of title 5.


(5) Deputy DirectorThere is established the position of Deputy Director, who shall—(A) be appointed by the Director; and

(B) serve as acting Director in the absence or unavailability of the Director.



(c) Term(1) In generalThe Director shall serve for a term of 5 years.


(2) Expiration of termAn individual may serve as Director after the expiration of the term for which appointed, until a successor has been appointed and qualified.


(3) Removal for causeThe President may remove the Director for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.



(d) Service restrictionNo Director or Deputy Director may hold any office, position, or employment in any Federal reserve bank, Federal home loan bank, c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5491_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau established</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Bureau established There is established in the Federal Reserve System, an independent bureau to be known as the “Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection”, which shall regulate the offering and provision of consumer financial products or services under the Federal consumer financial laws. The Bureau shall be considered an Executive agency, as defined in section 105 of title 5. Except as otherwise provided expressly by law, all Federal laws dealing with public or Federal contracts, property, works, officers, employees, budgets, or funds, including the provisions of chapters 5 and 7 of title 5, shall apply to the exercise of the powers of the Bureau.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5491_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director and Deputy Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Director and Deputy Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5491_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Term</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5491_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Service restriction No Director or Deputy Director may hold any office, position, or employment in any Federal reserve bank, Federal home loan bank, covered person, or service provider during the period of service of such person as Director or Deputy Director.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5491_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Offices The principal office of the Bureau shall be in the District of Columbia. The Director may establish regional offices of the Bureau, including in cities in which the Federal reserve banks, or branches of such banks, are located, in order to carry out the responsibilities assigned to the Bureau under the Federal consumer financial laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>