<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5497" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5497/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5497/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5497"><akn:num>5497</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding; penalties and fines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5497. Funding; penalties and fines(a) Transfer of funds from Board Of Governors(1) In generalEach year (or quarter of such year), beginning on the designated transfer date, and each quarter thereafter, the Board of Governors shall transfer to the Bureau from the combined earnings of the Federal Reserve System, the amount determined by the Director to be reasonably necessary to carry out the authorities of the Bureau under Federal consumer financial law, taking into account such other sums made available to the Bureau from the preceding year (or quarter of such year).


(2) Funding cap(A) In generalNotwithstanding paragraph (1), and in accordance with this paragraph, the amount that shall be transferred to the Bureau in each fiscal year shall not exceed a fixed percentage of the total operating expenses of the Federal Reserve System, as reported in the Annual Report, 2009, of the Board of Governors, equal to—(i) 10 percent of such expenses in fiscal year 2011;

(ii) 11 percent of such expenses in fiscal year 2012; and

(iii) 6.5 percent of such expenses in fiscal year 2013, and in each year thereafter.


(B) Adjustment of amountThe dollar amount referred to in subparagraph (A)(iii) shall be adjusted annually, using the percent increase, if any, in the employment cost index for total compensation for State and local government workers published by the Federal Government, or the successor index thereto, for the 12-month period ending on September 30 of the year preceding the transfer.


(C) ReviewabilityNotwithstanding any other provision in this title,11 See References in Text note below. the funds derived from the Federal Reserve System pursuant to this subsection shall not be subject to review by the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.



(3) Transition periodBeginning on July 21, 2010, and until the designated transfer date, the Board of Governors shall transfer to the Bureau the amount estimated by the Secretary needed to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5497_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of funds from Board Of Governors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer of funds from Board Of Governors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5497_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer Financial Protection Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consumer Financial Protection Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5497_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5497_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties and fines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Penalties and fines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5497_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations; annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations; annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>