<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5514" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5514/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5514/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5514"><akn:num>5514</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of nondepository covered persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5514. Supervision of nondepository covered persons(a) Scope of coverage(1) ApplicabilityNotwithstanding any other provision of this title,11 See References in Text note below. and except as provided in paragraph (3), this section shall apply to any covered person who—(A) offers or provides origination, brokerage, or servicing of loans secured by real estate for use by consumers primarily for personal, family, or household purposes, or loan modification or foreclosure relief services in connection with such loans;

(B) is a larger participant of a market for other consumer financial products or services, as defined by rule in accordance with paragraph (2);

(C) the Bureau has reasonable cause to determine, by order, after notice to the covered person and a reasonable opportunity for such covered person to respond, based on complaints collected through the system under section 5493(b)(3) of this title or information from other sources, that such covered person is engaging, or has engaged, in conduct that poses risks to consumers with regard to the offering or provision of consumer financial products or services;

(D) offers or provides to a consumer any private education loan, as defined in section 1650 of title 15, notwithstanding section 5517(a)(2)(A) of this title and subject to section 5517(a)(2)(C) of this title; or

(E) offers or provides to a consumer a payday loan.


(2) Rulemaking to define covered persons subject to this sectionThe Bureau shall consult with the Federal Trade Commission prior to issuing a rule, in accordance with paragraph (1)(B), to define covered persons subject to this section. The Bureau shall issue its initial rule not later than 1 year after the designated transfer date.


(3) Rules of construction(A) Certain persons excludedThis section shall not apply to persons described in section 5515(a) or 5516(a) of this title.


(B) Activity levelsFor purposes of computing activity levels under paragraph (1) or rules issued thereunder, activit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5514_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Scope of coverage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5514_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Supervision</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5514_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5514_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive rulemaking and examination authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exclusive rulemaking and examination authority Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law and except as provided in section 5581 of this title, to the extent that Federal law authorizes the Bureau and another Federal agency to issue regulations or guidance, conduct examinations, or require reports from a person described in subsection (a)(1) under such law for purposes of assuring compliance with Federal consumer financial law and any regulations thereunder, the Bureau shall have the exclusive authority to prescribe rules, issue guidance, conduct examinations, require reports, or issue exemptions with regard to a person described in subsection (a)(1), subject to those provisions of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5514_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Service providers A service provider to a person described in subsection (a)(1) shall be subject to the authority of the Bureau under this section, to the same extent as if such service provider were engaged in a service relationship with a bank, and the Bureau were an appropriate Federal banking agency under section 1867(c) of this title. In conducting any examination or requiring any report from a service provider subject to this subsection, the Bureau shall coordinate with the appropriate prudential regulator, as applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5514_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of Farm Credit Administration authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preservation of Farm Credit Administration authority No provision of this title 1 may be construed as modifying, limiting, or otherwise affecting the authority of the Farm Credit Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>