<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5515" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5515/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5515/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5515"><akn:num>5515</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of very large banks, savings associations, and credit unions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5515. Supervision of very large banks, savings associations, and credit unions(a) Scope of coverageThis section shall apply to any covered person that is—(1) an insured depository institution with total assets of more than $10,000,000,000 and any affiliate thereof; or

(2) an insured credit union with total assets of more than $10,000,000,000 and any affiliate thereof.


(b) Supervision(1) In generalThe Bureau shall have exclusive authority to require reports and conduct examinations on a periodic basis of persons described in subsection (a) for purposes of—(A) assessing compliance with the requirements of Federal consumer financial laws;

(B) obtaining information about the activities subject to such laws and the associated compliance systems or procedures of such persons; and

(C) detecting and assessing associated risks to consumers and to markets for consumer financial products and services.


(2) CoordinationTo minimize regulatory burden, the Bureau shall coordinate its supervisory activities with the supervisory activities conducted by prudential regulators and the State bank regulatory authorities, including consultation regarding their respective schedules for examining such persons described in subsection (a) and requirements regarding reports to be submitted by such persons.


(3) Use of existing reportsThe Bureau shall, to the fullest extent possible, use—(A) reports pertaining to a person described in subsection (a) that have been provided or required to have been provided to a Federal or State agency; and

(B) information that has been reported publicly.


(4) Preservation of authorityNothing in this title 11 See References in Text note below. may be construed as limiting the authority of the Director to require reports from a person described in subsection (a), as permitted under paragraph (1), regarding information owned or under the control of such person, regardless of whether such information is maintained, stored, or processed by another person.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5515_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Scope of coverage This section shall apply to any covered person that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5515_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Supervision</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5515_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Primary enforcement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Primary enforcement authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5515_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Service providers A service provider to a person described in subsection (a) shall be subject to the authority of the Bureau under this section, to the same extent as if the Bureau were an appropriate Federal banking agency under section 1867(c) of this title. In conducting any examination or requiring any report from a service provider subject to this subsection, the Bureau shall coordinate with the appropriate prudential regulator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5515_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Simultaneous and coordinated supervisory action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Simultaneous and coordinated supervisory action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>