<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5516" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5516/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5516/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5516"><akn:num>5516</akn:num><akn:heading>Other banks, savings associations, and credit unions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5516. Other banks, savings associations, and credit unions(a) Scope of coverageThis section shall apply to any covered person that is—(1) an insured depository institution with total assets of $10,000,000,000 or less; or

(2) an insured credit union with total assets of $10,000,000,000 or less.


(b) ReportsThe Director may require reports from a person described in subsection (a), as necessary to support the role of the Bureau in implementing Federal consumer financial law, to support its examination activities under subsection (c), and to assess and detect risks to consumers and consumer financial markets.(1) Use of existing reportsThe Bureau shall, to the fullest extent possible, use—(A) reports pertaining to a person described in subsection (a) that have been provided or required to have been provided to a Federal or State agency; and

(B) information that has been reported publicly.


(2) Preservation of authorityNothing in this subsection may be construed as limiting the authority of the Director from requiring from a person described in subsection (a), as permitted under paragraph (1), information owned or under the control of such person, regardless of whether such information is maintained, stored, or processed by another person.


(3) Reports of tax law noncomplianceThe Bureau shall provide the Commissioner of Internal Revenue with any report of examination or related information identifying possible tax law noncompliance.



(c) Examinations(1) In generalThe Bureau may, at its discretion, include examiners on a sampling basis of the examinations performed by the prudential regulator to assess compliance with the requirements of Federal consumer financial law of persons described in subsection (a).


(2) Agency coordinationThe prudential regulator shall—(A) provide all reports, records, and documentation related to the examination process for any institution included in the sample referred to in paragraph (1) to the Bureau on a timely and continual basis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5516_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Scope of coverage This section shall apply to any covered person that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5516_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports The Director may require reports from a person described in subsection (a), as necessary to support the role of the Bureau in implementing Federal consumer financial law, to support its examination activities under subsection (c), and to assess and detect risks to consumers and consumer financial markets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5516_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Examinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5516_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5516_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Service providers A service provider to a substantial number of persons described in subsection (a) shall be subject to the authority of the Bureau under section 5515 of this title to the same extent as if the Bureau were an appropriate Federal bank agency under section 1867(c) of this title. When conducting any examination or requiring any report from a service provider subject to this subsection, the Bureau shall coordinate with the appropriate prudential regulator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>