<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5519" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5519/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5519/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5519"><akn:num>5519</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion for auto dealers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5519. Exclusion for auto dealers(a) Sale, servicing, and leasing of motor vehicles excludedExcept as permitted in subsection (b), the Bureau may not exercise any rulemaking, supervisory, enforcement or any other authority, including any authority to order assessments, over a motor vehicle dealer that is predominantly engaged in the sale and servicing of motor vehicles, the leasing and servicing of motor vehicles, or both.


(b) Certain functions exceptedSubsection (a) shall not apply to any person, to the extent that such person—(1) provides consumers with any services related to residential or commercial mortgages or self-financing transactions involving real property;

(2) operates a line of business—(A) that involves the extension of retail credit or retail leases involving motor vehicles; and

(B) in which—(i) the extension of retail credit or retail leases are provided directly to consumers; and

(ii) the contract governing such extension of retail credit or retail leases is not routinely assigned to an unaffiliated third party finance or leasing source; or



(3) offers or provides a consumer financial product or service not involving or related to the sale, financing, leasing, rental, repair, refurbishment, maintenance, or other servicing of motor vehicles, motor vehicle parts, or any related or ancillary product or service.


(c) Preservation of authorities of other agenciesExcept as provided in subsections (b) and (d), nothing in this title,11 See References in Text note below. including subtitle F, shall be construed as modifying, limiting, or superseding the operation of any provision of Federal law, or otherwise affecting the authority of the Board of Governors, the Federal Trade Commission, or any other Federal agency, with respect to a person described in subsection (a).


(d) Federal Trade Commission authorityNotwithstanding section 57a of title 15, the Federal Trade Commission is authorized to prescribe rules under sections 45 and 57a(a)(1)(B) of t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5519_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale, servicing, and leasing of motor vehicles excluded</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sale, servicing, and leasing of motor vehicles excluded Except as permitted in subsection (b), the Bureau may not exercise any rulemaking, supervisory, enforcement or any other authority, including any authority to order assessments, over a motor vehicle dealer that is predominantly engaged in the sale and servicing of motor vehicles, the leasing and servicing of motor vehicles, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5519_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain functions excepted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certain functions excepted Subsection (a) shall not apply to any person, to the extent that such person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5519_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of authorities of other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preservation of authorities of other agencies Except as provided in subsections (b) and (d), nothing in this title,11 See References in Text note below. including subtitle F, shall be construed as modifying, limiting, or superseding the operation of any provision of Federal law, or otherwise affecting the authority of the Board of Governors, the Federal Trade Commission, or any other Federal agency, with respect to a person described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5519_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Trade Commission authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal Trade Commission authority Notwithstanding section 57a of title 15, the Federal Trade Commission is authorized to prescribe rules under sections 45 and 57a(a)(1)(B) of title 15.22 So in original. The period probably should be a comma. in accordance with section 553 of title 5, with respect to a person described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5519_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with Office of Service Member Affairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination with Office of Service Member Affairs The Board of Governors and the Federal Trade Commission shall coordinate with the Office of Service Member Affairs, to ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5519_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>