<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5551" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5551/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5551/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5551"><akn:num>5551</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5551. Relation to State law(a) In general(1) Rule of constructionThis title,11 See References in Text note below. other than sections 1044 through 1048,1 may not be construed as annulling, altering, or affecting, or exempting any person subject to the provisions of this title 1 from complying with, the statutes, regulations, orders, or interpretations in effect in any State, except to the extent that any such provision of law is inconsistent with the provisions of this title,1 and then only to the extent of the inconsistency.


(2) Greater protection under State lawFor purposes of this subsection, a statute, regulation, order, or interpretation in effect in any State is not inconsistent with the provisions of this title 1 if the protection that such statute, regulation, order, or interpretation affords to consumers is greater than the protection provided under this title.1 A determination regarding whether a statute, regulation, order, or interpretation in effect in any State is inconsistent with the provisions of this title 1 may be made by the Bureau on its own motion or in response to a nonfrivolous petition initiated by any interested person.



(b) Relation to other provisions of enumerated consumer laws that relate to State lawNo provision of this title,1 except as provided in section 1083,1 shall be construed as modifying, limiting, or superseding the operation of any provision of an enumerated consumer law that relates to the application of a law in effect in any State with respect to such Federal law.


(c) Additional consumer protection regulations in response to State action(1) Notice of proposed rule requiredThe Bureau shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking whenever a majority of the States has enacted a resolution in support of the establishment or modification of a consumer protection regulation by the Bureau.


(2) Bureau considerations required for issuance of final regulationBefore prescribing a final regulation based upon a notice issued pur</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5551_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5551_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other provisions of enumerated consumer laws that relate to State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relation to other provisions of enumerated consumer laws that relate to State law No provision of this title,1 except as provided in section 1083,1 shall be construed as modifying, limiting, or superseding the operation of any provision of an enumerated consumer law that relates to the application of a law in effect in any State with respect to such Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5551_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional consumer protection regulations in response to State action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional consumer protection regulations in response to State action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>