<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5552" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5552/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5552/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5552"><akn:num>5552</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of enforcement powers of States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5552. Preservation of enforcement powers of States(a) In general(1) Action by StateExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the attorney general (or the equivalent thereof) of any State may bring a civil action in the name of such State in any district court of the United States in that State or in State court that is located in that State and that has jurisdiction over the defendant, to enforce provisions of this title 11 See References in Text note below. or regulations issued under this title,1 and to secure remedies under provisions of this title 1 or remedies otherwise provided under other law. A State regulator may bring a civil action or other appropriate proceeding to enforce the provisions of this title 1 or regulations issued under this title 1 with respect to any entity that is State-chartered, incorporated, licensed, or otherwise authorized to do business under State law (except as provided in paragraph (2)), and to secure remedies under provisions of this title 1 or remedies otherwise provided under other provisions of law with respect to such an entity.


(2) Action by State against national bank or Federal savings association to enforce rules(A) In generalExcept as permitted under subparagraph (B), the attorney general (or equivalent thereof) of any State may not bring a civil action in the name of such State against a national bank or Federal savings association to enforce a provision of this title.1


(B) Enforcement of rules permittedThe attorney general (or the equivalent thereof) of any State may bring a civil action in the name of such State against a national bank or Federal savings association in any district court of the United States in the State or in State court that is located in that State and that has jurisdiction over the defendant to enforce a regulation prescribed by the Bureau under a provision of this title 1 and to secure remedies under provisions of this title 1 or remedies otherwise provided under other law.



(3) Rule of constru</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5552_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5552_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5552_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations The Bureau shall prescribe regulations to implement the requirements of this section and, from time to time, provide guidance in order to further coordinate actions with the State attorneys general and other regulators.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5552_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of State authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preservation of State authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>