<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5564" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5564/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5564/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5564"><akn:num>5564</akn:num><akn:heading>Litigation authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5564. Litigation authority(a) In generalIf any person violates a Federal consumer financial law, the Bureau may, subject to sections 5514, 5515, and 5516 of this title, commence a civil action against such person to impose a civil penalty or to seek all appropriate legal and equitable relief including a permanent or temporary injunction as permitted by law.


(b) RepresentationThe Bureau may act in its own name and through its own attorneys in enforcing any provision of this title,11 See References in Text note below. rules thereunder, or any other law or regulation, or in any action, suit, or proceeding to which the Bureau is a party.


(c) Compromise of actionsThe Bureau may compromise or settle any action if such compromise is approved by the court.


(d) Notice to the Attorney General(1) In generalWhen commencing a civil action under Federal consumer financial law, or any rule thereunder, the Bureau shall notify the Attorney General and, with respect to a civil action against an insured depository institution or insured credit union, the appropriate prudential regulator.


(2) Notice and coordination(A) Notice of other actionsIn addition to any notice required under paragraph (1), the Bureau shall notify the Attorney General concerning any action, suit, or proceeding to which the Bureau is a party, except an action, suit, or proceeding that involves the offering or provision of consumer financial products or services.


(B) CoordinationIn order to avoid conflicts and promote consistency regarding litigation of matters under Federal law, the Attorney General and the Bureau shall consult regarding the coordination of investigations and proceedings, including by negotiating an agreement for coordination by not later than 180 days after the designated transfer date. The agreement under this subparagraph shall include provisions to ensure that parallel investigations and proceedings involving the Federal consumer financial laws are conducted in a manner that avoids</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If any person violates a Federal consumer financial law, the Bureau may, subject to sections 5514, 5515, and 5516 of this title, commence a civil action against such person to impose a civil penalty or to seek all appropriate legal and equitable relief including a permanent or temporary injunction as permitted by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Representation The Bureau may act in its own name and through its own attorneys in enforcing any provision of this title,11 See References in Text note below. rules thereunder, or any other law or regulation, or in any action, suit, or proceeding to which the Bureau is a party.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise of actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compromise of actions The Bureau may compromise or settle any action if such compromise is approved by the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to the Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice to the Attorney General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appearance before the Supreme Court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Appearance before the Supreme Court The Bureau may represent itself in its own name before the Supreme Court of the United States, provided that the Bureau makes a written request to the Attorney General within the 10-day period which begins on the date of entry of the judgment which would permit any party to file a petition for writ of certiorari, and the Attorney General concurs with such request or fails to take action within 60 days of the request of the Bureau.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Forum Any civil action brought under this title 1 may be brought in a United States district court or in any court of competent jurisdiction of a state in a district in which the defendant is located or resides or is doing business, and such court shall have jurisdiction to enjoin such person and to require compliance with any Federal consumer financial law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5564_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for bringing action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Time for bringing action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>