<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5581" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5581/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5581/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5581"><akn:num>5581</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of consumer financial protection functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5581. Transfer of consumer financial protection functions(a) Defined termsFor purposes of this part—(1) the term “consumer financial protection functions” means—(A) all authority to prescribe rules or issue orders or guidelines pursuant to any Federal consumer financial law, including performing appropriate functions to promulgate and review such rules, orders, and guidelines; and

(B) the examination authority described in subsection (c)(1), with respect to a person described in section 5515(a) of this title; and


(2) the terms “transferor agency” and “transferor agencies” mean, respectively—(A) the Board of Governors (and any Federal reserve bank, as the context requires), the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Trade Commission, the National Credit Union Administration, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Office of Thrift Supervision, and the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and the heads of those agencies; and

(B) the agencies listed in subparagraph (A), collectively.



(b) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (c), consumer financial protection functions are transferred as follows:(1) Board of Governors(A) Transfer of functionsAll consumer financial protection functions of the Board of Governors are transferred to the Bureau.


(B) Board of Governors authorityThe Bureau shall have all powers and duties that were vested in the Board of Governors, relating to consumer financial protection functions, on the day before the designated transfer date.



(2) Comptroller of the Currency(A) Transfer of functionsAll consumer financial protection functions of the Comptroller of the Currency are transferred to the Bureau.


(B) Comptroller authorityThe Bureau shall have all powers and duties that were vested in the Comptroller of the Currency, relating to consumer financial protection functions, on the day before the designated transfer date.



(3) Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision(A) Transfer of functionsAll </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5581_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defined terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Defined terms For purposes of this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5581_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In general Except as provided in subsection (c), consumer financial protection functions are transferred as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5581_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities of the prudential regulators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorities of the prudential regulators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5581_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective date Subsections (b) and (c) shall become effective on the designated transfer date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>