<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5584" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5584/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5584/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5584"><akn:num>5584</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5584. Transfer of certain personnel(a) In general(1) Certain Federal Reserve System employees transferred(A) Identifying employees for transferThe Bureau and the Board of Governors shall—(i) jointly determine the number of employees of the Board of Governors necessary to perform or support the consumer financial protection functions of the Board of Governors that are transferred to the Bureau by this title; 11 See References in Text note below. and

(ii) consistent with the number determined under clause (i), jointly identify employees of the Board of Governors for transfer to the Bureau, in a manner that the Bureau and the Board of Governors, in their sole discretion, determine equitable.


(B) Identified employees transferredAll employees of the Board of Governors identified under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be transferred to the Bureau for employment.


(C) Federal reserve bank employeesEmployees of any Federal reserve bank who are performing consumer financial protection functions on behalf of the Board of Governors shall be treated as employees of the Board of Governors for purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B).



(2) Certain FDIC employees transferred(A) Identifying employees for transferThe Bureau and the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall—(i) jointly determine the number of employees of that Corporation necessary to perform or support the consumer financial protection functions of the Corporation that are transferred to the Bureau by this title; 1 and

(ii) consistent with the number determined under clause (i), jointly identify employees of the Corporation for transfer to the Bureau, in a manner that the Bureau and the Board of Directors of the Corporation, in their sole discretion, determine equitable.


(B) Identified employees transferredAll employees of the Corporation identified under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be transferred to the Bureau for employment.



(3) Certain NCUA employees transferred(A) Identifying empl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of transfers and position assignments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Timing of transfers and position assignments Each employee to be transferred under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of function</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer of function</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equal status and tenure positions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Equal status and tenure positions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional certification requirements limited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional certification requirements limited Examiners transferred to the Bureau are not subject to any additional certification requirements before being placed in a comparable examiner position at the Bureau examining the same types of institutions as they examined before they were transferred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel actions limited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Personnel actions limited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Pay</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reorganization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reorganization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5584_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of uniform pay and classification system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Implementation of uniform pay and classification system Not later than 2 years after the designated transfer date, the Bureau shall implement a uniform pay and classification system for all employees transferred under this title.1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>