<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5603" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5603/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5603/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5603"><akn:num>5603</akn:num><akn:heading>Review, report, and program with respect to exchange facilitators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5603. Review, report, and program with respect to exchange facilitators(a) ReviewThe Director shall review all Federal laws and regulations relating to the protection of consumers who use exchange facilitators for transactions primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.


(b) ReportNot later than 1 year after the designated transfer date, the Director shall submit to Congress a report describing—(1) recommendations for legislation to ensure the appropriate protection of consumers who use exchange facilitators for transactions primarily for personal, family, or household purposes;

(2) recommendations for updating the regulations of Federal departments and agencies to ensure the appropriate protection of such consumers; and

(3) recommendations for regulations to ensure the appropriate protection of such consumers.


(c) ProgramNot later than 2 years after the date of the submission of the report under subsection (b), the Bureau shall, consistent with part B, propose regulations or otherwise establish a program to protect consumers who use exchange facilitators.


(d) Exchange facilitator definedIn this section, the term “exchange facilitator” means a person that—(1) facilitates, for a fee, an exchange of like kind property by entering into an agreement with a taxpayer by which the exchange facilitator acquires from the taxpayer the contractual rights to sell the taxpayer’s relinquished property and transfers a replacement property to the taxpayer as a qualified intermediary (within the meaning of Treasury Regulations section 1.1031(k)–1(g)(4)) or enters into an agreement with the taxpayer to take title to a property as an exchange accommodation titleholder (within the meaning of Revenue Procedure 2000–37) or enters into an agreement with a taxpayer to act as a qualified trustee or qualified escrow holder (within the meaning of Treasury Regulations section 1.1031(k)–1(g)(3));

(2) maintains an office for the purpose of soliciting business to perform the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Review The Director shall review all Federal laws and regulations relating to the protection of consumers who use exchange facilitators for transactions primarily for personal, family, or household purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report Not later than 1 year after the designated transfer date, the Director shall submit to Congress a report describing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program Not later than 2 years after the date of the submission of the report under subsection (b), the Bureau shall, consistent with part B, propose regulations or otherwise establish a program to protect consumers who use exchange facilitators.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange facilitator defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exchange facilitator defined In this section, the term “exchange facilitator” means a person that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>