<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5641" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5641/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5641/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5641"><akn:num>5641</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced compensation structure reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5641. Enhanced compensation structure reporting(a) Enhanced disclosure and reporting of compensation arrangements(1) In generalNot later than 9 months after July 21, 2010, the appropriate Federal regulators jointly shall prescribe regulations or guidelines to require each covered financial institution to disclose to the appropriate Federal regulator the structures of all incentive-based compensation arrangements offered by such covered financial institutions sufficient to determine whether the compensation structure—(A) provides an executive officer, employee, director, or principal shareholder of the covered financial institution with excessive compensation, fees, or benefits; or

(B) could lead to material financial loss to the covered financial institution.


(2) Rules of constructionNothing in this section shall be construed as requiring the reporting of the actual compensation of particular individuals. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require a covered financial institution that does not have an incentive-based payment arrangement to make the disclosures required under this subsection.



(b) Prohibition on certain compensation arrangementsNot later than 9 months after July 21, 2010, the appropriate Federal regulators shall jointly prescribe regulations or guidelines that prohibit any types of incentive-based payment arrangement, or any feature of any such arrangement, that the regulators determine encourages inappropriate risks by covered financial institutions—(1) by providing an executive officer, employee, director, or principal shareholder of the covered financial institution with excessive compensation, fees, or benefits; or

(2) that could lead to material financial loss to the covered financial institution.


(c) StandardsThe appropriate Federal regulators shall—(1) ensure that any standards for compensation established under subsections (a) or (b) are comparable to the standards established under section 1831p–1 11 See References in Tex</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5641_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced disclosure and reporting of compensation arrangements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enhanced disclosure and reporting of compensation arrangements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5641_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on certain compensation arrangements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition on certain compensation arrangements Not later than 9 months after July 21, 2010, the appropriate Federal regulators shall jointly prescribe regulations or guidelines that prohibit any types of incentive-based payment arrangement, or any feature of any such arrangement, that the regulators determine encourages inappropriate risks by covered financial institutions—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5641_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Standards The appropriate Federal regulators shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5641_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement The provisions of this section and the regulations issued under this section shall be enforced under section 505 of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act [15 U.S.C. 6805] and, for purposes of such section, a violation of this section or such regulations shall be treated as a violation of subtitle A of title V of such Act [15 U.S.C. 6801 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5641_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5641_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for certain financial institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemption for certain financial institutions The requirements of this section shall not apply to covered financial institutions with assets of less than $1,000,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>