<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5701"><akn:num>5701</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5701. Definitions
In this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Appropriate committees of CongressThe term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—(A) the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship, the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Finance, the Committee on the Budget, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Small Business, the Committee on Agriculture, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on the Budget, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.


(2) Appropriate Federal banking agencyThe term “appropriate Federal banking agency”—(A) has the same meaning as in section 1813(q) of this title; and

(B) includes the National Credit Union Administration Board in the case of any credit union the deposits of which are insured in accordance with the Federal Credit Union Act [12 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.].


(3) Enrolled loanThe term “enrolled loan” means a loan made by a financial institution lender that is enrolled by a participating State in an approved State capital access program in accordance with this chapter.


(4) Federal contributionThe term “Federal contribution” means the portion of the contribution made by a participating State to, or for the account of, an approved State program that is made with Federal funds allocated to the State by the Secretary under section 5702 of this title.


(5) Financial institutionThe term “financial institution” means any insured depository institution, insured credit union, or community development financial institution, as those terms are each defined in section 4702 of this title.


(6) Participating StateThe term “participating State” means any State that has been approved for participation in the Program under section 5703 of this title.


(7) ProgramThe term “Program” means the State Small Business Credit In</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate committees of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Appropriate committees of Congress The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate Federal banking agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appropriate Federal banking agency The term “appropriate Federal banking agency”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrolled loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Enrolled loan The term “enrolled loan” means a loan made by a financial institution lender that is enrolled by a participating State in an approved State capital access program in accordance with this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal contribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Federal contribution The term “Federal contribution” means the portion of the contribution made by a participating State to, or for the account of, an approved State program that is made with Federal funds allocated to the State by the Secretary under section 5702 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Financial institution The term “financial institution” means any insured depository institution, insured credit union, or community development financial institution, as those terms are each defined in section 4702 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participating State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Participating State The term “participating State” means any State that has been approved for participation in the Program under section 5703 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Program The term “Program” means the State Small Business Credit Initiative established under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying loan or swap funding facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Qualifying loan or swap funding facility The term “qualifying loan or swap funding facility” means a contractual arrangement between a participating State and a private financial entity under which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Reserve fund The term “reserve fund” means a fund, established by a participating State, dedicated to a particular financial institution lender, for the purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5701_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) State The term “State” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>