<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5708" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5708/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5708/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5708"><akn:num>5708</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation and administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5708. Implementation and administration(a) General authorities and dutiesThe Secretary shall—(1) consult with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration and the appropriate Federal banking agencies on the administration of the Program;

(2) establish minimum national standards for approved State programs;

(3) provide technical assistance to States for starting State programs and generally disseminate best practices;

(4) manage, administer, and perform necessary program integrity functions for the Program; and

(5) ensure adequate oversight of the approved State programs, including oversight of the cash flows, performance, and compliance of each approved State program.


(b) AppropriationsThere is hereby appropriated to the Secretary, out of funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,500,000,000 to carry out the Program, including to pay reasonable costs of administering the Program.


(c) Termination of Secretary’s Program administration functionsThe authorities and duties of the Secretary to implement and administer the Program shall terminate at the end of the 7-year period beginning on March 11, 2021.


(d) Expedited contractingDuring the 1-year period beginning on March 11, 2021, the Secretary may enter into contracts without regard to any other provision of law regarding public contracts, for purposes of carrying out this chapter.


(e) Technical assistanceOf the amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2021 to carry out the Program, $500,000,000 may be used by the Secretary to—(1) provide funds to States to carry out a technical assistance plan under which a State will provide legal, accounting, and financial advisory services, either directly or contracted with legal, accounting, and financial advisory firms, with priority given to business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, to very small businesses and business enterprises owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5708_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authorities and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authorities and duties The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5708_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appropriations There is hereby appropriated to the Secretary, out of funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,500,000,000 to carry out the Program, including to pay reasonable costs of administering the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5708_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Secretary’s Program administration functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Termination of Secretary’s Program administration functions The authorities and duties of the Secretary to implement and administer the Program shall terminate at the end of the 7-year period beginning on March 11, 2021.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5708_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited contracting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expedited contracting During the 1-year period beginning on March 11, 2021, the Secretary may enter into contracts without regard to any other provision of law regarding public contracts, for purposes of carrying out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5708_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance Of the amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2021 to carry out the Program, $500,000,000 may be used by the Secretary to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>