<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5802"><akn:num>5802</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5802. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) BenchmarkThe term “benchmark” means an index of interest rates or dividend rates that is used, in whole or in part, as the basis of or as a reference for calculating or determining any valuation, payment, or other measurement.


(2) Benchmark administratorThe term “benchmark administrator” means a person that publishes a benchmark for use by third parties.


(3) Benchmark replacementThe term “benchmark replacement” means a benchmark, or an interest rate or dividend rate (which may or may not be based in whole or in part on a prior setting of LIBOR), to replace LIBOR or any interest rate or dividend rate based on LIBOR, whether on a temporary, permanent, or indefinite basis, under or with respect to a LIBOR contract.


(4) Benchmark replacement conforming changesThe term “benchmark replacement conforming changes” means any technical, administrative, or operational changes, alterations, or modifications that—(A) the Board determines, in its discretion, would address 1 or more issues affecting the implementation, administration, and calculation of the Board-selected benchmark replacement in LIBOR contracts; or

(B) solely with respect to a LIBOR contract that is not a consumer loan, in the reasonable judgment of a calculating person, are otherwise necessary or appropriate to permit the implementation, administration, and calculation of the Board-selected benchmark replacement under or with respect to a LIBOR contract after giving due consideration to any benchmark replacement conforming changes under subparagraph (A).


(5) BoardThe term “Board” means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.


(6) Board-selected benchmark replacementThe term “Board-selected benchmark replacement” means a benchmark replacement identified by the Board that is based on SOFR, including any tenor spread adjustment pursuant to section 5803(e) of this title.


(7) Calculating personThe term “calculating person” means, with respect to any LI</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benchmark</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Benchmark The term “benchmark” means an index of interest rates or dividend rates that is used, in whole or in part, as the basis of or as a reference for calculating or determining any valuation, payment, or other measurement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benchmark administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Benchmark administrator The term “benchmark administrator” means a person that publishes a benchmark for use by third parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benchmark replacement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Benchmark replacement The term “benchmark replacement” means a benchmark, or an interest rate or dividend rate (which may or may not be based in whole or in part on a prior setting of LIBOR), to replace LIBOR or any interest rate or dividend rate based on LIBOR, whether on a temporary, permanent, or indefinite basis, under or with respect to a LIBOR contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benchmark replacement conforming changes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Benchmark replacement conforming changes The term “benchmark replacement conforming changes” means any technical, administrative, or operational changes, alterations, or modifications that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Board The term “Board” means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board-selected benchmark replacement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Board-selected benchmark replacement The term “Board-selected benchmark replacement” means a benchmark replacement identified by the Board that is based on SOFR, including any tenor spread adjustment pursuant to section 5803(e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculating person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Calculating person The term “calculating person” means, with respect to any LIBOR contract, any person, including the determining person, responsible for calculating or determining any valuation, payment, or other measurement based on a benchmark.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer; credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Consumer; credit The terms “consumer” and “credit” have the meanings given the terms in section 1602 of title 15.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Consumer loan The term “consumer loan” means a consumer credit transaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5802_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determining person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Determining person The term “determining person” means, with respect to any LIBOR contract, any person with the authority, right, or obligation, including on a temporary basis (as identified by the LIBOR contract or by the governing law of the LIBOR contract, as appropriate) to determine a benchmark replacement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>