<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5904"><akn:num>5904</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of subsidiaries of insured depository institutions and Federal qualified payment stablecoin</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5904. Approval of subsidiaries of insured depository institutions and Federal qualified payment stablecoin issuers(a) Application(1) In generalEach primary Federal payment stablecoin regulator shall—(A) receive, review, and consider for approval applications from any insured depository institution that seeks to issue payment stablecoins through a subsidiary and any nonbank entity, Federal branch, or uninsured national bank that is chartered by the Comptroller pursuant to title LXII of the Revised Statutes, and that seeks to issue payment stablecoins as a Federal qualified payment stablecoin issuer; and

(B) establish a process and framework for the licensing, regulation, examination, and supervision of such entities that prioritizes the safety and soundness of such entities.


(2) Authority to issue regulations and process applicationsThe primary Federal payment stablecoin regulators shall, before the date described in section 5913 of this title—(A) issue regulations consistent with that section to carry out this section; and

(B) pursuant to the regulations described in subparagraph (A), accept and process applications described in paragraph (1).


(3) Mandatory approval processA primary Federal payment stablecoin regulator shall, upon receipt of a substantially complete application received under paragraph (1), evaluate and make a determination on each application based on the criteria established under this chapter.



(b) Evaluation of applicationsA substantially complete application received under subsection (a) shall be evaluated by the primary Federal payment stablecoin regulator using the factors described in subsection (c).


(c) Factors to be consideredThe factors described in this subsection are the following:(1) The ability of the applicant (or, in the case of an applicant that is an insured depository institution, the subsidiary of the applicant), based on financial condition and resources, to meet the requirements set forth under section 5903 of this</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5904_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5904_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation of applications A substantially complete application received under subsection (a) shall be evaluated by the primary Federal payment stablecoin regulator using the factors described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5904_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors to be considered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Factors to be considered The factors described in this subsection are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5904_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing for decision; grounds for denial</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Timing for decision; grounds for denial</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5904_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports on pending applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports on pending applications Each primary Federal payment stablecoin regulator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5904_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safe harbor for pending applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Safe harbor for pending applications The primary Federal payment stablecoin regulators may waive the application of the requirements of this chapter for a period not to exceed 12 months beginning on the effective date of this chapter, with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5904_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rulemaking Consistent with section 5913 of this title, the primary Federal payment stablecoin regulators shall issue rules necessary for the regulation of the issuance of payment stablecoins, but may not impose requirements in addition to the requirements specified under section 5903 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5904_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other licensing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Relation to other licensing requirements The provisions of this section supersede and preempt any State requirement for a charter, license, or other authorization to do business with respect to a Federal qualified payment stablecoin issuer or subsidiary of an insured depository institution or credit union that is approved under this section to be a permitted payment stablecoin issuer. Nothing in this subsection shall preempt or supersede the authority of a State to charter, license, supervise, or regulate an insured depository institution or credit union chartered in such State or to supervise a subsidiary of such insured depository institution or credit union that is approved under this section to be a permitted payment stablecoin issuer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5904_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Certification required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>