<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5906"><akn:num>5906</akn:num><akn:heading>State qualified payment stablecoin issuers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5906. State qualified payment stablecoin issuers(a) In generalA State payment stablecoin regulator shall have supervisory, examination, and enforcement authority over all State qualified payment stablecoin issuers of such State.


(b) Authority to enter into agreements with the BoardA State payment stablecoin regulator may enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Board, by mutual agreement, under which the Board may participate in the supervision, examination, and enforcement of this chapter with respect to the State qualified payment stablecoin issuers of such State.


(c) Sharing of informationA State payment stablecoin regulator and the Board shall share information on an ongoing basis with respect to a State qualified payment stablecoin issuer of such State, including a copy of the initial application and any accompanying documents.


(d) RulemakingA State payment stablecoin regulator may issue orders and rules under section 5903 of this title applicable to State qualified payment stablecoin issuers to the same extent as the primary Federal payment stablecoin regulators issue orders and rules under section 5903 of this title applicable to permitted payment stablecoin issuers that are not State qualified payment stablecoin issuers.


(e) Enforcement authority in unusual and exigent circumstances(1) Board(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (C), under unusual and exigent circumstances that the Board determines to exist, the Board may, after not less than 48 hours’ prior written notice to the applicable State payment stablecoin regulator, take an enforcement action against a State qualified payment stablecoin issuer or an institution-affiliated party of such issuer for violations of this chapter during such unusual and exigent circumstances.


(B) RulemakingConsistent with section 5913 of this title, the Board shall issue rules to set forth the unusual and exigent circumstances in which the Board may act under this paragraph.


(C) LimitationsIf, after </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A State payment stablecoin regulator shall have supervisory, examination, and enforcement authority over all State qualified payment stablecoin issuers of such State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to enter into agreements with the Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to enter into agreements with the Board A State payment stablecoin regulator may enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Board, by mutual agreement, under which the Board may participate in the supervision, examination, and enforcement of this chapter with respect to the State qualified payment stablecoin issuers of such State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5906_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sharing of information A State payment stablecoin regulator and the Board shall share information on an ongoing basis with respect to a State qualified payment stablecoin issuer of such State, including a copy of the initial application and any accompanying documents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5906_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rulemaking A State payment stablecoin regulator may issue orders and rules under section 5903 of this title applicable to State qualified payment stablecoin issuers to the same extent as the primary Federal payment stablecoin regulators issue orders and rules under section 5903 of this title applicable to permitted payment stablecoin issuers that are not State qualified payment stablecoin issuers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5906_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement authority in unusual and exigent circumstances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement authority in unusual and exigent circumstances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5906_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect on State law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>