<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/5907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5907"><akn:num>5907</akn:num><akn:heading>Anti-money laundering protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5907. Anti-money laundering protections(a) Payment stablecoins issued by a foreign payment stablecoin issuer(1) In generalA payment stablecoin that is issued by a foreign payment stablecoin issuer may not be publicly offered, sold, or otherwise made available for trading in the United States by a digital asset service provider unless the foreign payment stablecoin issuer has the technological capability to comply and complies with the terms of any lawful order.


(2) Enforcement(A) AuthorityThe Secretary of the Treasury shall have the authority to designate any foreign issuer that publicly offers, sells, or otherwise makes available a payment stablecoin in violation of paragraph (1) as noncompliant.


(B) Designation as noncompliantNot later than 30 days after the Department of the Treasury has identified a foreign payment stablecoin issuer of any payment stablecoin trading in the United States that is in violation of paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with relevant Federal agencies, may, pursuant to the authority under subparagraph (A), designate the foreign payment stablecoin issuer as noncompliant and notify the foreign payment stablecoin issuer in writing of the designation.



(3) AppealA determination of noncompliance under this subsection is subject to judicial review in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit.



(b) Publication of designation; prohibition on secondary trading(1) In generalIf a foreign payment stablecoin issuer does not come into compliance with the lawful order within 30 days from the date of issuance of the written notice described in subsection (a), except as provided in subsection (c), the Secretary of the Treasury shall—(A) publish the determination of noncompliance in the Federal Register, including a statement on the failure of the foreign payment stablecoin issuer to comply with the lawful order after the written notice; and

(B) issue a notification in the Federal Register</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment stablecoins issued by a foreign payment stablecoin issuer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payment stablecoins issued by a foreign payment stablecoin issuer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of designation; prohibition on secondary trading</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Publication of designation; prohibition on secondary trading</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver and licensing authority exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver and licensing authority exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5907_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of construction Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as altering the existing authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to block, restrict, or limit transactions involving payment stablecoins that reference or are denominated in United States dollars that are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>