<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/624" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/624/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/624/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_624"><akn:num>624</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of receiver or conservator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 624. Appointment of receiver or conservator(A) In general.—The Board may appoint a conservator or receiver for a corporation organized under the provisions of this subchapter to the same extent and in the same manner as the Comptroller of the Currency may appoint a conservator or receiver for a national bank, and the conservator or receiver for such corporation shall exercise the same powers, functions, and duties, subject to the same limitations, as a conservator or receiver for a national bank.

(B) Equivalent authority.—The Board shall have the same authority with respect to any conservator or receiver appointed for a corporation organized under the provisions of this subchapter under this section and any such corporation as the Comptroller of the Currency has with respect to a conservator or receiver of a national bank and the national bank for which a conservator or receiver has been appointed.

(C) Title 11 petitions.—The Board may direct the conservator or receiver of a corporation organized under the provisions of this subchapter to file a petition pursuant to title 11, in which case, title 11 shall apply to the corporation in lieu of otherwise applicable Federal or State insolvency law.

(Dec. 23, 1913, ch. 6, § 25A(16), formerly § 25(a) (par.), as added Dec. 24, 1919, ch. 18, 41 Stat. 378; amended Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 614, title II, § 203(a), 49 Stat. 704; renumbered § 25A (par.), Pub. L. 102–242, title I, § 142(e)(2), Dec. 19, 1991, 105 Stat. 2281; renumbered § 25A(16), and amended Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title I, § 112(e)], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, 2763A–396.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subchapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this section”, meaning section 25A of act Dec. 23, 1913, which is classified to this subchapter (§ 611 et seq.).

Codification
Section is comprised of par. (16) of section 25A of act Dec. 23, 1913, which comprises this subchapter. For complete classification of section 25A of this Act, see Codif</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_624_A"><akn:num>(A)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(A) The Board may appoint a conservator or receiver for a corporation organized under the provisions of this subchapter to the same extent and in the same manner as the Comptroller of the Currency may appoint a conservator or receiver for a national bank, and the conservator or receiver for such corporation shall exercise the same powers, functions, and duties, subject to the same limitations, as a conservator or receiver for a national bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_624_B"><akn:num>(B)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equivalent authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(B) The Board shall have the same authority with respect to any conservator or receiver appointed for a corporation organized under the provisions of this subchapter under this section and any such corporation as the Comptroller of the Currency has with respect to a conservator or receiver of a national bank and the national bank for which a conservator or receiver has been appointed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_624_C"><akn:num>(C)</akn:num><akn:heading>Title 11 petitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(C) The Board may direct the conservator or receiver of a corporation organized under the provisions of this subchapter to file a petition pursuant to title 11, in which case, title 11 shall apply to the corporation in lieu of otherwise applicable Federal or State insolvency law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>