<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_635a"><akn:num>635a</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 635a. Management of Bank(a) Establishment as independent agencyThe Export-Import Bank of the United States shall constitute an independent agency of the United States and neither the Bank nor any of its functions, powers, or duties shall be transferred to or consolidated with any other department, agency, or corporation of the Government unless the Congress shall otherwise by law provide.


(b) President and First Vice President of the Bank; appointment; dutiesThere shall be a President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States, who shall be appointed by the President of the United States by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall serve as chief executive officer of the Bank. There shall be a First Vice President of the Bank, who shall be appointed by the President of the United States by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, who shall serve as President of the Bank during the absence or disability of or in the event of a vacancy in the office of President of the Bank, and who shall at other times perform such functions as the President of the Bank may from time to time prescribe.


(c) Board of Directors; composition; oath; terms; duties; quorum; bylaws(1) There shall be a Board of Directors of the Bank consisting of the President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States, who shall serve as Chairman, the First Vice President who shall serve as Vice Chairman, and three additional persons appointed by the President of the United States by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.

(2) Of the five members of the Board, not more than three shall be members of any one political party.

(3) Omitted

(4) Before entering upon his duties, each of the directors shall take an oath faithfully to discharge the duties of his office.

(5) The directors, in addition to their duties as members of the Board, shall perform such additional duties and may hold such other offices in the administration of the Bank as the President of the Ba</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment as independent agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment as independent agency The Export-Import Bank of the United States shall constitute an independent agency of the United States and neither the Bank nor any of its functions, powers, or duties shall be transferred to or consolidated with any other department, agency, or corporation of the Government unless the Congress shall otherwise by law provide.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>President and First Vice President of the Bank; appointment; duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) President and First Vice President of the Bank; appointment; duties There shall be a President of the Export-Import Bank of the United States, who shall be appointed by the President of the United States by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall serve as chief executive officer of the Bank. There shall be a First Vice President of the Bank, who shall be appointed by the President of the United States by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, who shall serve as President of the Bank during the absence or disability of or in the event of a vacancy in the office of President of the Bank, and who shall at other times perform such functions as the President of the Bank may from time to time prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors; composition; oath; terms; duties; quorum; bylaws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Board of Directors; composition; oath; terms; duties; quorum; bylaws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committee; appointment; composition; meetings; advice to Bank; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Advisory Committee; appointment; composition; meetings; advice to Bank; report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflicting personal interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conflicting personal interests</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small Business Division</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Small Business Division</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small business specialists</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Small business specialists</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small Business Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Small Business Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of financing for socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns and small business concerns owned by women</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Office of financing for socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns and small business concerns owned by women</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to use portion of bank surplus to update information technology systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authority to use portion of bank surplus to update information technology systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>