<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_635g"><akn:num>635g</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress; time for submission; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 635g. Report to Congress; time for submission; contents(a) Annual submission of reportThe Export-Import Bank of the United States shall transmit to the Congress annually a complete and detailed report of its operations. Such report shall be as of the close of business on the last day of each fiscal year.


(b) Report on allocation of sums set aside for small business exports(1) The Bank shall include in its annual report to the Congress a report on the allocation of the sums set aside for small business exports pursuant to section 635(b)(1)(E) of this title.

(2) Such report shall specify—(A) the total number and dollar volume of loans made from the sums set aside;

(B) the number and dollar volume of loans made through the consortia program under section 635(b)(1)(E)(vii) of this title;

(C) the amount of guarantees and insurance provided for small business exports;

(D) the number of recipients of financing from the sums set aside who have not previously participated in the Bank’s programs;

(E) the number of commitments entered into in amounts less than $500,000; and

(F) any recommendations for increasing the participation of banks and other institutions in the programs authorized under section 635(b)(1)(E) of this title.


(3) For the purpose of this subsection, the Bank’s report shall be transmitted to the Committee on Small Business of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives.


(c) Technology to assist small businessesThe Bank shall include in its annual report to the Congress under subsection (a) of this section for each of fiscal years 2002 through 2006 a report on the efforts made by the Bank to carry out subparagraphs (E)(x) and (J) of section 635(b)(1) of this title, and on how the efforts are assisting small business concerns (as defined in section 632(a) of title 15).


(d) Number of small business suppliers of Bank usersThe Bank shall estimate on the basis of an annual survey or tabulation the number of entitie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual submission of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual submission of report The Export-Import Bank of the United States shall transmit to the Congress annually a complete and detailed report of its operations. Such report shall be as of the close of business on the last day of each fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on allocation of sums set aside for small business exports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report on allocation of sums set aside for small business exports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology to assist small businesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technology to assist small businesses The Bank shall include in its annual report to the Congress under subsection (a) of this section for each of fiscal years 2002 through 2006 a report on the efforts made by the Bank to carry out subparagraphs (E)(x) and (J) of section 635(b)(1) of this title, and on how the efforts are assisting small business concerns (as defined in section 632(a) of title 15).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number of small business suppliers of Bank users</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Number of small business suppliers of Bank users The Bank shall estimate on the basis of an annual survey or tabulation the number of entities that are suppliers of users of the Bank and that are small business concerns (as defined in section 632(a) of title 15) located in the United States, and shall include the estimate in its annual report to the Congress under subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach to certain small businesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Outreach to certain small businesses The Bank shall include in its annual report to the Congress under subsection (a) of this section a description of outreach efforts made by the Bank to any socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns (as defined in section 637(a)(4) of title 15), small business concerns (as defined in section 632(a) of title 15) owned by women, and small business concerns (as defined in section 632(a) of title 15) employing fewer than 100 employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional reports Not later than March 31 of each year, the Bank shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate reports on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring of default rates on bank financing; reports on default rates; safety and soundness review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Monitoring of default rates on bank financing; reports on default rates; safety and soundness review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Categorization of purpose of loans and long-term guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Categorization of purpose of loans and long-term guarantees In the annual report of the Bank under subsection (a), the Bank shall categorize each loan and long-term guarantee made by the Bank in the fiscal year covered by the report, and according to the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to Bank products by the textile industry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Access to Bank products by the textile industry The Bank shall include in its annual report to the Congress under subsection (a) of this section a report on the determinations made by the Advisory Committee under section 635a(d)(5) of this title in the year covered by the report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Textile and apparel supply chain financing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Textile and apparel supply chain financing The Bank shall include in its annual report to the Congress under subsection (a) of this section a description of the success of the Bank in providing effective and reasonably priced financing to the United States textile and apparel industry for exports of goods manufactured in the United States that are used as components in global textile and apparel supply chains in the year covered by the report, and steps the Bank has taken to increase the use of Bank products by such firms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>