<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635g–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635g–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635g–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_635g_1"><akn:num>635g–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual competitiveness report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 635g–1. Annual competitiveness report(a) In generalNot later than June 30 of each year, the Bank shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following:(1) Actions of Bank in providing financing on a competitive basis, and to minimize competition in government-supported export financingA description of the actions of the Bank in complying with the second and third sentences of section 635(b)(1)(A) of this title. In this part of the report, the Bank shall include a survey of all other major export-financing facilities available from other governments and government-related agencies through which foreign exporters compete with United States exporters (including through use of market windows (as defined pursuant to section 635i–3(h)(7) of this title)) and, to the extent such information is available to the Bank, indicate in specific terms the ways in which the Bank’s rates, terms, and other conditions compare with those offered from such other governments directly or indirectly. With respect to the preceding sentence, the Bank shall use all available information to estimate the annual amount of export financing available from each such government and government-related agency. In this part of the report, the Bank shall include a survey of a representative number of United States exporters and United States commercial lending institutions which provide export credit on the experience of the exporters and institutions in meeting financial competition from other countries whose exporters compete with United States exporters.


(2) Role of Bank in implementing strategic plan prepared by the Trade Promotion Coordinating CommitteeA description of the role of the Bank in implementing the strategic plan prepared by the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee in accordance with section 4727 of title 15.


(3) Tied aid credit program and fundThe report required by section 635i–3(g) of this title.


(4) Purpose of all Bank transactionsA des</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than June 30 of each year, the Bank shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of additional comments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inclusion of additional comments The report required by subsection (a) shall include such additional comments as any member of the Board of Directors may submit to the Board for inclusion in the report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635g_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>