<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635i–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635i–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635i–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_635i_5"><akn:num>635i–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental policy and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 635i–5. Environmental policy and procedures(a) Environmental effects consideration(1) In generalConsistent with the objectives of section 635(b)(1)(A) of this title, the Bank shall establish procedures to take into account the potential beneficial and adverse environmental effects of goods and services for which support is requested under its direct lending and guarantee programs. Such procedures shall provide for the public disclosure of environmental assessments and supplemental environmental reports required to be submitted to the Bank, including remediation or mitigation plans and procedures, and related monitoring reports. The preceding sentence shall not be interpreted to require the public disclosure of any information described in section 1905 of title 18. Such procedures shall apply to any transaction involving a project—(A) for which long-term support of $25,000,000 (or, if less than $25,000,000, the threshold established pursuant to international agreements, including the Common Approaches for Officially Supported Export Credits and Environmental and Social Due Diligence, as adopted by the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development Council on June 28, 2012, and the risk-management framework adopted by financial institutions for determining, assessing, and managing environmental and social risk in projects (commonly referred to as the “Equator Principles”)) or more is requested from the Bank;

(B) for which the Bank’s support would be critical to its implementation; and

(C) which may have significant environmental effects upon the global commons or any country not participating in the project, or may produce an emission, an effluent, or a principal product that is prohibited or strictly regulated pursuant to Federal environmental law.


(2) Authority to withhold financingThe procedures established under paragraph (1) shall permit the Board of Directors, in its judgment, to withhold financing from a project for environmental reasons or to app</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635i_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental effects consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Environmental effects consideration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635i_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Bank programs to encourage certain exports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of Bank programs to encourage certain exports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635i_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion in report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inclusion in report to Congress The Bank shall provide in its annual report to the Congress a summary of its activities under subsections (a) and (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635i_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interpretation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Interpretation Nothing in this section shall be construed to create any cause of action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>