<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/635q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_635q"><akn:num>635q</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of tied aid credit program in United States Export-Import Bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 635q. Establishment of tied aid credit program in United States Export-Import Bank(a) Establishment and elements of program; cooperation with Trade and Development Agency and private institutions and entities(1) The Chairman of the Export-Import Bank of the United States shall establish, within the Export-Import Bank of the United States, a program of tied aid credits for United States exports.

(2) The program shall be carried out in cooperation with the Trade and Development Agency and with private financial institutions or entities, as appropriate.

(3) The program may include—(A) the combined use of the credits, loans, or guarantees offered by the Export-Import Bank of the United States with concessional financing or grants made available under section 635r(d) of this title, by methods including the blending of the financing of, or parallel financing by, the Bank and the Trade and Development Agency; and

(B) the combined use of credits, loans, or guarantees offered by the Bank, with financing offered by private financial institutions or entities, by methods including the blending of the financing of, or parallel financing by, the Bank and private institutions or entities.



(b) Purpose of programThe purpose of the tied aid credit program under this section is to offer or arrange for financing for the export of United States goods and services which is substantially as concessional as foreign financing for which there is reasonable proof that such foreign financing is being offered to, or arranged for, a bona fide foreign competitor for a United States export sale.


(c) FundThe Chairman of the Bank is authorized to establish a fund, as necessary, for carrying out the tied aid credit program described in this section.


(d) Availability of concessional financing or grantsConcessional financing or grants made available under section 635r(d) of this title for the purposes of the mixed financing program established under this section shall be made available in a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and elements of program; cooperation with Trade and Development Agency and private institutions and entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and elements of program; cooperation with Trade and Development Agency and private institutions and entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose of program The purpose of the tied aid credit program under this section is to offer or arrange for financing for the export of United States goods and services which is substantially as concessional as foreign financing for which there is reasonable proof that such foreign financing is being offered to, or arranged for, a bona fide foreign competitor for a United States export sale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fund The Chairman of the Bank is authorized to establish a fund, as necessary, for carrying out the tied aid credit program described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_635q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of concessional financing or grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of concessional financing or grants Concessional financing or grants made available under section 635r(d) of this title for the purposes of the mixed financing program established under this section shall be made available in accordance with the provisions of section 635r(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>