<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/92a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/92a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/92a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_92a"><akn:num>92a</akn:num><akn:heading>Trust powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 92a. Trust powers(a) Authority of Comptroller of the CurrencyThe Comptroller of the Currency shall be authorized and empowered to grant by special permit to national banks applying therefor, when not in contravention of State or local law, the right to act as trustee, executor, administrator, registrar of stocks and bonds, guardian of estates, assignee, receiver, or in any other fiduciary capacity in which State banks, trust companies, or other corporations which come into competition with national banks are permitted to act under the laws of the State in which the national bank is located.


(b) Grant and exercise of powers deemed not in contravention of State or local lawWhenever the laws of such State authorize or permit the exercise of any or all of the foregoing powers by State banks, trust companies, or other corporations which compete with national banks, the granting to and the exercise of such powers by national banks shall not be deemed to be in contravention of State or local law within the meaning of this section.


(c) Segregation of fiduciary and general assets; separate books and records; access of State banking authorities to reports of examinations, books, rec­ords, and assetsNational banks exercising any or all of the powers enumerating 11 So in original. Probably should be “enumerated”. in this section shall segregate all assets held in any fiduciary capacity from the general assets of the bank and shall keep a separate set of books and records showing in proper detail all transactions engaged in under authority of this section. The State banking authorities may have access to reports of examination made by the Comptroller of the Currency insofar as such reports relate to the trust department of such bank, but nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing the State banking authorities to examine the books, records, and assets of such bank.


(d) Prohibited operations; separate investment account; collateral for certain funds used in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Comptroller of the Currency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Comptroller of the Currency The Comptroller of the Currency shall be authorized and empowered to grant by special permit to national banks applying therefor, when not in contravention of State or local law, the right to act as trustee, executor, administrator, registrar of stocks and bonds, guardian of estates, assignee, receiver, or in any other fiduciary capacity in which State banks, trust companies, or other corporations which come into competition with national banks are permitted to act under the laws of the State in which the national bank is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant and exercise of powers deemed not in contravention of State or local law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant and exercise of powers deemed not in contravention of State or local law Whenever the laws of such State authorize or permit the exercise of any or all of the foregoing powers by State banks, trust companies, or other corporations which compete with national banks, the granting to and the exercise of such powers by national banks shall not be deemed to be in contravention of State or local law within the meaning of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Segregation of fiduciary and general assets; separate books and records; access of State banking authorities to reports of examinations, books, rec­ords, and assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Segregation of fiduciary and general assets; separate books and records; access of State banking authorities to reports of examinations, books, rec­ords, and assets National banks exercising any or all of the powers enumerating 11 So in original. Probably should be “enumerated”. in this section shall segregate all assets held in any fiduciary capacity from the general assets of the bank and shall keep a separate set of books and records showing in proper detail all transactions engaged in under authority of this section. The State banking authorities may have access to reports of examination made by the Comptroller of the Currency insofar as such reports relate to the trust department of such bank, but nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing the State banking authorities to examine the books, records, and assets of such bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited operations; separate investment account; collateral for certain funds used in conduct of business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibited operations; separate investment account; collateral for certain funds used in conduct of business No national bank shall receive in its trust department deposits of current funds subject to check or the deposit of checks, drafts, bills of exchange, or other items for collection or exchange purposes. Funds deposited or held in trust by the bank awaiting investment shall be carried in a separate account and shall not be used by the bank in the conduct of its business unless it shall first set aside in the trust department United States bonds or other securities approved by the Comptroller of the Currency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien and claim upon bank failure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Lien and claim upon bank failure In the event of the failure of such bank the owners of the funds held in trust for investment shall have a lien on the bonds or other securities so set apart in addition to their claim against the estate of the bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits of securities for protection of private or court trusts; execution of and exemption from bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Deposits of securities for protection of private or court trusts; execution of and exemption from bond Whenever the laws of a State require corporations acting in a fiduciary capacity to deposit securities with the State authorities for the protection of private or court trusts, national banks so acting shall be required to make similar deposits and securities so deposited shall be held for the protection of private or court trusts, as provided by the State law. National banks in such cases shall not be required to execute the bond usually required of individuals if State corporations under similar circumstances are exempt from this requirement. National banks shall have power to execute such bond when so required by the laws of the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officials’ oath or affidavit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Officials’ oath or affidavit In any case in which the laws of a State require that a corporation acting as trustee, executor, administrator, or in any capacity specified in this section, shall take an oath or make an affidavit, the president, vice president, cashier, or trust officer of such national bank may take the necessary oath or execute the necessary affidavit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans of trust funds to officers and employees prohibited; penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Loans of trust funds to officers and employees prohibited; penalties It shall be unlawful for any national banking association to lend any officer, director, or employee any funds held in trust under the powers conferred by this section. Any officer, director, or employee making such loan, or to whom such loan is made, may be fined not more than $5,000, or imprisoned not more than five years, or may be both fined and imprisoned, in the discretion of the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations determinative of grant or denial of applications; minimum capital and surplus for issuance of permit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Considerations determinative of grant or denial of applications; minimum capital and surplus for issuance of permit In passing upon applications for permission to exercise the powers enumerated in this section, the Comptroller of the Currency may take into consideration the amount of capital and surplus of the applying bank, whether or not such capital and surplus is sufficient under the circumstances of the case, the needs of the community to be served, and any other facts and circumstances that seem to him proper, and may grant or refuse the application accordingly: Provided, That no permit shall be issued to any national banking association having a capital and surplus less than the capital and surplus required by State law of State banks, trust companies, and corporations exercising such powers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_92a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surrender of authorization; board resolution; Comptroller certification; activities affected; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Surrender of authorization; board resolution; Comptroller certification; activities affected; regulations Any national banking association desiring to surrender its right to exercise the powers granted under this section, in order to relieve itself of the necessity of complying with the requirements of this section, or to have returned to it any securities which it may have deposited with the State authorities for the protection of private or court trusts, or for any other purpose, may file with the Comptroller of the Currency a certified copy of a resolution of its board of directors signifying such desire. Upon receipt of such resolution, the Comptroller of the Currency, after satisfying himself that such bank has been relieved in accordance with State law of all duties as trustee, executory,22 So in original. Probably should be “executor,”. administrator, registrar of stocks and bonds, guardian of estates, assignee, receiver, or other fiduciary, under court, private, or other ap</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>