<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/93" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/93/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/12/93/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_93"><akn:num>93</akn:num><akn:heading>Violation of provisions of chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 93. Violation of provisions of chapter(a) Forfeiture of franchise; personal liability of directorsIf the directors of any national banking association shall knowingly violate, or knowingly permit any of the officers, agents, or servants of the association to violate any of the provisions of title 62 of the Revised Statutes, all the rights, privileges, and franchises of the association shall be thereby forfeited. Such violation shall, however, be determined and adjudged by a proper district or Territorial court of the United States in a suit brought for that purpose by the Comptroller of the Currency, in his own name, before the association shall be declared dissolved. And in cases of such violation, every director who participated in or assented to the same shall be held liable in his personal and individual capacity for all damages which the association, its shareholders, or any other person, shall have sustained in consequence of such violation.


(b) Civil money penalty(1) First tierAny national banking association which, and any institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to such association who, violates any provision of title 62 of the Revised Statutes or any of the provisions of section 92a of this title, or any regulation issued pursuant thereto, shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for each day during which such violation continues.


(2) Second tierNotwithstanding paragraph (1), any national banking association which, and any institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to such association who, commits any violation described in paragraph (1) which— 11 So in original. The words “, commits any violation described in paragraph (1) which” probably should not appear.(A)(i) commits any violation described in any 22 So in original. The word “any” probably should not appear. paragraph (1);

(ii) recklessly engages in an unsafe or unsou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_93_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeiture of franchise; personal liability of directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Forfeiture of franchise; personal liability of directors If the directors of any national banking association shall knowingly violate, or knowingly permit any of the officers, agents, or servants of the association to violate any of the provisions of title 62 of the Revised Statutes, all the rights, privileges, and franchises of the association shall be thereby forfeited. Such violation shall, however, be determined and adjudged by a proper district or Territorial court of the United States in a suit brought for that purpose by the Comptroller of the Currency, in his own name, before the association shall be declared dissolved. And in cases of such violation, every director who participated in or assented to the same shall be held liable in his personal and individual capacity for all damages which the association, its shareholders, or any other person, shall have sustained in consequence of such violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_93_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil money penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil money penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_93_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice under this section after separation from service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice under this section after separation from service The resignation, termination of employment or participation, or separation of an institution-affiliated party (within the meaning of section 1813(u) of this title) with respect to such an association (including a separation caused by the closing of such an association) shall not affect the jurisdiction and authority of the Comptroller of the Currency to issue any notice and proceed under this section against any such party, if such notice is served before the end of the 6-year period beginning on the date such party ceased to be such a party with respect to such association (whether such date occurs before, on, or after August 9, 1989).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_93_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forfeiture of franchise for money laundering or cash transaction reporting offenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Forfeiture of franchise for money laundering or cash transaction reporting offenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_93_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>55 So in original. Probably should be “(e)”. Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Comptroller of the Currency may act in the Comptroller’s own name and through the Comptroller’s own attorneys in enforcing any provision of title 62 of the Revised Statutes, regulations thereunder, or any other law or regulation, or in any action, suit, or proceeding to which the Comptroller of the Currency is a party.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>