<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_111"><akn:num>111</akn:num><akn:heading>Assaulting, resisting, or impeding certain officers or employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 111. Assaulting, resisting, or impeding certain officers or employees(a) In General.—Whoever—(1) forcibly assaults, resists, opposes, impedes, intimidates, or interferes with any person designated in section 1114 of this title while engaged in or on account of the performance of official duties; or

(2) forcibly assaults or intimidates any person who formerly served as a person designated in section 1114 on account of the performance of official duties during such person’s term of service,


shall, where the acts in violation of this section constitute only simple assault, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both, and where such acts involve physical contact with the victim of that assault or the intent to commit another felony, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 8 years, or both.

(b) Enhanced Penalty.—Whoever, in the commission of any acts described in subsection (a), uses a deadly or dangerous weapon (including a weapon intended to cause death or danger but that fails to do so by reason of a defective component) or inflicts bodily injury, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.

(c) Extraterritorial Jurisdiction.—There is extraterritorial jurisdiction over the conduct prohibited by this section.

(June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 688; Pub. L. 100–690, title VI, § 6487(a), Nov. 18, 1988, 102 Stat. 4386; Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, § 320101(a), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2108; Pub. L. 104–132, title VII, § 727(c), Apr. 24, 1996, 110 Stat. 1302; Pub. L. 107–273, div. C, title I, § 11008(b), Nov. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 1818; Pub. L. 110–177, title II, § 208(b), Jan. 7, 2008, 121 Stat. 2538; Pub. L. 117–59, § 3(1), Nov. 18, 2021, 135 Stat. 1469.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., §§ 118, 254 (Mar. 4, 1909, ch. 321, § 62, 35 Stat. 1100; May 18, 1934, ch. 299, § 2, 48 Stat. 781).
This section consolidates sections 118 and 254 with changes in phraseolo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whoever— shall, where the acts in violation of this section constitute only simple assault, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both, and where such acts involve physical contact with the victim of that assault or the intent to commit another felony, be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 8 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced Penalty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Whoever, in the commission of any acts described in subsection (a), uses a deadly or dangerous weapon (including a weapon intended to cause death or danger but that fails to do so by reason of a defective component) or inflicts bodily injury, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_111_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extraterritorial Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) There is extraterritorial jurisdiction over the conduct prohibited by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>