<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1707" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1707/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1707/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1707"><akn:num>1707</akn:num><akn:heading>Theft of property used by Postal Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1707. Theft of property used by Postal Service
Whoever steals, purloins, or embezzles any property used by the Postal Service, or appropriates any such property to his own or any other than its proper use, or conveys away any such property to the hindrance or detriment of the public service, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than three years, or both; but if the value of such property does not exceed $1,000, he shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 779; Pub. L. 91–375, § 6(j)(18), Aug. 12, 1970, 84 Stat. 778; Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G), (H), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2147; Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a), Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3511.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 313 (Mar. 4, 1909, ch. 321, § 190, 35 Stat. 1124).
The phrase “used by” was substituted for “in use by or belonging to” in order to limit the application of the section to property used by the Post Office Department. Theft of public property belonging to governmental departments is covered by section 641 of this title.
A fine of “$1,000” was substituted for “$200,” thus increasing the maximum to conform with other comparable sections. (See section 1705 of this title.)
The smaller penalty for an offense involving property valued at $100 or less was added. (See reviser’s notes under sections 641 and 645 of this title.)
Minor changes in phraseology were made.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–294 substituted “$1,000” for “$100”.
1994—Pub. L. 103–322 substituted “fined under this title” for “fined not more than $1,000” after “service, shall be” and for “fined not more than $500” after “he shall be”.
1970—Pub. L. 91–375 substituted “Postal Service” for “Post Office Department”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1970 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 91–375 effective within 1 year after Aug. 12, 1970, on date established </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>