<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1752" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1752/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1752/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1752"><akn:num>1752</akn:num><akn:heading>Restricted building or grounds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1752. Restricted building or grounds(a) Whoever—(1) knowingly enters or remains in any restricted building or grounds without lawful authority to do so;

(2) knowingly, and with intent to impede or disrupt the orderly conduct of Government business or official functions, engages in disorderly or disruptive conduct in, or within such proximity to, any restricted building or grounds when, or so that, such conduct, in fact, impedes or disrupts the orderly conduct of Government business or official functions;

(3) knowingly, and with the intent to impede or disrupt the orderly conduct of Government business or official functions, obstructs or impedes ingress or egress to or from any restricted building or grounds; or 11 So in original. The word “or” probably should not appear.

(4) knowingly engages in any act of physical violence against any person or property in any restricted building or grounds; 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by “or”.

(5) knowingly and willfully operates an unmanned aircraft system with the intent to knowingly and willfully direct or otherwise cause such unmanned aircraft system to enter or operate within or above a restricted building or grounds;


or attempts or conspires to do so, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).

(b) The punishment for a violation of subsection (a) is—(1) a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both, if—(A) the person, during and in relation to the offense, uses or carries a deadly or dangerous weapon or firearm; or

(B) the offense results in significant bodily injury as defined by section 2118(e)(3); and


(2) a fine under this title or imprisonment for not more than one year, or both, in any other case.


(c) In this section—(1) the term “restricted buildings or grounds” means any posted, cordoned off, or otherwise restricted area—(A) of the White House or its grounds, or the Vice President’s official residence or its grounds;

(B) of a building or grounds wher</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whoever— or attempts or conspires to do so, shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The punishment for a violation of subsection (a) is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1752_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>