<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1791" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1791/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1791/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1791"><akn:num>1791</akn:num><akn:heading>Providing or possessing contraband in prison</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1791. Providing or possessing contraband in prison(a) Offense.—Whoever—(1) in violation of a statute or a rule or order issued under a statute, provides to an inmate of a prison a prohibited object, or attempts to do so; or

(2) being an inmate of a prison, makes, possesses, or obtains, or attempts to make or obtain, a prohibited object;


shall be punished as provided in subsection (b) of this section.

(b) Punishment.—The punishment for an offense under this section is a fine under this title or—(1) imprisonment for not more than 20 years, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(C) of this section;

(2) imprisonment for not more than 10 years, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(A) of this section;

(3) imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(B) of this section;

(4) imprisonment for not more than one year, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(D), (d)(1)(E), or (d)(1)(F) of this section; and

(5) imprisonment for not more than 6 months, or both, if the object is specified in subsection (d)(1)(G) of this section.


(c) Consecutive Punishment Required in Certain Cases.—Any punishment imposed under subsection (b) for a violation of this section involving a controlled substance shall be consecutive to any other sentence imposed by any court for an offense involving such a controlled substance. Any punishment imposed under subsection (b) for a violation of this section by an inmate of a prison shall be consecutive to the sentence being served by such inmate at the time the inmate commits such violation.

(d) Definitions.—As used in this section—(1) the term “prohibited object” means—(A) a firearm or destructive device or a controlled substance in schedule I or II, other than marijuana or a controlled substance referred to in subparagraph (C) of this subsection;

(B) marijuana or a controlled substance in schedule III, other than a controlled substance re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whoever— shall be punished as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Punishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The punishment for an offense under this section is a fine under this title or—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consecutive Punishment Required in Certain Cases.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Any punishment imposed under subsection (b) for a violation of this section involving a controlled substance shall be consecutive to any other sentence imposed by any court for an offense involving such a controlled substance. Any punishment imposed under subsection (b) for a violation of this section by an inmate of a prison shall be consecutive to the sentence being served by such inmate at the time the inmate commits such violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>