<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1854" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1854/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1854/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1854"><akn:num>1854</akn:num><akn:heading>Trees boxed for pitch or turpentine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1854. Trees boxed for pitch or turpentine
Whoever cuts, chips, chops, or boxes any tree upon any lands belonging to the United States, or upon any lands covered by or embraced in any unperfected settlement, application, filing, entry, selection, or location, made under any law of the United States, for the purpose of obtaining from such tree any pitch, turpentine, or other substance; or
Whoever buys, trades for, or in any manner acquires any pitch, turpentine, or other substance, or any article or commodity made from any such pitch, turpentine, or other substance, with knowledge that the same has been so unlawfully obtained—
Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 788; Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 601(a)(8), Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3498.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 105 (Mar. 4, 1909, ch. 321, § 51, 35 Stat. 1098).
Reference to persons aiding, encouraging, or causing was deleted as unnecessary since such persons are made principals by section 2 of this title.
Maximum fine was increased from $500 to $1,000 to conform to other comparable sections of this chapter. (See sections 1851 and 1852 of this title.)
Minor changes also were made in phraseology.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–294 substituted “fined under this title” for “fined not more than $1,000” in last par.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>