<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1865" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1865/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/1865/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1865"><akn:num>1865</akn:num><akn:heading>National Park Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1865. National Park Service(a) Violation of Regulations Relating to Use and Management of National Park System Units.—A person that violates any regulation authorized by section 100751(a) of title 54 shall be imprisoned not more than 6 months, fined under this title, or both, and be adjudged to pay all cost of the proceedings.

(b) Financial Disclosure by Officers or Employees Performing Functions or Duties Under Subchapter III of Chapter 1007 of Title 54.—An officer or employee of the Department of the Interior who is subject to, and knowingly violates, section 100737 of title 54 or any regulation prescribed under that section shall be imprisoned not more than one year, fined under this title, or both.

(c) Offenses Relating to Structures and Vegetation.—A person that willfully destroys, mutilates, defaces, injures, or removes any monument, statue, marker, guidepost, or other structure, or that willfully destroys, cuts, breaks, injures, or removes any tree, shrub, or plant within a national military park shall be imprisoned not less than 15 days nor more than one year, fined under this title but not less than $10 for each monument, statue, marker, guidepost, or other structure, tree, shrub, or plant that is destroyed, defaced, injured, cut, or removed, or both.

(d) Trespassing in a National Military Park To Hunt or Shoot.—An individual who trespasses in a national military park to hunt or shoot, or hunts game of any kind in a national military park with a gun or dog, or sets a trap or net or other device in a national military park to hunt or catch game of any kind, shall be imprisoned not less than 5 nor more than 30 days, fined under this title, or both.

(Added Pub. L. 113–287, § 4(a)(1), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3260.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


1865(a)16 U.S.C. 3 (1st sentence words after “National Park Service”) Aug. 25, 1916, ch. 408, § 3 (1st sentence words after “National Park </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violation of Regulations Relating to Use and Management of National Park System Units.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A person that violates any regulation authorized by section 100751(a) of title 54 shall be imprisoned not more than 6 months, fined under this title, or both, and be adjudged to pay all cost of the proceedings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial Disclosure by Officers or Employees Performing Functions or Duties Under Subchapter III of Chapter 1007 of Title 54.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An officer or employee of the Department of the Interior who is subject to, and knowingly violates, section 100737 of title 54 or any regulation prescribed under that section shall be imprisoned not more than one year, fined under this title, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offenses Relating to Structures and Vegetation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A person that willfully destroys, mutilates, defaces, injures, or removes any monument, statue, marker, guidepost, or other structure, or that willfully destroys, cuts, breaks, injures, or removes any tree, shrub, or plant within a national military park shall be imprisoned not less than 15 days nor more than one year, fined under this title but not less than $10 for each monument, statue, marker, guidepost, or other structure, tree, shrub, or plant that is destroyed, defaced, injured, cut, or removed, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trespassing in a National Military Park To Hunt or Shoot.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An individual who trespasses in a national military park to hunt or shoot, or hunts game of any kind in a national military park with a gun or dog, or sets a trap or net or other device in a national military park to hunt or catch game of any kind, shall be imprisoned not less than 5 nor more than 30 days, fined under this title, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>