<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2114" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2114/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2114/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2114"><akn:num>2114</akn:num><akn:heading>Mail, money, or other property of United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2114. Mail, money, or other property of United States(a) Assault.—A person who assaults any person having lawful charge, control, or custody of any mail matter or of any money or other property of the United States, with intent to rob, steal, or purloin such mail matter, money, or other property of the United States, or robs or attempts to rob any such person of mail matter, or of any money, or other property of the United States, shall, for the first offense, be imprisoned not more than ten years; and if in effecting or attempting to effect such robbery he wounds the person having custody of such mail, money, or other property of the United States, or puts his life in jeopardy by the use of a dangerous weapon, or for a subsequent offense, shall be imprisoned not more than twenty-five years.

(b) Receipt, Possession, Concealment, or Disposal of Property.—A person who receives, possesses, conceals, or disposes of any money or other property that has been obtained in violation of this section, knowing the same to have been unlawfully obtained, shall be imprisoned not more than 10 years, fined under this title, or both.

(June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 797; Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 223(d), Oct. 12, 1984, 98 Stat. 2028; Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXV, § 3562, Nov. 29, 1990, 104 Stat. 4927; Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXII, §§ 320602, 320903(a)(3), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2115, 2124; Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 604(b)(17), Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3507.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 320 (Mar. 4, 1909, ch. 321, § 197, 35 Stat. 1126; Aug. 26, 1935, ch. 694, 49 Stat. 867).
The attention of Congress is directed to the mandatory minimum punishment provisions of sections 2113(e) and 2114 of this title. These were left unchanged because of the controversial question involved. Such legislative attempts to control the discretion of the sentencing judge are contrary to the opinions of experienced criminologists and criminal law experts. T</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2114_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assault.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A person who assaults any person having lawful charge, control, or custody of any mail matter or of any money or other property of the United States, with intent to rob, steal, or purloin such mail matter, money, or other property of the United States, or robs or attempts to rob any such person of mail matter, or of any money, or other property of the United States, shall, for the first offense, be imprisoned not more than ten years; and if in effecting or attempting to effect such robbery he wounds the person having custody of such mail, money, or other property of the United States, or puts his life in jeopardy by the use of a dangerous weapon, or for a subsequent offense, shall be imprisoned not more than twenty-five years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2114_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipt, Possession, Concealment, or Disposal of Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A person who receives, possesses, conceals, or disposes of any money or other property that has been obtained in violation of this section, knowing the same to have been unlawfully obtained, shall be imprisoned not more than 10 years, fined under this title, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>