<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2250" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2250/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2250/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2250"><akn:num>2250</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2250. Failure to register(a) In General.—Whoever—(1) is required to register under the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act;

(2)(A) is a sex offender as defined for the purposes of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act by reason of a conviction under Federal law (including the Uniform Code of Military Justice), the law of the District of Columbia, Indian tribal law, or the law of any territory or possession of the United States; or

(B) travels in interstate or foreign commerce, or enters or leaves, or resides in, Indian country; and


(3) knowingly fails to register or update a registration as required by the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act;


shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.

(b) International Travel Reporting Violations.—Whoever—(1) is required to register under the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (42 U.S.C. 16901 et seq.); 11 See References in Text note below.

(2) knowingly fails to provide information required by the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act relating to intended travel in foreign commerce; and

(3) engages or attempts to engage in the intended travel in foreign commerce;


shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.

(c) Affirmative Defense.—In a prosecution for a violation under subsection (a) or (b), it is an affirmative defense that—(1) uncontrollable circumstances prevented the individual from complying;

(2) the individual did not contribute to the creation of such circumstances in reckless disregard of the requirement to comply; and

(3) the individual complied as soon as such circumstances ceased to exist.


(d) Crime of Violence.—(1) In general.—An individual described in subsection (a) or (b) who commits a crime of violence under Federal law (including the Uniform Code of Military Justice), the law of the District of Columbia, Indian tribal law, or the law of any territory or possession of the Uni</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2250_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whoever— shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2250_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Travel Reporting Violations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Whoever— shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2250_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affirmative Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In a prosecution for a violation under subsection (a) or (b), it is an affirmative defense that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2250_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crime of Violence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>