<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2332f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2332f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2332f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2332f"><akn:num>2332f</akn:num><akn:heading>Bombings of places of public use, government facilities, public transportation systems and infrastru</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2332f. Bombings of places of public use, government facilities, public transportation systems and infrastructure facilities(a) Offenses.—(1) In general.—Whoever unlawfully delivers, places, discharges, or detonates an explosive or other lethal device in, into, or against a place of public use, a state or government facility, a public transportation system, or an infrastructure facility—(A) with the intent to cause death or serious bodily injury, or

(B) with the intent to cause extensive destruction of such a place, facility, or system, where such destruction results in or is likely to result in major economic loss,


shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (c).

(2) Attempts and conspiracies.—Whoever attempts or conspires to commit an offense under paragraph (1) shall be punished as prescribed in subsection (c).


(b) Jurisdiction.—There is jurisdiction over the offenses in subsection (a) if—(1) the offense takes place in the United States and—(A) the offense is committed against another state or a government facility of such state, including its embassy or other diplomatic or consular premises of that state;

(B) the offense is committed in an attempt to compel another state or the United States to do or abstain from doing any act;

(C) at the time the offense is committed, it is committed—(i) on board a vessel flying the flag of another state;

(ii) on board an aircraft which is registered under the laws of another state; or

(iii) on board an aircraft which is operated by the government of another state;


(D) a perpetrator is found outside the United States;

(E) a perpetrator is a national of another state or a stateless person; or

(F) a victim is a national of another state or a stateless person;


(2) the offense takes place outside the United States and—(A) a perpetrator is a national of the United States or is a stateless person whose habitual residence is in the United States;

(B) a victim is a national of the United States;

(C) a perpetrator i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) There is jurisdiction over the offenses in subsection (a) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Whoever violates this section shall be punished as provided under section 2332a(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions to Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) This section does not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2332f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) As used in this section, the term—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>