<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2334" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2334/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2334/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2334"><akn:num>2334</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction and venue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2334. Jurisdiction and venue(a) General Venue.—Any civil action under section 2333 of this title against any person may be instituted in the district court of the United States for any district where any plaintiff resides or where any defendant resides or is served, or has an agent. Process in such a civil action may be served in any district where the defendant resides, is found, or has an agent.

(b) Special Maritime or Territorial Jurisdiction.—If the actions giving rise to the claim occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, as defined in section 7 of this title, then any civil action under section 2333 of this title against any person may be instituted in the district court of the United States for any district in which any plaintiff resides or the defendant resides, is served, or has an agent.

(c) Service on Witnesses.—A witness in a civil action brought under section 2333 of this title may be served in any other district where the defendant resides, is found, or has an agent.

(d) Convenience of the Forum.—The district court shall not dismiss any action brought under section 2333 of this title on the grounds of the inconvenience or inappropriateness of the forum chosen, unless—(1) the action may be maintained in a foreign court that has jurisdiction over the subject matter and over all the defendants;

(2) that foreign court is significantly more convenient and appropriate; and

(3) that foreign court offers a remedy which is substantially the same as the one available in the courts of the United States.


(e) Consent of Certain Parties to Personal Jurisdiction.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), for purposes of any civil action under section 2333 of this title, a defendant shall be deemed to have consented to personal jurisdiction in such civil action if, regardless of the date of the occurrence of the act of international terrorism upon which such civil action was filed, the defendant—(A) aft</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2334_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Venue.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any civil action under section 2333 of this title against any person may be instituted in the district court of the United States for any district where any plaintiff resides or where any defendant resides or is served, or has an agent. Process in such a civil action may be served in any district where the defendant resides, is found, or has an agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2334_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Maritime or Territorial Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If the actions giving rise to the claim occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, as defined in section 7 of this title, then any civil action under section 2333 of this title against any person may be instituted in the district court of the United States for any district in which any plaintiff resides or the defendant resides, is served, or has an agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2334_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service on Witnesses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A witness in a civil action brought under section 2333 of this title may be served in any other district where the defendant resides, is found, or has an agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2334_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Convenience of the Forum.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The district court shall not dismiss any action brought under section 2333 of this title on the grounds of the inconvenience or inappropriateness of the forum chosen, unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2334_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consent of Certain Parties to Personal Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>