<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2421" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2421/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2421/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2421"><akn:num>2421</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2421. Transportation generally(a) In General.—Whoever knowingly transports any individual in interstate or foreign commerce, or in any Territory or Possession of the United States, with intent that such individual engage in prostitution, or in any sexual activity for which any person can be charged with a criminal offense, or attempts to do so, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.

(b) Requests To Prosecute Violations by State Attorneys General.—(1) In general.—The Attorney General shall grant a request by a State attorney general that a State or local attorney be cross designated to prosecute a violation of this section unless the Attorney General determines that granting the request would undermine the administration of justice.

(2) Reason for denial.—If the Attorney General denies a request under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall submit to the State attorney general a detailed reason for the denial not later than 60 days after the date on which a request is received.


(Added Pub. L. 114–22, title III, § 303, May 29, 2015, 129 Stat. 255.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 2421, act June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 812; May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 47, 63 Stat. 96; Pub. L. 99–628, § 5(b)(1), Nov. 7, 1986, 100 Stat. 3511; Pub. L. 105–314, title I, § 106, Oct. 30, 1998, 112 Stat. 2977, related to transportation of individuals generally, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 114–22, title III, § 303, May 29, 2015, 129 Stat. 255.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2421_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whoever knowingly transports any individual in interstate or foreign commerce, or in any Territory or Possession of the United States, with intent that such individual engage in prostitution, or in any sexual activity for which any person can be charged with a criminal offense, or attempts to do so, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2421_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requests To Prosecute Violations by State Attorneys General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>