<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2441" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2441/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2441/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2441"><akn:num>2441</akn:num><akn:heading>War crimes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2441. War crimes(a) Offense.—Whoever, whether inside or outside the United States, commits a war crime, in any of the circumstances described in subsection (b), shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for life or any term of years, or both, and if death results to the victim, shall also be subject to the penalty of death.

(b) Jurisdiction.—There is jurisdiction over an offense described in subsection (a) if—(1) the offense occurs in whole or in part within the United States; or

(2) regardless of where the offense occurs—(A) the victim or offender is—(i) a national of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence; or

(ii) a member of the Armed Forces of the United States, regardless of nationality; or


(B) the offender is present in the United States, regardless of the nationality of the victim or offender.



(c) Definition.—As used in this section the term “war crime” means any conduct—(1) defined as a grave breach in any of the international conventions signed at Geneva 12 August 1949, or any protocol to such convention to which the United States is a party;

(2) prohibited by Article 23, 25, 27, or 28 of the Annex to the Hague Convention IV, Respecting the Laws and Customs of War on Land, signed 18 October 1907;

(3) which constitutes a grave breach of common Article 3 (as defined in subsection (d)) when committed in the context of and in association with an armed conflict not of an international character; or

(4) of a person who, in relation to an armed conflict and contrary to the provisions of the Protocol on Prohibitions or Restrictions on the Use of Mines, Booby-Traps and Other Devices as amended at Geneva on 3 May 1996 (Protocol II as amended on 3 May 1996), when the United States is a party to such Protocol, willfully kills or causes serious injury to civilians.


(d) Common Article 3 Violations.—(1) Prohibited conduct.—In subsection (c)(3), the term “grave breach of common Article 3” means any conduct (such conduct c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whoever, whether inside or outside the United States, commits a war crime, in any of the circumstances described in subsection (b), shall be fined under this title or imprisoned for life or any term of years, or both, and if death results to the victim, shall also be subject to the penalty of death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) There is jurisdiction over an offense described in subsection (a) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) As used in this section the term “war crime” means any conduct—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common Article 3 Violations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of Certain Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In the case of an offense described in subsection (a) and further described in subsections (c)(1) and (c)(3), an indictment may be found or an information may be instituted at any time without limitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Input From Other Agency Heads.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Defense and Secretary of State may submit to the Attorney General for consideration their views generally regarding potential benefits, or potential adverse consequences for nationals, servicemembers, or employees of the United States, of prosecutions of offenses for which jurisdiction exists under subsection (b)(2)(B).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Judicial Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Certifications under subsection (f) and input from other agency heads under subsection (g) are not subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2441_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nothing in this section shall be construed as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>