<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/25" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/25/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/25/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_25"><akn:num>25</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of minors in crimes of violence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 25. Use of minors in crimes of violence(a) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Crime of violence.—The term “crime of violence” has the meaning set forth in section 16.

(2) Minor.—The term “minor” means a person who has not reached 18 years of age.

(3) Uses.—The term “uses” means employs, hires, persuades, induces, entices, or coerces.


(b) Penalties.—Any person who is 18 years of age or older, who intentionally uses a minor to commit a crime of violence for which such person may be prosecuted in a court of the United States, or to assist in avoiding detection or apprehension for such an offense, shall—(1) for the first conviction, be subject to twice the maximum term of imprisonment and twice the maximum fine that would otherwise be authorized for the offense; and

(2) for each subsequent conviction, be subject to 3 times the maximum term of imprisonment and 3 times the maximum fine that would otherwise be authorized for the offense.


(Added Pub. L. 108–21, title VI, § 601[(a)], Apr. 30, 2003, 117 Stat. 686.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any person who is 18 years of age or older, who intentionally uses a minor to commit a crime of violence for which such person may be prosecuted in a court of the United States, or to assist in avoiding detection or apprehension for such an offense, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>