<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2523" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2523/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/2523/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2523"><akn:num>2523</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive agreements on access to data by foreign governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2523. Executive agreements on access to data by foreign governments(a) Definitions.—In this section—(1) the term “lawfully admitted for permanent residence” has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101(a)); and

(2) the term “United States person” means a citizen or national of the United States, an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, an unincorporated association a substantial number of members of which are citizens of the United States or aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence, or a corporation that is incorporated in the United States.


(b) Executive Agreement Requirements.—For purposes of this chapter, chapter 121, and chapter 206, an executive agreement governing access by a foreign government to data subject to this chapter, chapter 121, or chapter 206 shall be considered to satisfy the requirements of this section if the Attorney General, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, determines, and submits a written certification of such determination to Congress, including a written certification and explanation of each consideration in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4), that—(1) the domestic law of the foreign government, including the implementation of that law, affords robust substantive and procedural protections for privacy and civil liberties in light of the data collection and activities of the foreign government that will be subject to the agreement, if—(A) such a determination under this section takes into account, as appropriate, credible information and expert input; and

(B) the factors to be met in making such a determination include whether the foreign government—(i) has adequate substantive and procedural laws on cybercrime and electronic evidence, as demonstrated by being a party to the Convention on Cybercrime, done at Budapest November 23, 2001, and entered into force January 7, 2004, or through domestic laws that are consistent with definitions and the r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Agreement Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For purposes of this chapter, chapter 121, and chapter 206, an executive agreement governing access by a foreign government to data subject to this chapter, chapter 121, or chapter 206 shall be considered to satisfy the requirements of this section if the Attorney General, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, determines, and submits a written certification of such determination to Congress, including a written certification and explanation of each consideration in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4), that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Judicial Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A determination or certification made by the Attorney General under subsection (b) shall not be subject to judicial or administrative review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Date of Certification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewal of Determination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revisions to Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A revision to an agreement under this section shall be treated as a new agreement for purposes of this section and shall be subject to the certification requirement under subsection (b), and to the procedures under subsection (d), except that for purposes of a revision to an agreement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Any determination or certification under subsection (b) regarding an executive agreement under this section, including any termination or renewal of such an agreement, shall be published in the Federal Register as soon as is reasonably practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2523_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimization Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) A United States authority that receives the content of a communication described in subsection (b)(4)(H) from a foreign government in accordance with an executive agreement under this section shall use procedures that, to the maximum extent possible, meet the definition of minimization procedures in section 101 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (50 U.S.C. 1801) to appropriately protect nonpublicly available information concerning United States persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>