<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/288" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/288/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/288/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_288"><akn:num>288</akn:num><akn:heading>False claims for postal losses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 288. False claims for postal losses
Whoever makes, alleges, or presents any claim or application for indemnity for the loss of any registered or insured letter, parcel, package, or other article or matter, or the contents thereof, knowing such claim or application to be false, fictitious, or fraudulent; or
Whoever for the purpose of obtaining or aiding to obtain the payment or approval of any such claim or application, makes or uses any false statement, certificate, affidavit, or deposition; or
Whoever knowingly and willfully misrepresents, or misstates, or, for the purpose aforesaid, knowingly and willfully conceals any material fact or circumstance in respect of any such claim or application for indemnity—
Shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than one year, or both.
Where the amount of such claim or application for indemnity is less than $1,000 only a fine shall be imposed.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 698; Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(G), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2147; Pub. L. 104–294, title VI, § 606(a), Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3511.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 354 (Mar. 4, 1909, ch. 321, § 224, 35 Stat. 1133; Aug. 5, 1939, ch. 429, 53 Stat. 1203).
Reference to persons causing, assisting, aiding, or abetting, was omitted as such persons are made principals by section 2 of this title.
Changes in phraseology were made.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–294 substituted “$1,000” for “$100” in fifth par.
1994—Pub. L. 103–322 substituted “fined under this title” for “fined not more than $500” in fourth par.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>