<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3071" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3071/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3071/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3071"><akn:num>3071</akn:num><akn:heading>Information for which rewards authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3071. Information for which rewards authorized(a) With respect to acts of terrorism primarily within the territorial jurisdiction of the United States, the Attorney General may reward any individual who furnishes information—(1) leading to the arrest or conviction, in any country, of any individual or individuals for the commission of an act of terrorism against a United States person or United States property; or

(2) leading to the arrest or conviction, in any country, of any individual or individuals for conspiring or attempting to commit an act of terrorism against a United States person or property; or

(3) leading to the prevention, frustration, or favorable resolution of an act of terrorism against a United States person or property.


(b) With respect to acts of espionage involving or directed at the United States, the Attorney General may reward any individual who furnishes information—(1) leading to the arrest or conviction, in any country, of any individual or individuals for commission of an act of espionage against the United States;

(2) leading to the arrest or conviction, in any country, of any individual or individuals for conspiring or attempting to commit an act of espionage against the United States; or

(3) leading to the prevention or frustration of an act of espionage against the United States.


(Added Pub. L. 98–533, title I, § 101(a), Oct. 19, 1984, 98 Stat. 2706; amended Pub. L. 103–359, title VIII, § 803(a), Oct. 14, 1994, 108 Stat. 3438.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–359 designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short TitlePub. L. 98–533, § 1, Oct. 19, 1984, 98 Stat. 2706, provided that: “This Act [enacting this chapter and section 2708 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse, amending sections 2669, 2678 and 2704 of Title 22, enacting provisions set out as a note under section 5928 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees and amending p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) With respect to acts of terrorism primarily within the territorial jurisdiction of the United States, the Attorney General may reward any individual who furnishes information—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3071_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) With respect to acts of espionage involving or directed at the United States, the Attorney General may reward any individual who furnishes information—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>