<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3113"><akn:num>3113</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquor violations in Indian country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3113. Liquor violations in Indian country
If any superintendent of Indian affairs, or commanding officer of a military post, or special agent of the Office of Indian Affairs for the suppression of liquor traffic among Indians and in the Indian country and any authorized deputies under his supervision has probable cause to believe that any person is about to introduce or has introduced any spirituous liquor, beer, wine or other intoxicating liquors named in sections 1154 and 1156 of this title into the Indian country in violation of law, he may cause the places, conveyances, and packages of such person to be searched. If any such intoxicating liquor is found therein, the same, together with such conveyances and packages of such person, shall be seized and delivered to the proper officer, and shall be proceeded against by libel in the proper court, and forfeited, one-half to the informer and one-half to the use of the United States. If such person be a trader, his license shall be revoked and his bond put in suit.
Any person in the service of the United States authorized by this section to make searches and seizures, or any Indian may take and destroy any ardent spirits or wine found in the Indian country, except such as are kept or used for scientific, sacramental, medicinal, or mechanical purposes or such as may be introduced therein by the Department of the Army.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 820; Oct. 31, 1951, ch. 655, § 30, 65 Stat. 721; Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330004(15), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2142.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on sections 246, 248, 252 of title 25, U.S.C., 1940 ed., Indians (R.S. § 2140; Mar. 1, 1907, ch. 2285, 34 Stat. 1017; May 18, 1916, ch. 125, § 1, 39 Stat. 124).
Said sections 246, 248, and 252 were consolidated. References to Indian agent and subagent were deleted since those positions no longer exist. See section 64 of title 25, U.S.C., 1940 ed., Indians, and notes thereunder.
Words “except such as are kept or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>