<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3193" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3193/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3193/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3193"><akn:num>3193</akn:num><akn:heading>Receiving agent’s authority over offenders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3193. Receiving agent’s authority over offenders
A duly appointed agent to receive, in behalf of the United States, the delivery, by a foreign government, of any person accused of crime committed within the United States, and to convey him to the place of his trial, shall have all the powers of a marshal of the United States, in the several districts through which it may be necessary for him to pass with such prisoner, so far as such power is requisite for the prisoner’s safe-keeping.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 825.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 18, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 660 (R.S. § 5276).
Words “jurisdiction of the” were omitted in view of the definition of United States in section 5 of this title.
Minor changes only were made in phraseology.

Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 11517. Issuance and Signature by Secretary of State of Warrants Appointing Agents To Return Fugitives From Justice Extradited to United States
Ex. Ord. No. 11517, Mar. 19, 1970, 35 F.R. 4937, provided:
WHEREAS the President of the United States, under section 3192 of Title 18, United States Code, has been granted the power to take all necessary measures for the transportation, safekeeping and security against lawless violence of any person delivered by any foreign government to an agent of the United States for return to the United States for trial for any offense of which he is duly accused; and
WHEREAS fugitives from justice in the United States whose extradition from abroad has been requested by the Government of the United States and granted by a foreign government are to be returned in the custody of duly appointed agents in accordance with the provisions of section 3193 of Title 18, United States Code; and
WHEREAS such duly appointed agents under the provisions of the law mentioned above, being authorized to receive delivery of the fugitive in behalf of the United States and to convey him to the place of his trial, are given the powers of a marshal of the United S</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>