<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3512" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3512/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3512/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3512"><akn:num>3512</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign requests for assistance in criminal investigations and prosecutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3512. Foreign requests for assistance in criminal investigations and prosecutions(a) Execution of Request for Assistance.—(1) In general.—Upon application, duly authorized by an appropriate official of the Department of Justice, of an attorney for the Government, a Federal judge may issue such orders as may be necessary to execute a request from a foreign authority for assistance in the investigation or prosecution of criminal offenses, or in proceedings related to the prosecution of criminal offenses, including proceedings regarding forfeiture, sentencing, and restitution.

(2) Scope of orders.—Any order issued by a Federal judge pursuant to paragraph (1) may include the issuance of—(A) a search warrant, as provided under Rule 41 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure;

(B) a warrant or order for contents of stored wire or electronic communications or for records related thereto, as provided under section 2703 of this title;

(C) an order for a pen register or trap and trace device as provided under section 3123 of this title; or

(D) an order requiring the appearance of a person for the purpose of providing testimony or a statement, or requiring the production of documents or other things, or both.



(b) Appointment of Persons To Take Testimony or Statements.—(1) In general.—In response to an application for execution of a request from a foreign authority as described under subsection (a), a Federal judge may also issue an order appointing a person to direct the taking of testimony or statements or of the production of documents or other things, or both.

(2) Authority of appointed person.—Any person appointed under an order issued pursuant to paragraph (1) may—(A) issue orders requiring the appearance of a person, or the production of documents or other things, or both;

(B) administer any necessary oath; and

(C) take testimony or statements and receive documents or other things.



(c) Filing of Requests.—Except as provided under subsection (d), an appli</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Execution of Request for Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Persons To Take Testimony or Statements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of Requests.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Except as provided under subsection (d), an application for execution of a request from a foreign authority under this section may be filed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Search Warrant Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An application for execution of a request for a search warrant from a foreign authority under this section, other than an application for a warrant issued as provided under section 2703 of this title, shall be filed in the district in which the place or person to be searched is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Search Warrant Standard.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A Federal judge may issue a search warrant under this section only if the foreign offense for which the evidence is sought involves conduct that, if committed in the United States, would be considered an offense punishable by imprisonment for more than one year under Federal or State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of Order or Warrant.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Except as provided under subsection (d), an order or warrant issued pursuant to this section may be served or executed in any place in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude any foreign authority or an interested person from obtaining assistance in a criminal investigation or prosecution pursuant to section 1782 of title 28, United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3512_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) As used in this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>