<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3572" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3572/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3572/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3572"><akn:num>3572</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of a sentence of fine and related matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3572. Imposition of a sentence of fine and related matters(a) Factors To Be Considered.—In determining whether to impose a fine, and the amount, time for payment, and method of payment of a fine, the court shall consider, in addition to the factors set forth in section 3553(a)—(1) the defendant’s income, earning capacity, and financial resources;

(2) the burden that the fine will impose upon the defendant, any person who is financially dependent on the defendant, or any other person (including a government) that would be responsible for the welfare of any person financially dependent on the defendant, relative to the burden that alternative punishments would impose;

(3) any pecuniary loss inflicted upon others as a result of the offense;

(4) whether restitution is ordered or made and the amount of such restitution;

(5) the need to deprive the defendant of illegally obtained gains from the offense;

(6) the expected costs to the government of any imprisonment, supervised release, or probation component of the sentence;

(7) whether the defendant can pass on to consumers or other persons the expense of the fine; and

(8) if the defendant is an organization, the size of the organization and any measure taken by the organization to discipline any officer, director, employee, or agent of the organization responsible for the offense and to prevent a recurrence of such an offense.


(b) Fine Not to Impair Ability to Make Restitution.—If, as a result of a conviction, the defendant has the obligation to make restitution to a victim of the offense, other than the United States, the court shall impose a fine or other monetary penalty only to the extent that such fine or penalty will not impair the ability of the defendant to make restitution.

(c) Effect of Finality of Judgment.—Notwithstanding the fact that a sentence to pay a fine can subsequently be—(1) modified or remitted under section 3573;

(2) corrected under rule 35 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors To Be Considered.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In determining whether to impose a fine, and the amount, time for payment, and method of payment of a fine, the court shall consider, in addition to the factors set forth in section 3553(a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fine Not to Impair Ability to Make Restitution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If, as a result of a conviction, the defendant has the obligation to make restitution to a victim of the offense, other than the United States, the court shall impose a fine or other monetary penalty only to the extent that such fine or penalty will not impair the ability of the defendant to make restitution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Finality of Judgment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding the fact that a sentence to pay a fine can subsequently be— a judgment that includes such a sentence is a final judgment for all other purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time, Method of Payment, and Related Items.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative Sentence Precluded.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) At the time a defendant is sentenced to pay a fine, the court may not impose an alternative sentence to be carried out if the fine is not paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility for Payment of Monetary Obligation Relating to Organization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) If a sentence includes a fine, special assessment, restitution or other monetary obligation (including interest) with respect to an organization, each individual authorized to make disbursements for the organization has a duty to pay the obligation from assets of the organization. If such an obligation is imposed on a director, officer, shareholder, employee, or agent of an organization, payments may not be made, directly or indirectly, from assets of the organization, unless the court finds that such payment is expressly permissible under applicable State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security for Stayed Fine.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) If a sentence imposing a fine is stayed, the court shall, absent exceptional circumstances (as determined by the court)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delinquency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) A fine or payment of restitution is delinquent if a payment is more than 30 days late.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Default.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A fine or payment of restitution is in default if a payment is delinquent for more than 90 days. Notwithstanding any installment schedule, when a fine or payment of restitution is in default, the entire amount of the fine or restitution is due within 30 days after notification of the default, subject to the provisions of section 3613A.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>