<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3573" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3573/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3573/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3573"><akn:num>3573</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition of the Government for modification or remission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3573. Petition of the Government for modification or remission
Upon petition of the Government showing that reasonable efforts to collect a fine or assessment are not likely to be effective, the court may, in the interest of justice—(1) remit all or part of the unpaid portion of the fine or special assessment, including interest and penalties;

(2) defer payment of the fine or special assessment to a date certain or pursuant to an installment schedule; or

(3) extend a date certain or an installment schedule previously ordered.


A petition under this subsection shall be filed in the court in which sentence was originally imposed, unless the court transfers jurisdiction to another court. This section shall apply to all fines and assessments irrespective of the date of imposition.
(Added Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 212(a)(2), Oct. 12, 1984, 98 Stat. 1997; amended Pub. L. 100–185, § 8(a), Dec. 11, 1987, 101 Stat. 1282; Pub. L. 100–690, title VII, § 7082(a), Nov. 18, 1988, 102 Stat. 4407.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsFor a prior section 3573, applicable to offenses committed prior to Nov. 1, 1987, see note set out preceding section 3551 of this title.

Amendments1988—Pub. L. 100–690 inserted at end “This section shall apply to all fines and assessments irrespective of the date of imposition.”
1987—Pub. L. 100–185 substituted “Petition of the Government for modification or remission” for “Modification or remission of fine” in section catchline and amended text generally, revising and restating as a single paragraph with three numbered clauses provisions formerly contained in subsecs. (a) and (b).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Nov. 1, 1987, and applicable only to offenses committed after the taking effect of this section, see section 235(a)(1) of Pub. L. 98–473, set out as a note under section 3551 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3573_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) remit all or part of the unpaid portion of the fine or special assessment, including interest and penalties;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3573_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) defer payment of the fine or special assessment to a date certain or pursuant to an installment schedule; or</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3573_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) extend a date certain or an installment schedule previously ordered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>