<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3583" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3583/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3583/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3583"><akn:num>3583</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of a term of supervised release after imprisonment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3583. Inclusion of a term of supervised release after imprisonment(a) In General.—The court, in imposing a sentence to a term of imprisonment for a felony or a misdemeanor, may include as a part of the sentence a requirement that the defendant be placed on a term of supervised release after imprisonment, except that the court shall include as a part of the sentence a requirement that the defendant be placed on a term of supervised release if such a term is required by statute or if the defendant has been convicted for the first time of a domestic violence crime as defined in section 3561(b).

(b) Authorized Terms of Supervised Release.—Except as otherwise provided, the authorized terms of supervised release are—(1) for a Class A or Class B felony, not more than five years;

(2) for a Class C or Class D felony, not more than three years; and

(3) for a Class E felony, or for a misdemeanor (other than a petty offense), not more than one year.


(c) Factors To Be Considered in Including a Term of Supervised Release.—The court, in determining whether to include a term of supervised release, and, if a term of supervised release is to be included, in determining the length of the term and the conditions of supervised release, shall consider the factors set forth in section 3553(a)(1), (a)(2)(B), (a)(2)(C), (a)(2)(D), (a)(4), (a)(5), (a)(6), and (a)(7).

(d) Conditions of Supervised Release.—The court shall order, as an explicit condition of supervised release, that the defendant not commit another Federal, State, or local crime during the term of supervision, that the defendant make restitution in accordance with sections 3663 and 3663A, or any other statute authorizing a sentence of restitution, and that the defendant not unlawfully possess a controlled substance. The court shall order as an explicit condition of supervised release for a defendant convicted for the first time of a domestic violence crime as defined in section 3561(b) that the defendant attend a public,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The court, in imposing a sentence to a term of imprisonment for a felony or a misdemeanor, may include as a part of the sentence a requirement that the defendant be placed on a term of supervised release after imprisonment, except that the court shall include as a part of the sentence a requirement that the defendant be placed on a term of supervised release if such a term is required by statute or if the defendant has been convicted for the first time of a domestic violence crime as defined in section 3561(b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Terms of Supervised Release.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as otherwise provided, the authorized terms of supervised release are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors To Be Considered in Including a Term of Supervised Release.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The court, in determining whether to include a term of supervised release, and, if a term of supervised release is to be included, in determining the length of the term and the conditions of supervised release, shall consider the factors set forth in section 3553(a)(1), (a)(2)(B), (a)(2)(C), (a)(2)(D), (a)(4), (a)(5), (a)(6), and (a)(7).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of Supervised Release.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The court shall order, as an explicit condition of supervised release, that the defendant not commit another Federal, State, or local crime during the term of supervision, that the defendant make restitution in accordance with sections 3663 and 3663A, or any other statute authorizing a sentence of restitution, and that the defendant not unlawfully possess a controlled substance. The court shall order as an explicit condition of supervised release for a defendant convicted for the first time of a domestic violence crime as defined in section 3561(b) that the defendant attend a public, private, or private nonprofit offender rehabilitation program that has been approved by the court, in consultation with a State Coalition Against Domestic Violence or other appropriate experts, if an approved program is readily available within a 50-mile radius of the legal residence of the defendant. The court shall order, as an explicit condition of supervised release for a person required to registe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of Conditions or Revocation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The court may, after considering the factors set forth in section 3553(a)(1), (a)(2)(B), (a)(2)(C), (a)(2)(D), (a)(4), (a)(5), (a)(6), and (a)(7)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written Statement of Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The court shall direct that the probation officer provide the defendant with a written statement that sets forth all the conditions to which the term of supervised release is subject, and that is sufficiently clear and specific to serve as a guide for the defendant’s conduct and for such supervision as is required.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory Revocation for Possession of Controlled Substance or Firearm or for Refusal To Comply With Drug Testing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) If the defendant— the court shall revoke the term of supervised release and require the defendant to serve a term of imprisonment not to exceed the maximum term of imprisonment authorized under subsection (e)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervised Release Following Revocation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) When a term of supervised release is revoked and the defendant is required to serve a term of imprisonment, the court may include a requirement that the defendant be placed on a term of supervised release after imprisonment. The length of such a term of supervised release shall not exceed the term of supervised release authorized by statute for the offense that resulted in the original term of supervised release, less any term of imprisonment that was imposed upon revocation of supervised release.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delayed Revocation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The power of the court to revoke a term of supervised release for violation of a condition of supervised release, and to order the defendant to serve a term of imprisonment and, subject to the limitations in subsection (h), a further term of supervised release, extends beyond the expiration of the term of supervised release for any period reasonably necessary for the adjudication of matters arising before its expiration if, before its expiration, a warrant or summons has been issued on the basis of an allegation of such a violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3583_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervised Release Terms for Terrorism Predicates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Notwithstanding subsection (b), the authorized term of supervised release for any offense listed in section 2332b(g)(5)(B) is any term of years or life.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>