<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3612" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3612/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3612/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3612"><akn:num>3612</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of unpaid fine or restitution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3612. Collection of unpaid fine or restitution(a) Notification of Receipt and Related Matters.—The clerk or the person designated under section 604(a)(18) of title 28 shall notify the Attorney General of each receipt of a payment with respect to which a certification is made under subsection (b), together with other appropriate information relating to such payment. The notification shall be provided—(1) in such manner as may be agreed upon by the Attorney General and the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts; and

(2) within 15 days after the receipt or at such other time as may be determined jointly by the Attorney General and the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts.


If the fifteenth day under paragraph (2) is a Saturday, Sunday, or legal public holiday, the clerk, or the person designated under section 604(a)(18) of title 28, shall provide notification not later than the next day that is not a Saturday, Sunday, or legal public holiday.

(b) Information to be Included in Judgment; Judgment to be Transmitted to Attorney General.—(1) A judgment or order imposing, modifying, or remitting a fine or restitution order of more than $100 shall include—(A) the name, social security account number, mailing address, and residence address of the defendant;

(B) the docket number of the case;

(C) the original amount of the fine or restitution order and the amount that is due and unpaid;

(D) the schedule of payments (if other than immediate payment is permitted under section 3572(d));

(E) a description of any modification or remission;

(F) if other than immediate payment is permitted, a requirement that, until the fine or restitution order is paid in full, the defendant notify the Attorney General of any change in the mailing address or residence address of the defendant not later than thirty days after the change occurs; and

(G) in the case of a restitution order, information sufficient to identify each victim t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Receipt and Related Matters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The clerk or the person designated under section 604(a)(18) of title 28 shall notify the Attorney General of each receipt of a payment with respect to which a certification is made under subsection (b), together with other appropriate information relating to such payment. The notification shall be provided— If the fifteenth day under paragraph (2) is a Saturday, Sunday, or legal public holiday, the clerk, or the person designated under section 604(a)(18) of title 28, shall provide notification not later than the next day that is not a Saturday, Sunday, or legal public holiday.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information to be Included in Judgment; Judgment to be Transmitted to Attorney General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility for Collection.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Attorney General shall be responsible for collection of an unpaid fine or restitution concerning which a certification has been issued as provided in subsection (b). An order of restitution, pursuant to section 3556, does not create any right of action against the United States by the person to whom restitution is ordered to be paid. Any money received from a defendant shall be disbursed so that each of the following obligations is paid in full in the following sequence:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Delinquency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Within ten working days after a fine or restitution is determined to be delinquent as provided in section 3572(h), the Attorney General shall notify the person whose fine or restitution is delinquent, to inform the person of the delinquency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Default.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Within ten working days after a fine or restitution is determined to be in default as provided in section 3572(i), the Attorney General shall notify the person defaulting to inform the person that the fine or restitution is in default and the entire unpaid balance, including interest and penalties, is due within thirty days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest on Fines and restitution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for Delinquent Fine.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) If a fine or restitution becomes delinquent, the defendant shall pay, as a penalty, an amount equal to 10 percent of the principal amount that is delinquent. If a fine or restitution becomes in default, the defendant shall pay, as a penalty, an additional amount equal to 15 percent of the principal amount that is in default.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of Interest or Penalty by Attorney General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Attorney General may waive all or part of any interest or penalty under this section or any interest or penalty relating to a fine imposed under any prior law if, as determined by the Attorney General, reasonable efforts to collect the interest or penalty are not likely to be effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Payments relating to fines and restitution shall be applied in the following order: (1) to principal; (2) to costs; (3) to interest; and (4) to penalties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of Offices of the United States Attorney and Department Components.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>