<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3742" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3742/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/3742/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3742"><akn:num>3742</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of a sentence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3742. Review of a sentence(a) Appeal by a Defendant.—A defendant may file a notice of appeal in the district court for review of an otherwise final sentence if the sentence—(1) was imposed in violation of law;

(2) was imposed as a result of an incorrect application of the sentencing guidelines; or

(3) is greater than the sentence specified in the applicable guideline range to the extent that the sentence includes a greater fine or term of imprisonment, probation, or supervised release than the maximum established in the guideline range, or includes a more limiting condition of probation or supervised release under section 3563(b)(6) or (b)(11) 11 See References in Text note below. than the maximum established in the guideline range; or

(4) was imposed for an offense for which there is no sentencing guideline and is plainly unreasonable.


(b) Appeal by the Government.—The Government may file a notice of appeal in the district court for review of an otherwise final sentence if the sentence—(1) was imposed in violation of law;

(2) was imposed as a result of an incorrect application of the sentencing guidelines;

(3) is less than the sentence specified in the applicable guideline range to the extent that the sentence includes a lesser fine or term of imprisonment, probation, or supervised release than the minimum established in the guideline range, or includes a less limiting condition of probation or supervised release under section 3563(b)(6) or (b)(11) 1 than the minimum established in the guideline range; or

(4) was imposed for an offense for which there is no sentencing guideline and is plainly unreasonable.


The Government may not further prosecute such appeal without the personal approval of the Attorney General, the Solicitor General, or a deputy solicitor general designated by the Solicitor General.

(c) Plea Agreements.—In the case of a plea agreement that includes a specific sentence under rule 11(e)(1)(C) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure—(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal by a Defendant.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A defendant may file a notice of appeal in the district court for review of an otherwise final sentence if the sentence—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal by the Government.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Government may file a notice of appeal in the district court for review of an otherwise final sentence if the sentence— The Government may not further prosecute such appeal without the personal approval of the Attorney General, the Solicitor General, or a deputy solicitor general designated by the Solicitor General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plea Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In the case of a plea agreement that includes a specific sentence under rule 11(e)(1)(C) of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Record on Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If a notice of appeal is filed in the district court pursuant to subsection (a) or (b), the clerk shall certify to the court of appeals—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Upon review of the record, the court of appeals shall determine whether the sentence— The court of appeals shall give due regard to the opportunity of the district court to judge the credibility of the witnesses, and shall accept the findings of fact of the district court unless they are clearly erroneous and, except with respect to determinations under subsection (3)(A) or (3)(B), shall give due deference to the district court’s application of the guidelines to the facts. With respect to determinations under subsection (3)(A) or (3)(B), the court of appeals shall review de novo the district court’s application of the guidelines to the facts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decision and Disposition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) If the court of appeals determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sentencing Upon Remand.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A district court to which a case is remanded pursuant to subsection (f)(1) or (f)(2) shall resentence a defendant in accordance with section 3553 and with such instructions as may have been given by the court of appeals, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to a Sentence by a Magistrate Judge.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) An appeal of an otherwise final sentence imposed by a United States magistrate judge may be taken to a judge of the district court, and this section shall apply (except for the requirement of approval by the Attorney General or the Solicitor General in the case of a Government appeal) as though the appeal were to a court of appeals from a sentence imposed by a district court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guideline Not Expressed as a Range.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) For the purpose of this section, the term “guideline range” includes a guideline range having the same upper and lower limits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3742_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>