<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/4048" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/4048/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/4048/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4048"><akn:num>4048</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for health care services for prisoners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4048. Fees for health care services for prisoners(a) Definitions.—In this section—(1) the term “account” means the trust fund account (or institutional equivalent) of a prisoner;

(2) the term “Director” means the Director of the Bureau of Prisons;

(3) the term “health care provider” means any person who is—(A) authorized by the Director to provide health care services; and

(B) operating within the scope of such authorization;


(4) the term “health care visit”—(A) means a visit, as determined by the Director, by a prisoner to an institutional or noninstitutional health care provider; and

(B) does not include a visit initiated by a prisoner—(i) pursuant to a staff referral; or

(ii) to obtain staff-approved follow-up treatment for a chronic condition; and



(5) the term “prisoner” means—(A) any individual who is incarcerated in an institution under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Prisons; or

(B) any other individual, as designated by the Director, who has been charged with or convicted of an offense against the United States.



(b) Fees for Health Care Services.—(1) In general.—The Director, in accordance with this section and with such regulations as the Director shall promulgate to carry out this section, may assess and collect a fee for health care services provided in connection with each health care visit requested by a prisoner.

(2) Exclusion.—The Director may not assess or collect a fee under this section for preventative health care services, emergency services, prenatal care, diagnosis or treatment of chronic infectious diseases, mental health care, or substance abuse treatment, as determined by the Director.


(c) Persons Subject to Fee.—Each fee assessed under this section shall be collected by the Director from the account of—(1) the prisoner receiving health care services in connection with a health care visit described in subsection (b)(1); or

(2) in the case of health care services provided in connection with a health care visit described </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for Health Care Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons Subject to Fee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each fee assessed under this section shall be collected by the Director from the account of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of Fee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Any fee assessed and collected under this section shall be in an amount of not less than $1.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Consent Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the consent of a prisoner shall not be required for the collection of a fee from the account of the prisoner under this section. However, each such prisoner shall be given a reasonable opportunity to dispute the amount of the fee or whether the prisoner qualifies under an exclusion under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Refusal of Treatment For Financial Reasons.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section may be construed to permit any refusal of treatment to a prisoner on the basis that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Prisoners of Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Each person who is or becomes a prisoner shall be provided with written and oral notices of the provisions of this section and the applicability of this section to the prisoner. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a fee under this section may not be assessed against, or collected from, such person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Prisoners of Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The regulations promulgated by the Director under subsection (b)(1), and any amendments to those regulations, shall not take effect until the expiration of the 30-day period beginning on the date on which each prisoner in the prison system is provided with written and oral notices of the provisions of those regulations (or amendments, as the case may be). A fee under this section may not be assessed against, or collected from, a prisoner pursuant to such regulations (or amendments, as the case may be) for services provided before the expiration of such period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4048_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice Before Public Comment Period.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Before the beginning of any period a proposed regulation under this section is open to public comment, the Director shall provide written and oral notice of the provisions of that proposed regulation to groups that advocate on behalf of Federal prisoners and to each prisoner subject to such proposed regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>