<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/48" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/48/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/48/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_48"><akn:num>48</akn:num><akn:heading>Animal crushing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 48. Animal crushing(a) Offenses.—(1) Crushing.—It shall be unlawful for any person to purposely engage in animal crushing in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States.

(2) Creation of animal crush videos.—It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly create an animal crush video, if—(A) the person intends or has reason to know that the animal crush video will be distributed in, or using a means or facility of, interstate or foreign commerce; or

(B) the animal crush video is distributed in, or using a means or facility of, interstate or foreign commerce.


(3) Distribution of animal crush videos.—It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sell, market, advertise, exchange, or distribute an animal crush video in, or using a means or facility of, interstate or foreign commerce.


(b) Extraterritorial Application.—This section applies to the knowing sale, marketing, advertising, exchange, distribution, or creation of an animal crush video outside of the United States, if—(1) the person engaging in such conduct intends or has reason to know that the animal crush video will be transported into the United States or its territories or possessions; or

(2) the animal crush video is transported into the United States or its territories or possessions.


(c) Penalties.—Whoever violates this section shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 7 years, or both.

(d) Exceptions.—(1) In general.—This section does not apply with regard to any conduct, or a visual depiction of that conduct, that is—(A) a customary and normal veterinary, agricultural husbandry, or other animal management practice;

(B) the slaughter of animals for food;

(C) hunting, trapping, fishing, a sporting activity not otherwise prohibited by Federal law, predator control, or pest control;

(D) medical or scientific research;

(E) necessary to protect the life or property of a person; or

(F) perfo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extraterritorial Application.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) This section applies to the knowing sale, marketing, advertising, exchange, distribution, or creation of an animal crush video outside of the United States, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Whoever violates this section shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 7 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Preemption.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt the law of any State or local subdivision thereof to protect animals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>