<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/5037" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/5037/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/5037/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5037"><akn:num>5037</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispositional hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5037. Dispositional hearing(a) If the court finds a juvenile to be a juvenile delinquent, the court shall hold a disposition hearing concerning the appropriate disposition no later than twenty court days after the juvenile delinquency hearing unless the court has ordered further study pursuant to subsection (d). After the disposition hearing, and after considering any pertinent policy statements promulgated by the Sentencing Commission pursuant to 28 U.S.C. 994, the court may suspend the findings of juvenile delinquency, place him on probation, or commit him to official detention which may include a term of juvenile delinquent supervision to follow detention. In addition, the court may enter an order of restitution pursuant to section 3556. With respect to release or detention pending an appeal or a petition for a writ of certiorari after disposition, the court shall proceed pursuant to the provisions of chapter 207.

(b) The term for which probation may be ordered for a juvenile found to be a juvenile delinquent may not extend—(1) in the case of a juvenile who is less than eighteen years old, beyond the lesser of—(A) the date when the juvenile becomes twenty-one years old; or

(B) the maximum term that would be authorized by section 3561(c) if the juvenile had been tried and convicted as an adult; or


(2) in the case of a juvenile who is between eighteen and twenty-one years old, beyond the lesser of—(A) three years; or

(B) the maximum term that would be authorized by section 3561(c) if the juvenile had been tried and convicted as an adult.



The provisions dealing with probation set forth in sections 3563 and 3564 are applicable to an order placing a juvenile on probation. If the juvenile violates a condition of probation at any time prior to the expiration or termination of the term of probation, the court may, after a dispositional hearing and after considering any pertinent policy statements promulgated by the Sentencing Commission pursuant to section 994 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5037_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) If the court finds a juvenile to be a juvenile delinquent, the court shall hold a disposition hearing concerning the appropriate disposition no later than twenty court days after the juvenile delinquency hearing unless the court has ordered further study pursuant to subsection (d). After the disposition hearing, and after considering any pertinent policy statements promulgated by the Sentencing Commission pursuant to 28 U.S.C. 994, the court may suspend the findings of juvenile delinquency, place him on probation, or commit him to official detention which may include a term of juvenile delinquent supervision to follow detention. In addition, the court may enter an order of restitution pursuant to section 3556. With respect to release or detention pending an appeal or a petition for a writ of certiorari after disposition, the court shall proceed pursuant to the provisions of chapter 207.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5037_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The term for which probation may be ordered for a juvenile found to be a juvenile delinquent may not extend— The provisions dealing with probation set forth in sections 3563 and 3564 are applicable to an order placing a juvenile on probation. If the juvenile violates a condition of probation at any time prior to the expiration or termination of the term of probation, the court may, after a dispositional hearing and after considering any pertinent policy statements promulgated by the Sentencing Commission pursuant to section 994 of title 28, revoke the term of probation and order a term of official detention. The term of official detention authorized upon revocation of probation shall not exceed the terms authorized in section 5037(c)(2)(A) and (B). The application of sections 5037(c)(2)(A) and (B) shall be determined based upon the age of the juvenile at the time of the disposition of the revocation proceeding. If a juvenile is over the age of 21 years old at the time of the revoca</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5037_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term for which official detention may be ordered for a juvenile found to be a juvenile delinquent may not extend— Section 3624 is applicable to an order placing a juvenile under detention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5037_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5037_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If the court desires more detailed information concerning an alleged or adjudicated delinquent, it may commit him, after notice and hearing at which the juvenile is represented by counsel, to the custody of the Attorney General for observation and study by an appropriate agency. Such observation and study shall be conducted on an out-patient basis, unless the court determines that inpatient observation and study are necessary to obtain the desired information. In the case of an alleged juvenile delinquent, inpatient study may be ordered only with the consent of the juvenile and his attorney. The agency shall make a complete study of the alleged or adjudicated delinquent to ascertain his personal traits, his capabilities, his background, any previous delinquency or criminal experience, any mental or physical defect, and any other relevant factors. The Attorney General shall submit to the court and the attorneys for the juvenile and the Government the results of the study within thir</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>