<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_702"><akn:num>702</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniform of armed forces and Public Health Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 702. Uniform of armed forces and Public Health Service
Whoever, in any place within the jurisdiction of the United States or in the Canal Zone, without authority, wears the uniform or a distinctive part thereof or anything similar to a distinctive part of the uniform of any of the armed forces of the United States, Public Health Service or any auxiliary of such, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 645, 62 Stat. 732; May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 15(a), 63 Stat. 91; Pub. L. 103–322, title XXXIII, § 330016(1)(E), Sept. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 2146.)

Historical and Revision Notes
1948 ActBased on section 1393 of title 10, U.S.C., 1940 ed., Army and Air Force, and section 228 of title 42, U.S.C., 1940 ed., The Public Health and Welfare (June 3, 1916, ch. 134, § 125, 39 Stat. 216 (2d paragraph); July 1, 1944, ch. 373, § 510, 58 Stat. 711).
“Auxiliary of such” was inserted to extend protection to the uniforms of any auxiliary corps that may be established.
Fine of “$250” was substituted for “$300” as being more consonant with the penalties provided for similar offenses in this chapter.
Minor changes of phraseology also were made.

1949 ActThis section [section 15] inserts “armed forces” in the catch line and text of section 702 of title 18, U.S.C., and thereby includes the Air Force which was formerly part of the Army. (See note to sec. 5 [of 1949 Act, set out in Legislative History note under section 244 of title 18]). Also, it incorporates in such section the provisions of act of April 15, 1948 (ch. 188, 62 Stat. 172), which relates to this section as well as to section 1393 of title 10, U.S.C. (one of the sources of such sec. 701), as it existed at the time of the enactment of the revision of title 18 and which was not incorporated in title 18 when the revision was enacted. In this connection specific reference to the Canal Zone, Guam, American Samoa, and the Virgin Islands, as contained in such act of April 15</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>