<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_704"><akn:num>704</akn:num><akn:heading>Military medals or decorations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 704. Military medals or decorations(a) In General.—Whoever knowingly purchases, attempts to purchase, solicits for purchase, mails, ships, imports, exports, produces blank certificates of receipt for, manufactures, sells, attempts to sell, advertises for sale, trades, barters, or exchanges for anything of value any decoration or medal authorized by Congress for the armed forces of the United States, or any of the service medals or badges awarded to the members of such forces, or the ribbon, button, or rosette of any such badge, decoration or medal, or any colorable imitation thereof, except when authorized under regulations made pursuant to law, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.

(b) Fraudulent Representations About Receipt of Military Decorations or Medals.—Whoever, with intent to obtain money, property, or other tangible benefit, fraudulently holds oneself out to be a recipient of a decoration or medal described in subsection (c)(2) or (d) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than one year, or both.

(c) Enhanced Penalty for Offenses Involving Congressional Medal of Honor.—(1) In general.—If a decoration or medal involved in an offense under subsection (a) is a Congressional Medal of Honor, in lieu of the punishment provided in that subsection, the offender shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.

(2) Congressional medal of honor defined.—In this subsection, the term “Congressional Medal of Honor” means—(A) a medal of honor awarded under section 7271, 8291, or 9271 of title 10 or section 491 11 See References in Text note below. of title 14;

(B) a duplicate medal of honor issued under section 7284, 8306, or 9284 of title 10 or section 504 1 of title 14; or

(C) a replacement of a medal of honor provided under section 7277, 8303, or 9277 of title 10 or section 501 1 of title 14.



(d) Enhanced Penalty for Offenses Involving Certain Other Medals.—(1) In general.—If </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whoever knowingly purchases, attempts to purchase, solicits for purchase, mails, ships, imports, exports, produces blank certificates of receipt for, manufactures, sells, attempts to sell, advertises for sale, trades, barters, or exchanges for anything of value any decoration or medal authorized by Congress for the armed forces of the United States, or any of the service medals or badges awarded to the members of such forces, or the ribbon, button, or rosette of any such badge, decoration or medal, or any colorable imitation thereof, except when authorized under regulations made pursuant to law, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than six months, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fraudulent Representations About Receipt of Military Decorations or Medals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Whoever, with intent to obtain money, property, or other tangible benefit, fraudulently holds oneself out to be a recipient of a decoration or medal described in subsection (c)(2) or (d) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than one year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced Penalty for Offenses Involving Congressional Medal of Honor.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced Penalty for Offenses Involving Certain Other Medals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>