<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/841" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/841/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/841/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_841"><akn:num>841</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 841. Definitions
As used in this chapter—(a) “Person” means any individual, corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, society, or joint stock company.

(b) “Interstate” or foreign commerce means commerce between any place in a State and any place outside of that State, or within any possession of the United States (not including the Canal Zone) or the District of Columbia, and commerce between places within the same State but through any place outside of that State. “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the possessions of the United States (not including the Canal Zone).

(c) “Explosive materials” means explosives, blasting agents, and detonators.

(d) Except for the purposes of subsections (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), and (j) of section 844 of this title, “explosives” means any chemical compound mixture, or device, the primary or common purpose of which is to function by explosion; the term includes, but is not limited to, dynamite and other high explosives, black powder, pellet powder, initiating explosives, detonators, safety fuses, squibs, detonating cord, igniter cord, and igniters. The Attorney General shall publish and revise at least annually in the Federal Register a list of these and any additional explosives which he determines to be within the coverage of this chapter. For the purposes of subsections (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), and (i) of section 844 of this title, the term “explosive” is defined in subsection (j) of such section 844.

(e) “Blasting agent” means any material or mixture, consisting of fuel and oxidizer, intended for blasting, not otherwise defined as an explosive: Provided, That the finished product, as mixed for use or shipment, cannot be detonated by means of a numbered 8 test blasting cap when unconfined.

(f) “Detonator” means any device containing a detonating charge that is used for initiating detonation in an explosive; the term includes, but is not limited to, electric blasting</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Person” means any individual, corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, society, or joint stock company.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Interstate” or foreign commerce means commerce between any place in a State and any place outside of that State, or within any possession of the United States (not including the Canal Zone) or the District of Columbia, and commerce between places within the same State but through any place outside of that State. “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the possessions of the United States (not including the Canal Zone).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Explosive materials” means explosives, blasting agents, and detonators.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Except for the purposes of subsections (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), and (j) of section 844 of this title, “explosives” means any chemical compound mixture, or device, the primary or common purpose of which is to function by explosion; the term includes, but is not limited to, dynamite and other high explosives, black powder, pellet powder, initiating explosives, detonators, safety fuses, squibs, detonating cord, igniter cord, and igniters. The Attorney General shall publish and revise at least annually in the Federal Register a list of these and any additional explosives which he determines to be within the coverage of this chapter. For the purposes of subsections (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), and (i) of section 844 of this title, the term “explosive” is defined in subsection (j) of such section 844.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Blasting agent” means any material or mixture, consisting of fuel and oxidizer, intended for blasting, not otherwise defined as an explosive: Provided, That the finished product, as mixed for use or shipment, cannot be detonated by means of a numbered 8 test blasting cap when unconfined.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Detonator” means any device containing a detonating charge that is used for initiating detonation in an explosive; the term includes, but is not limited to, electric blasting caps of instantaneous and delay types, blasting caps for use with safety fuses and detonating-cord delay connectors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) “Importer” means any person engaged in the business of importing or bringing explosive materials into the United States for purposes of sale or distribution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Manufacturer” means any person engaged in the business of manufacturing explosive materials for purposes of sale or distribution or for his own use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) “Dealer” means any person engaged in the business of distributing explosive materials at wholesale or retail.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_841_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) “Permittee” means any user of explosives for a lawful purpose, who has obtained either a user permit or a limited permit under the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>