<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/983" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/983/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/18/983/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_983"><akn:num>983</akn:num><akn:heading>General rules for civil forfeiture proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 983. General rules for civil forfeiture proceedings(a) Notice; Claim; Complaint.—(1)(A)(i) Except as provided in clauses (ii) through (v), in any nonjudicial civil forfeiture proceeding under a civil forfeiture statute, with respect to which the Government is required to send written notice to interested parties, such notice shall be sent in a manner to achieve proper notice as soon as practicable, and in no case more than 60 days after the date of the seizure.

(ii) No notice is required if, before the 60-day period expires, the Government files a civil judicial forfeiture action against the property and provides notice of that action as required by law.

(iii) If, before the 60-day period expires, the Government does not file a civil judicial forfeiture action, but does obtain a criminal indictment containing an allegation that the property is subject to forfeiture, the Government shall either—(I) send notice within the 60 days and continue the nonjudicial civil forfeiture proceeding under this section; or

(II) terminate the nonjudicial civil forfeiture proceeding, and take the steps necessary to preserve its right to maintain custody of the property as provided in the applicable criminal forfeiture statute.


(iv) In a case in which the property is seized by a State or local law enforcement agency and turned over to a Federal law enforcement agency for the purpose of forfeiture under Federal law, notice shall be sent not more than 90 days after the date of seizure by the State or local law enforcement agency.

(v) If the identity or interest of a party is not determined until after the seizure or turnover but is determined before a declaration of forfeiture is entered, notice shall be sent to such interested party not later than 60 days after the determination by the Government of the identity of the party or the party’s interest.


(B) A supervisory official in the headquarters office of the seizing agency may extend the period for sending notice under subpar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice; Claim; Complaint.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Burden of Proof.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In a suit or action brought under any civil forfeiture statute for the civil forfeiture of any property—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Innocent Owner Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motion To Set Aside Forfeiture.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release Of Seized Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proportionality.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Fine.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Forfeiture Statute Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section, the term “civil forfeiture statute”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_983_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restraining Orders; Protective Orders.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>