<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1033" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1033/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1033/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1033"><akn:num>1033</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1033. Definitions
For purposes of this chapter—(a) The term “adulterated” applies to any egg or egg product under one or more of the following circumstances—(1) if it bears or contains any poisonous or deleterious substance which may render it injurious to health; but in case the substance is not an added substance, such article shall not be considered adulterated under this clause if the quantity of such substance in or on such article does not ordinarily render it injurious to health;

(2)(A) if it bears or contains any added poisonous or added deleterious substance (other than one which is (i) a pesticide chemical in or on a raw agricultural commodity; (ii) a food additive; or (iii) a color additive) which may, in the judgment of the Secretary, make such article unfit for human food;

(B) if it is, in whole or in part, a raw agricultural commodity and such commodity bears or contains a pesticide chemical which is unsafe within the meaning of section 346a of this title;

(C) if it bears or contains any food additive which is unsafe within the meaning of section 348 of this title;

(D) if it bears or contains any color additive which is unsafe within the meaning of section 379e of this title: Provided, That an article which is not otherwise deemed adulterated under clause (B), (C), or (D) shall nevertheless be deemed adulterated if use of the pesticide chemical, food additive, or color additive, in or on such article, is prohibited by regulations of the Secretary in official plants;


(3) if it consists in whole or in part of any filthy, putrid, or decomposed substance, or if it is otherwise unfit for human food;

(4) if it has been prepared, packaged, or held under insanitary conditions whereby it may have become contaminated with filth, or whereby it may have been rendered injurious to health;

(5) if it is an egg which has been subjected to incubation or the product of any egg which has been subjected to incubation;

(6) if its container is composed, in whole </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The term “adulterated” applies to any egg or egg product under one or more of the following circumstances—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The term “capable of use as human food” shall apply to any egg or egg product, unless it is denatured, or otherwise identified, as required by regulations prescribed by the Secretary to deter its use as human food.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term “commerce” means interstate, foreign, or intrastate commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term “container” or “package” includes any box, can, tin, plastic, or other receptacle, wrapper, or cover.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The term “egg handler” means any person who engages in any business in commerce which involves buying or selling any eggs (as a poultry producer or otherwise), or processing any egg products, or otherwise using any eggs in the preparation of human food.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The term “egg product” means any dried, frozen, or liquid eggs, with or without added ingredients, excepting products which contain eggs only in a relatively small proportion or historically have not been, in the judgment of the Secretary, considered by consumers as products of the egg food industry, and which may be exempted by the Secretary under such conditions as he may prescribe to assure that the egg ingredients are not adulterated and such products are not represented as egg products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The term “egg” means the shell egg of the domesticated chicken, turkey, duck, goose, or guinea.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The term “Fair Packaging and Labeling Act” [15 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.] means the Act so entitled, approved November 3, 1966 (80 Stat. 1296), and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The term “Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act” [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.] means the Act so entitled, approved June 25, 1938 (52 Stat. 1040), and Acts amendatory thereof or supplementary thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1033_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The term “inspection” means the application of such inspection methods and techniques as are deemed necessary by the responsible Secretary to carry out the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>