<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1179" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1179/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1179/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1179"><akn:num>1179</akn:num><akn:heading>National Drug Abuse Training Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1179. National Drug Abuse Training Center(a) Establishment; functions; general policies; transfer of supervisionThe Director shall establish a National Drug Abuse Training Center (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Center”) to develop, conduct, and support a full range of training programs relating to drug abuse prevention functions. The Director shall consult with the National Advisory Council for Drug Abuse Prevention regarding the general policies of the Center. The Director may supervise the operation of the Center initially, but shall transfer the supervision of the operation of the Center to the National Institute on Drug Abuse not later than December 31, 1974.


(b) Activities and materialThe Center shall conduct or arrange for training programs, seminars, meetings, conferences, and other related activities, including the furnishing of training and educational materials for use by others.


(c) Persons eligible for services and facilitiesThe services and facilities of the Center shall, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Director, be available to (1) Federal, State, and local governmental officials, and their respective staffs, (2) medical and paramedical personnel, and educators, and (3) other persons, including drug dependent persons, requiring training or education in drug abuse prevention.


(d) Authorization of appropriations; fiscal year availability(1) For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1972, $3,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1973, $5,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1974, and $6,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1975.

(2) Sums appropriated under this subsection shall remain available for obligation or expenditure in the fiscal year for which appropriated and in the fiscal year next following.


(Pub. L. 92–255, title IV, § 412, Mar. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 84.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextT</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1179_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; functions; general policies; transfer of supervision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; functions; general policies; transfer of supervision The Director shall establish a National Drug Abuse Training Center (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Center”) to develop, conduct, and support a full range of training programs relating to drug abuse prevention functions. The Director shall consult with the National Advisory Council for Drug Abuse Prevention regarding the general policies of the Center. The Director may supervise the operation of the Center initially, but shall transfer the supervision of the operation of the Center to the National Institute on Drug Abuse not later than December 31, 1974.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1179_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities and material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities and material The Center shall conduct or arrange for training programs, seminars, meetings, conferences, and other related activities, including the furnishing of training and educational materials for use by others.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1179_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons eligible for services and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Persons eligible for services and facilities The services and facilities of the Center shall, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Director, be available to (1) Federal, State, and local governmental officials, and their respective staffs, (2) medical and paramedical personnel, and educators, and (3) other persons, including drug dependent persons, requiring training or education in drug abuse prevention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1179_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations; fiscal year availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations; fiscal year availability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>