<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/151" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/151/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/151/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_151"><akn:num>151</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation and sale of worthless or harmful products for domestic animals prohibited; preparation t</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 151. Preparation and sale of worthless or harmful products for domestic animals prohibited; preparation to be in compliance with rules at licensed establishments
It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, or corporation to prepare, sell, barter, or exchange in the District of Columbia, or in the Territories, or in any place under the jurisdiction of the United States, or to ship or deliver for shipment in or from the United States, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, or any place under the jurisdiction of the United States, any worthless, contaminated, dangerous, or harmful virus, serum, toxin, or analogous product intended for use in the treatment of domestic animals, and no person, firm, or corporation shall prepare, sell, barter, exchange, or ship as aforesaid any virus, serum, toxin, or analogous product manufactured within the United States and intended for use in the treatment of domestic animals, unless and until the said virus, serum, toxin, or analogous product shall have been prepared, under and in compliance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Agriculture, at an establishment holding an unsuspended and unrevoked license issued by the Secretary of Agriculture as hereinafter authorized.
(Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 145, § 1 (part), 37 Stat. 832; Pub. L. 99–198, title XVII, § 1768(a), Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1654.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The sections of this chapter are comprised of the sentences of the eighth paragraph under the heading “Bureau of Animal Industry,” in the Department of Agriculture Appropriation Act, 1914, as amended.
Another section 1768 of Pub. L. 99–198, cited as a credit to this section, amended section 136y of Title 7, Agriculture.

Amendments1985—Pub. L. 99–198 substituted “in or from the United States, the District of Columbia, any territory of the United States, or any place under the jurisdiction of the United States” for “from one State or Territory or the District of Columbia to any other State</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>