<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1536" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1536/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1536/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1536"><akn:num>1536</akn:num><akn:heading>Community-based coalition enhancement grants to address local drug crises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1536. Community-based coalition enhancement grants to address local drug crises(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.


(2) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy.


(3) Drug-Free Communities Act of 1997The term “Drug-Free Communities Act of 1997” means chapter 2 of the National Narcotics Leadership Act of 1988 (21 U.S.C. 1521 et seq.).


(4) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means an organization that—(A) on or before the date of submitting an application for a grant under this section, receives or has received a grant under the Drug-Free Communities Act of 1997; and

(B) has documented, using local data, rates of abuse of opioids or methamphetamines at levels that are—(i) significantly higher than the national average as determined by the Secretary (including appropriate consideration of the results of the Monitoring the Future Survey published by the National Institute on Drug Abuse and the National Survey on Drug Use and Health published by the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration); or

(ii) higher than the national average, as determined by the Secretary (including appropriate consideration of the results of the surveys described in clause (i)), over a sustained period of time.



(5) Emerging drug abuse issueThe term “emerging drug abuse issue” means a substance use disorder within an area involving—(A) a sudden increase in demand for particular drug abuse treatment services relative to previous demand; and

(B) a lack of resources in the area to address the emerging problem.


(6) Local drug crisisThe term “local drug crisis” means, with respect to the area served by an eligible entity—(A) a sudden increase in the abuse of opioids or methamphetamines, as documented by local data;

(B) the abuse of prescription medications, specifically opioids or methamp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1536_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1536_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program authorized The Director, in coordination with the Administrator, may make grants to eligible entities to implement comprehensive community-wide strategies that address local drug crises and emerging drug abuse issues within the area served by the eligible entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1536_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1536_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds An eligible entity shall use a grant received under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1536_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Supplement not supplant An eligible entity shall use Federal funds received under this section only to supplement the funds that would, in the absence of those Federal funds, be made available from other Federal and non-Federal sources for the activities described in this section, and not to supplant those funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1536_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Evaluation A grant under this section shall be subject to the same evaluation requirements and procedures as the evaluation requirements and procedures imposed on the recipient of a grant under the Drug-Free Communities Act of 1997, and may also include an evaluation of the effectiveness at reducing abuse of opioids or methamphetamines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1536_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on administrative expenses Not more than 8 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year may be used to pay for administrative expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1536_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Delegation authority The Director may enter into an interagency agreement with the Administrator to delegate authority for the execution of grants and for such other activities as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1536_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2021.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>