<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1605"><akn:num>1605</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for dismissal of civil actions against biomaterials suppliers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1605. Procedures for dismissal of civil actions against biomaterials suppliers(a) Motion to dismissA defendant may, at any time during which a motion to dismiss may be filed under applicable law, move to dismiss an action against it on the grounds that the defendant is a biomaterials supplier and one or more of the following:(1) The defendant is not liable as a manufacturer, as provided in section 1604(b) of this title.

(2) The defendant is not liable as a seller, as provided in section 1604(c) of this title.

(3) The defendant is not liable for furnishing raw materials or component parts for the implant that failed to meet applicable contractual requirements or specifications, as provided in section 1604(d) of this title.

(4) The claimant did not name the manufacturer as a party to the action, as provided in subsection (b).


(b) Manufacturer of implant shall be named a partyIn any civil action covered by this chapter, the claimant shall be required to name the manufacturer of the implant as a party to the action, unless—(1) the manufacturer is subject to service of process solely in a jurisdiction in which the biomaterials supplier is not domiciled or subject to a service of process; or

(2) a claim against the manufacturer is barred by applicable law or rule of practice.


(c) Proceeding on motion to dismissThe following rules shall apply to any proceeding on a motion to dismiss filed by a defendant under this section:(1) Effect of motion to dismiss on discovery(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), if a defendant files a motion to dismiss under subsection (a), no discovery shall be permitted in connection with the action that is the subject of the motion, other than discovery necessary to determine a motion to dismiss for lack of jurisdiction, until such time as the court rules on the motion to dismiss.


(B) DiscoveryIf a defendant files a motion to dismiss under subsection (a)(3) on the grounds that it did not furnish raw materials or compon</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motion to dismiss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Motion to dismiss A defendant may, at any time during which a motion to dismiss may be filed under applicable law, move to dismiss an action against it on the grounds that the defendant is a biomaterials supplier and one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturer of implant shall be named a party</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Manufacturer of implant shall be named a party In any civil action covered by this chapter, the claimant shall be required to name the manufacturer of the implant as a party to the action, unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeding on motion to dismiss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Proceeding on motion to dismiss The following rules shall apply to any proceeding on a motion to dismiss filed by a defendant under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Summary judgment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Summary judgment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dismissal with prejudice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Dismissal with prejudice An order granting a motion to dismiss or for summary judgment pursuant to this section shall be entered with prejudice, except insofar as the moving defendant may be rejoined to the action as provided in section 1606 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturer conduct of litigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Manufacturer conduct of litigation The manufacturer of an implant that is the subject of an action covered under this chapter shall be permitted to conduct litigation on any motion for summary judgment or dismissal filed by a biomaterials supplier who is a defendant under this section on behalf of such supplier if the manufacturer and any other defendant in such action enter into a valid and applicable contractual agreement under which the manufacturer agrees to bear the cost of such litigation or to conduct such litigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>