<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1701"><akn:num>1701</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1701. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) AgencyThe term “agency” has the meaning given the term “executive agency” in section 102 of title 31.


(2) Appropriate congressional committees(A) In generalThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means—(i) the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and

(ii) the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.


(B) Submission to CongressAny submission to Congress shall mean submission to the appropriate congressional committees.



(3) Demand reductionThe term “demand reduction” means any activity conducted by a National Drug Control Program agency, other than an enforcement activity, that is intended to reduce or prevent the use of drugs or support, expand, or provide treatment and recovery efforts, including—(A) education about the dangers of illicit drug use;

(B) services, programs, or strategies to prevent substance use disorder, including evidence-based education campaigns, community-based prevention programs, collection and disposal of unused prescription drugs, and services to at-risk populations to prevent or delay initial use of an illicit drug;

(C) substance use disorder treatment;

(D) support for long-term recovery from substance use disorders;

(E) drug-free workplace programs;

(F) drug testing, including the testing of employees;

(G) interventions for illicit drug use and dependence;

(H) expanding availability of access to health care services for the treatment of substance use disorders;

(I) international drug control coordination and cooperation with respect to activities described in this paragraph;

(J) pre- and post-arrest criminal justice interventions such as diversion programs, drug courts, and the provision of evidence-based treatment to individuals with subs</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agency The term “agency” has the meaning given the term “executive agency” in section 102 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appropriate congressional committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demand reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Demand reduction The term “demand reduction” means any activity conducted by a National Drug Control Program agency, other than an enforcement activity, that is intended to reduce or prevent the use of drugs or support, expand, or provide treatment and recovery efforts, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Director The term “Director” means the Director of National Drug Control Policy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Drug The term “drug” has the meaning given the term “controlled substance” in section 802(6) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Drug control The term “drug control” means any activity conducted by a National Drug Control Program agency involving supply reduction or demand reduction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emerging drug threat</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Emerging drug threat The term “emerging drug threat” means the occurrence of a new and growing trend in the use of an illicit drug or class of drugs, including rapid expansion in the supply of or demand for such drug.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Illicit drug use; illicit drugs; illegal drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Illicit drug use; illicit drugs; illegal drugs The terms “illicit drug use”, “illicit drugs”, and “illegal drugs” include the illegal or illicit use of prescription drugs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Law enforcement The term “law enforcement” or “drug law enforcement” means all efforts by a Federal, State, local, or Tribal government agency to enforce the drug laws of the United States or any State, including investigation, arrest, prosecution, and incarceration or other punishments or penalties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1701_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Drug Control Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) National Drug Control Program The term “National Drug Control Program” means programs, policies, and activities undertaken by National Drug Control Program agencies pursuant to the responsibilities of such agencies under the National Drug Control Strategy, including any activities involving supply reduction, demand reduction, or State, local, and tribal 11 So in original. Probably should be “Tribal”. affairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>