<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1703" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1703/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1703/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1703"><akn:num>1703</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and duties of Director and Deputy Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1703. Appointment and duties of Director and Deputy Directors(a) Appointment(1) In general(A) Director(i) In generalThere shall be at the head of the Office a Director who shall hold the same rank and status as the head of an executive department listed in section 101 of title 5.


(ii) AppointmentThe Director shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall serve at the pleasure of the President.



(B) Deputy DirectorThere shall be a Deputy Director who shall report directly to the Director, and who shall be appointed by the President, and shall serve at the pleasure of the President.


(C) CoordinatorsThe following coordinators shall be appointed by the Director:(i) Performance Budget Coordinator, as described in subsection (c)(5).

(ii) Interdiction Coordinator, as described in section 1710 of this title.

(iii) Emerging and Continuing Threats Coordinator, as described in section 1708 of this title.

(iv) State, Local, and Tribal Affairs Coordinator, to carry out the activities described in subsection (j).

(v) Demand Reduction Coordinator, as described in subparagraph (D).


(D) Demand Reduction CoordinatorThe Director shall designate or appoint a United States Demand Reduction Coordinator to be responsible for the activities described in section 1701(3) of this title. For purposes of carrying out the previous sentence, the Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent).



(2) Duties of Deputy Director of National Drug Control PolicyThe Deputy Director of National Drug Control Policy shall—(A) carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Director; and

(B) serve as the Director in the absence of the Director or during any period in which the office of the Director is vacant.


(3) Acting DirectorIf the Director dies, resigns, or is otherwise unable to perform the functions and duties of the o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Responsibilities The Director—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Drug Control Program budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National Drug Control Program budget</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of the Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Powers of the Director In carrying out subsection (b), the Director may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel detailed to Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Personnel detailed to Office</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund control notices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fund control notices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability to certain programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Inapplicability to certain programs The provisions of this section shall not apply to the National Intelligence Program, the Joint Military Intelligence Program, and Tactical and Related Activities, unless such program or an element of such program is designated as a National Drug Control Program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Construction Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as derogating the authorities and responsibilities of the Director of National Intelligence or the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency contained in the National Security Act of 1947 [50 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.], the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 [50 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.], or any other law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Model acts program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Model acts program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>State, Local, and Tribal Affairs Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) State, Local, and Tribal Affairs Coordinator The Director shall designate or appoint a United States State, Local, and Tribal Affairs Coordinator to perform the duties of the Office outlined in this section and section 1705 of this title and such other duties as may be determined by the Director with respect to coordination of drug control efforts between agencies and State, local, and Tribal governments. For purposes of carrying out the previous sentence, the Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>