<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1705" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1705/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1705/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1705"><akn:num>1705</akn:num><akn:heading>Development, submission, implementation, and assessment of National Drug Control Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1705. Development, submission, implementation, and assessment of National Drug Control Strategy(a) In general(1) Statement of drug policy prioritiesThe Director shall release a statement of drug control policy priorities in the calendar year of a Presidential inauguration following the inauguration, but not later than April 1.


(2) National Drug Control Strategy submitted by the PresidentNot later than the first Monday in February following the year in which the term of the President commences, and every 2 years thereafter, the President shall submit to Congress a National Drug Control Strategy.



(b) Development of the National Drug Control Strategy(1) PromulgationThe Director shall promulgate the National Drug Control Strategy, which shall set forth a comprehensive plan to reduce illicit drug use and the consequences of such illicit drug use in the United States by limiting the availability of and reducing the demand for illegal drugs and promoting prevention, early intervention, treatment, and recovery support for individuals with substance use disorders.


(2) State and local commitmentThe Director shall seek the support and commitment of State, local, and Tribal officials in the formulation and implementation of the National Drug Control Strategy.


(3) Strategy based on evidenceThe Director shall ensure the National Drug Control Strategy is based on the best available evidence regarding the policies that are most effective in reducing the demand for and supply of illegal drugs.


(4) Process for development and submission of National Drug Control StrategyIn developing and effectively implementing the National Drug Control Strategy, the Director—(A) shall consult with—(i) the heads of the National Drug Control Program agencies;

(ii) each Coordinator listed in section 1703 of this title;

(iii) the Interdiction Committee and the Emerging Threats Committee;

(iv) the appropriate congressional committees and any other committee of jurisdiction;

(v) State, lo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1705_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1705_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of the National Drug Control Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development of the National Drug Control Strategy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1705_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of the National Drug Control Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents of the National Drug Control Strategy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1705_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of revised Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Submission of revised Strategy The President may submit to Congress a revised National Drug Control Strategy that meets the requirements of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1705_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure of Director to Submit National Drug Control Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Failure of Director to Submit National Drug Control Strategy If the Director does not submit a National Drug Control Strategy to Congress in accordance with subsection (a)(2), not later than five days after the first Monday in February following the year in which the term of the President commences, the Director shall send a notification to the appropriate congressional committees—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1705_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug Control Data Dashboard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Drug Control Data Dashboard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1705_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of an annual national drug control assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Development of an annual national drug control assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1705_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance measurement system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Performance measurement system Not later than February 1 of each year, the Director shall submit to Congress as part of the National Drug Control Strategy, a description of a national drug control performance measurement system, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1705_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Modifications A description of any modifications made during the preceding year to the national drug performance measurement system described in subsection (c) 44 Probably should be “(h)”. shall be included in each report submitted under subsection (b).55 Probably should be “(d)”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>