<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1706" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1706/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1706/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1706"><akn:num>1706</akn:num><akn:heading>High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1706. High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program(a) Establishment(1) In generalThere is established in the Office a program to be known as the High Intensity Drug Trafficking Areas Program (in this section referred to as the “Program”).


(2) PurposeThe purpose of the Program is to reduce drug trafficking and drug production in the United States by—(A) facilitating cooperation among Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies to share information and implement coordinated enforcement activities;

(B) enhancing law enforcement intelligence sharing among Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies;

(C) providing reliable law enforcement intelligence to law enforcement agencies needed to design effective enforcement strategies and operations; and

(D) supporting coordinated law enforcement strategies which maximize use of available resources to reduce the supply of illegal drugs in designated areas and in the United States as a whole.



(b) Designation(1) In generalThe Director, in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Homeland Security, heads of the National Drug Control Program agencies, and the Governor of each applicable State, may designate any specified area of the United States as a high intensity drug trafficking area.


(2) ActivitiesAfter making a designation under paragraph (1) and in order to provide Federal assistance to the area so designated, the Director may—(A) obligate such sums as are appropriated for the Program;

(B) direct the temporary reassignment of Federal personnel to such area, subject to the approval of the head of the department or agency that employs such personnel;

(C) take any other action authorized under section 1703 of this title to provide increased Federal assistance to those areas; and

(D) coordinate activities under this section (specifically administrative, recordkeeping, and funds management activities) with State, local, and tribal officia</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitions for designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Petitions for designation The Director shall establish regulations under which a coalition of interested law enforcement agencies from an area may petition for designation as a high intensity drug trafficking area. Such regulations shall provide for a regular review by the Director of the petition, including a recommendation regarding the merit of the petition to the Director by a panel of qualified, independent experts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors for consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Factors for consideration In considering whether to designate an area under this section as a high intensity drug trafficking area, the Director shall consider, in addition to such other criteria as the Director considers to be appropriate, the extent to which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization of high intensity drug trafficking areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Organization of high intensity drug trafficking areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of funds The Director shall ensure that not more than a total of 5 percent of Federal funds appropriated for the Program are expended for substance use disorder treatment programs and drug prevention programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Counterterrorism activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Counterterrorism activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Role of Drug Enforcement Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Role of Drug Enforcement Administration The Director, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall ensure that a representative of the Drug Enforcement Administration is included in the Intelligence Support Center for each high intensity drug trafficking area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual HIDTA Program budget submissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Annual HIDTA Program budget submissions As part of the documentation that supports the President’s annual budget request for the Office, the Director shall submit to Congress a budget justification that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1706_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emerging threat response fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Emerging threat response fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>