<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1708" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1708/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1708/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1708"><akn:num>1708</akn:num><akn:heading>Emerging Threats Committee, plan, and media campaign</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1708. Emerging Threats Committee, plan, and media campaign(a) Emerging and Continuing Threats CoordinatorThe Director shall designate or appoint a United States Emerging and Continuing Threats Coordinator to perform the duties of that position described in this section and such other duties as may be determined by the Director. For purposes of carrying out the previous sentence, the Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent).


(b) Emerging Threats Committee(1) In generalThe Emerging Threats Committee shall—(A) monitor evolving and emerging drug threats in the United States;

(B) identify and discuss evolving and emerging drug trends in the United States using the criteria required to be established under paragraph (6);

(C) assist in the formulation of and oversee implementation of any plan described in subsection (d);

(D) provide such other advice to the Coordinator and Director concerning strategy and policies for emerging drug threats and trends as the Committee determines to be appropriate; and

(E) disseminate and facilitate the sharing with Federal, State, local, and Tribal officials and other entities as determined by the Director of pertinent information and data relating to—(i) recent trends in drug supply and demand;

(ii) fatal and nonfatal overdoses;

(iii) demand for and availability of evidence-based substance use disorder treatment, including the extent of the unmet treatment need, and treatment admission trends;

(iv) recent trends in drug interdiction, supply, and demand from State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies; and

(v) other subject matter as determined necessary by the Director.



(2) ChairpersonThe Director shall designate one of the members of the Emerging Threats Committee to serve as Chairperson.


(3) MembersThe Director shall appoint other members of the Committee, which shall include—(A) representatives</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emerging and Continuing Threats Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Emerging and Continuing Threats Coordinator The Director shall designate or appoint a United States Emerging and Continuing Threats Coordinator to perform the duties of that position described in this section and such other duties as may be determined by the Director. For purposes of carrying out the previous sentence, the Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emerging Threats Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Emerging Threats Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of media campaign</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation of media campaign Upon designation of an emerging drug threat, the Director shall evaluate whether a media campaign would be appropriate to address that threat.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>National anti-drug media campaign</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) National anti-drug media campaign</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1708_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Office to carry out this section, $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2018 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>