<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1710" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1710/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1710/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1710"><akn:num>1710</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug Interdiction Coordinator and Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1710. Drug Interdiction Coordinator and Committee(a) United States Interdiction Coordinator(1) In generalThe Director shall designate or appoint an appointee in the Senior Executive Service or an appointee in a position at level 15 of the General Schedule (or equivalent) as the United States Interdiction Coordinator to perform the duties of that position described in paragraph (2) and such other duties as may be determined by the Director with respect to coordination of efforts to interdict illicit drugs from entering the United States.


(2) ResponsibilitiesThe United States Interdiction Coordinator shall be responsible to the Director for—(A) coordinating the interdiction activities of the National Drug Control Program agencies to ensure consistency with the National Drug Control Strategy;

(B) on behalf of the Director, developing and issuing, on or before September 1 of each year and in accordance with paragraph (4), a National Interdiction Command and Control Plan to ensure the coordination and consistency described in subparagraph (A);

(C) assessing the sufficiency of assets committed to illicit drug interdiction by the relevant National Drug Control Program agencies; and

(D) advising the Director on the efforts of each National Drug Control Program agency to implement the National Interdiction Command and Control Plan.


(3) StaffThe Director shall assign such permanent staff of the Office as he considers appropriate to assist the United States Interdiction Coordinator to carry out the responsibilities described in paragraph (2), and may request that appropriate National Drug Control Program agencies detail or assign staff to assist in carrying out such responsibilities.


(4) National Interdiction Command and Control Plan(A) PurposesThe National Interdiction Command and Control Plan shall—(i) set forth the Government’s strategy for drug interdiction;

(ii) state the specific roles and responsibilities of the relevant National Drug Control Program agencie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1710_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States Interdiction Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) United States Interdiction Coordinator</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1710_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interdiction Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interdiction Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1710_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>International coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) International coordination The Director may facilitate international drug control coordination efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>