<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/1903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1903"><akn:num>1903</akn:num><akn:heading>Public identification of significant foreign narcotics traffickers and required reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1903. Public identification of significant foreign narcotics traffickers and required reports(a) Provision of information to the PresidentThe Secretary of the Treasury, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, and the Director of Central Intelligence shall consult among themselves and provide the appropriate and necessary information to enable the President to submit the report under subsection (b). This information shall also be provided to the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy.


(b) Public identification and sanctioning of significant foreign narcotics traffickersNot later than June 1, 2000, and not later than June 1 of each year thereafter, the President shall submit a report to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committees on the Judiciary, International Relations, Armed Services, and Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and to the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committees on the Judiciary, Foreign Relations, Armed Services, and Finance of the Senate—(1) identifying publicly the foreign persons that the President determines are appropriate for sanctions pursuant to this chapter; and

(2) detailing publicly the President’s intent to impose sanctions upon these significant foreign narcotics traffickers pursuant to this chapter.


The report required in this subsection shall not include information on persons upon which United States sanctions imposed under this chapter, or otherwise on account of narcotics trafficking, are already in effect.

(c) Unclassified report requiredThe report required by subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form and made available to the public.


(d) Classified report(1) Not later than July 1, 2000, and not later than July 1 of each year thereafter, the President shall provide the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate with a report in cla</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of information to the President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Provision of information to the President The Secretary of the Treasury, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of State, and the Director of Central Intelligence shall consult among themselves and provide the appropriate and necessary information to enable the President to submit the report under subsection (b). This information shall also be provided to the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public identification and sanctioning of significant foreign narcotics traffickers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public identification and sanctioning of significant foreign narcotics traffickers Not later than June 1, 2000, and not later than June 1 of each year thereafter, the President shall submit a report to the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committees on the Judiciary, International Relations, Armed Services, and Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and to the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committees on the Judiciary, Foreign Relations, Armed Services, and Finance of the Senate— The report required in this subsection shall not include information on persons upon which United States sanctions imposed under this chapter, or otherwise on account of narcotics trafficking, are already in effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unclassified report required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Unclassified report required The report required by subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form and made available to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classified report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Classified report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of certain information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusion of certain information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notification required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations not to apply sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Determinations not to apply sanctions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes in determinations to impose sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Changes in determinations to impose sanctions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1903_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of classified information in Federal court challenges relating to designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Protection of classified information in Federal court challenges relating to designations In any judicial review of a determination made under this section, if the determination was based on classified information (as defined in section 1(a) of the Classified Information Procedures Act) such information may be submitted to the reviewing court ex parte and in camera. This subsection does not confer or imply any right to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>