<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/2302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/2302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/2302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2302"><akn:num>2302</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2302. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Alien; national; national of the United StatesThe terms “alien”, “national”, and “national of the United States” have the meanings given those terms in section 1101 of title 8.


(2) Appropriate congressional committees and leadershipThe term “appropriate congressional committees and leadership” means—(A) the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the majority leader and the minority leader of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Oversight and Reform, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Speaker and the minority leader of the House of Representatives.


(3) Controlled substance; listed chemicalThe terms “controlled substance”, “listed chemical”, “narcotic drug”, and “opioid” have the meanings given those terms in section 802 of this title.


(4) EntityThe term “entity” means a partnership, joint venture, association, corporation, organization, network, group, or subgroup, or any form of business collaboration.


(5) Foreign opioid traffickerThe term “foreign opioid trafficker” means any foreign person that the President determines plays a significant role in opioid trafficking.


(6) Foreign personThe term “foreign person”—(A) means—(i) any citizen or national of a foreign country; or

(ii) any entity not organized under the laws of the United States or a jurisdiction within the United States; and


(B) does not include the government of a foreign country.


(7) KnowinglyThe term “knowingly”, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a pers</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alien; national; national of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Alien; national; national of the United States The terms “alien”, “national”, and “national of the United States” have the meanings given those terms in section 1101 of title 8.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees and leadership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appropriate congressional committees and leadership The term “appropriate congressional committees and leadership” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Controlled substance; listed chemical</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Controlled substance; listed chemical The terms “controlled substance”, “listed chemical”, “narcotic drug”, and “opioid” have the meanings given those terms in section 802 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Entity The term “entity” means a partnership, joint venture, association, corporation, organization, network, group, or subgroup, or any form of business collaboration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign opioid trafficker</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Foreign opioid trafficker The term “foreign opioid trafficker” means any foreign person that the President determines plays a significant role in opioid trafficking.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Foreign person The term “foreign person”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Knowingly</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Knowingly The term “knowingly”, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opioid trafficking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Opioid trafficking The term “opioid trafficking” means any illicit activity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Person The term “person” means an individual or entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) United States person The term “United States person” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>