<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/2361" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/2361/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/2361/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2361"><akn:num>2361</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of transnational criminal organizations in suspicious transactions reports of the Financia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2361. Treatment of transnational criminal organizations in suspicious transactions reports of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network(a) Filing instructionsNot later than 180 days after April 24, 2024, the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall issue guidance or instructions to United States financial institutions for filing reports on suspicious transactions required under section 1010.320 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, related to suspected fentanyl trafficking by transnational criminal organizations.


(b) Prioritization of reports relating to fentanyl trafficking or transnational criminal organizationsThe Director shall prioritize research into reports described in subsection (a) that indicate a connection to trafficking of fentanyl or related synthetic opioids or financing of suspected transnational criminal organizations.


(Pub. L. 118–50, div. E, title II, § 3202, Apr. 24, 2024, 138 Stat. 941.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2361_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing instructions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Filing instructions Not later than 180 days after April 24, 2024, the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall issue guidance or instructions to United States financial institutions for filing reports on suspicious transactions required under section 1010.320 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, related to suspected fentanyl trafficking by transnational criminal organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2361_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prioritization of reports relating to fentanyl trafficking or transnational criminal organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prioritization of reports relating to fentanyl trafficking or transnational criminal organizations The Director shall prioritize research into reports described in subsection (a) that indicate a connection to trafficking of fentanyl or related synthetic opioids or financing of suspected transnational criminal organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>