<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/2401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/2401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/2401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2401"><akn:num>2401</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2401. Definitions(1) Anti-doping organizationThe term “anti-doping organization” has the meaning given the term in Article 2 of the Convention.


(2) AthleteThe term “athlete” has the meaning given the term in Article 2 of the Convention.


(3) CodeThe term “Code” means the World Anti-Doping Code most recently adopted by WADA on March 5, 2003.


(4) ConventionThe term “Convention” means the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization International Convention Against Doping in Sport done at Paris October 19, 2005, and ratified by the United States in 2008.


(5) Major international sport competitionThe term “Major International Sport Competition”— 11 So in original. Term is not capitalized as used in this chapter.(A) means a competition—(i) in which one or more United States athletes and three or more athletes from other countries participate;

(ii) that is governed by the anti-doping rules and principles of the Code; and

(iii) in which—(I) the competition organizer or sanctioning body receives sponsorship or other financial support from an organization doing business in the United States; or

(II) the competition organizer or sanctioning body receives compensation for the right to broadcast the competition in the United States; and



(B) includes a competition that is a single event or a competition that consists of a series of events held at different times which, when combined, qualify an athlete or team for an award or other recognition.


(6) PersonThe term “person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or other entity.


(7) Prohibited methodThe term “prohibited method” has the meaning given the term in Article 2 of the Convention.


(8) Prohibited substanceThe term “prohibited substance” has the meaning given the term in Article 2 of the Convention.


(9) Scheme in commerceThe term “scheme in commerce” means any scheme effectuated in whole or in part through the use in interstate or foreign commerce of any facil</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Anti-doping organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Anti-doping organization The term “anti-doping organization” has the meaning given the term in Article 2 of the Convention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Athlete</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Athlete The term “athlete” has the meaning given the term in Article 2 of the Convention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Code</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Code The term “Code” means the World Anti-Doping Code most recently adopted by WADA on March 5, 2003.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Convention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Convention The term “Convention” means the United Nations Educational, Scientific, and Cultural Organization International Convention Against Doping in Sport done at Paris October 19, 2005, and ratified by the United States in 2008.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Major international sport competition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Major international sport competition The term “Major International Sport Competition”— 11 So in original. Term is not capitalized as used in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Person The term “person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, association, or other entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited method</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Prohibited method The term “prohibited method” has the meaning given the term in Article 2 of the Convention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited substance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Prohibited substance The term “prohibited substance” has the meaning given the term in Article 2 of the Convention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scheme in commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Scheme in commerce The term “scheme in commerce” means any scheme effectuated in whole or in part through the use in interstate or foreign commerce of any facility for transportation or communication.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>USADA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) USADA The term “USADA” means the United States Anti-Doping Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>