<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_321"><akn:num>321</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions; generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 321. Definitions; generally
For the purposes of this chapter—(a)(1) The term “State”, except as used in the last sentence of section 372(a) of this title, means any State or Territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.

(2) The term “Territory” means any Territory or possession of the United States, including the District of Columbia, and excluding the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Canal Zone.


(b) The term “interstate commerce” means (1) commerce between any State or Territory and any place outside thereof, and (2) commerce within the District of Columbia or within any other Territory not organized with a legislative body.

(c) The term “Department” means Department of Health and Human Services.

(d) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.

(e) The term “person” includes individual, partnership, corporation, and association.

(f) The term “food” means (1) articles used for food or drink for man or other animals, (2) chewing gum, and (3) articles used for components of any such article.

(g)(1) The term “drug” means (A) articles recognized in the official United States Pharmacopoeia,11 So in original. Probably should be “Pharmacopeia,”. official Homoeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States, or official National Formulary, or any supplement to any of them; and (B) articles intended for use in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease in man or other animals; and (C) articles (other than food) intended to affect the structure or any function of the body of man or other animals; and (D) articles intended for use as a component of any article specified in clause (A), (B), or (C). A food or dietary supplement for which a claim, subject to sections 343(r)(1)(B) and 343(r)(3) of this title or sections 343(r)(1)(B) and 343(r)(5)(D) of this title, is made in accordance with the requirements of section 343(r) of this title is not a drug solely because the la</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The term “interstate commerce” means (1) commerce between any State or Territory and any place outside thereof, and (2) commerce within the District of Columbia or within any other Territory not organized with a legislative body.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term “Department” means Department of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The term “person” includes individual, partnership, corporation, and association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The term “food” means (1) articles used for food or drink for man or other animals, (2) chewing gum, and (3) articles used for components of any such article.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The term “cosmetic” means (1) articles intended to be rubbed, poured, sprinkled, or sprayed on, introduced into, or otherwise applied to the human body or any part thereof for cleansing, beautifying, promoting attractiveness, or altering the appearance, and (2) articles intended for use as a component of any such articles; except that such term shall not include soap.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The term “official compendium” means the official United States Pharmacopoeia, official Homoeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States, official National Formulary, or any supplement to any of them.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>