<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/321b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/321b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/321b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_321b"><akn:num>321b</akn:num><akn:heading>“Package” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 321b. “Package” defined
The word “package” where it occurs the second and last time in the act entitled “An act to amend section 8 of an act entitled, ‘An act for preventing the manufacture, sale, or transportation of adulterated or misbranded or poisonous deleterious foods, drugs, medicines, and liquors, and for regulating traffic therein, and for other purposes,’ ” approved March 3, 1913, shall include and shall be construed to include wrapped meats inclosed in papers or other materials as prepared by the manufacturers thereof for sale.
(July 24, 1919, ch. 26, 41 Stat. 271.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextAn act approved March 3, 1913, referred to in text, is act Mar. 3, 1913, ch. 117, 37 Stat. 732, which amended section 10 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
“An act for preventing the manufacture, sale, or transportation of adulterated or misbranded or poisonous deleterious foods, drugs, medicines, and liquors, and for regulating traffic therein, and for other purposes”, referred to in text, is act June 30, 1906, ch. 3915, 34 Stat. 768, which was classified to subchapter I (§ 1 et seq.) of chapter 1 of this title, was repealed (except for section 14a which was transferred to section 376 of this title) by act June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 1002(a), formerly § 902(a), 52 Stat. 1059; renumbered § 1002(a), Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title I, § 101(b)(2), June 22, 2009, 123 Stat. 1784, and is covered by this chapter.

Codification
Section, which was not enacted as part of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act which comprises this chapter, was formerly classified to the last sentence of paragraph third of section 10 of this title. Section 1002(a) of act June 25, 1938, set out as an Effective Date note under section 301 of this title, provided that this section should remain in force and effect and be applicable to the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>