<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/343" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/343/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/343/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_343"><akn:num>343</akn:num><akn:heading>Misbranded food</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 343. Misbranded food
A food shall be deemed to be misbranded—(a) False or misleading labelIf (1) its labeling is false or misleading in any particular, or (2) in the case of a food to which section 350 of this title applies, its advertising is false or misleading in a material respect or its labeling is in violation of section 350(b)(2) of this title.


(b) Offer for sale under another nameIf it is offered for sale under the name of another food.


(c) Imitation of another foodIf it is an imitation of another food, unless its label bears, in type of uniform size and prominence, the word “imitation” and, immediately thereafter, the name of the food imitated.


(d) Misleading containerIf its container is so made, formed, or filled as to be misleading.


(e) Package formIf in package form unless it bears a label containing (1) the name and place of business of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor; and (2) an accurate statement of the quantity of the contents in terms of weight, measure, or numerical count, except that under clause (2) of this paragraph reasonable variations shall be permitted, and exemptions as to small packages shall be established, by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.


(f) Prominence of information on labelIf any word, statement, or other information required by or under authority of this chapter to appear on the label or labeling is not prominently placed thereon with such conspicuousness (as compared with other words, statements, designs, or devices, in the labeling) and in such terms as to render it likely to be read and understood by the ordinary individual under customary conditions of purchase and use.


(g) Representation as to definition and standard of identityIf it purports to be or is represented as a food for which a definition and standard of identity has been prescribed by regulations as provided by section 341 of this title, unless (1) it conforms to such definition and standard, and (2) its label bears the name of the fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>False or misleading label</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) False or misleading label If (1) its labeling is false or misleading in any particular, or (2) in the case of a food to which section 350 of this title applies, its advertising is false or misleading in a material respect or its labeling is in violation of section 350(b)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offer for sale under another name</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Offer for sale under another name If it is offered for sale under the name of another food.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imitation of another food</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Imitation of another food If it is an imitation of another food, unless its label bears, in type of uniform size and prominence, the word “imitation” and, immediately thereafter, the name of the food imitated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Misleading container</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Misleading container If its container is so made, formed, or filled as to be misleading.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Package form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Package form If in package form unless it bears a label containing (1) the name and place of business of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor; and (2) an accurate statement of the quantity of the contents in terms of weight, measure, or numerical count, except that under clause (2) of this paragraph reasonable variations shall be permitted, and exemptions as to small packages shall be established, by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prominence of information on label</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prominence of information on label If any word, statement, or other information required by or under authority of this chapter to appear on the label or labeling is not prominently placed thereon with such conspicuousness (as compared with other words, statements, designs, or devices, in the labeling) and in such terms as to render it likely to be read and understood by the ordinary individual under customary conditions of purchase and use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation as to definition and standard of identity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Representation as to definition and standard of identity If it purports to be or is represented as a food for which a definition and standard of identity has been prescribed by regulations as provided by section 341 of this title, unless (1) it conforms to such definition and standard, and (2) its label bears the name of the food specified in the definition and standard, and, insofar as may be required by such regulations, the common names of optional ingredients (other than spices, flavoring, and coloring) present in such food.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation as to standards of quality and fill of container</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Representation as to standards of quality and fill of container If it purports to be or is represented as— For purposes of paragraph (3), a determination by the Secretary that a process or treatment has not been shown to meet the requirements of subclauses (I) through (III) of subparagraph (B)(i) shall constitute final agency action under such subclauses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Label where no representation as to definition and standard of identity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Label where no representation as to definition and standard of identity Unless its label bears (1) the common or usual name of the food, if any there be, and (2) in case it is fabricated from two or more ingredients, the common or usual name of each such ingredient and if the food purports to be a beverage containing vegetable or fruit juice, a statement with appropriate prominence on the information panel of the total percentage of such fruit or vegetable juice contained in the food; except that spices, flavorings, and colors not required to be certified under section 379e(c) of this title 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. unless sold as spices, flavorings, or such colors, may be designated as spices, flavorings, and colorings without naming each. To the extent that compliance with the requirements of clause (2) of this paragraph is impracticable, or results in deception or unfair competition, exemptions shall be established by regulations promulgated by t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation for special dietary use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Representation for special dietary use If it purports to be or is represented for special dietary uses, unless its label bears such information concerning its vitamin, mineral, and other dietary properties as the Secretary determines to be, and by regulations prescribes as, necessary in order fully to inform purchasers as to its value for such uses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>