<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/348" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/348/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/348/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_348"><akn:num>348</akn:num><akn:heading>Food additives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 348. Food additives(a) Unsafe food additives; exception for conformity with exemption or regulationA food additive shall, with respect to any particular use or intended use of such additives, be deemed to be unsafe for the purposes of the application of clause (2)(C) of section 342(a) of this title, unless—(1) it and its use or intended use conform to the terms of an exemption which is in effect pursuant to subsection (j) of this section;

(2) there is in effect, and it and its use or intended use are in conformity with, a regulation issued under this section prescribing the conditions under which such additive may be safely used; or

(3) in the case of a food additive as defined in this chapter that is a food contact substance, there is—(A) in effect, and such substance and the use of such substance are in conformity with, a regulation issued under this section prescribing the conditions under which such additive may be safely used; or

(B) a notification submitted under subsection (h) that is effective.



While such a regulation relating to a food additive, or such a notification under subsection (h)(1) relating to a food additive that is a food contact substance, is in effect, and has not been revoked pursuant to subsection (i), a food shall not, by reason of bearing or containing such a food additive in accordance with the regulation or notification, be considered adulterated under section 342(a)(1) of this title.

(b) Petition for regulation prescribing conditions of safe use; contents; description of production methods and controls; samples; notice of regulation(1) Any person may, with respect to any intended use of a food additive, file with the Secretary a petition proposing the issuance of a regulation prescribing the conditions under which such additive may be safely used.

(2) Such petition shall, in addition to any explanatory or supporting data, contain—(A) the name and all pertinent information concerning such food additive, including, where availab</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unsafe food additives; exception for conformity with exemption or regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unsafe food additives; exception for conformity with exemption or regulation A food additive shall, with respect to any particular use or intended use of such additives, be deemed to be unsafe for the purposes of the application of clause (2)(C) of section 342(a) of this title, unless— While such a regulation relating to a food additive, or such a notification under subsection (h)(1) relating to a food additive that is a food contact substance, is in effect, and has not been revoked pursuant to subsection (i), a food shall not, by reason of bearing or containing such a food additive in accordance with the regulation or notification, be considered adulterated under section 342(a)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition for regulation prescribing conditions of safe use; contents; description of production methods and controls; samples; notice of regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Petition for regulation prescribing conditions of safe use; contents; description of production methods and controls; samples; notice of regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval or denial of petition; time for issuance of order; evaluation of data; factors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Approval or denial of petition; time for issuance of order; evaluation of data; factors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation issued on Secretary’s initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulation issued on Secretary’s initiative The Secretary may at any time, upon his own initiative, propose the issuance of a regulation prescribing, with respect to any particular use of a food additive, the conditions under which such additive may be safely used, and the reasons therefor. After the thirtieth day following publication of such a proposal, the Secretary may by order establish a regulation based upon the proposal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication and effective date of orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Publication and effective date of orders Any order, including any regulation established by such order, issued under subsection (c) or (d) of this section, shall be published and shall be effective upon publication, but the Secretary may stay such effectiveness if, after issuance of such order, a hearing is sought with respect to such order pursuant to subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objections and public hearing; basis and contents of order; statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Objections and public hearing; basis and contents of order; statement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification relating to food contact substance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notification relating to food contact substance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment or repeal of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Amendment or repeal of regulations The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe the procedure by which regulations under the foregoing provisions of this section may be amended or repealed, and such procedure shall conform to the procedure provided in this section for the promulgation of such regulations. The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe the procedure by which the Secretary may deem a notification under subsection (h) to no longer be effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_348_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions for investigational use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exemptions for investigational use Without regard to subsections (b) to (i), inclusive, of this section, the Secretary shall by regulation provide for exempting from the requirements of this section any food additive, and any food bearing or containing such additive, intended solely for investigational use by qualified experts when in his opinion such exemption is consistent with the public health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>