<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350a–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350a–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350a–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_350a_1"><akn:num>350a–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Protecting infants and improving formula supply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 350a–1. Protecting infants and improving formula supply(a) Definitions(1) In generalIn this section, the term “infant formula” has the meaning given such term in section 201(z) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 321(z)).


(2) Omitted


(b) Office of Critical Foods(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish within the Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition an office to be known as the Office of Critical Foods. The Secretary shall appoint a Director to lead such Office.


(2) DutiesThe Office of Critical Foods shall be responsible for oversight, coordination, and facilitation of activities related to critical foods, as defined in section 201(ss) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 321(ss)], as added by subsection (a)(2).



(c) Omitted

(d) ReportNot later than one year after December 29, 2022, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives that includes—(1) the number of premarket submissions for new infant formula the Secretary has received under section 412(d) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 350a(d)) each year since 2012;

(2) how many of such submissions received requests from the Secretary for additional information;

(3) how long after receiving such submissions the Secretary sent such requests for additional information;

(4) what additional information the Secretary requested of the persons submitting such submissions; and

(5) the date each new infant formula described in subparagraph (A) 11 So in original. There is no subparagraph (A). was first marketed, if available.


(e) Infant formula flexibilitiesThe Secretary shall publish a list on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services providing information on how to identify appropriate substitutes for infant formula products in shortage that are relied upon by infants and other individuals wi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Critical Foods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Office of Critical Foods</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than one year after December 29, 2022, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Infant formula flexibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Infant formula flexibilities The Secretary shall publish a list on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services providing information on how to identify appropriate substitutes for infant formula products in shortage that are relied upon by infants and other individuals with inborn errors of metabolism or other serious health conditions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>International harmonization of infant formula requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) International harmonization of infant formula requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transparency and accountability to support infant formula innovation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transparency and accountability to support infant formula innovation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response to recall</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Response to recall</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with manufacturer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Coordination with manufacturer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350a_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>National strategy on infant formula</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) National strategy on infant formula</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>