<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_350g"><akn:num>350g</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazard analysis and risk-based preventive controls</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 350g. Hazard analysis and risk-based preventive controls(a) In generalThe owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall, in accordance with this section, evaluate the hazards that could affect food manufactured, processed, packed, or held by such facility, identify and implement preventive controls to significantly minimize or prevent the occurrence of such hazards and provide assurances that such food is not adulterated under section 342 of this title or misbranded under section 343(w) of this title, monitor the performance of those controls, and maintain records of this monitoring as a matter of routine practice.


(b) Hazard analysisThe owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall—(1) identify and evaluate known or reasonably foreseeable hazards that may be associated with the facility, including—(A) biological, chemical, physical, and radiological hazards, natural toxins, pesticides, drug residues, decomposition, parasites, allergens, and unapproved food and color additives; and

(B) hazards that occur naturally, or may be unintentionally introduced; and


(2) identify and evaluate hazards that may be intentionally introduced, including by acts of terrorism; and

(3) develop a written analysis of the hazards.


(c) Preventive controlsThe owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall identify and implement preventive controls, including at critical control points, if any, to provide assurances that—(1) hazards identified in the hazard analysis conducted under subsection (b)(1) will be significantly minimized or prevented;

(2) any hazards identified in the hazard analysis conducted under subsection (b)(2) will be significantly minimized or prevented and addressed, consistent with section 350i of this title, as applicable; and

(3) the food manufactured, processed, packed, or held by such facility will not be adulterated under section 342 of this title or misbranded under section 343(w) of this title.


(d) Monitoring of effectiven</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall, in accordance with this section, evaluate the hazards that could affect food manufactured, processed, packed, or held by such facility, identify and implement preventive controls to significantly minimize or prevent the occurrence of such hazards and provide assurances that such food is not adulterated under section 342 of this title or misbranded under section 343(w) of this title, monitor the performance of those controls, and maintain records of this monitoring as a matter of routine practice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazard analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hazard analysis The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preventive controls</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preventive controls The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall identify and implement preventive controls, including at critical control points, if any, to provide assurances that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring of effectiveness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Monitoring of effectiveness The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall monitor the effectiveness of the preventive controls implemented under subsection (c) to provide assurances that the outcomes described in subsection (c) shall be achieved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corrective actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Corrective actions The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall establish procedures to ensure that, if the preventive controls implemented under subsection (c) are not properly implemented or are found to be ineffective—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Verification The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall verify that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Recordkeeping The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall maintain, for not less than 2 years, records documenting the monitoring of the preventive controls implemented under subsection (c), instances of nonconformance material to food safety, the results of testing and other appropriate means of verification under subsection (f)(4), instances when corrective actions were implemented, and the efficacy of preventive controls and corrective actions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written plan and documentation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Written plan and documentation The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall prepare a written plan that documents and describes the procedures used by the facility to comply with the requirements of this section, including analyzing the hazards under subsection (b) and identifying the preventive controls adopted under subsection (c) to address those hazards. Such written plan, together with the documentation described in subsection (g), shall be made promptly available to a duly authorized representative of the Secretary upon oral or written request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to reanalyze</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Requirement to reanalyze The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility shall conduct a reanalysis under subsection (b) whenever a significant change is made in the activities conducted at a facility operated by such owner, operator, or agent if the change creates a reasonable potential for a new hazard or a significant increase in a previously identified hazard or not less frequently than once every 3 years, whichever is earlier. Such reanalysis shall be completed and additional preventive controls needed to address the hazard identified, if any, shall be implemented before the change in activities at the facility is operative. Such owner, operator, or agent shall revise the written plan required under subsection (h) if such a significant change is made or document the basis for the conclusion that no additional or revised preventive controls are needed. The Secretary may require a reanalysis under this section to respond to new hazards and developments in scientific unders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350g_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for seafood, juice, and low-acid canned food facilities subject to HACCP</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exemption for seafood, juice, and low-acid canned food facilities subject to HACCP</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>