<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_350h"><akn:num>350h</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for produce safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 350h. Standards for produce safety(a) Proposed rulemaking(1) In general(A) RulemakingNot later than 1 year after January 4, 2011, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture and representatives of State departments of agriculture (including with regard to the national organic program established under the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990 [7 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.]), and in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall publish a notice of proposed rulemaking to establish science-based minimum standards for the safe production and harvesting of those types of fruits and vegetables, including specific mixes or categories of fruits and vegetables, that are raw agricultural commodities for which the Secretary has determined that such standards minimize the risk of serious adverse health consequences or death.


(B) Determination by SecretaryWith respect to small businesses and very small businesses (as such terms are defined in the regulation promulgated under subparagraph (A)) that produce and harvest those types of fruits and vegetables that are raw agricultural commodities that the Secretary has determined are low risk and do not present a risk of serious adverse health consequences or death, the Secretary may determine not to include production and harvesting of such fruits and vegetables in such rulemaking, or may modify the applicable requirements of regulations promulgated pursuant to this section.



(2) Public inputDuring the comment period on the notice of proposed rulemaking under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall conduct not less than 3 public meetings in diverse geographical areas of the United States to provide persons in different regions an opportunity to comment.


(3) ContentThe proposed rulemaking under paragraph (1) shall—(A) provide sufficient flexibility to be applicable to various types of entities engaged in the production and harvesting of fruits and vegetables that are raw agricultural commodities, includin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposed rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proposed rulemaking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Final regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement The Secretary may coordinate with the Secretary of Agriculture and, as appropriate, shall contract and coordinate with the agency or department designated by the Governor of each State to perform activities to ensure compliance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Guidance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350h_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for direct farm marketing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemption for direct farm marketing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350h_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Clarification This section shall not apply to produce that is produced by an individual for personal consumption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350h_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for activities of facilities subject to section 350g of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exception for activities of facilities subject to This section shall not apply to activities of a facility that are subject to section 350g of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>