<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_350j"><akn:num>350j</akn:num><akn:heading>Targeting of inspection resources for domestic facilities, foreign facilities, and ports of entry; a</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 350j. Targeting of inspection resources for domestic facilities, foreign facilities, and ports of entry; annual report(a) Identification and inspection of facilities(1) IdentificationThe Secretary shall identify high-risk facilities and shall allocate resources to inspect facilities according to the known safety risks of the facilities, which shall be based on the following factors:(A) The known safety risks of the food manufactured, processed, packed, or held at the facility.

(B) The compliance history of a facility, including with regard to food recalls, outbreaks of foodborne illness, and violations of food safety standards.

(C) The rigor and effectiveness of the facility’s hazard analysis and risk-based preventive controls.

(D) Whether the food manufactured, processed, packed, or held at the facility meets the criteria for priority under section 381(h)(1) of this title.

(E) Whether the food or the facility that manufactured, processed, packed, or held such food has received a certification as described in section 381(q) or 384b of this title, as appropriate.

(F) Any other criteria deemed necessary and appropriate by the Secretary for purposes of allocating inspection resources.


(2) Inspections(A) In generalBeginning on January 4, 2011, the Secretary shall increase the frequency of inspection of all facilities.


(B) Domestic high-risk facilitiesThe Secretary shall increase the frequency of inspection of domestic facilities identified under paragraph (1) as high-risk facilities such that each such facility is inspected—(i) not less often than once in the 5-year period following January 4, 2011; and

(ii) not less often than once every 3 years thereafter.


(C) Domestic non-high-risk facilitiesThe Secretary shall ensure that each domestic facility that is not identified under paragraph (1) as a high-risk facility is inspected—(i) not less often than once in the 7-year period following January 4, 2011; and

(ii) not less often than once every 5 years there</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification and inspection of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Identification and inspection of facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification and inspection at ports of entry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification and inspection at ports of entry The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall allocate resources to inspect any article of food imported into the United States according to the known safety risks of the article of food, which shall be based on the following factors:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency agreements with respect to seafood</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interagency agreements with respect to seafood</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination The Secretary shall improve coordination and cooperation with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Homeland Security to target food inspection resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Facility For purposes of this section, the term “facility” means a domestic facility or a foreign facility that is required to register under section 350d of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>