<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/350m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_350m"><akn:num>350m</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for critical food</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 350m. Requirements for critical food(a) Notification of meaningful disruption for critical food(1) In generalA manufacturer of a critical food (as defined in section 321(ss) of this title) shall notify the Secretary of a permanent discontinuance in the manufacture or an interruption of the manufacture of such food that is likely to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply of such food in the United States, and the reasons for such discontinuance or interruption, as soon as practicable, but not later than 5 business days after such discontinuance or such interruption.


(2) Distribution of informationNot later than 5 calendar days after receiving a notification under paragraph (1), if the Secretary has determined that such discontinuance or interruption has resulted, or is likely to result, in a shortage of such critical food, the Secretary shall distribute, to the Secretary of Agriculture and to the maximum extent practicable to the appropriate entities, as determined by the Secretary through such means as the Secretary determines appropriate, information on such shortage.


(3) ConfidentialityNothing in this subsection authorizes the Secretary to disclose any information that is a trade secret or confidential information subject to section 552(b)(4) of title 5 or section 1905 of title 18.


(4) Meaningful disruptionIn this subsection, the term “meaningful disruption”—(A) means a change in production that is reasonably likely to lead to a significant reduction in the supply of a critical food by a manufacturer that affects the ability of the manufacturer to meet expected demand for its product; and

(B) does not include interruptions in manufacturing due to matters such as routine maintenance, changes or discontinuance of flavors, colors, or other insignificant formulation characteristics, or insignificant changes in manufacturing so long as the manufacturer expects to resume operations in a short period of time.



(b) Risk management plansEach manufacturer </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of meaningful disruption for critical food</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notification of meaningful disruption for critical food</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk management plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Risk management plans Each manufacturer of a critical food shall develop, maintain, and implement, as appropriate, a redundancy risk management plan that identifies and evaluates risks to the supply of the food, as applicable, for each establishment in which such food is manufactured. A risk management plan under this subsection—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_350m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to meet requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Failure to meet requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>