<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/352" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/352/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/352/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_352"><akn:num>352</akn:num><akn:heading>Misbranded drugs and devices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 352. Misbranded drugs and devices
A drug or device shall be deemed to be misbranded—(a) False or misleading label(1) If its labeling is false or misleading in any particular. Health care economic information provided to a payor, formulary committee, or other similar entity with knowledge and expertise in the area of health care economic analysis, carrying out its responsibilities for the selection of drugs or devices for coverage or reimbursement, shall not be considered to be false or misleading under this paragraph if the health care economic information relates to an indication approved under section 355, 360(k), 360c(f)(2), or 360e of this title or section 262 of title 42 for such drug or device, is based on competent and reliable scientific evidence, and includes, where applicable, a conspicuous and prominent statement describing any material differences between the health care economic information and the labeling approved for the drug or device under section 355, 360(k), 360c(f)(2), or 360e of this title or section 262 of title 42. The requirements set forth in section 355, 360(k), 360c(f)(2), or 360e of this title or section 262 of title 42 shall not apply to health care economic information provided to such a payor, committee, or entity in accordance with this paragraph. Information that is relevant to the substantiation of the health care economic information presented pursuant to this paragraph shall be made available to the Secretary upon request.

(2)(A) For purposes of this paragraph,11 So in original. The term “health care economic information” appears only in par. (1). the term “health care economic information” means any analysis (including the clinical data, inputs, clinical or other assumptions, methods, results, and other components underlying or comprising the analysis) that identifies, measures, or describes the economic consequences, which may be based on the separate or aggregated clinical consequences of the represented health outcomes, of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>False or misleading label</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) False or misleading label</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Package form; contents of label</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Package form; contents of label If in package form unless it bears a label containing (1) the name and place of business of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor; and (2) an accurate statement of the quantity of the contents in terms of weight, measure, or numerical count: Provided, That under clause (2) of this paragraph reasonable variations shall be permitted, and exemptions as to small packages shall be established, by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prominence of information on label</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prominence of information on label If any word, statement, or other information required by or under authority of this chapter to appear on the label or labeling is not prominently placed thereon with such conspicuousness (as compared with other words, statements, designs, or devices, in the labeling) and in such terms as to render it likely to be read and understood by the ordinary individual under customary conditions of purchase and use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 105–115, title I, § 126(b), Nov. 21, 1997, 111 Stat. 2327</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of drugs or devices by established names</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Designation of drugs or devices by established names</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Directions for use and warnings on label</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Directions for use and warnings on label Unless its labeling bears (1) adequate directions for use; and (2) such adequate warnings against use in those pathological conditions or by children where its use may be dangerous to health, or against unsafe dosage or methods or duration of administration or application, in such manner and form, as are necessary for the protection of users, except that where any requirement of clause (1) of this paragraph, as applied to any drug or device, is not necessary for the protection of the public health, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations exempting such drug or device from such requirement. Required labeling for prescription devices intended for use in health care facilities or by a health care professional and required labeling for in vitro diagnostic devices intended for use by health care professionals or in blood establishments may be made available solely by electronic means, provided that the labeling complies with all applicable req</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representations as recognized drug; packing and labeling; inconsistent requirements for designation of drug</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Representations as recognized drug; packing and labeling; inconsistent requirements for designation of drug If it purports to be a drug the name of which is recognized in an official compendium, unless it is packaged and labeled as prescribed therein. The method of packing may be modified with the consent of the Secretary. Whenever a drug is recognized in both the United States Pharmacopoeia and the Homoeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States, it shall be subject to the requirements of the United States Pharmacopoeia with respect to packaging and labeling unless it is labeled and offered for sale as a homoeopathic drug, in which case it shall be subject to the provisions of the Homoeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States, and not those of the United States Pharmacopoeia, except that in the event of inconsistency between the requirements of this paragraph and those of paragraph (e) as to the name by which the drug or its ingredients shall be designated, the requirements of p</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deteriorative drugs; packing and labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Deteriorative drugs; packing and labeling If it has been found by the Secretary to be a drug liable to deterioration, unless it is packaged in such form and manner, and its label bears a statement of such precautions, as the Secretary shall by regulations require as necessary for the protection of the public health. No such regulation shall be established for any drug recognized in an official compendium until the Secretary shall have informed the appropriate body charged with the revision of such compendium of the need for such packaging or labeling requirements and such body shall have failed within a reasonable time to prescribe such requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug; misleading container; imitation; offer for sale under another name</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Drug; misleading container; imitation; offer for sale under another name</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health-endangering when used as prescribed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Health-endangering when used as prescribed If it is dangerous to health when used in the dosage or manner, or with the frequency or duration prescribed, recommended, or suggested in the labeling thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>