<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/353b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/353b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/353b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_353b"><akn:num>353b</akn:num><akn:heading>Outsourcing facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 353b. Outsourcing facilities(a) In generalSections 352(f)(1), 355, and 360eee–1 of this title shall not apply to a drug compounded by or under the direct supervision of a licensed pharmacist in a facility that elects to register as an outsourcing facility if each of the following conditions is met:(1) Registration and reportingThe drug is compounded in an outsourcing facility that is in compliance with the requirements of subsection (b).


(2) Bulk drug substancesThe drug is compounded in an outsourcing facility that does not compound using bulk drug substances (as defined in section 207.3(a)(4) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation)), unless—(A)(i) the bulk drug substance appears on a list established by the Secretary identifying bulk drug substances for which there is a clinical need, by—(I) publishing a notice in the Federal Register proposing bulk drug substances to be included on the list, including the rationale for such proposal;

(II) providing a period of not less than 60 calendar days for comment on the notice; and

(III) publishing a notice in the Federal Register designating bulk drug substances for inclusion on the list; or


(ii) the drug compounded from such bulk drug substance appears on the drug shortage list in effect under section 356e of this title at the time of compounding, distribution, and dispensing;


(B) if an applicable monograph exists under the United States Pharmacopeia, the National Formulary, or another compendium or pharmacopeia recognized by the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph, the bulk drug substances each comply with the monograph;

(C) the bulk drug substances are each manufactured by an establishment that is registered under section 360 of this title (including a foreign establishment that is registered under section 360(i) of this title); and

(D) the bulk drug substances are each accompanied by a valid certificate of analysis.


(3) Ingredients (other than bulk drug substances)If any</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Sections 352(f)(1), 355, and 360eee–1 of this title shall not apply to a drug compounded by or under the direct supervision of a licensed pharmacist in a facility that elects to register as an outsourcing facility if each of the following conditions is met:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of outsourcing facilities and reporting of drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Registration of outsourcing facilities and reporting of drugs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>22 So in original. Two subsecs. (d) have been enacted. Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>2 Obligation to pay fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment of the fee under section 379j–62 of this title, as described in subsection (a)(9), shall not relieve an outsourcing facility that is licensed as a pharmacy in any State that requires pharmacy licensing fees of its obligation to pay such State fees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>