<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/353d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/353d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/353d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_353d"><akn:num>353d</akn:num><akn:heading>Process to update labeling for certain generic drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 353d. Process to update labeling for certain generic drugs(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) The term “covered drug” means a drug approved under section 355(c) of this title—(A) for which there are no unexpired patents included in the list under section 355(j)(7) of this title and no unexpired period of exclusivity;

(B) for which the approval of the application has been withdrawn for reasons other than safety or effectiveness; and

(C) for which—(i)(I) there is new scientific evidence available pertaining to new or existing conditions of use that is not reflected in the approved labeling;

(II) the approved labeling does not reflect current legal and regulatory requirements for content or format; or

(III) there is a relevant accepted use in clinical practice that is not reflected in the approved labeling; and


(ii) updating the approved labeling would benefit the public health.



(2) The term “period of exclusivity”, with respect to a drug approved under section 355(c) of this title, means any period of exclusivity under clause (ii), (iii), or (iv) of section 355(c)(3)(E) of this title, clause (ii), (iii), or (iv) of section 355(j)(5)(F) of this title, or section 355a, 355f, or 360cc of this title.

(3) The term “generic version” means a drug approved under section 355(j) of this title whose reference listed drug is a covered drug.

(4) The term “relevant accepted use” means a use for a drug in clinical practice that is supported by scientific evidence that appears to the Secretary to meet the standards for approval under section 355 of this title.

(5) The term “selected drug” means a covered drug for which the Secretary has determined through the process under subsection (c) that the labeling should be changed.


(b) Identification of covered drugsThe Secretary may identify covered drugs for which labeling updates would provide a public health benefit. To assist in identifying covered drugs, the Secretary may do one or both of the following:(1) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of covered drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification of covered drugs The Secretary may identify covered drugs for which labeling updates would provide a public health benefit. To assist in identifying covered drugs, the Secretary may do one or both of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of drugs for updating</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Selection of drugs for updating If the Secretary determines, with respect to a covered drug, that the available scientific evidence meets the standards under section 355 of this title for adding or modifying information to the labeling or providing supplemental information to the labeling regarding the use of the covered drug, the Secretary may initiate the process under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiation of the process of updating</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Initiation of the process of updating If the Secretary determines that labeling changes are appropriate for a selected drug pursuant to subsection (c), the Secretary shall provide notice to the holders of approved applications for a generic version of such drug that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response to notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Response to notification Within 30 days of receipt of notification provided by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (d), the holder of an approved application for a generic version of the selected drug shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of application holder’s response</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Review of application holder’s response</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Violation If the holder of an approved application for the generic version of the selected drug does not comply with the requirements of subsection (f)(2), such generic version of the selected drug shall be deemed to be misbranded under section 352 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations; generic drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations; generic drugs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rules of construction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_353d_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reports Not later than 4 years after December 27, 2020, and every 4 years thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, a report that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>