<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/354" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/354/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/354/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_354"><akn:num>354</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterinary feed directive drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 354. Veterinary feed directive drugs(a) Lawful veterinary feed directive requirement(1) A drug intended for use in or on animal feed which is limited by an approved application filed pursuant to section 360b(b) of this title, a conditionally-approved application filed pursuant to section 360ccc of this title, or an index listing pursuant to section 360ccc–1 of this title to use under the professional supervision of a licensed veterinarian is a veterinary feed directive drug. Any animal feed bearing or containing a veterinary feed directive drug shall be fed to animals only by or upon a lawful veterinary feed directive issued by a licensed veterinarian in the course of the veterinarian’s professional practice. When labeled, distributed, held, and used in accordance with this section, a veterinary feed directive drug and any animal feed bearing or containing a veterinary feed directive drug shall be exempt from section 352(f) of this title.

(2) A veterinary feed directive is lawful if it—(A) contains such information as the Secretary may by general regulation or by order require; and

(B) is in compliance with the conditions and indications for use of the drug set forth in the notice published pursuant to section 360b(i) of this title, or the index listing pursuant to section 360ccc–1(e) of this title.


(3)(A) Any persons involved in the distribution or use of animal feed bearing or containing a veterinary feed directive drug and the licensed veterinarian issuing the veterinary feed directive shall maintain a copy of the veterinary feed directive applicable to each such feed, except in the case of a person distributing such feed to another person for further distribution. Such person distributing the feed shall maintain a written acknowledgment from the person to whom the feed is shipped stating that that person shall not ship or move such feed to an animal production facility without a veterinary feed directive or ship such feed to another person for further dist</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_354_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lawful veterinary feed directive requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Lawful veterinary feed directive requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_354_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling and advertising</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Labeling and advertising A veterinary feed directive drug and any feed bearing or containing a veterinary feed directive drug shall be deemed to be misbranded if their labeling fails to bear such cautionary statement and such other information as the Secretary may by general regulation or by order prescribe, or their advertising fails to conform to the conditions and indications for use published pursuant to section 360b(i) of this title, or the index listing pursuant to section 360ccc–1(e) of this title or fails to contain the general cautionary statement prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_354_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonprescription status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nonprescription status Neither a drug subject to this section, nor animal feed bearing or containing such a drug, shall be deemed to be a prescription article under any Federal or State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>