<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_356"><akn:num>356</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited approval of drugs for serious or life-threatening diseases or conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 356. Expedited approval of drugs for serious or life-threatening diseases or conditions(a) Designation of a drug as a breakthrough therapy(1) In generalThe Secretary shall, at the request of the sponsor of a drug, expedite the development and review of such drug if the drug is intended, alone or in combination with 1 or more other drugs, to treat a serious or life-threatening disease or condition and preliminary clinical evidence indicates that the drug may demonstrate substantial improvement over existing therapies on 1 or more clinically significant endpoints, such as substantial treatment effects observed early in clinical development. (In this section, such a drug is referred to as a “breakthrough therapy”.)


(2) Request for designationThe sponsor of a drug may request the Secretary to designate the drug as a breakthrough therapy. A request for the designation may be made concurrently with, or at any time after, the submission of an application for the investigation of the drug under section 355(i) of this title or section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262(a)(3)].


(3) Designation(A) In generalNot later than 60 calendar days after the receipt of a request under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall determine whether the drug that is the subject of the request meets the criteria described in paragraph (1). If the Secretary finds that the drug meets the criteria, the Secretary shall designate the drug as a breakthrough therapy and shall take such actions as are appropriate to expedite the development and review of the application for approval of such drug.


(B) ActionsThe actions to expedite the development and review of an application under subparagraph (A) may include, as appropriate—(i) holding meetings with the sponsor and the review team throughout the development of the drug;

(ii) providing timely advice to, and interactive communication with, the sponsor regarding the development of the drug to ensure that the development program </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of a drug as a breakthrough therapy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation of a drug as a breakthrough therapy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of drug as fast track product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation of drug as fast track product</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accelerated approval of a drug for a serious or life-threatening disease or condition, including a fast track product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Accelerated approval of a drug for a serious or life-threatening disease or condition, including a fast track product</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of incomplete applications for approval of a fast track product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of incomplete applications for approval of a fast track product</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Construction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awareness efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Awareness efforts The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regenerative advanced therapy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regenerative advanced therapy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited population pathway for antibacterial and antifungal drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limited population pathway for antibacterial and antifungal drugs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>