<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_356d"><akn:num>356d</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination; task force and strategic plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 356d. Coordination; task force and strategic plan(a) Task force and strategic plan(1) In general(A) Task forceAs soon as practicable after July 9, 2012, the Secretary shall establish a task force to develop and implement a strategic plan for enhancing the Secretary’s response to preventing and mitigating drug shortages.


(B) Strategic planThe strategic plan described in subparagraph (A) shall include—(i) plans for enhanced interagency and intra-agency coordination, communication, and decisionmaking;

(ii) plans for ensuring that drug shortages are considered when the Secretary initiates a regulatory action that could precipitate a drug shortage or exacerbate an existing drug shortage;

(iii) plans for effective communication with outside stakeholders, including who the Secretary should alert about potential or actual drug shortages, how the communication should occur, and what types of information should be shared;

(iv) plans for considering the impact of drug shortages on research and clinical trials; and

(v) an examination of whether to establish a “qualified manufacturing partner program”, as described in subparagraph (C).


(C) Description of programIn conducting the examination of a “qualified manufacturing partner program” under subparagraph (B)(v), the Secretary—(i) shall take into account that—(I) a “qualified manufacturer”, for purposes of such program, would need to have the capability and capacity to supply products determined or anticipated to be in shortage; and

(II) in examining the capability and capacity to supply products in shortage, the “qualified manufacturer” could have a site that manufactures a drug listed under section 356e of this title or have the capacity to produce drugs in response to a shortage within a rapid timeframe; and


(ii) shall examine whether incentives are necessary to encourage the participation of “qualified manufacturers” in such a program.


(D) ConsultationIn carrying out this paragraph, the task force shall ensure</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Task force and strategic plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Task force and strategic plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Communication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Communication The Secretary shall ensure that, prior to any enforcement action or issuance of a warning letter that the Secretary determines could reasonably be anticipated to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply in the United States of a drug described under section 356c(a) of this title, there is communication with the appropriate office of the Food and Drug Administration with expertise regarding drug shortages regarding whether the action or letter could cause, or exacerbate, a shortage of the drug.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Action If the Secretary determines, after the communication described in subsection (b), that an enforcement action or a warning letter could reasonably cause or exacerbate a shortage of a drug described under section 356c(a) of this title, then the Secretary shall evaluate the risks associated with the impact of such shortage upon patients and those risks associated with the violation involved before taking such action or issuing such letter, unless there is imminent risk of serious adverse health consequences or death to humans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting by other entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting by other entities The Secretary shall identify or establish a mechanism by which health care providers and other third-party organizations may report to the Secretary evidence of a drug shortage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review and construction No determination, finding, action, or omission of the Secretary under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Temporary sunset Subsection (a) shall cease to be effective on the date that is 5 years after July 9, 2012. Subsections (b), (c), and (e) shall not be in effect during the period beginning 5 years after July 9, 2012, and ending on December 29, 2022. Subsections (b), (c), and (e) shall be in effect beginning on December 29, 2022.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coordination The Secretary shall ensure timely and effective internal coordination and alignment among the field investigators of the Food and Drug Administration and the staff of the Center for Drug Evaluation and Research’s Office of Compliance and Drug Shortage Program regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>