<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_356i"><akn:num>356i</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt reports of marketing status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 356i. Prompt reports of marketing status(a) Notification of withdrawalThe holder of an application approved under subsection (c) or (j) of section 355 of this title or subsection (a) or (k) of section 262 of title 42 shall notify the Secretary in writing 180 days prior to withdrawing the approved drug from sale, or if 180 days is not practicable as soon as practicable but not later than the date of withdrawal. The holder shall include with such notice the—(1) National Drug Code;

(2) identity of the drug by established name (or, in the case of a biological product, the proper name) and by proprietary name, if any;

(3) new drug application number, abbreviated application number, or biologics license application number;

(4) strength of the drug;

(5) date on which the drug is expected to no longer be available for sale; and

(6) reason for withdrawal of the drug.


(b) Notification of drug not available for saleThe holder of an application approved under subsection (c) or (j) of section 355 of this title or subsection (a) or (k) of section 262 of title 42 shall notify the Secretary in writing within 180 calendar days of the date of approval of the drug if the drug will not be available for sale within 180 calendar days of such date of approval. The holder shall include with such notice the—(1) identity of the drug by established name (or, in the case of a biological product, the proper name) and by proprietary name, if any;

(2) new drug application number, abbreviated application number, or biologics license application number;

(3) strength of the drug;

(4) date on which the drug will be available for sale, if known; and

(5) reason for not marketing the drug after approval.


(c) Additional one-time reportWithin 180 days of December 29, 2022, all holders of applications approved under subsection (a) or (k) of section 262 of title 42 shall review the information in the list published under section 262(k)(9)(A) of title 42 and shall submit a written notice to th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of withdrawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notification of withdrawal The holder of an application approved under subsection (c) or (j) of section 355 of this title or subsection (a) or (k) of section 262 of title 42 shall notify the Secretary in writing 180 days prior to withdrawing the approved drug from sale, or if 180 days is not practicable as soon as practicable but not later than the date of withdrawal. The holder shall include with such notice the—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of drug not available for sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification of drug not available for sale The holder of an application approved under subsection (c) or (j) of section 355 of this title or subsection (a) or (k) of section 262 of title 42 shall notify the Secretary in writing within 180 calendar days of the date of approval of the drug if the drug will not be available for sale within 180 calendar days of such date of approval. The holder shall include with such notice the—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional one-time report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional one-time report Within 180 days of December 29, 2022, all holders of applications approved under subsection (a) or (k) of section 262 of title 42 shall review the information in the list published under section 262(k)(9)(A) of title 42 and shall submit a written notice to the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to meet requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Failure to meet requirements If a holder of an approved application fails to submit the information required under subsection (a), (b), or (c), the Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356i_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Updates The Secretary shall update the list published under section 355(j)(7)(A) of this title based on the information provided under subsections (a), (b), and (c) by moving drugs that are not available for sale from the active section to the discontinued section of the list, except that drugs the Secretary determines have been withdrawn from sale for reasons of safety or effectiveness shall be removed from the list in accordance with section 355(j)(7)(C) of this title. The Secretary shall update the list published under section 262(k)(9)(A) of title 42 based on information provided under subsections (a), (b), and (c) by identifying as discontinued biological products that are not available for sale, except that biological products for which the license has been revoked or suspended for safety, purity, or potency reasons shall be removed from the list in accordance with section 262(k)(9)(B) of title 42. The Secretary shall make monthly updates to the lists referred to in the prece</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356i_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of notices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on use of notices Any notice submitted under this section shall not be made public by the Secretary and shall be used solely for the purpose of the updates described in subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>