<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_356j"><akn:num>356j</akn:num><akn:heading>Discontinuance or interruption in the production of medical devices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 356j. Discontinuance or interruption in the production of medical devices(a) In generalA manufacturer of a device that—(1) is critical to public health during a public health emergency, including devices that are life-supporting, life-sustaining, or intended for use in emergency medical care or during surgery; or

(2) for which the Secretary determines that information on potential meaningful supply disruptions of such device is needed during, or in advance of, a public health emergency;


shall, during, or in advance of, a public health emergency declared by the Secretary under section 247d of title 42, notify the Secretary, in accordance with subsection (b), of a permanent discontinuance in the manufacture of the device (except for discontinuances as a result of an approved modification of the device) or an interruption of the manufacture of the device that is likely to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply of that device in the United States, and the reasons for such discontinuance or interruption.

(b) TimingA notice required under subsection (a) shall be submitted to the Secretary—(1) at least 6 months prior to the date of the discontinuance or interruption; or

(2) if compliance with paragraph (1) is not possible, as soon as practicable.


(c) Distribution(1) Public availabilityTo the maximum extent practicable, subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall distribute, through such means as the Secretary determines appropriate, information on the discontinuance or interruption of the manufacture of devices reported under subsection (a) to appropriate organizations, including physician, health provider, patient organizations, and supply chain partners, as appropriate and applicable, as described in subsection (g).


(2) Public health exceptionThe Secretary may choose not to make information collected under this section publicly available pursuant to this section if the Secretary determines that disclosure of such information would adversely affect the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A manufacturer of a device that— shall, during, or in advance of, a public health emergency declared by the Secretary under section 247d of title 42, notify the Secretary, in accordance with subsection (b), of a permanent discontinuance in the manufacture of the device (except for discontinuances as a result of an approved modification of the device) or an interruption of the manufacture of the device that is likely to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply of that device in the United States, and the reasons for such discontinuance or interruption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Timing A notice required under subsection (a) shall be submitted to the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Confidentiality Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to disclose any information that is a trade secret or confidential information subject to section 552(b)(4) of title 5 or section 1905 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to meet requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Failure to meet requirements If a person fails to submit information required under subsection (a) in accordance with subsection (b)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited inspections and reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expedited inspections and reviews If, based on notifications described in subsection (a) or (h) or any other relevant information, the Secretary concludes that there is, or is likely to be, a shortage of an 11 So in original. Probably should be “a”. device, the Secretary shall, as appropriate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Device shortage list</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Device shortage list</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional notifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Additional notifications The Secretary may receive voluntary notifications from a manufacturer of a device that is life-supporting, life-sustaining, or intended for use in emergency medical care or during surgery, or any other device the Secretary determines to be critical to the public health, pertaining to a permanent discontinuance in the manufacture of the device (except for any discontinuance as a result of an approved modification of the device) or an interruption of the manufacture of the device that is likely to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply of that device in the United States, and the reasons for such discontinuance or interruption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the authority of the Secretary on March 27, 2020, to expedite the review of devices under section 360e of this title, section 360e–3 of this title relating to the priority review program for devices, and section 360bbb–3 of this title relating to the emergency use authorization authorities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356j_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>