<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/356k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_356k"><akn:num>356k</akn:num><akn:heading>Platform technologies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 356k. Platform technologies(a) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program for the designation of platform technologies that meet the criteria described in subsection (b).


(b) CriteriaA platform technology incorporated within or utilized by a drug or biological product is eligible for designation as a designated platform technology under this section if—(1) the platform technology is incorporated in, or utilized by, a drug approved under section 355 of this title or a biological product licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262];

(2) preliminary evidence submitted by the sponsor of the approved or licensed drug described in paragraph (1), or a sponsor that has been granted a right of reference to data submitted in the application for such drug, demonstrates that the platform technology has the potential to be incorporated in, or utilized by, more than one drug without an adverse effect on quality, manufacturing, or safety; and

(3) data or information submitted by the applicable person under paragraph (2) indicates that incorporation or utilization of the platform technology has a reasonable likelihood to bring significant efficiencies to the drug development or manufacturing process and to the review process.


(c) Request for designationA person may request the Secretary designate a platform technology as a designated platform technology concurrently with, or at any time after, submission under section 355(i) of this title or section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262(a)(3)] for the investigation of a drug that incorporates or utilizes the platform technology that is the subject of the request.


(d) Designation(1) In generalNot later than 90 calendar days after the receipt of a request under subsection (c), the Secretary shall determine whether the platform technology that is the subject of the request meets the criteria described in subsection (b).


(2) DesignationIf the Secretary determines tha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall establish a program for the designation of platform technologies that meet the criteria described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria A platform technology incorporated within or utilized by a drug or biological product is eligible for designation as a designated platform technology under this section if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Request for designation A person may request the Secretary designate a platform technology as a designated platform technology concurrently with, or at any time after, submission under section 355(i) of this title or section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262(a)(3)] for the investigation of a drug that incorporates or utilizes the platform technology that is the subject of the request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Designation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356k_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Actions The Secretary may take actions to expedite the development and review of an application for a drug that incorporates or utilizes a designated platform technology, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356k_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leveraging data from designated platform technologies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Leveraging data from designated platform technologies The Secretary shall, consistent with applicable standards for approval, authorization, or licensure under this chapter and section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262(a)], allow the sponsor of an application under section 355(b) of this title or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act or a request for emergency use authorization under section 360bbb–3 of this title, in order to support approval, licensure, or authorization, to reference or rely upon data and information within an application or request for a drug or biological product that incorporates or utilizes the same platform technology designated under subsection (d), provided that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356k_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes to a designated platform technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Changes to a designated platform technology A sponsor of more than one application approved under section 355(b) of this title or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262(a)] for drugs that incorporate or utilize a designated platform technology may submit a single supplemental application for proposed changes to the designated platform technology that may be applicable to more than one such drug that incorporates or utilizes the same designated platform technology. Such supplemental application may cross-reference data and information submitted in other applications and may include one or more comparability protocols regarding how such changes to the platform technology would be made for each applicable drug or biological product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356k_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_356k_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>