<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/357" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/357/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/357/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_357"><akn:num>357</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualification of drug development tools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 357. Qualification of drug development tools(a) Process for qualification(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a process for the qualification of drug development tools for a proposed context of use under which—(A)(i) a requestor initiates such process by submitting a letter of intent to the Secretary; and

(ii) the Secretary accepts or declines to accept such letter of intent;


(B)(i) if the Secretary accepts the letter of intent, a requestor submits a qualification plan to the Secretary; and

(ii) the Secretary accepts or declines to accept the qualification plan; and


(C)(i) if the Secretary accepts the qualification plan, the requestor submits to the Secretary a full qualification package;

(ii) the Secretary determines whether to accept such qualification package for review; and

(iii) if the Secretary accepts such qualification package for review, the Secretary conducts such review in accordance with this section.



(2) Acceptance and review of submissions(A) In generalSubparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) shall apply with respect to the treatment of a letter of intent, a qualification plan, or a full qualification package submitted under paragraph (1) (referred to in this paragraph as “qualification submissions”).


(B) Acceptance factors; nonacceptanceThe Secretary shall determine whether to accept a qualification submission based on factors which may include the scientific merit of the qualification submission. A determination not to accept a submission under paragraph (1) shall not be construed as a final determination by the Secretary under this section regarding the qualification of a drug development tool for its proposed context of use.


(C) Prioritization of qualification reviewThe Secretary may prioritize the review of a full qualification package submitted under paragraph (1) with respect to a drug development tool, based on factors determined appropriate by the Secretary, including—(i) as applicable, the severity, rarity, or prevalence of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_357_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Process for qualification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Process for qualification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_357_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of qualification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effect of qualification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_357_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transparency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transparency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_357_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_357_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>