<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360"><akn:num>360</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of producers of drugs or devices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360. Registration of producers of drugs or devices(a) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) the term “manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing” shall include repackaging or otherwise changing the container, wrapper, or labeling of any drug package or device package in furtherance of the distribution of the drug or device from the original place of manufacture to the person who makes final delivery or sale to the ultimate consumer or user; and

(2) the term “name” shall include in the case of a partnership the name of each partner and, in the case of a corporation, the name of each corporate officer and director, and the State of incorporation.


(b) Annual registration(1) During the period beginning on October 1 and ending on December 31 of each year, every person who owns or operates any establishment in any State engaged in the manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing of a drug or drugs shall register with the Secretary the name of such person, places of business of such person, all such establishments, the unique facility identifier of each such establishment, and a point of contact e-mail address.

(2) During the period beginning on October 1 and ending on December 31 of each year, every person who owns or operates any establishment in any State engaged in the manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing of a device or devices shall register with the Secretary his name, places of business, and all such establishments.

(3) The Secretary shall specify the unique facility identifier system that shall be used by registrants under paragraph (1). The requirement to include a unique facility identifier in a registration under paragraph (1) shall not apply until the date that the identifier system is specified by the Secretary under the preceding sentence.


(c) New producersEvery person upon first engaging in the manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing of a drug or drug</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual registration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>New producers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) New producers Every person upon first engaging in the manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing of a drug or drugs or a device or devices in any establishment which he owns or operates in any State shall immediately register with the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional establishments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional establishments Every person duly registered in accordance with the foregoing subsections of this section shall immediately register with the Secretary any additional establishment which he owns or operates in any State and in which he begins the manufacture, preparation, propagation, compounding, or processing of a drug or drugs or a device or devices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration number; uniform system for identification of devices intended for human use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Registration number; uniform system for identification of devices intended for human use The Secretary may assign a registration number to any person or any establishment registered in accordance with this section. The Secretary may also assign a listing number to each drug or class of drugs listed under subsection (j). Any number assigned pursuant to the preceding sentence shall be the same as that assigned pursuant to the National Drug Code. The Secretary may by regulation prescribe a uniform system for the identification of devices intended for human use and may require that persons who are required to list such devices pursuant to subsection (j) shall list such devices in accordance with such system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of registrations for inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Availability of registrations for inspection The Secretary shall make available for inspection, to any person so requesting, any registration filed pursuant to this section; except that any list submitted pursuant to paragraph (3) of subsection (j) and the information accompanying any list or notice filed under paragraph (1) or (2) of that subsection shall be exempt from such inspection unless the Secretary finds that such an exemption would be inconsistent with protection of the public health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions from application of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exclusions from application of section The foregoing subsections of this section shall not apply to— In this subsection, the term “wholesale distributor” means any person (other than the manufacturer or the initial importer) who distributes a device from the original place of manufacture to the person who makes the final delivery or sale of the device to the ultimate consumer or user.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Inspections</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of foreign establishments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Registration of foreign establishments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of lists of drugs and devices manufactured, prepared, propagated and compounded by registrants; statements; accompanying disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Filing of lists of drugs and devices manufactured, prepared, propagated and compounded by registrants; statements; accompanying disclosures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>