<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360bbb_3"><akn:num>360bbb–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for medical products for use in emergencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360bbb–3. Authorization for medical products for use in emergencies(a) In general(1) Emergency usesNotwithstanding any provision of this chapter and section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262], and subject to the provisions of this section, the Secretary may authorize the introduction into interstate commerce, during the effective period of a declaration under subsection (b), of a drug, device, or biological product intended for use in an actual or potential emergency (referred to in this section as an “emergency use”).


(2) Approval status of productAn authorization under paragraph (1) may authorize an emergency use of a product that—(A) is not approved, licensed, or cleared for commercial distribution under section 355, 360(k), 360b, or 360e of this title or section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262] or conditionally approved under section 360ccc of this title (referred to in this section as an “unapproved product”); or

(B) is approved, conditionally approved under section 360ccc of this title, licensed, or cleared under such a provision, but which use is not under such provision an approved, conditionally approved under section 360ccc of this title, licensed, or cleared use of the product (referred to in this section as an “unapproved use of an approved product”).


(3) Relation to other usesAn emergency use authorized under paragraph (1) for a product is in addition to any other use that is authorized for the product under a section of this chapter or the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.] referred to in paragraph (2)(A).


(4) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(A) The term “biological product” has the meaning given such term in section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262].

(B) The term “emergency use” has the meaning indicated for such term in paragraph (1).

(C) The term “product” means a drug, device, or biological product.

(D) The term “unapproved product” has the meaning indicated</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of emergency or threat justifying emergency authorized use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Declaration of emergency or threat justifying emergency authorized use</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for issuance of authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria for issuance of authorization The Secretary may issue an authorization under this section with respect to the emergency use of a product only if, after consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, the Director of the National Institutes of Health, and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (to the extent feasible and appropriate given the applicable circumstances described in subsection (b)(1)), the Secretary concludes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Scope of authorization An authorization of a product under this section shall state—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conditions of authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Duration of authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and revocation of authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Review and revocation of authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication; confidential information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Publication; confidential information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions committed to agency discretion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Actions committed to agency discretion Actions under the authority of this section by the Secretary, by the Secretary of Defense, or by the Secretary of Homeland Security are committed to agency discretion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Rules of construction The following applies with respect to this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>