<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–0" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–0/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–0/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360bbb_0"><akn:num>360bbb–0</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanded access policy required for investigational drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360bbb–0. Expanded access policy required for investigational drugs(a) In generalThe manufacturer or distributor of one or more investigational drugs for the diagnosis, monitoring, or treatment of one or more serious diseases or conditions shall make available the policy of the manufacturer or distributor on evaluating and responding to requests submitted under section 360bbb(b) of this title for provision of such a drug.


(b) Public availability of expanded access policyThe policies under subsection (a) shall be made public and readily available, such as by posting such policies on a publicly available Internet website. Such policies may be generally applicable to all investigational drugs of such manufacturer or distributor.


(c) Content of policyA policy described in subsection (a) shall include—(1) contact information for the manufacturer or distributor to facilitate communication about requests described in subsection (a);

(2) procedures for making such requests;

(3) the general criteria the manufacturer or distributor will use to evaluate such requests for individual patients, and for responses to such requests;

(4) the length of time the manufacturer or distributor anticipates will be necessary to acknowledge receipt of such requests; and

(5) a hyperlink or other reference to the clinical trial record containing information about the expanded access for such drug that is required under section 282(j)(2)(A)(ii)(II)(gg) of title 42.


(d) No guarantee of accessThe posting of policies by manufacturers and distributors under subsection (a) shall not serve as a guarantee of access to any specific investigational drug by any individual patient.


(e) Revised policyNothing in this section shall prevent a manufacturer or distributor from revising a policy required under this section at any time.


(f) ApplicationThis section shall apply to a manufacturer or distributor with respect to an investigational drug beginning on the earlier of—(1) the first initiatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The manufacturer or distributor of one or more investigational drugs for the diagnosis, monitoring, or treatment of one or more serious diseases or conditions shall make available the policy of the manufacturer or distributor on evaluating and responding to requests submitted under section 360bbb(b) of this title for provision of such a drug.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public availability of expanded access policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public availability of expanded access policy The policies under subsection (a) shall be made public and readily available, such as by posting such policies on a publicly available Internet website. Such policies may be generally applicable to all investigational drugs of such manufacturer or distributor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Content of policy A policy described in subsection (a) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No guarantee of access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No guarantee of access The posting of policies by manufacturers and distributors under subsection (a) shall not serve as a guarantee of access to any specific investigational drug by any individual patient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revised policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Revised policy Nothing in this section shall prevent a manufacturer or distributor from revising a policy required under this section at any time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application This section shall apply to a manufacturer or distributor with respect to an investigational drug beginning on the earlier of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>