<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–3a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–3a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–3a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360bbb_3a"><akn:num>360bbb–3a</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency use of medical products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360bbb–3a. Emergency use of medical products(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible productThe term “eligible product” means a product that—(A) is approved or cleared under this subchapter, conditionally approved under section 360ccc of this title, or licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262];

(B)(i) is intended for use to prevent, diagnose, or treat a disease or condition involving a biological, chemical, radiological, or nuclear agent or agents; or

(ii) is intended for use to prevent, diagnose, or treat a serious or life-threatening disease or condition caused by a product described in clause (i); and


(C) is intended for use during the circumstances under which—(i) a determination described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 360bbb–3(b)(1) of this title has been made by the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense, or the Secretary, respectively; or

(ii) the identification of a material threat described in subparagraph (D) of section 360bbb–3(b)(1) of this title has been made pursuant to section 319F–2 of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 247d–6b].



(2) ProductThe term “product” means a drug, device, or biological product.



(b) Expiration dating(1) In generalThe Secretary may extend the expiration date and authorize the introduction or delivery for introduction into interstate commerce of an eligible product after the expiration date provided by the manufacturer if—(A) the expiration date extension is intended to support the United States ability to protect—(i) the public health; or

(ii) military preparedness and effectiveness; and


(B) the expiration date extension is supported by an appropriate scientific evaluation that is conducted or accepted by the Secretary.


(2) Requirements and conditionsAny extension of an expiration date under paragraph (1) shall, as part of the extension, identify—(A) each specific lot, batch, or other unit of the product for which extended expiration i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration dating</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expiration dating</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Current good manufacturing practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Current good manufacturing practice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency dispensing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Emergency dispensing The requirements of subsections (b) and (f) of section 353, section 354, and section 360j(e) of this title shall not apply to an eligible product, and the product shall not be considered an unapproved product (as defined in section 360bbb–3(a)(2)(A) of this title) and shall not be deemed adulterated or misbranded under this chapter because it is dispensed without an individual prescription, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_3a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency use instructions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Emergency use instructions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>