<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–0a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–0a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–0a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360bbb_0a"><akn:num>360bbb–0a</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigational drugs for use by eligible patients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360bbb–0a. Investigational drugs for use by eligible patients(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) the term “eligible patient” means a patient—(A) who has been diagnosed with a life-threatening disease or condition (as defined in section 312.81 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations));

(B) who has exhausted approved treatment options and is unable to participate in a clinical trial involving the eligible investigational drug, as certified by a physician, who—(i) is in good standing with the physician’s licensing organization or board; and

(ii) will not be compensated directly by the manufacturer for so certifying; and


(C) who has provided to the treating physician written informed consent regarding the eligible investigational drug, or, as applicable, on whose behalf a legally authorized representative of the patient has provided such consent;


(2) the term “eligible investigational drug” means an investigational drug (as such term is used in section 360bbb of this title)—(A) for which a Phase 1 clinical trial has been completed;

(B) that has not been approved or licensed for any use under section 355 of this title or section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262];

(C)(i) for which an application has been filed under section 355(b) of this title or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262(a)]; or

(ii) that is under investigation in a clinical trial that—(I) is intended to form the primary basis of a claim of effectiveness in support of approval or licensure under section 355 of this title or section 351 of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262]; and

(II) is the subject of an active investigational new drug application under section 355(i) of this title or section 351(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262(a)(3)], as applicable; and



(D) the active development or production of which is ongoing and has not been discontinued by the manufacturer or placed on </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exemptions Eligible investigational drugs provided to eligible patients in compliance with this section are exempt from sections 352(f), 353(b)(4), 355(a), and 355(i) of this title, section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262(a)], and parts 50, 56, and 312 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), provided that the sponsor of such eligible investigational drug or any person who manufactures, distributes, prescribes, dispenses, introduces or delivers for introduction into interstate commerce, or provides to an eligible patient an eligible investigational drug pursuant to this section is in compliance with the applicable requirements set forth in sections 312.6, 312.7, and 312.8(d)(1) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations) that apply to investigational drugs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of clinical outcomes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of clinical outcomes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_0a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>