<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–4b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–4b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360bbb–4b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360bbb_4b"><akn:num>360bbb–4b</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical countermeasure master files</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360bbb–4b. Medical countermeasure master files(a) Applicability of reference(1) In generalA person may submit data and information in a master file to the Secretary with the intent to reference, or to authorize, in writing, another person to reference, such data or information to support a medical countermeasure submission (including a supplement or amendment to any such submission), without requiring the master file holder to disclose the data and information to any such persons authorized to reference the master file. Such data and information shall be available for reference by the master file holder or by a person authorized by the master file holder, in accordance with applicable privacy and confidentiality protocols and regulations.


(2) Reference of certain master filesIn the case that data or information within a medical countermeasure master file is used only to support the conditional approval of an application filed under section 360ccc of this title, such master file may be relied upon to support the effectiveness of a product that is the subject of a subsequent medical countermeasure submission only if such application is supplemented by additional data or information to support review and approval in a manner consistent with the standards applicable to such review and approval for such countermeasure, qualified countermeasure, or qualified pandemic or epidemic product.



(b) Medical countermeasure master file content(1) In generalA master file under this section may include data or information to support—(A) the development of medical countermeasure submissions to support the approval, licensure, classification, clearance, conditional approval, or authorization of one or more security countermeasures, qualified countermeasures, or qualified pandemic or epidemic products; and

(B) the manufacture of security countermeasures, qualified countermeasures, or qualified pandemic or epidemic products.


(2) Required updatesThe Secretary may require, as app</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_4b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability of reference</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_4b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical countermeasure master file content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Medical countermeasure master file content</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_4b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sponsor reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sponsor reference</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_4b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acknowledgment of and reliance upon a master file by the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acknowledgment of and reliance upon a master file by the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_4b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rules of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360bbb_4b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>