<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360ccc" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360ccc/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360ccc/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360ccc"><akn:num>360ccc</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditional approval of new animal drugs for minor use and minor species and certain new animal drug</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360ccc. Conditional approval of new animal drugs for minor use and minor species and certain new animal drugs(a) Application requirements(1)(A) Except as provided in paragraph (3), any person may file with the Secretary an application for conditional approval of—(i) a new animal drug intended for a minor use or a minor species; or

(ii) a new animal drug not intended for a minor use or minor species—(I) that is intended to treat a serious or life-threatening disease or condition or addresses an unmet animal or human health need; and

(II) for which the Secretary determines that a demonstration of effectiveness would require a complex or particularly difficult study or studies.



(B) The Secretary shall, not later than September 30, 2019, issue guidance or regulations further clarifying the criteria specified in subparagraph (A)(ii).

(C) An application under this paragraph shall comply in all respects with the provisions of section 360b of this title except for subsections (a)(4), (b)(2), (c)(1), (c)(2), (c)(3), (d)(1), (e), (h), and (n) of such section unless otherwise stated in this section, and any additional provisions of this section.

(D) New animal drugs for which conditional approval is sought under this section are subject to the same safety standards that would be applied to new animal drugs under section 360b(d) of this title (including, for antimicrobial new animal drugs, with respect to antimicrobial resistance).


(2) The applicant shall submit to the Secretary as part of an application for the conditional approval of a new animal drug—(A) all information necessary to meet the requirements of section 360b(b)(1) of this title except section 360b(b)(1)(A) of this title;

(B) full reports of investigations which have been made to show whether or not such drug is safe under section 360b(d) of this title (including, for an antimicrobial new animal drug, with respect to antimicrobial resistance) and there is a reasonable expectation of effectiveness for u</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of approval or hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Order of approval or hearing Within 180 days after the filing of an application pursuant to subsection (a), or such additional period as may be agreed upon by the Secretary and the applicant, the Secretary shall either—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of approval or refusal after hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Order of approval or refusal after hearing If the Secretary finds, after giving the applicant notice and an opportunity for an informal hearing, that— the Secretary shall issue an order refusing to conditionally approve the application. If, after such notice and opportunity for an informal hearing, the Secretary finds that paragraphs (1) through (3) do not apply, the Secretary shall issue an order conditionally approving the application effective for one year and publish a Federal Register notice of the conditional approval. Any order issued under this subsection refusing to conditionally approve an application shall state the findings upon which it is based.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective period; renewal; refusal of renewal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effective period; renewal; refusal of renewal A conditional approval under this section is effective for a 1-year period and is thereafter renewable by the Secretary annually for up to 4 additional 1-year terms. A conditional approval shall be in effect for no more than 5 years from the date of approval under subsection (b)(1) or (c) of this section unless extended as provided for in subsection (h) of this section. The following shall also apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of conditional approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Withdrawal of conditional approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Labeling</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Amendment of application A conditionally approved new animal drug application may not be amended or supplemented to add indications for use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of approval after conditional approval period termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Order of approval after conditional approval period termination 180 days prior to the termination date established under subsection (d) of this section, an applicant shall have submitted all the information necessary to support a complete new animal drug application in accordance with section 360b(b)(1) of this title or the conditional approval issued under this section is no longer in effect. Following review of this information, the Secretary shall either— Upon issuance of an order approving the application, product labeling and administrative records of approval shall be modified accordingly. If the Secretary has not issued an order under section 360b(c) of this title approving such application prior to the termination date established under subsection (d) of this section, the conditional approval issued under this section is no longer in effect unless the Secretary grants an extension of an additional 180-day period so that the Secretary can complete review of the application. </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Judicial review The decision of the Secretary under subsection (c), (d), or (e) of this section refusing or withdrawing conditional approval of an application shall constitute final agency action subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definition In this section and section 360ccc–1 of this title, the term “transgenic animal” means an animal whose genome contains a nucleotide sequence that has been intentionally modified in vitro, and the progeny of such an animal; Provided that the term “transgenic animal” does not include an animal of which the nucleotide sequence of the genome has been modified solely by selective breeding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>