<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360cc" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360cc/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360cc/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360cc"><akn:num>360cc</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection for drugs for rare diseases or conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360cc. Protection for drugs for rare diseases or conditions(a) Exclusive approval, certification, or licenseExcept as provided in subsection (b), if the Secretary—(1) approves an application filed pursuant to section 355 of this title, or

(2) issues a license under section 262 of title 42


for a drug designated under section 360bb of this title for a rare disease or condition, the Secretary may not approve another application under section 355 of this title or issue another license under section 262 of title 42 for the same drug for the same disease or condition for a person who is not the holder of such approved application or of such license until the expiration of seven years from the date of the approval of the approved application or the issuance of the license. Section 355(c)(2) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title does not apply to the refusal to approve an application under the preceding sentence.

(b) ExceptionsDuring the 7-year period described in subsection (a) for an approved application under section 355 of this title or license under section 262 of title 42, the Secretary may approve an application or issue a license for a drug that is otherwise the same, as determined by the Secretary, as the already approved drug for the same rare disease or condition if—(1) the Secretary finds, after providing the holder of exclusive approval or licensure notice and opportunity for the submission of views, that during such period the holder of the exclusive approval or licensure cannot ensure the availability of sufficient quantities of the drug to meet the needs of persons with the disease or condition for which the drug was designated; or

(2) the holder provides the Secretary in writing the consent of such holder for the approval of other applications or the issuance of other licenses before the expiration of such seven-year period.


(c) Condition of clinical superiority(1) In generalIf a sponsor of a drug that is designated under section 360b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360cc_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive approval, certification, or license</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Exclusive approval, certification, or license Except as provided in subsection (b), if the Secretary— for a drug designated under section 360bb of this title for a rare disease or condition, the Secretary may not approve another application under section 355 of this title or issue another license under section 262 of title 42 for the same drug for the same disease or condition for a person who is not the holder of such approved application or of such license until the expiration of seven years from the date of the approval of the approved application or the issuance of the license. Section 355(c)(2) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title does not apply to the refusal to approve an application under the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360cc_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions During the 7-year period described in subsection (a) for an approved application under section 355 of this title or license under section 262 of title 42, the Secretary may approve an application or issue a license for a drug that is otherwise the same, as determined by the Secretary, as the already approved drug for the same rare disease or condition if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360cc_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Condition of clinical superiority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Condition of clinical superiority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360cc_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations The Secretary may promulgate regulations for the implementation of subsection (c). Beginning on August 18, 2017, until such time as the Secretary promulgates regulations in accordance with this subsection, the Secretary may apply any definitions set forth in regulations that were promulgated prior to such date, to the extent such definitions are not inconsistent with the terms of this section, as amended by such Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360cc_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration of clinical superiority standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Demonstration of clinical superiority standard To assist sponsors in demonstrating clinical superiority as described in subsection (c), the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>