<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360ccc–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360ccc–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360ccc–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360ccc_1"><akn:num>360ccc–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Index of legally marketed unapproved new animal drugs for minor species</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360ccc–1. Index of legally marketed unapproved new animal drugs for minor species(a) Establishment and content(1) The Secretary shall establish an index limited to—(A) new animal drugs intended for use in a minor species for which there is a reasonable certainty that the animal or edible products from the animal will not be consumed by humans or food-producing animals; and

(B) new animal drugs intended for use only in a hatchery, tank, pond, or other similar contained man-made structure in an early, non-food life stage of a food-producing minor species, where safety for humans is demonstrated in accordance with the standard of section 360b(d) of this title (including, for an antimicrobial new animal drug, with respect to antimicrobial resistance).


(2) The index shall not include a new animal drug that is contained in or a product of a transgenic animal.


(b) ConferencesAny person intending to file a request under this section shall be entitled to one or more conferences to discuss the requirements for indexing a new animal drug.


(c) Request for determination of eligibility for inclusion in index(1) Any person may submit a request to the Secretary for a determination whether a new animal drug may be eligible for inclusion in the index. Such a request shall include—(A) information regarding the need for the new animal drug, the species for which the new animal drug is intended, the proposed intended use and conditions of use, and anticipated annual distribution;

(B) information to support the conclusion that the proposed use meets the conditions of subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) of this section;

(C) information regarding the components and composition of the new animal drug;

(D) a description of the methods used in, and the facilities and controls used for, the manufacture, processing, and packing of such new animal drug;

(E) an environmental assessment that meets the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 [42 U.S.C. 43</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and content</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conferences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conferences Any person intending to file a request under this section shall be entitled to one or more conferences to discuss the requirements for indexing a new animal drug.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for determination of eligibility for inclusion in index</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Request for determination of eligibility for inclusion in index</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for addition to index</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Request for addition to index</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Index contents; publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Index contents; publication</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal from index; suspended listing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Removal from index; suspended listing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations concerning exemptions for investigational use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations concerning exemptions for investigational use For purposes of indexing new animal drugs under this section, to the extent consistent with the public health, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations for exempting from the operation of section 360b of this title minor species new animal drugs and animal feeds bearing or containing new animal drugs intended solely for investigational use by experts qualified by scientific training and experience to investigate the safety and effectiveness of minor species animal drugs. Such regulations may, at the discretion of the Secretary, among other conditions relating to the protection of the public health, provide for conditioning such exemption upon the establishment and maintenance of such records, and the making of such reports to the Secretary, by the manufacturer or the sponsor of the investigation of such article, of data (including but not limited to analytical reports by investigators) obtained as a result of such investig</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Labeling contents The labeling of a new animal drug that is the subject of an index listing shall state, prominently and conspicuously—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Records and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ccc_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public disclosure of safety and effectiveness data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Public disclosure of safety and effectiveness data</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>