<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360ff" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360ff/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360ff/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360ff"><akn:num>360ff</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority review to encourage treatments for rare pediatric diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360ff. Priority review to encourage treatments for rare pediatric diseases(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Priority reviewThe term “priority review”, with respect to a human drug application as defined in section 379g(1) of this title, means review and action by the Secretary on such application not later than 6 months after receipt by the Secretary of such application, as described in the Manual of Policies and Procedures of the Food and Drug Administration and goals identified in the letters described in section 101(b) of the Prescription Drug User Fee Amendments of 2012.


(2) Priority review voucherThe term “priority review voucher” means a voucher issued by the Secretary to the sponsor of a rare pediatric disease product application that entitles the holder of such voucher to priority review of a single human drug application submitted under section 355(b)(1) of this title or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262(a)] after the date of approval of the rare pediatric disease product application.


(3) Rare pediatric diseaseThe term “rare pediatric disease” means a disease that meets each of the following criteria:(A) The disease is a serious or life-threatening disease in which the serious or life-threatening manifestations primarily affect individuals aged from birth to 18 years, including age groups often called neonates, infants, children, and adolescents.

(B) The disease is a rare disease or condition, within the meaning of section 360bb of this title.


(4) Rare pediatric disease product applicationThe term “rare pediatric disease product application” means a human drug application, as defined in section 379g(1) of this title, that—(A) is for a drug or biological product that is for the prevention or treatment of a rare pediatric disease;

(B)(i) is for such a drug—(I) that contains no active moiety (as defined by the Secretary in section 314.3 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations)) that has bee</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ff_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ff_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority review voucher</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority review voucher</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ff_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority review user fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority review user fee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ff_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Designation process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ff_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marketing of rare pediatric disease products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Marketing of rare pediatric disease products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ff_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notice and report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ff_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Eligibility for other programs Nothing in this section precludes a sponsor who seeks a priority review voucher under this section from participating in any other incentive program, including under this chapter, except that no sponsor of a rare pediatric disease product application may receive more than one priority review voucher issued under any section of this chapter with respect to the drug for which the application is made..33 So in original.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ff_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Relation to other provisions The provisions of this section shall supplement, not supplant, any other provisions of this chapter or the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.] that encourage the development of drugs for tropical diseases and rare pediatric diseases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360ff_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO study and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) GAO study and report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>