<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360fff–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360fff–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360fff–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360fff_4"><akn:num>360fff–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance; other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360fff–4. Guidance; other provisions(a) Guidance(1) In general(A) Draft guidanceNot later than 1 year after November 26, 2014, the Secretary shall issue draft guidance on the implementation of, and compliance with, the requirements with respect to sunscreen under this part, including guidance on—(i) the format and content of information submitted by a sponsor in support of a request under section 360fff–1 of this title or a pending request;

(ii) the data required to meet the safety and efficacy standard for determining whether a nonprescription sunscreen active ingredient or combination of nonprescription sunscreen active ingredients is GRASE and is not misbranded;

(iii) the process by which a request under section 360fff–1 of this title or a pending request is withdrawn; and

(iv) the process by which the Secretary will carry out section 360fff–3(c) of this title, including with respect to how the Secretary will address the total number of requests received under section 360fff–1 of this title and pending requests.


(B) Final guidanceThe Secretary shall finalize the guidance described in subparagraph (A) not later than 2 years after November 26, 2014.


(C) Inapplicability of Paperwork Reduction ActChapter 35 of title 44 shall not apply to collections of information made for purposes of guidance under this subsection.



(2) Submissions pending issuance of final guidanceIrrespective of whether final guidance under paragraph (1) has been issued—(A) persons may, beginning on November 26, 2014, make submissions under this part; and

(B) the Secretary shall review and act upon such submissions in accordance with this part.



(b) Rules of construction(1) Currently marketed sunscreensNothing in this part shall be construed to affect the marketing of sunscreens that are marketed in interstate commerce on or before November 26, 2014, except as otherwise provided in this part.


(2) Ensuring safety and effectivenessNothing in this part shall be construed to alter the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360fff_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Guidance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360fff_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rules of construction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360fff_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Timelines The timelines for the processes and procedures under paragraphs (1), (2), (5), and (6) of section 360fff–3(a) of this title shall not apply to any requests submitted to the Secretary under section 360fff–1 of this title after the date that is 6 years after November 26, 2014.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>