<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360i"><akn:num>360i</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and reports on devices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360i. Records and reports on devices(a) General ruleEvery person who is a manufacturer or importer of a device intended for human use shall establish and maintain such records, make such reports, and provide such information, as the Secretary may by regulation reasonably require to assure that such device is not adulterated or misbranded and to otherwise assure its safety and effectiveness. Regulations prescribed under the preceding sentence—(1) shall require a device manufacturer or importer to report to the Secretary whenever the manufacturer or importer receives or otherwise becomes aware of information that reasonably suggests that one of its marketed devices—(A) may have caused or contributed to a death or serious injury, or

(B) has malfunctioned and that such device or a similar device marketed by the manufacturer or importer would be likely to cause or contribute to a death or serious injury if the malfunction were to recur, which report under this subparagraph—(i) shall be submitted in accordance with part 803 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), unless the Secretary grants an exemption or variance from, or an alternative to, a requirement under such regulations pursuant to section 803.19 of such part, if the device involved is—(I) a class III device;

(II) a class II device that is permanently implantable, is life supporting, or is life sustaining; or

(III) a type of device which the Secretary has, by notice published in the Federal Register or letter to the person who is the manufacturer or importer of the device, indicated should be subject to such part 803 in order to protect the public health;


(ii) shall, if the device is not subject to clause (i), be submitted in accordance with criteria established by the Secretary for reports made pursuant to this clause, which criteria shall require the reports to be in summary form and made on a quarterly basis; or

(iii) shall, if the device is imported into the United States </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Every person who is a manufacturer or importer of a device intended for human use shall establish and maintain such records, make such reports, and provide such information, as the Secretary may by regulation reasonably require to assure that such device is not adulterated or misbranded and to otherwise assure its safety and effectiveness. Regulations prescribed under the preceding sentence— In prescribing such regulations, the Secretary shall have due regard for the professional ethics of the medical profession and the interests of patients. The prohibitions of paragraph (7) of this subsection continue to apply to rec­ords, reports, and information concerning any individual who has been a patient, irrespective of whether or when he ceases to be a patient. The Secretary shall by regulation require distributors to keep records and make such records available to the Secretary upon request. Paragraphs (4) and (8) apply to distributors to the same extent and in the same ma</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>User reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) User reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons exempt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Persons exempt Subsection (a) shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 105–115, title II, § 213(a)(2), Nov. 21, 1997, 111 Stat. 2347</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360i_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Device tracking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Device tracking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360i_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unique device identification system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Unique device identification system Not later than December 31, 2012, the Secretary shall issue proposed regulations establishing a unique device identification system for medical devices requiring the label of devices to bear a unique identifier, unless the Secretary requires an alternative placement or provides an exception for a particular device or type of device. The unique identifier shall adequately identify the device through distribution and use, and may include information on the lot or serial number. The Secretary shall finalize the proposed regulations not later than 6 months after the close of the comment period and shall implement the final regulations with respect to devices that are implantable, life-saving, or life sustaining not later than 2 years after the regulations are finalized, taking into account patient access to medical devices and therapies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360i_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports of removals and corrections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports of removals and corrections</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360i_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of devices in the postmarket risk identification and analysis system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Inclusion of devices in the postmarket risk identification and analysis system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360i_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Postmarket pilot</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Postmarket pilot</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>