<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360kk" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360kk/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360kk/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360kk"><akn:num>360kk</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance standards for electronic products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360kk. Performance standards for electronic products(a) Promulgation of regulations(1) The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe performance standards for electronic products to control the emission of electronic product radiation from such products if he determines that such standards are necessary for the protection of the public health and safety. Such standards may include provisions for the testing of such products and the measurement of their electronic product radiation emissions, may require the attachment of warning signs and labels, and may require the provision of instructions for the installation, operation, and use of such products. Such standards may be prescribed from time to time whenever such determinations are made, but the first of such standards shall be prescribed prior to January 1, 1970. In the development of such standards, the Secretary shall consult with Federal and State departments and agencies having related responsibilities or interests and with appropriate professional organizations and interested persons, including representatives of industries and labor organizations which would be affected by such standards, and shall give consideration to—(A) the latest available scientific and medical data in the field of electronic product radiation;

(B) the standards currently recommended by (i) other Federal agencies having responsibilities relating to the control and measurement of electronic product radiation, and (ii) public or private groups having an expertise in the field of electronic product radiation;

(C) the reasonableness and technical feasibility of such standards as applied to a particular electronic product;

(D) the adaptability of such standards to the need for uniformity and reliability of testing and measuring procedures and equipment; and

(E) in the case of a component, or accessory described in paragraph (2)(B) of section 360hh of this title, the performance of such article in the manufactured or assembled product for</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360kk_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Promulgation of regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360kk_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrative procedure The provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 (relating to the administrative procedure for rulemaking), and of chapter 7 of title 5 (relating to judicial review), shall apply with respect to any regulation prescribing, amending, or revoking any standard prescribed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360kk_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Publication in Federal Register Each regulation prescribing, amending, or revoking a standard shall specify the date on which it shall take effect which, in the case of any regulation prescribing, or amending any standard, may not be sooner than one year or not later than two years after the date on which such regulation is issued, unless the Secretary finds, for good cause shown, that an earlier or later effective date is in the public interest and publishes in the Federal Register his reason for such finding, in which case such earlier or later date shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360kk_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360kk_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of record</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability of record A certified copy of the transcript of the record and administrative proceedings under this section shall be furnished by the Secretary to any interested party at his request, and payment of the costs thereof, and shall be admissible in any criminal, exclusion of imports, or other proceeding arising under or in respect of this part irrespective of whether proceedings with respect to the regulation have previously been initiated or become final under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360kk_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Electronic Product Radiation Safety Standards Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Technical Electronic Product Radiation Safety Standards Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360kk_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Review and evaluation The Secretary shall review and evaluate on a continuing basis testing programs carried out by industry to assure the adequacy of safeguards against hazardous electronic product radiation and to assure that electronic products comply with standards prescribed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360kk_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Product certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Product certification Every manufacturer of an electronic product to which is applicable a standard in effect under this section shall furnish to the distributor or dealer at the time of delivery of such product, in the form of a label or tag permanently affixed to such product or in such manner as approved by the Secretary, the certification that such product conforms to all applicable standards under this section. Such certification shall be based upon a test, in accordance with such standard, of the individual article to which it is attached or upon a testing program which is in accord with good manufacturing practice and which has not been disapproved by the Secretary (in such manner as he shall prescribe by regulation) on the grounds that it does not assure the adequacy of safeguards against hazardous electronic product radiation or that it does not assure that electronic products comply with the standards prescribed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>