<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360oo" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360oo/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/360oo/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_360oo"><akn:num>360oo</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 360oo. Prohibited acts(a) It shall be unlawful—(1) for any manufacturer to introduce, or to deliver for introduction, into commerce, or to import into the United States, any electronic product which does not comply with an applicable standard prescribed pursuant to section 360kk of this title;

(2) for any person to fail to furnish any notification or other material or information required by section 360ll or 360nn of this title; or to fail to comply with the requirements of section 360ll(f) of this title;

(3) for any person to fail or to refuse to establish or maintain records required by this part or to permit access by the Secretary or any of his duly authorized representatives to, or the copying of, such records, or to permit entry or inspection, as required by or pursuant to section 360nn of this title;

(4) for any person to fail or to refuse to make any report required pursuant to section 360nn(b) of this title or to furnish or preserve any information required pursuant to section 360nn(f) of this title; or

(5) for any person (A) to fail to issue a certification as required by section 360kk(h) of this title, or (B) to issue such a certification when such certification is not based upon a test or testing program meeting the requirements of section 360kk(h) of this title or when the issuer, in the exercise of due care, would have reason to know that such certification is false or misleading in a material respect.


(b) The Secretary may exempt any electronic product, or class thereof, from all or part of subsection (a), upon such conditions as he may find necessary to protect the public health or welfare, for the purpose of research, investigations, studies, demonstrations, or training, or for reasons of national security.

(June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 538, formerly act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III, § 538, formerly § 360B, as added Pub. L. 90–602, § 2(3), Oct. 18, 1968, 82 Stat. 1184; renumbered § 538 and amended Pub. L. 101–629, § 19(a)(1)(B), (2)(F), (3</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360oo_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) It shall be unlawful—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_360oo_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may exempt any electronic product, or class thereof, from all or part of subsection (a), upon such conditions as he may find necessary to protect the public health or welfare, for the purpose of research, investigations, studies, demonstrations, or training, or for reasons of national security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>