<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_364a"><akn:num>364a</akn:num><akn:heading>Adverse events</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 364a. Adverse events(a) Serious adverse event reporting requirementsThe responsible person shall submit to the Secretary any report received of a serious adverse event associated with the use, in the United States, of a cosmetic product manufactured, packed, or distributed by such person.


(b) Submission of reports(1) Serious adverse event reportThe responsible person shall submit to the Secretary a serious adverse event report accompanied by a copy of the label on or within the retail packaging of such cosmetic product no later than 15 business days after the report is received by the responsible person.


(2) New medical informationThe responsible person shall submit to the Secretary any new and material medical information, related to a serious adverse event report submitted to the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (1), that is received by the responsible person within 1 year of the initial report to the Secretary, no later than 15 business days after such information is received by such responsible person.


(3) Consolidation of reportsThe Secretary shall develop systems to enable responsible persons to submit a single report that includes duplicate reports of, or new medical information related to, a serious adverse event.



(c) ExemptionsThe Secretary may establish by regulation an exemption to any of the requirements of this section if the Secretary determines that such exemption would have no significant adverse effect on public health.


(d) Contact informationThe responsible person shall receive reports of adverse events through the domestic address, domestic telephone number, or electronic contact information included on the label in accordance with section 364e(a) of this title.


(e) Maintenance and inspection of adverse event records(1) MaintenanceThe responsible person shall maintain records related to each report of an adverse event associated with the use, in the United States, of a cosmetic product manufactured or distributed by such perso</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Serious adverse event reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Serious adverse event reporting requirements The responsible person shall submit to the Secretary any report received of a serious adverse event associated with the use, in the United States, of a cosmetic product manufactured, packed, or distributed by such person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submission of reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exemptions The Secretary may establish by regulation an exemption to any of the requirements of this section if the Secretary determines that such exemption would have no significant adverse effect on public health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contact information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contact information The responsible person shall receive reports of adverse events through the domestic address, domestic telephone number, or electronic contact information included on the label in accordance with section 364e(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance and inspection of adverse event records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Maintenance and inspection of adverse event records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fragrance and flavor ingredients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fragrance and flavor ingredients If the Secretary has reasonable grounds to believe that an ingredient or combination of ingredients in a fragrance or flavor has caused or contributed to a serious adverse event required to be reported under this section, the Secretary may request in writing a list of such ingredients or categories of ingredients in the specific fragrances or flavors in the cosmetic product, from the responsible person. The responsible person shall ensure that the requested information is submitted to the Secretary within 30 days of such request. In response to a request under section 552 of title 5, information submitted to the Secretary under this subsection shall be withheld under section 552(b)(3) of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protected information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Protected information A serious adverse event report submitted to the Secretary under this section, including any new medical information submitted under subsection (b)(2), or an adverse event report, or any new information, voluntarily submitted to the Secretary shall be considered to be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effect of section</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>