<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_364c"><akn:num>364c</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration and product listing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 364c. Registration and product listing(a) Submission of registration(1) Initial registration(A) Existing facilitiesEvery person that, on December 29, 2022, owns or operates a facility that engages in the manufacturing or processing of a cosmetic product for distribution in the United States shall register each facility with the Secretary not later than 1 year after December 29, 2022.


(B) New facilitiesEvery person that owns or operates a facility that first engages, after December 29, 2022, in manufacturing or processing of a cosmetic product for distribution in the United States, shall register with the Secretary such facility within 60 days of first engaging in such activity or 60 days after the deadline for registration under subparagraph (A), whichever is later.



(2) Biennial renewal of registrationA person required to register a facility under paragraph (1) shall renew such registrations with the Secretary biennially.


(3) Contract manufacturersIf a facility manufactures or processes cosmetic products on behalf of a responsible person, the Secretary shall require only a single registration for such facility even if such facility is manufacturing or processing its own cosmetic products or cosmetic products on behalf of more than one responsible person. Such single registration may be submitted to the Secretary by such facility or any responsible person whose products are manufactured or processed at such facility.


(4) Updates to contentA person that is required to register under subsection (a)(1) shall notify the Secretary within 60 days of any changes to information required under subsection (b)(2).


(5) Abbreviated renewal registrationsThe Secretary shall provide for an abbreviated registration renewal process for any person that owns or operates a facility that has not been required to submit updates under paragraph (4) for a registered facility since submission of the most recent registration of such facility under paragraph (1) or (2).



(b) Form</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission of registration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Format; contents of registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Format; contents of registration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cosmetic product listing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cosmetic product listing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facility registration and product listing numbers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Facility registration and product listing numbers At the time of the initial registration of any facility under subsection (a)(1) or initial listing of any cosmetic product under (c)(1),11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “subsection”. the Secretary shall assign a facility registration number to the facility and a product listing number to each cosmetic product. The Secretary shall not make such product listing number publicly available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Confidentiality In response to a request under section 552 of title 5, information described in subsection (b)(2)(D) or (c)(4)(A)(i) that is derived from a registration or listing under this section shall be withheld under section 552(b)(3) of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspensions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Suspensions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>