<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_364e"><akn:num>364e</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 364e. Labeling(a) General requirementEach cosmetic product shall bear a label that includes a domestic address, domestic phone number, or electronic contact information, which may include a website, through which the responsible person can receive adverse event reports with respect to such cosmetic product.


(b) Fragrance allergensThe responsible person shall identify on the label of a cosmetic product each fragrance allergen included in such cosmetic product. Substances that are fragrance allergens for purposes of this subsection shall be determined by the Secretary by regulation. The Secretary shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking promulgating the regulation implementing this requirement not later than 18 months after December 29, 2022, and not later than 180 days after the date on which the public comment period on the proposed rulemaking closes, shall issue a final rulemaking. In promulgating regulations implementing this subsection, the Secretary shall consider international, State, and local requirements for allergen disclosure, including the substance and format of requirements in the European Union, and may establish threshold levels of amounts of substances subject to disclosure pursuant to such regulations.


(c) Cosmetic products for professional use(1) Definition of professionalFor purposes of this subsection, the term “professional” means an individual who is licensed by an official State authority to practice in the field of cosmetology, nail care, barbering, or esthetics.


(2) Professional use labelingA cosmetic product introduced into interstate commerce and intended to be used only by a professional shall bear a label that—(A) contains a clear and prominent statement that the product shall be administered or used only by licensed professionals; and

(B) is in conformity with the requirements of the Secretary for cosmetics labeling under this chapter and section 1453(a) of title 15.



(June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 609, as added Pub. L. 117–32</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General requirement Each cosmetic product shall bear a label that includes a domestic address, domestic phone number, or electronic contact information, which may include a website, through which the responsible person can receive adverse event reports with respect to such cosmetic product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fragrance allergens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fragrance allergens The responsible person shall identify on the label of a cosmetic product each fragrance allergen included in such cosmetic product. Substances that are fragrance allergens for purposes of this subsection shall be determined by the Secretary by regulation. The Secretary shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking promulgating the regulation implementing this requirement not later than 18 months after December 29, 2022, and not later than 180 days after the date on which the public comment period on the proposed rulemaking closes, shall issue a final rulemaking. In promulgating regulations implementing this subsection, the Secretary shall consider international, State, and local requirements for allergen disclosure, including the substance and format of requirements in the European Union, and may establish threshold levels of amounts of substances subject to disclosure pursuant to such regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cosmetic products for professional use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cosmetic products for professional use</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>