<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_364g"><akn:num>364g</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory recall authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 364g. Mandatory recall authority(a) In generalIf the Secretary determines that there is a reasonable probability that a cosmetic is adulterated under section 361 of this title or misbranded under section 362 of this title and the use of or exposure to such cosmetic will cause serious adverse health consequences or death, the Secretary shall provide the responsible person with an opportunity to voluntarily cease distribution and recall such article. If the responsible person refuses to or does not voluntarily cease distribution or recall such cosmetic within the time and manner prescribed by the Secretary (if so prescribed), the Secretary may, by order, require, as the Secretary determines necessary, such person to immediately cease distribution of such article.


(b) HearingThe Secretary shall provide the responsible person who is subject to an order under subsection (a) with an opportunity for an informal hearing, to be held not later than 10 days after the date of issuance of the order, on whether adequate evidence exists to justify the order.


(c) Order resolutionAfter an order is issued according to the process under subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary shall, except as provided in subsection (d)—(1) vacate the order, if the Secretary determines that inadequate grounds exist to support the actions required by the order;

(2) continue the order ceasing distribution of the cosmetic until a date specified in such order; or

(3) amend the order to require a recall of the cosmetic, including any requirements to notify appropriate persons, a timetable for the recall to occur, and a schedule for updates to be provided to the Secretary regarding such recall.


(d) Action following orderAny person who is subject to an order pursuant to paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (c) shall immediately cease distribution of or recall, as applicable, the cosmetic and provide notification as required by such order.


(e) Notice to persons affectedIf the Secretary determines nece</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If the Secretary determines that there is a reasonable probability that a cosmetic is adulterated under section 361 of this title or misbranded under section 362 of this title and the use of or exposure to such cosmetic will cause serious adverse health consequences or death, the Secretary shall provide the responsible person with an opportunity to voluntarily cease distribution and recall such article. If the responsible person refuses to or does not voluntarily cease distribution or recall such cosmetic within the time and manner prescribed by the Secretary (if so prescribed), the Secretary may, by order, require, as the Secretary determines necessary, such person to immediately cease distribution of such article.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hearing The Secretary shall provide the responsible person who is subject to an order under subsection (a) with an opportunity for an informal hearing, to be held not later than 10 days after the date of issuance of the order, on whether adequate evidence exists to justify the order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Order resolution After an order is issued according to the process under subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary shall, except as provided in subsection (d)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action following order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Action following order Any person who is subject to an order pursuant to paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (c) shall immediately cease distribution of or recall, as applicable, the cosmetic and provide notification as required by such order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to persons affected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice to persons affected If the Secretary determines necessary, the Secretary may require the person subject to an order pursuant to subsection (a) or an amended order pursuant to paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (c) to provide either a notice of a recall order for, or an order to cease distribution of, such cosmetic, as applicable, under this section to appropriate persons, including persons who manufacture, distribute, import, or offer for sale such product that is the subject of an order and to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public notification In conducting a recall under this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No delegation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No delegation The authority conferred by this section to order a recall or vacate a recall order shall not be delegated to any officer or employee other than the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effect Nothing in this section shall affect the authority of the Secretary to request or participate in a voluntary recall, or to issue an order to cease distribution or to recall under any other provision of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>