<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/364i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_364i"><akn:num>364i</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for certain products and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 364i. Exemption for certain products and facilities(a) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in subsection (b), a cosmetic product or facility that is also subject to the requirements of subchapter V shall be exempt from the requirements of sections 364a, 364b, 364c, 364d, 364e(a), 364f, and 364g of this title.


(b) ExceptionA facility described in subsection (a) that also manufactures or processes cosmetic products that are not subject to the requirements of subchapter V shall not be exempt from the requirements of sections 364a, 364b, 364c, 364d, 364e(a), 364f, and 364g of this title, with respect to such cosmetic products.


(June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 613, as added Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title III, § 3502, Dec. 29, 2022, 136 Stat. 5857.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Construction; ConfidentialityNothing in section 3502 of Pub. L. 117–328, which enacted this section, to be construed to authorize the disclosure of information that is prohibited from disclosure under section 331(j) of this title or section 1905 of title 18 or that is subject to withholding under section 552(b)(4) of title 5, see section 3503(c)(2) of Pub. L. 117–328, set out as a note under section 364 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding any other provision of law, except as provided in subsection (b), a cosmetic product or facility that is also subject to the requirements of subchapter V shall be exempt from the requirements of sections 364a, 364b, 364c, 364d, 364e(a), 364f, and 364g of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_364i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception A facility described in subsection (a) that also manufactures or processes cosmetic products that are not subject to the requirements of subchapter V shall not be exempt from the requirements of sections 364a, 364b, 364c, 364d, 364e(a), 364f, and 364g of this title, with respect to such cosmetic products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>