<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/374" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/374/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/374/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_374"><akn:num>374</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 374. Inspection(a) Right of agents to enter; scope of inspection; notice; promptness; exclusions(1) For purposes of enforcement of this chapter, officers or employees duly designated by the Secretary, upon presenting appropriate credentials and a written notice to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, are authorized (A) to enter, at reasonable times, any factory, warehouse, or establishment in which food, drugs, devices, tobacco products, or cosmetics are manufactured, processed, packed, or held, for introduction into interstate commerce or after such introduction, or to enter any vehicle being used to transport or hold such food, drugs, devices, tobacco products, or cosmetics in interstate commerce; and (B) to inspect, at reasonable times and within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner, such factory, warehouse, establishment, or vehicle and all pertinent equipment, finished and unfinished materials, containers, and labeling therein. In the case of any person (excluding farms and restaurants) who manufactures, processes, packs, transports, distributes, holds, or imports foods, the inspection shall extend to all records and other information described in section 350c of this title, when the standard for records inspection under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 350c(a) of this title applies, subject to the limitations established in section 350c(d) of this title. In the case of a facility (as defined in section 364 of this title) that manufactures or processes cosmetic products, the inspection shall extend to all records and other information described in sections 364a, 364b, and 364f of this title, when the standard for records inspection under such section applies. In the case of any factory, warehouse, establishment, or consulting laboratory in which prescription drugs, nonprescription drugs intended for human use, devices, or tobacco products are manufactured, processed, packed, or held, the inspection shall extend to all things therein (including reco</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_374_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of agents to enter; scope of inspection; notice; promptness; exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Right of agents to enter; scope of inspection; notice; promptness; exclusions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_374_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written report to owner; copy to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Written report to owner; copy to Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_374_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipt for samples taken</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Receipt for samples taken If the officer or employee making any such inspection of a factory, warehouse, or other establishment has obtained any sample in the course of the inspection, upon completion of the inspection and prior to leaving the premises he shall give to the owner, operator, or agent in charge a receipt describing the samples obtained.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_374_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Analysis of samples furnished owner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Analysis of samples furnished owner Whenever in the course of any such inspection of a factory or other establishment where food is manufactured, processed, or packed, the officer or employee making the inspection obtains a sample of any such food, and an analysis is made of such sample for the purpose of ascertaining whether such food consists in whole or in part of any filthy, putrid, or decomposed substance, or is otherwise unfit for food, a copy of the results of such analysis shall be furnished promptly to the owner, operator, or agent in charge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_374_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accessibility of records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Accessibility of records Every person required under section 360i or 360j(g) of this title to maintain records and every person who is in charge or custody of such records shall, upon request of an officer or employee designated by the Secretary, permit such officer or employee at all reasonable times to have access to, and to copy and verify, such records.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_374_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Recordkeeping</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_374_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections by accredited persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Inspections by accredited persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_374_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvements to inspections process for device establishments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Improvements to inspections process for device establishments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>