<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379aa–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379aa–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379aa–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_379aa_1"><akn:num>379aa–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Serious adverse event reporting for dietary supplements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 379aa–1. Serious adverse event reporting for dietary supplements(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Adverse eventThe term “adverse event” means any health-related event associated with the use of a dietary supplement that is adverse.


(2) Serious adverse eventThe term “serious adverse event” is an adverse event that—(A) results in—(i) death;

(ii) a life-threatening experience;

(iii) inpatient hospitalization;

(iv) a persistent or significant disability or incapacity; or

(v) a congenital anomaly or birth defect; or


(B) requires, based on reasonable medical judgment, a medical or surgical intervention to prevent an outcome described under subparagraph (A).


(3) Serious adverse event reportThe term “serious adverse event report” means a report that is required to be submitted to the Secretary under subsection (b).



(b) Reporting requirement(1) In generalThe manufacturer, packer, or distributor of a dietary supplement whose name (pursuant to section 343(e)(1) of this title) appears on the label of a dietary supplement marketed in the United States (referred to in this section as the “responsible person”) shall submit to the Secretary any report received of a serious adverse event associated with such dietary supplement when used in the United States, accompanied by a copy of the label on or within the retail packaging of such dietary supplement.


(2) RetailerA retailer whose name appears on the label described in paragraph (1) as a distributor may, by agreement, authorize the manufacturer or packer of the dietary supplement to submit the required reports for such dietary supplements to the Secretary so long as the retailer directs to the manufacturer or packer all adverse events associated with such dietary supplement that are reported to the retailer through the address or telephone number described in section 343(y) of this title.



(c) Submission of reports(1) Timing of reportsThe responsible person shall submit to the Secretary a serious adverse event r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379aa_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379aa_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reporting requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379aa_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission of reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379aa_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contents of reports Each serious adverse event report under this section shall be submitted to the Secretary using the MedWatch form, which may be modified by the Secretary for dietary supplements, and may be accompanied by additional information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379aa_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance and inspection of records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Maintenance and inspection of records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379aa_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protected information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Protected information A serious adverse event report submitted to the Secretary under this section, including any new medical information submitted under subsection (c)(2), or an adverse event report voluntarily submitted to the Secretary shall be considered to be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379aa_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rule of construction The submission of any adverse event report in compliance with this section shall not be construed as an admission that the dietary supplement involved caused or contributed to the adverse event.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379aa_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Preemption</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379aa_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>