<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379dd" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379dd/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379dd/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_379dd"><akn:num>379dd</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and functions of the Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 379dd. Establishment and functions of the Foundation(a) In generalA nonprofit corporation to be known as the Reagan-Udall Foundation for the Food and Drug Administration (referred to in this part as the “Foundation”) shall be established in accordance with this section. The Foundation shall be headed by an Executive Director, appointed by the members of the Board of Directors under subsection (e).11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (g).” The Foundation shall not be an agency or instrumentality of the United States Government.


(b) Purpose of FoundationThe purpose of the Foundation is to advance the mission of the Food and Drug Administration to modernize medical, veterinary, food, food ingredient, and cosmetic product development, accelerate innovation, and enhance product safety.


(c) Duties of the FoundationThe Foundation shall—(1) taking into consideration the Critical Path reports and priorities published by the Food and Drug Administration, identify unmet needs in the development, manufacture, and evaluation of the safety and effectiveness, including postapproval, of devices, including diagnostics, biologics, and drugs, and the safety of food, food ingredients, and cosmetics, and including the incorporation of more sensitive and predictive tools and devices to measure safety;

(2) establish goals and priorities in order to meet the unmet needs identified in paragraph (1);

(3) in consultation with the Secretary, identify existing and proposed Federal intramural and extramural research and development programs relating to the goals and priorities established under paragraph (2), coordinate Foundation activities with such programs, and minimize Foundation duplication of existing efforts;

(4) award grants to, or enter into contracts, memoranda of understanding, or cooperative agreements with, scientists and entities, which may include the Food and Drug Administration, university consortia, public-private partnerships, institutions of higher educ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A nonprofit corporation to be known as the Reagan-Udall Foundation for the Food and Drug Administration (referred to in this part as the “Foundation”) shall be established in accordance with this section. The Foundation shall be headed by an Executive Director, appointed by the members of the Board of Directors under subsection (e).11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (g).” The Foundation shall not be an agency or instrumentality of the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose of Foundation The purpose of the Foundation is to advance the mission of the Food and Drug Administration to modernize medical, veterinary, food, food ingredient, and cosmetic product development, accelerate innovation, and enhance product safety.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of the Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties of the Foundation The Foundation shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Board of Directors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Incorporation The ex officio members of the Board shall serve as incorporators and shall take whatever actions necessary to incorporate the Foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonprofit status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nonprofit status In carrying out subsection (b), the Board shall establish such policies and bylaws under subsection (d), and the Executive Director shall carry out such activities under subsection (g), as may be necessary to ensure that the Foundation maintains status as an organization that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Executive Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administrative powers In carrying out this part, the Board, acting through the Executive Director, may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of funds from other sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Acceptance of funds from other sources The Executive Director may solicit and accept on behalf of the Foundation, any funds, gifts, grants, devises, or bequests of real or personal property made to the Foundation, including from private entities, for the purposes of carrying out the duties of the Foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379dd_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of Federal employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Service of Federal employees Federal Government employees may serve on committees advisory to the Foundation and otherwise cooperate with and assist the Foundation in carrying out its functions, so long as such employees do not direct or control Foundation activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>