<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_379h"><akn:num>379h</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to assess and use drug fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 379h. Authority to assess and use drug fees(a) Types of feesBeginning in fiscal year 2023, the Secretary shall assess and collect fees in accordance with this section as follows:(1) Human drug application fee(A) In generalEach person that submits, on or after September 1, 1992, a human drug application shall be subject to a fee as follows:(i) A fee established under subsection (c)(6) for a human drug application for which clinical data (other than bioavailability or bioequivalence studies) with respect to safety or effectiveness are required for approval.

(ii) A fee established under subsection (c)(6) for a human drug application for which clinical data (other than bioavailability or bioequivalence studies) with respect to safety or effectiveness are not required for approval. Such fee shall be half of the amount of the fee established under clause (i).


(B) PaymentThe fee required by subparagraph (A) shall be due upon submission of the application.


(C) Exception for previously filed applicationIf a human drug application was submitted by a person that paid the fee for such application, was accepted for filing, and was not approved or was withdrawn prior to approval (without a waiver), the submission of a human drug application for the same product by the same person (or the person’s licensee, assignee, or successor) shall not be subject to a fee under subparagraph (A).


(D) Refund of fee if application refused for filing or withdrawn before filingThe Secretary shall refund 75 percent of the fee paid under subparagraph (B) for any application which is refused for filing or withdrawn without a waiver before filing.


(E) Fees for applications previously refused for filing or withdrawn before filingA human drug application that was submitted but was refused for filing, or was withdrawn before being accepted or refused for filing, shall be subject to the full fee under subparagraph (A) upon being resubmitted or filed over protest, unless the fee is waived or red</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Types of fees Beginning in fiscal year 2023, the Secretary shall assess and collect fees in accordance with this section as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee revenue amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fee revenue amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments; annual fee setting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adjustments; annual fee setting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee waiver or reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fee waiver or reduction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of failure to pay fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect of failure to pay fees A human drug application or supplement submitted by a person subject to fees under subsection (a) shall be considered incomplete and shall not be accepted for filing by the Secretary until all such fees owed by such person have been paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting and availability of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Crediting and availability of fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of unpaid fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Collection of unpaid fees In any case where the Secretary does not receive payment of a fee assessed under subsection (a) within 30 days after it is due, such fee shall be treated as a claim of the United States Government subject to subchapter II of chapter 37 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written requests for waivers, reductions, exemptions, and returns; disputes concerning fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Written requests for waivers, reductions, exemptions, and returns; disputes concerning fees To qualify for consideration for a waiver or reduction under subsection (d), an exemption under subsection (k), or the return of any fee paid under this section, including if the fee is claimed to have been paid in error, a person shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379h_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Construction This section may not be construed to require that the number of full-time equivalent positions in the Department of Health and Human Services, for officers, employers, and advisory committees not engaged in the process of the review of human drug applications, be reduced to offset the number of officers, employees, and advisory committees so engaged.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>