<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379j–31" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379j–31/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379j–31/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_379j_31"><akn:num>379j–31</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to collect and use fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 379j–31. Authority to collect and use fees(a) In general(1) Purpose and authorityFor fiscal year 2010 and each subsequent fiscal year, the Secretary shall, in accordance with this section, assess and collect fees from—(A) the responsible party for each domestic facility (as defined in section 350d(b) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title) and the United States agent for each foreign facility subject to a reinspection in such fiscal year, to cover reinspection-related costs for such year;

(B) the responsible party for a domestic facility (as defined in section 350d(b) 1 of this title) and an importer who does not comply with a recall order under section 350l of this title or under section 350a(f) of this title in such fiscal year, to cover food recall activities associated with such order performed by the Secretary, including technical assistance, follow-up effectiveness checks, and public notifications, for such year;

(C) each importer participating in the voluntary qualified importer program under section 384b of this title in such year, to cover the administrative costs of such program for such year; and

(D) each importer subject to a reinspection in such fiscal year, to cover reinspection-related costs for such year.


(2) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(A) the term “reinspection” means—(i) with respect to domestic facilities (as defined in section 350d(b) 1 of this title), 1 or more inspections conducted under section 374 of this title subsequent to an inspection conducted under such provision which identified noncompliance materially related to a food safety requirement of this chapter, specifically to determine whether compliance has been achieved to the Secretary’s satisfaction; and

(ii) with respect to importers, 1 or more examinations conducted under section 381 of this title subsequent to an examination conducted under such provision which identified noncompliance materially related to a food safety requirement of this chapter,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_31_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_31_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_31_ii"><akn:num>(ii)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(ii) Crediting of fees In establishing the fee amounts under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall provide for the crediting of fees from the previous year to the next year if the Secretary overestimated the amount of fees needed to carry out such activities, and consider the need to account for any adjustment of fees and such other factors as the Secretary determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_31_iii"><akn:num>(iii)</akn:num><akn:heading>Published guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(iii) Published guidelines Not later than 180 days after January 4, 2011, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a proposed set of guidelines in consideration of the burden of fee amounts on small business. Such consideration may include reduced fee amounts for small businesses. The Secretary shall provide for a period of public comment on such guidelines. The Secretary shall adjust the fee schedule for small businesses subject to such fees only through notice and comment rulemaking.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_31_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_31_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting and availability of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Crediting and availability of fees Fees authorized under subsection (a) shall be collected and available for obligation only to the extent and in the amount provided in appropriations Acts. Such fees are authorized to remain available until expended. Such sums as may be necessary may be transferred from the Food and Drug Administration salaries and expenses account without fiscal year limitation to such appropriation account for salaries and expenses with such fiscal year limitation. The sums transferred shall be available solely for the purpose of paying the operating expenses of the Food and Drug Administration employees and contractors performing activities associated with these food safety fees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_31_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Collection of fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_31_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual report to Congress Not later than 120 days after each fiscal year for which fees are assessed under this section, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, to include a description of fees assessed and collected for each such year and a summary description of the entities paying such fees and the types of business in which such entities engage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_31_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations For fiscal year 2010 and each fiscal year thereafter, there is authorized to be appropriated for fees under this section an amount equal to the total revenue amount determined under subsection (b) for the fiscal year, as adjusted or otherwise affected under the other provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>