<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379j–42" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379j–42/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/379j–42/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_379j_42"><akn:num>379j–42</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to assess and use human generic drug fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 379j–42. Authority to assess and use human generic drug fees(a) Types of feesBeginning in fiscal year 2023, the Secretary shall assess and collect fees in accordance with this section as follows:(1) One-time backlog fee for abbreviated new drug applications pending on October 1, 2012(A) In generalEach person that owns an abbreviated new drug application that is pending on October 1, 2012, and that has not received a tentative approval prior to that date, shall be subject to a fee for each such application, as calculated under subparagraph (B).


(B) Method of fee amount calculationThe amount of each one-time backlog fee shall be calculated by dividing $50,000,000 by the total number of abbreviated new drug applications pending on October 1, 2012, that have not received a tentative approval as of that date.


(C) NoticeNot later than October 31, 2012, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a notice announcing the amount of the fee required by subparagraph (A).


(D) Fee due dateThe fee required by subparagraph (A) shall be due no later than 30 calendar days after the date of the publication of the notice specified in subparagraph (C).


(E) SunsetThis paragraph shall cease to be effective October 1, 2022.



(2) Drug master file fee(A) In generalEach person that owns a Type II active pharmaceutical ingredient drug master file that is referenced on or after October 1, 2012, in a generic drug submission by any initial letter of authorization shall be subject to a drug master file fee.


(B) One-time paymentIf a person has paid a drug master file fee for a Type II active pharmaceutical ingredient drug master file, the person shall not be required to pay a subsequent drug master file fee when that Type II active pharmaceutical ingredient drug master file is subsequently referenced in generic drug submissions.


(C) NoticeNot later than 60 days before the start of each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Types of fees Beginning in fiscal year 2023, the Secretary shall assess and collect fees in accordance with this section as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee revenue amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fee revenue amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual fee setting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual fee setting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Identification of facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of failure to pay fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect of failure to pay fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting and availability of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Crediting and availability of fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_379j_42_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of unpaid fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Collection of unpaid fees In any case where the Secretary does not receive payment of a fee assessed under subsection (a) within 30 calendar days after it is due, such fee shall be treated as a claim of the United States Government subject to subchapter II of chapter 37 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>