<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/382" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/382/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/382/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_382"><akn:num>382</akn:num><akn:heading>Exports of certain unapproved products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 382. Exports of certain unapproved products(a) Drugs or devices intended for human or animal use which require approval or licensingA drug or device—(1) which, in the case of a drug—(A)(i) requires approval by the Secretary under section 355 of this title before such drug may be introduced or delivered for introduction into interstate commerce; or

(ii) requires licensing by the Secretary under section 262 of title 42 or by the Secretary of Agriculture under the Act of March 4, 1913 [21 U.S.C. 151 et seq.] (known as the Virus-Serum Toxin Act) before it may be introduced or delivered for introduction into interstate commerce;


(B) does not have such approval or license; and

(C) is not exempt from such sections or Act; and


(2) which, in the case of a device—(A) does not comply with an applicable requirement under section 360d or 360e of this title;

(B) under section 360j(g) of this title is exempt from either such section; or

(C) is a banned device under section 360f of this title, is adulterated, misbranded, and in violation of such sections or Act unless the export of the drug or device is, except as provided in subsection (f), authorized under subsection (b), (c), (d), or (e) or section 381(e)(2) of this title. If a drug or device described in paragraphs (1) and (2) may be exported under subsection (b) and if an application for such drug or device under section 355 or 360e of this title or section 262 of title 42 was disapproved, the Secretary shall notify the appropriate public health official of the country to which such drug will be exported of such disapproval.



(b) List of eligible countries for export; criteria for addition to list; direct export; petition for exemption(1)(A) A drug or device described in subsection (a) may be exported to any country, if the drug or device complies with the laws of that country and has valid marketing authorization by the appropriate authority—(i) in Australia, Canada, Israel, Japan, New Zealand, Switzerland, or Sou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drugs or devices intended for human or animal use which require approval or licensing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Drugs or devices intended for human or animal use which require approval or licensing A drug or device—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of eligible countries for export; criteria for addition to list; direct export; petition for exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) List of eligible countries for export; criteria for addition to list; direct export; petition for exemption</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigational use exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Investigational use exemption A drug or device intended for investigational use in any country described in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (b)(1)(A) may be exported in accordance with the laws of that country and shall be exempt from regulation under section 355(i) or 360j(g) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Anticipation of market authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Anticipation of market authorization A drug or device intended for formulation, filling, packaging, labeling, or further processing in anticipation of market authorization in any country described in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (b)(1)(A) may be exported for use in accordance with the laws of that country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diagnosis, prevention, or treatment of tropical disease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Diagnosis, prevention, or treatment of tropical disease</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of export of drug or device</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition of export of drug or device A drug or device may not be exported under this section— In making a finding under paragraph (4)(B), (5), or (6) the Secretary shall consult with the appropriate public health official in the affected country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notification of Secretary The exporter of a drug or device exported under subsection (b)(1) shall provide a simple notification to the Secretary identifying the drug or device when the exporter first begins to export such drug or device to any country listed in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (b)(1)(A). When an exporter of a drug or device first begins to export a drug or device to a country which is not listed in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (b)(1)A),11 So in original. Probably should be subsection “(b)(1)(A),”. the exporter shall provide a simple notification to the Secretary identifying the drug or device and the country to which such drug or device is being exported. Any exporter of a drug or device shall maintain records of all drugs or devices exported and the countries to which they were exported.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>References to Secretary and term “drug”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) References to Secretary and term “drug” For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_382_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Exportation Insulin and antibiotic drugs may be exported without regard to the requirements in this section if the insulin and antibiotic drugs meet the requirements of section 381(e)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>