<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/384" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/384/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/384/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_384"><akn:num>384</akn:num><akn:heading>Importation of prescription drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 384. Importation of prescription drugs(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ImporterThe term “importer” means a pharmacist or wholesaler.


(2) PharmacistThe term “pharmacist” means a person licensed by a State to practice pharmacy, including the dispensing and selling of prescription drugs.


(3) Prescription drugThe term “prescription drug” means a drug subject to section 353(b) of this title, other than—(A) a controlled substance (as defined in section 802 of this title);

(B) a biological product (as defined in section 262 of title 42);

(C) an infused drug (including a peritoneal dialysis solution);

(D) an intravenously injected drug;

(E) a drug that is inhaled during surgery; or

(F) a drug which is a parenteral drug, the importation of which pursuant to subsection (b) is determined by the Secretary to pose a threat to the public health, in which case section 381(d)(1) of this title shall continue to apply.


(4) Qualifying laboratoryThe term “qualifying laboratory” means a laboratory in the United States that has been approved by the Secretary for the purposes of this section.


(5) Wholesaler(A) In generalThe term “wholesaler” means a person licensed as a wholesaler or distributor of prescription drugs in the United States under section 353(e)(2)(A) of this title.


(B) ExclusionThe term “wholesaler” does not include a person authorized to import drugs under section 381(d)(1) of this title.




(b) RegulationsThe Secretary, after consultation with the United States Trade Representative and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, shall promulgate regulations permitting pharmacists and wholesalers to import prescription drugs from Canada into the United States.


(c) LimitationThe regulations under subsection (b) shall—(1) require that safeguards be in place to ensure that each prescription drug imported under the regulations complies with section 355 of this title (including with respect to being safe and effective for the intended use of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations The Secretary, after consultation with the United States Trade Representative and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, shall promulgate regulations permitting pharmacists and wholesalers to import prescription drugs from Canada into the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation The regulations under subsection (b) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information and records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Testing The regulations under subsection (b) shall require—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of foreign sellers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Registration of foreign sellers Any establishment within Canada engaged in the distribution of a prescription drug that is imported or offered for importation into the United States shall register with the Secretary the name and place of business of the establishment and the name of the United States agent for the establishment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of importation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Suspension of importation The Secretary shall require that importations of a specific prescription drug or importations by a specific importer under subsection (b) be immediately suspended on discovery of a pattern of importation of that specific prescription drug or by that specific importer of drugs that are counterfeit or in violation of any requirement under this section, until an investigation is completed and the Secretary determines that the public is adequately protected from counterfeit and violative prescription drugs being imported under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approved labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Approved labeling The manufacturer of a prescription drug shall provide an importer written authorization for the importer to use, at no cost, the approved labeling for the prescription drug.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charitable contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Charitable contributions Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, section 381(d)(1) of this title continues to apply to a prescription drug that is donated or otherwise supplied at no charge by the manufacturer of the drug to a charitable or humanitarian organization (including the United Nations and affiliates) or to a government of a foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver authority for importation by individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Waiver authority for importation by individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>