<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/384d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/384d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/384d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_384d"><akn:num>384d</akn:num><akn:heading>Accreditation of third-party auditors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 384d. Accreditation of third-party auditors(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Audit agentThe term “audit agent” means an individual who is an employee or agent of an accredited third-party auditor and, although not individually accredited, is qualified to conduct food safety audits on behalf of an accredited third-party auditor.


(2) Accreditation bodyThe term “accreditation body” means an authority that performs accreditation of third-party auditors.


(3) Third-party auditorThe term “third-party auditor” means a foreign government, agency of a foreign government, foreign cooperative, or any other third party, as the Secretary determines appropriate in accordance with the model standards described in subsection (b)(2), that is eligible to be considered for accreditation to conduct food safety audits to certify that eligible entities meet the applicable requirements of this section. A third-party auditor may be a single individual. A third-party auditor may employ or use audit agents to help conduct consultative and regulatory audits.


(4) Accredited third-party auditorThe term “accredited third-party auditor” means a third-party auditor accredited by an accreditation body to conduct audits of eligible entities to certify that such eligible entities meet the applicable requirements of this section. An accredited third-party auditor may be an individual who conducts food safety audits to certify that eligible entities meet the applicable requirements of this section.


(5) Consultative auditThe term “consultative audit” means an audit of an eligible entity—(A) to determine whether such entity is in compliance with the provisions of this chapter and with applicable industry standards and practices; and

(B) the results of which are for internal purposes only.


(6) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means a foreign entity, including a foreign facility registered under section 350d of this title, in the food import supply chain that chooses to be audited by </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accreditation system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Accreditation system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Third-party auditors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Third-party auditors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recertification of eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recertification of eligible entities An eligible entity shall apply for annual recertification by an accredited third-party auditor if such entity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>False statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) False statements Any statement or representation made— shall be subject to section 1001 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Monitoring To ensure compliance with the requirements of this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publicly available registry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Publicly available registry The Secretary shall establish a publicly available registry of accreditation bodies and of accredited third-party auditors, including the name of, contact information for, and other information deemed necessary by the Secretary about such bodies and auditors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_384d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>