<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_387"><akn:num>387</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 387. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) AdditiveThe term “additive” means any substance the intended use of which results or may reasonably be expected to result, directly or indirectly, in its becoming a component or otherwise affecting the characteristic of any tobacco product (including any substances intended for use as a flavoring or coloring or in producing, manufacturing, packing, processing, preparing, treating, packaging, transporting, or holding), except that such term does not include tobacco or a pesticide chemical residue in or on raw tobacco or a pesticide chemical.


(2) BrandThe term “brand” means a variety of tobacco product distinguished by the tobacco used, tar content, nicotine content, flavoring used, size, filtration, packaging, logo, registered trademark, brand name, identifiable pattern of colors, or any combination of such attributes.


(3) CigaretteThe term “cigarette”—(A) means a product that—(i) is a tobacco product; and

(ii) meets the definition of the term “cigarette” in section 1332(1) of title 15; and


(B) includes tobacco, in any form, that is functional in the product, which, because of its appearance, the type of tobacco used in the filler, or its packaging and labeling, is likely to be offered to, or purchased by, consumers as a cigarette or as roll-your-own tobacco.


(4) Cigarette tobaccoThe term “cigarette tobacco” means any product that consists of loose tobacco that is intended for use by consumers in a cigarette. Unless otherwise stated, the requirements applicable to cigarettes under this subchapter shall also apply to cigarette tobacco.


(5) CommerceThe term “commerce” has the meaning given that term by section 1332(2) of title 15.


(6) Counterfeit tobacco productThe term “counterfeit tobacco product” means a tobacco product (or the container or labeling of such a product) that, without authorization, bears the trademark, trade name, or other identifying mark, imprint, or device, or any likeness thereof, of a tobacco</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additive</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Additive The term “additive” means any substance the intended use of which results or may reasonably be expected to result, directly or indirectly, in its becoming a component or otherwise affecting the characteristic of any tobacco product (including any substances intended for use as a flavoring or coloring or in producing, manufacturing, packing, processing, preparing, treating, packaging, transporting, or holding), except that such term does not include tobacco or a pesticide chemical residue in or on raw tobacco or a pesticide chemical.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Brand</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Brand The term “brand” means a variety of tobacco product distinguished by the tobacco used, tar content, nicotine content, flavoring used, size, filtration, packaging, logo, registered trademark, brand name, identifiable pattern of colors, or any combination of such attributes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigarette</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Cigarette The term “cigarette”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cigarette tobacco</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Cigarette tobacco The term “cigarette tobacco” means any product that consists of loose tobacco that is intended for use by consumers in a cigarette. Unless otherwise stated, the requirements applicable to cigarettes under this subchapter shall also apply to cigarette tobacco.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Commerce The term “commerce” has the meaning given that term by section 1332(2) of title 15.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Counterfeit tobacco product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Counterfeit tobacco product The term “counterfeit tobacco product” means a tobacco product (or the container or labeling of such a product) that, without authorization, bears the trademark, trade name, or other identifying mark, imprint, or device, or any likeness thereof, of a tobacco product listed in a registration under section 387e(i)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Distributor The term “distributor” as regards a tobacco product means any person who furthers the distribution of a tobacco product, whether domestic or imported, at any point from the original place of manufacture to the person who sells or distributes the product to individuals for personal consumption. Common carriers are not considered distributors for purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Illicit trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Illicit trade The term “illicit trade” means any practice or conduct prohibited by law which relates to production, shipment, receipt, possession, distribution, sale, or purchase of tobacco products including any practice or conduct intended to facilitate such activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Indian country The term “Indian country” has the meaning given such term in section 1151 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given such term in section 5304(e) of title 25.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>