<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_387d"><akn:num>387d</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of health information to the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 387d. Submission of health information to the Secretary(a) RequirementEach tobacco product manufacturer or importer, or agents thereof, shall submit to the Secretary the following information:(1) Not later than 6 months after June 22, 2009, a listing of all ingredients, including tobacco, substances, compounds, and additives that are, as of such date, added by the manufacturer to the tobacco, paper, filter, or other part of each tobacco product by brand and by quantity in each brand and subbrand.

(2) A description of the content, delivery, and form of nicotine in each tobacco product measured in milligrams of nicotine in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary in accordance with section 1333(e) of title 15.

(3) Beginning 3 years after June 22, 2009, a listing of all constituents, including smoke constituents as applicable, identified by the Secretary as harmful or potentially harmful to health in each tobacco product, and as applicable in the smoke of each tobacco product, by brand and by quantity in each brand and subbrand. Effective beginning 3 years after June 22, 2009, the manufacturer, importer, or agent shall comply with regulations promulgated under section 387o of this title in reporting information under this paragraph, where applicable.

(4) Beginning 6 months after June 22, 2009, all documents developed after June 22, 2009 that relate to health, toxicological, behavioral, or physiologic effects of current or future tobacco products, their constituents (including smoke constituents), ingredients, components, and additives.


(b) Data submissionAt the request of the Secretary, each tobacco product manufacturer or importer of tobacco products, or agents thereof, shall submit the following:(1) Any or all documents (including underlying scientific information) relating to research activities, and research findings, conducted, supported, or possessed by the manufacturer (or agents thereof) on the health, toxicological, behavioral, or physio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement Each tobacco product manufacturer or importer, or agents thereof, shall submit to the Secretary the following information:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data submission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Data submission At the request of the Secretary, each tobacco product manufacturer or importer of tobacco products, or agents thereof, shall submit the following: An importer of a tobacco product not manufactured in the United States shall supply the information required of a tobacco product manufacturer under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for submission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Time for submission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data list</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Data list</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Data collection Not later than 24 months after June 22, 2009, the Secretary shall establish, and periodically revise as appropriate, a list of harmful and potentially harmful constituents, including smoke constituents, to health in each tobacco product by brand and by quantity in each brand and subbrand. The Secretary shall publish a public notice requesting the submission by interested persons of scientific and other information concerning the harmful and potentially harmful constituents in tobacco products and tobacco smoke.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>