<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_387f"><akn:num>387f</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions respecting control of tobacco products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 387f. General provisions respecting control of tobacco products(a) In generalAny requirement established by or under section 387b, 387c, 387e, or 387i of this title applicable to a tobacco product shall apply to such tobacco product until the applicability of the requirement to the tobacco product has been changed by action taken under section 387g of this title, section 387j of this title, section 387k of this title, or subsection (d) of this section, and any requirement established by or under section 387b, 387c, 387e, or 387i of this title which is inconsistent with a requirement imposed on such tobacco product under section 387g of this title, section 387j of this title, section 387k of this title, or subsection (d) of this section shall not apply to such tobacco product.


(b) Information on public access and commentEach notice of proposed rulemaking or other notification under section 387g, 387h, 387i, 387j, or 387k of this title or under this section, any other notice which is published in the Federal Register with respect to any other action taken under any such section and which states the reasons for such action, and each publication of findings required to be made in connection with rulemaking under any such section shall set forth—(1) the manner in which interested persons may examine data and other information on which the notice or findings is 11 So in original. Probably should be “are”. based; and

(2) the period within which interested persons may present their comments on the notice or findings (including the need therefore) orally or in writing, which period shall be at least 60 days but may not exceed 90 days unless the time is extended by the Secretary by a notice published in the Federal Register stating good cause therefore.


(c) Limited confidentiality of informationAny information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Secretary or the Secretary’s representative under section 387c, 387d, 387g, 387h, 387i, 387j, 387k, or 374 of this title</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Any requirement established by or under section 387b, 387c, 387e, or 387i of this title applicable to a tobacco product shall apply to such tobacco product until the applicability of the requirement to the tobacco product has been changed by action taken under section 387g of this title, section 387j of this title, section 387k of this title, or subsection (d) of this section, and any requirement established by or under section 387b, 387c, 387e, or 387i of this title which is inconsistent with a requirement imposed on such tobacco product under section 387g of this title, section 387j of this title, section 387k of this title, or subsection (d) of this section shall not apply to such tobacco product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on public access and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information on public access and comment Each notice of proposed rulemaking or other notification under section 387g, 387h, 387i, 387j, or 387k of this title or under this section, any other notice which is published in the Federal Register with respect to any other action taken under any such section and which states the reasons for such action, and each publication of findings required to be made in connection with rulemaking under any such section shall set forth—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited confidentiality of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limited confidentiality of information Any information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Secretary or the Secretary’s representative under section 387c, 387d, 387g, 387h, 387i, 387j, 387k, or 374 of this title, or under subsection (e) or (f) of this section, which is exempt from disclosure under subsection (a) of section 552 of title 5 by reason of subsection (b)(4) of that section shall be considered confidential and shall not be disclosed, except that the information may be disclosed to other officers or employees concerned with carrying out this subchapter, or when relevant in any proceeding under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Good manufacturing practice requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Good manufacturing practice requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Research and development The Secretary may enter into contracts for research, testing, and demonstrations respecting tobacco products and may obtain tobacco products for research, testing, and demonstration purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>