<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_387g"><akn:num>387g</akn:num><akn:heading>Tobacco product standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 387g. Tobacco product standards(a) In general(1) Special rules(A) Special rule for cigarettesBeginning 3 months after June 22, 2009, a cigarette or any of its component parts (including the tobacco, filter, or paper) shall not contain, as a constituent (including a smoke constituent) or additive, an artificial or natural flavor (other than tobacco or menthol) or an herb or spice, including strawberry, grape, orange, clove, cinnamon, pineapple, vanilla, coconut, licorice, cocoa, chocolate, cherry, or coffee, that is a characterizing flavor of the tobacco product or tobacco smoke. Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed to limit the Secretary’s authority to take action under this section or other sections of this chapter applicable to menthol or any artificial or natural flavor, herb, or spice not specified in this subparagraph.


(B) Additional special ruleBeginning 2 years after June 22, 2009, a tobacco product manufacturer shall not use tobacco, including foreign grown tobacco, that contains a pesticide chemical residue that is at a level greater than is specified by any tolerance applicable under Federal law to domestically grown tobacco.



(2) Revision of tobacco product standardsThe Secretary may revise the tobacco product standards in paragraph (1) in accordance with subsection (c).


(3) Tobacco product standards(A) In generalThe Secretary may adopt tobacco product standards in addition to those in paragraph (1) if the Secretary finds that a tobacco product standard is appropriate for the protection of the public health.


(B) Determinations(i) ConsiderationsIn making a finding described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider scientific evidence concerning—(I) the risks and benefits to the population as a whole, including users and nonusers of tobacco products, of the proposed standard;

(II) the increased or decreased likelihood that existing users of tobacco products will stop using such products; and

(III) the increased or decreased l</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Considerations by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposed standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Proposed standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Promulgation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Menthol cigarettes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Menthol cigarettes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissolvable tobacco products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Dissolvable tobacco products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>