<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_387l"><akn:num>387l</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 387l. Judicial review(a) Right to review(1) In generalNot later than 30 days after—(A) the promulgation of a regulation under section 387g of this title establishing, amending, or revoking a tobacco product standard; or

(B) a denial of an application under section 387j(c) of this title,


any person adversely affected by such regulation or denial may file a petition for judicial review of such regulation or denial with the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia or for the circuit in which such person resides or has their principal place of business.

(2) Requirements(A) Copy of petitionA copy of the petition filed under paragraph (1) shall be transmitted by the clerk of the court involved to the Secretary.


(B) Record of proceedingsOn receipt of a petition under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall file in the court in which such petition was filed—(i) the record of the proceedings on which the regulation or order was based; and

(ii) a statement of the reasons for the issuance of such a regulation or order.


(C) Definition of recordIn this section, the term “record” means—(i) all notices and other matter published in the Federal Register with respect to the regulation or order reviewed;

(ii) all information submitted to the Secretary with respect to such regulation or order;

(iii) proceedings of any panel or advisory committee with respect to such regulation or order;

(iv) any hearing held with respect to such regulation or order; and

(v) any other information identified by the Secretary, in the administrative proceeding held with respect to such regulation or order, as being relevant to such regulation or order.




(b) Standard of reviewUpon the filing of the petition under subsection (a) for judicial review of a regulation or order, the court shall have jurisdiction to review the regulation or order in accordance with chapter 7 of title 5 and to grant appropriate relief, including interim relief, as provided for in such chapter. A </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Right to review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard of review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standard of review Upon the filing of the petition under subsection (a) for judicial review of a regulation or order, the court shall have jurisdiction to review the regulation or order in accordance with chapter 7 of title 5 and to grant appropriate relief, including interim relief, as provided for in such chapter. A regulation or denial described in subsection (a) shall be reviewed in accordance with section 706(2)(A) of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of judgment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Finality of judgment The judgment of the court affirming or setting aside, in whole or in part, any regulation or order shall be final, subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States upon certiorari or certification, as provided in section 1254 of title 28.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387l_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other remedies The remedies provided for in this section shall be in addition to, and not in lieu of, any other remedies provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387l_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and orders must recite basis in record</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations and orders must recite basis in record To facilitate judicial review, a regulation or order issued under section 387f, 387g, 387h, 387i, 387j, or 387p of this title shall contain a statement of the reasons for the issuance of such regulation or order in the record of the proceedings held in connection with its issuance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>