<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_387o"><akn:num>387o</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 387o. Regulation requirement(a) Testing, reporting, and disclosureNot later than 36 months after June 22, 2009, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations under this chapter that meet the requirements of subsection (b).


(b) Contents of rulesThe regulations promulgated under subsection (a)—(1) shall require testing and reporting of tobacco product constituents, ingredients, and additives, including smoke constituents, by brand and subbrand that the Secretary determines should be tested to protect the public health, provided that, for purposes of the testing requirements of this paragraph, tobacco products manufactured and sold by a single tobacco product manufacturer that are identical in all respects except the labels, packaging design, logo, trade dress, trademark, brand name, or any combination thereof, shall be considered as a single brand; and

(2) may require that tobacco product manufacturers, packagers, or importers make disclosures relating to the results of the testing of tar and nicotine through labels or advertising or other appropriate means, and make disclosures regarding the results of the testing of other constituents, including smoke constituents, ingredients, or additives, that the Secretary determines should be disclosed to the public to protect the public health and will not mislead consumers about the risk of tobacco-related disease.


(c) AuthorityThe Secretary shall have the authority under this subchapter to conduct or to require the testing, reporting, or disclosure of tobacco product constituents, including smoke constituents.


(d) Small tobacco product manufacturers(1) First compliance dateThe initial regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall not impose requirements on small tobacco product manufacturers before the later of—(A) the end of the 2-year period following the final promulgation of such regulations; and

(B) the initial date set by the Secretary for compliance with such regulations by manufacturers that are not small</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing, reporting, and disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Testing, reporting, and disclosure Not later than 36 months after June 22, 2009, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations under this chapter that meet the requirements of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of rules The regulations promulgated under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority The Secretary shall have the authority under this subchapter to conduct or to require the testing, reporting, or disclosure of tobacco product constituents, including smoke constituents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small tobacco product manufacturers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Small tobacco product manufacturers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extensions for limited laboratory capacity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Extensions for limited laboratory capacity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387o_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule of construction Nothing in subsection (d) or (e) shall be construed to authorize the extension of any deadline, or to otherwise affect any timeframe, under any provision of this chapter or the Family Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act other than this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>