<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_387q"><akn:num>387q</akn:num><akn:heading>Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 387q. Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee(a) EstablishmentNot later than 6 months after June 22, 2009, the Secretary shall establish a 12-member advisory committee, to be known as the Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Committee”).


(b) Membership(1) In general(A) MembersThe Secretary shall appoint as members of the Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee individuals who are technically qualified by training and experience in medicine, medical ethics, science, or technology involving the manufacture, evaluation, or use of tobacco products, who are of appropriately diversified professional backgrounds. The committee shall be composed of—(i) 7 individuals who are physicians, dentists, scientists, or health care professionals practicing in the area of oncology, pulmonology, cardiology, toxicology, pharmacology, addiction, or any other relevant specialty;

(ii) 1 individual who is an officer or employee of a State or local government or of the Federal Government;

(iii) 1 individual as a representative of the general public;

(iv) 1 individual as a representative of the interests of the tobacco manufacturing industry;

(v) 1 individual as a representative of the interests of the small business tobacco manufacturing industry, which position may be filled on a rotating, sequential basis by representatives of different small business tobacco manufacturers based on areas of expertise relevant to the topics being considered by the Advisory Committee; and

(vi) 1 individual as a representative of the interests of the tobacco growers.


(B) Nonvoting membersThe members of the committee appointed under clauses (iv), (v), and (vi) of subparagraph (A) shall serve as consultants to those described in clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (A) and shall be nonvoting representatives.


(C) Conflicts of interestNo members of the committee, other than members appointed pursuant to clauses (iv), (v), and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Not later than 6 months after June 22, 2009, the Secretary shall establish a 12-member advisory committee, to be known as the Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Committee”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Tobacco Products Scientific Advisory Committee shall provide advice, information, and recommendations to the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation; support; chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation; support; chapter 10 of title 5</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387q_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings of advisory panels and committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Proceedings of advisory panels and committees The Advisory Committee shall make and maintain a transcript of any proceeding of the panel or committee. Each such panel and committee shall delete from any transcript made under this subsection information which is exempt from disclosure under section 552(b) of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>