<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/387t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_387t"><akn:num>387t</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling, recordkeeping, records inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 387t. Labeling, recordkeeping, records inspection(a) Origin labeling(1) RequirementBeginning 1 year after June 22, 2009, the label, packaging, and shipping containers of tobacco products other than cigarettes for introduction or delivery for introduction into interstate commerce in the United States shall bear the statement “sale only allowed in the United States”. Beginning 15 months after the issuance of the regulations required by section 1333(d) of title 15, as amended by section 201 of Family 11 So in original. Probably should be “the Family”. Smoking Prevention and Tobacco Control Act, the label, packaging, and shipping containers of cigarettes for introduction or delivery for introduction into interstate commerce in the United States shall bear the statement “Sale only allowed in the United States”.


(2) Effective dateThe effective date specified in paragraph (1) shall be with respect to the date of manufacture, provided that, in any case, beginning 30 days after such effective date, a manufacturer shall not introduce into the domestic commerce of the United States any product, irrespective of the date of manufacture, that is not in conformance with such paragraph.



(b) Regulations concerning recordkeeping for tracking and tracing(1) In generalThe Secretary shall promulgate regulations regarding the establishment and maintenance of records by any person who manufactures, processes, transports, distributes, receives, packages, holds, exports, or imports tobacco products.


(2) InspectionIn promulgating the regulations described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider which records are needed for inspection to monitor the movement of tobacco products from the point of manufacture through distribution to retail outlets to assist in investigating potential illicit trade, smuggling, or counterfeiting of tobacco products.


(3) CodesThe Secretary may require codes on the labels of tobacco products or other designs or devices for the purpose of tracking </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Origin labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Origin labeling</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations concerning recordkeeping for tracking and tracing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations concerning recordkeeping for tracking and tracing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Records inspection If the Secretary has a reasonable belief that a tobacco product is part of an illicit trade or smuggling or is a counterfeit product, each person who manufactures, processes, transports, distributes, receives, holds, packages, exports, or imports tobacco products shall, at the request of an officer or employee duly designated by the Secretary, permit such officer or employee, at reasonable times and within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner, upon the presentation of appropriate credentials and a written notice to such person, to have access to and copy all records (including financial records) relating to such article that are needed to assist the Secretary in investigating potential illicit trade, smuggling, or counterfeiting of tobacco products. The Secretary shall not authorize an officer or employee of the government of any of the several States to exercise authority under the preceding sentence on Indian country without the express written consent </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Knowledge of illegal transaction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Knowledge of illegal transaction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_387t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Attorney General of the United States and the Secretary of the Treasury, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>