<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/392" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/392/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/392/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_392"><akn:num>392</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption of meats and meat food products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 392. Exemption of meats and meat food products(a) Law determinative of exemptionMeats and meat food products shall be exempt from the provisions of this chapter to the extent of the application or the extension thereto of the Meat Inspection Act, approved March 4, 1907, as amended [21 U.S.C. 601 et seq.].


(b) Laws unaffectedNothing contained in this chapter shall be construed as in any way affecting, modifying, repealing, or superseding the provisions of section 351 of Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262] (relating to viruses, serums, toxins, and analogous products applicable to man); the virus, serum, toxin, and analogous products provisions, applicable to domestic animals, of the Act of Congress approved March 4, 1913 (37 Stat. 832–833) [21 U.S.C. 151 et seq.]; the Filled Cheese Act of June 6, 1896 (U.S.C., 1934 ed., title 26, ch. 10), the Filled Milk Act of March 4, 1923 [21 U.S.C. 61 et seq.]; or the Import Milk Act of February 15, 1927 [21 U.S.C. 141 et seq.].


(June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 1002(b), (c), formerly § 902(b), (c), 52 Stat. 1059; Pub. L. 90–399, § 107, July 13, 1968, 82 Stat. 353; renumbered § 1002(b), (c), Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title I, § 101(b)(2), June 22, 2009, 123 Stat. 1784.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Meat Inspection Act, approved March 4, 1907, as amended, referred to in subsec. (a), is act Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907, titles I to IV, as added Dec. 15, 1967, Pub. L. 90–201, 81 Stat. 584, which are classified generally to subchapters I to IV (§ 601 et seq.) of chapter 12 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 601 of this title and Tables.
Act of March 4, 1913, referred to in subsec. (b), is act Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 145, 37 Stat. 828. The provisions of such act referred to relating to viruses, etc., applicable to domestic animals, are contained in the eighth paragraph under the heading “Bureau of Animal Industry”, 37 Stat. 832, as amended, popularly known as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_392_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law determinative of exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Law determinative of exemption Meats and meat food products shall be exempt from the provisions of this chapter to the extent of the application or the extension thereto of the Meat Inspection Act, approved March 4, 1907, as amended [21 U.S.C. 601 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_392_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Laws unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Laws unaffected Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed as in any way affecting, modifying, repealing, or superseding the provisions of section 351 of Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262] (relating to viruses, serums, toxins, and analogous products applicable to man); the virus, serum, toxin, and analogous products provisions, applicable to domestic animals, of the Act of Congress approved March 4, 1913 (37 Stat. 832–833) [21 U.S.C. 151 et seq.]; the Filled Cheese Act of June 6, 1896 (U.S.C., 1934 ed., title 26, ch. 10), the Filled Milk Act of March 4, 1923 [21 U.S.C. 61 et seq.]; or the Import Milk Act of February 15, 1927 [21 U.S.C. 141 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>