<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_399"><akn:num>399</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to enhance food safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 399. Grants to enhance food safety(a) In generalThe Secretary is authorized to make grants to eligible entities to—(1) undertake examinations, inspections, and investigations, and related food safety activities under section 372 of this title;

(2) train to the standards of the Secretary for the examination, inspection, and investigation of food manufacturing, processing, packing, holding, distribution, and importation, including as such examination, inspection, and investigation relate to retail food establishments;

(3) build the food safety capacity of the laboratories of such eligible entity, including the detection of zoonotic diseases;

(4) build the infrastructure and capacity of the food safety programs of such eligible entity to meet the standards as outlined in the grant application; and

(5) take appropriate action to protect the public health in response to—(A) a notification under section 398 of this title, including planning and otherwise preparing to take such action; or

(B) a recall of food under this chapter.



(b) Eligible entities; application(1) In generalIn this section, the term “eligible entity” means an entity—(A) that is—(i) a State;

(ii) a locality;

(iii) a territory;

(iv) an Indian tribe (as defined in section 5304(e) of title 25); or

(v) a nonprofit food safety training entity that collaborates with 1 or more institutions of higher education; and


(B) that submits an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and including such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.


(2) ContentsEach application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—(A) an assurance that the eligible entity has developed plans to engage in the types of activities described in subsection (a);

(B) a description of the types of activities to be funded by the grant;

(C) an itemization of how grant funds received under this section will be expended;

(D) a description of how grant activities will be monitored; and

(E) an agreeme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary is authorized to make grants to eligible entities to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities; application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entities; application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations The funds provided under subsection (a) shall be available to an eligible entity that receives a grant under this section only to the extent such entity funds the food safety programs of such entity independently of any grant under this section in each year of the grant at a level equal to the level of such funding in the previous year, increased by the Consumer Price Index. Such non-Federal matching funds may be provided directly or through donations from public or private entities and may be in cash or in-kind, fairly evaluated, including plant, equipment, or services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional authority The Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duration of awards The Secretary may award grants to an individual grant recipient under this section for periods of not more than 3 years. In the event the Secretary conducts a program evaluation, funding in the second year or third year of the grant, where applicable, shall be contingent on a successful program evaluation by the Secretary after the first year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Progress and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Progress and evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Supplement not supplant Grant funds received under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, non-Federal funds and any other Federal funds available to carry out the activities described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of making grants under this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2011 through 2015.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>