<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_399b"><akn:num>399b</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Women’s Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 399b. Office of Women’s Health(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Office of the Commissioner, an office to be known as the Office of Women’s Health (referred to in this section as the “Office”). The Office shall be headed by a director who shall be appointed by the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.


(b) PurposeThe Director of the Office shall—(1) report to the Commissioner of Food and Drugs on current Food and Drug Administration (referred to in this section as the “Administration”) levels of activity regarding women’s participation in clinical trials and the analysis of data by sex in the testing of drugs, medical devices, and biological products across, where appropriate, age, biological, and sociocultural contexts;

(2) establish short-range and long-range goals and objectives within the Administration for issues of particular concern to women’s health within the jurisdiction of the Administration, including, where relevant and appropriate, adequate inclusion of women and analysis of data by sex in Administration protocols and policies;

(3) provide information to women and health care providers on those areas in which differences between men and women exist;

(4) consult with pharmaceutical, biologics, and device manufacturers, health professionals with expertise in women’s issues, consumer organizations, and women’s health professionals on Administration policy with regard to women;

(5) make annual estimates of funds needed to monitor clinical trials and analysis of data by sex in accordance with needs that are identified; and

(6) serve as a member of the Department of Health and Human Services Coordinating Committee on Women’s Health (established under section 237a(b)(4) of title 42).


(c) Authorization of appropriationsFor the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2010 through 2014.


(June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 1011, as added Pub. L. 111–148, ti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Office of the Commissioner, an office to be known as the Office of Women’s Health (referred to in this section as the “Office”). The Office shall be headed by a director who shall be appointed by the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The Director of the Office shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2010 through 2014.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>