<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_399h"><akn:num>399h</akn:num><akn:heading>National Centers of Excellence in Advanced and Continuous Pharmaceutical Manufacturing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 399h. National Centers of Excellence in Advanced and Continuous Pharmaceutical Manufacturing(a) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs—(1) may, to support the advancement, development, and implementation of advanced and continuous pharmaceutical manufacturing—(A) solicit requests for designation as National Centers of Excellence in Advanced and Continuous Pharmaceutical Manufacturing (in this section referred to as a “National Center of Excellence”);

(B) beginning not later than one year after December 29, 2022, designate as National Centers of Excellence institutions of higher education or consortia of institutions of higher education that—(i) request such designation; and

(ii) meet the eligibility criteria specified in subsection (c); and


(C) award grants to such institutions or consortia of institutions; and


(2) shall so designate not more than 5 institutions of higher education or consortia of such institutions.


(b) Request for designationA request for designation under subsection (a) shall be made to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(c) Eligibility criteria for designationTo be eligible to receive a designation under this section, an institution of higher education or consortium of institutions of higher education shall include in its request for designation a description of the institution’s or consortium’s—(1) physical capacity and technical capabilities to conduct advanced research on, and to develop and implement, advanced and continuous pharmaceutical manufacturing;

(2) collaboration or partnerships with other institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, and large and small pharmaceutical manufacturers, including generic and nonprescription manufacturers, contract manufacturers, and other relevant entities;

(3) proven capacity to design, develop, implement, and demonstrate new, highly effectiv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Request for designation A request for designation under subsection (a) shall be made to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility criteria for designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility criteria for designation To be eligible to receive a designation under this section, an institution of higher education or consortium of institutions of higher education shall include in its request for designation a description of the institution’s or consortium’s—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination of designation The Secretary may terminate the designation of any National Center of Excellence designated under this section if the Secretary determines such National Center of Excellence no longer meets the criteria specified in subsection (c). Not later than 90 days before the effective date of such a termination, the Secretary shall provide written notice to the National Center of Excellence, including the rationale for such termination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conditions for designation As a condition of designation as a National Center of Excellence under this section, the Secretary shall require that an institution of higher education or consortium of institutions of higher education enter into an agreement with the Secretary under which the institution or consortium agrees—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399h_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399h_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual review and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Annual review and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399h_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399h_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>