<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/399i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_399i"><akn:num>399i</akn:num><akn:heading>Food and Drug Administration Working Capital Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 399i. Food and Drug Administration Working Capital Fund(a) In generalThere is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a Working Capital Fund (the Fund) to be administered by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), without fiscal year limitation, for the payment of salaries, travel, and other expenses necessary to the maintenance and operation of (1) a supply service for the purchase, storage, handling, issuance, packing, or shipping of stationery, supplies, materials, equipment, and blank forms, for which stocks may be maintained to meet, in whole or in part, the needs of the FDA and requisitions of other Government Offices, and (2) such other services as the Commissioner of the FDA, subject to review by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, determines may be performed more advantageously as central services. The Fund shall be reimbursed from applicable discretionary resources, notwithstanding any otherwise applicable purpose limitations, available when services are performed or stock furnished, or in advance, on a basis of rates which shall include estimated or actual charges for personal services, materials, equipment, information technology, and other expenses. Charges for equipment and information technology shall include costs associated with maintenance, repair, and depreciation (including improvement and replacement).


(b) AppropriationsOf any discretionary resources appropriated in this Act for fiscal year 2018 for “Department of Health and Human Services, Food and Drug Administration, Salaries and Expenses”, not to exceed $5,000,000 of amounts available as of September 30 may be transferred to and merged with the Fund established under subsection (a), notwithstanding any otherwise applicable purpose limitations.


(c) Emergency funds excludedNo amounts may be transferred pursuant to this section that are designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a Working Capital Fund (the Fund) to be administered by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), without fiscal year limitation, for the payment of salaries, travel, and other expenses necessary to the maintenance and operation of (1) a supply service for the purchase, storage, handling, issuance, packing, or shipping of stationery, supplies, materials, equipment, and blank forms, for which stocks may be maintained to meet, in whole or in part, the needs of the FDA and requisitions of other Government Offices, and (2) such other services as the Commissioner of the FDA, subject to review by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, determines may be performed more advantageously as central services. The Fund shall be reimbursed from applicable discretionary resources, notwithstanding any otherwise applicable purpose limitations, available when services are performed or stock furnished, or in advance, on a b</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appropriations Of any discretionary resources appropriated in this Act for fiscal year 2018 for “Department of Health and Human Services, Food and Drug Administration, Salaries and Expenses”, not to exceed $5,000,000 of amounts available as of September 30 may be transferred to and merged with the Fund established under subsection (a), notwithstanding any otherwise applicable purpose limitations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_399i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency funds excluded</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Emergency funds excluded No amounts may be transferred pursuant to this section that are designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>