<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/454" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/454/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/454/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_454"><akn:num>454</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal and State cooperation in development and administration of State poultry product inspection </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 454. Federal and State cooperation in development and administration of State poultry product inspection programs(a) State laws; planning, technical and financial assistance; advisory committeesIt is the policy of the Congress to protect the consuming public from poultry products that are adulterated or misbranded and to assist in efforts by State and other government agencies to accomplish this objective. In furtherance of this policy—(1) The Secretary is authorized, whenever he determines that it would effectuate the purposes of this chapter, to cooperate with the appropriate State agency in developing and administering a State poultry product inspection program in any State which has enacted a mandatory State poultry product inspection law that imposes ante mortem and post mortem inspection, reinspection and sanitation requirements that are at least equal to those under this chapter, with respect to all or certain classes of persons engaged in the State in slaughtering poultry or processing poultry products for use as human food solely for distribution within such State.

(2) The Secretary is further authorized, whenever he determines that it would effectuate the purposes of this chapter, to cooperate with appropriate State agencies in developing and administering State programs under State laws containing authorities at least equal to those provided in section 460 of this title; and to cooperate with other agencies of the United States in carrying out any provisions of this chapter. In carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Secretary may conduct such examinations, investigations, and inspections as he determines practicable through any officer or employee of any State or Territory or the District of Columbia commissioned by the Secretary for such purpose.

(3) Cooperation with State agencies under this section may include furnishing to the appropriate State agency (i) advisory assistance in planning and otherwise developing an adequate State program </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_454_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State laws; planning, technical and financial assistance; advisory committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State laws; planning, technical and financial assistance; advisory committees It is the policy of the Congress to protect the consuming public from poultry products that are adulterated or misbranded and to assist in efforts by State and other government agencies to accomplish this objective. In furtherance of this policy—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_454_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate State agency; performance of functions by subordinate governmental unit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appropriate State agency; performance of functions by subordinate governmental unit The appropriate State agency with which the Secretary may cooperate under this chapter shall be a single agency in the State which is primarily responsible for the coordination of the State programs having objectives similar to those under this chapter. When the State program includes performance of certain functions by a municipality or other subordinate governmental unit, such unit shall be deemed to be a part of the State agency for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_454_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intrastate activities; designation of State for regulation; publication of designation; exempted operations; termination of designation; review of operations in nondesignated States; annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Intrastate activities; designation of State for regulation; publication of designation; exempted operations; termination of designation; review of operations in nondesignated States; annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_454_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“State” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “State” defined As used in this section, the term “State” means any State (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico) or organized territory.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>