<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/473" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/473/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/473/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_473"><akn:num>473</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for improvements to meat and poultry facilities to allow for interstate shipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 473. Grants for improvements to meat and poultry facilities to allow for interstate shipment(a) In generalThe Secretary shall make grants to meat and poultry slaughter and processing facilities described in subsection (b) (including such facilities operating under State inspection or such facilities that are exempt from Federal inspection) to assist such facilities with respect to costs incurred in making improvements to such facilities and carrying out other planning activities necessary—(1) to obtain a Federal grant of inspection under the Federal Meat Inspection Act (21 U.S.C. 601 et seq.) or the Poultry Products Inspection Act (21 U.S.C. 451 et seq.), as applicable; or

(2) to operate as a State-inspected facility that is compliant with—(A) the Federal Meat Inspection Act (21 U.S.C. 601 et seq.) under the cooperative interstate shipment program established under section 501 of that Act (21 U.S.C. 683); or

(B) the Poultry Products Inspection Act (21 U.S.C. 451 et seq.) under the cooperative interstate shipment program established under section 31 of that Act (21 U.S.C. 472).



(b) Eligible facilitiesTo be eligible for a grant under this section, a meat or poultry slaughter or processing facility shall be—(1) in operation as of the date on which the facility submits to the Secretary an application for the grant; and

(2) seeking—(A) to obtain a Federal grant of inspection described in subsection (a)(1); or

(B) to be eligible for inspection under a cooperative interstate shipment program described in subparagraph (A) or (B), as applicable, of subsection (a)(2), in a State that participates in that program.



(c) Eligible activitiesA facility that receives a grant under this section may use the grant amount for—(1) the modernization or expansion of existing facilities;

(2) the modernization of equipment;

(3) compliance with packaging and labeling requirements under applicable law;

(4) compliance with safety requirements under applicable law;

(5) the develo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_473_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall make grants to meat and poultry slaughter and processing facilities described in subsection (b) (including such facilities operating under State inspection or such facilities that are exempt from Federal inspection) to assist such facilities with respect to costs incurred in making improvements to such facilities and carrying out other planning activities necessary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_473_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible facilities To be eligible for a grant under this section, a meat or poultry slaughter or processing facility shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_473_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible activities A facility that receives a grant under this section may use the grant amount for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_473_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_473_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_473_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding Of the funds of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there is appropriated to carry out this section $60,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2021 through 2023, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>