<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/609" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/609/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/609/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_609"><akn:num>609</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of animals and food products thereof, slaughtered and prepared during nighttime</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 609. Examination of animals and food products thereof, slaughtered and prepared during nighttime
The Secretary shall cause an examination and inspection of all amenable species, and the food products thereof, slaughtered and prepared in the establishments hereinbefore described for the purposes of commerce to be made during the nighttime as well as during the daytime when the slaughtering of said amenable species, or the preparation of said food products is conducted during the nighttime.
(Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907, title I, § 9, formerly 7th par., 34 Stat. 1262; renumbered § 9 and amended Pub. L. 90–201, §§ 1, 3, 12(a), Dec. 15, 1967, 81 Stat. 584, 588, 592; Pub. L. 99–641, title IV, § 403(d)(1), Nov. 10, 1986, 100 Stat. 3570; Pub. L. 109–97, title VII, § 798[(a)](1), Nov. 10, 2005, 119 Stat. 2166.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 77 of this title.

Amendments2005—Pub. L. 109–97 substituted “amenable species” for “cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, and other equines” in two places.
1986—Pub. L. 99–641 temporarily inserted “, except as provided in section 606 of this title,” after first reference to “other equines, and”. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1986 Amendment note below.
1967—Pub. L. 90–201, §§ 3, 12(a), struck out “interstate or foreign” before “commerce” and “of Agriculture” after “Secretary” and included horses, mules, and other equines in the list of animals, respectively.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2005 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 109–97 effective the day after 120 days after Nov. 10, 2005, see section 798(b) of Pub. L. 109–97, set out as a note under section 601 of this title.

Effective and Termination Dates of 1986 AmendmentPub. L. 99–641, title IV, § 403(d)(1), Nov. 10, 1986, 100 Stat. 3570, provided that the amendment made by that section is effective only during the 6-year period beginning Nov. 10, 1986.
Pub. L. 99–641, title IV, § 408, Nov. 10, 1986, 100 St</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>