<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/610" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/610/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/610/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_610"><akn:num>610</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 610. Prohibited acts
No person, firm, or corporation shall, with respect to any cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, or other equines, or any carcasses, parts of carcasses, meat or meat food products of any such animals—(a) Slaughtering animals or preparation of articles capable of use as human foodslaughter any such animals or prepare any such articles which are capable of use as human food at any establishment preparing any such articles for commerce, except in compliance with the requirements of this chapter;


(b) Humane methods of slaughterslaughter or handle in connection with slaughter any such animals in any manner not in accordance with the Act of August 27, 1958 (72 Stat. 862; 7 U.S.C. 1901–1906);


(c) Sales, transportation, and other transactionssell, transport, offer for sale or transportation, or receive for transportation, in commerce, (1) any such articles which (A) are capable of use as human food and (B) are adulterated or misbranded at the time of such sale, transportation, offer for sale or transportation, or receipt for transportation; or (2) any articles required to be inspected under this subchapter unless they have been so inspected and passed;


(d) Adulteration or misbrandingdo, with respect to any such articles which are capable of use as human food, any act while they are being transported in commerce or held for sale after such transportation, which is intended to cause or has the effect of causing such articles to be adulterated or misbranded.


(Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907, title I, § 10, formerly 8th par., 34 Stat. 1262; renumbered § 10 and amended Pub. L. 90–201, §§ 1, 7, Dec. 15, 1967, 81 Stat. 584, 589; Pub. L. 95–445, § 3, Oct. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 1069.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextAct of August 27, 1958, referred to in subsec. (b), is Pub. L. 85–765, Aug. 27, 1958, 72 Stat. 862, which is classified generally to chapter 48 (§ 1901 et seq.) of Title 7, Agriculture. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Slaughtering animals or preparation of articles capable of use as human food</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Slaughtering animals or preparation of articles capable of use as human food slaughter any such animals or prepare any such articles which are capable of use as human food at any establishment preparing any such articles for commerce, except in compliance with the requirements of this chapter;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Humane methods of slaughter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Humane methods of slaughter slaughter or handle in connection with slaughter any such animals in any manner not in accordance with the Act of August 27, 1958 (72 Stat. 862; 7 U.S.C. 1901–1906);</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales, transportation, and other transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sales, transportation, and other transactions sell, transport, offer for sale or transportation, or receive for transportation, in commerce, (1) any such articles which (A) are capable of use as human food and (B) are adulterated or misbranded at the time of such sale, transportation, offer for sale or transportation, or receipt for transportation; or (2) any articles required to be inspected under this subchapter unless they have been so inspected and passed;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_610_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adulteration or misbranding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adulteration or misbranding do, with respect to any such articles which are capable of use as human food, any act while they are being transported in commerce or held for sale after such transportation, which is intended to cause or has the effect of causing such articles to be adulterated or misbranded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>