<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_611"><akn:num>611</akn:num><akn:heading>Devices, marks, labels, and certificates; simulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 611. Devices, marks, labels, and certificates; simulations(a) Devices to be made under authorization of SecretaryNo brand manufacturer, printer, or other person, firm, or corporation shall cast, print, lithograph, or otherwise make any device containing any official mark or simulation thereof, or any label bearing any such mark or simulation, or any form of official certificate or simulation thereof, except as authorized by the Secretary.


(b) Other misconductNo person, firm, or corporation shall—(1) forge any official device, mark, or certificate;

(2) without authorization from the Secretary use any official device, mark, or certificate, or simulation thereof, or alter, detach, deface, or destroy any official device, mark, or certificate;

(3) contrary to the regulations prescribed by the Secretary, fail to use, or to detach, deface, or destroy any official device, mark, or certificate;

(4) knowingly possess, without promptly notifying the Secretary or his representative, any official device or any counterfeit, simulated, forged, or improperly altered official certificate or any device or label or any carcass of any animal, or part or product thereof, bearing any counterfeit, simulated, forged, or improperly altered official mark;

(5) knowingly make any false statement in any shipper’s certificate or other nonofficial or official certificate provided for in the regulations prescribed by the Secretary; or

(6) knowingly represent that any article has been inspected and passed, or exempted, under this chapter when, in fact, it has, respectively, not been so inspected and passed, or exempted.


(Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907, title I, § 11, formerly 9th par., 34 Stat. 1263; renumbered § 11 and amended Pub. L. 90–201, §§ 1, 8, Dec. 15, 1967, 81 Stat. 584, 589.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 79 of this title.

Amendments1967—Pub. L. 90–201, § 8, clarified application to brand manufacturers and printers of existing prohibition ag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_611_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Devices to be made under authorization of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Devices to be made under authorization of Secretary No brand manufacturer, printer, or other person, firm, or corporation shall cast, print, lithograph, or otherwise make any device containing any official mark or simulation thereof, or any label bearing any such mark or simulation, or any form of official certificate or simulation thereof, except as authorized by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_611_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other misconduct</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other misconduct No person, firm, or corporation shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>