<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/618" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/618/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/618/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_618"><akn:num>618</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of inspectors’ certificates, and of copies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 618. Delivery of inspectors’ certificates, and of copies
The inspectors provided for under this subchapter shall be authorized to give official certificates of the condition of the carcasses and products of amenable species; and one copy of every certificate granted under the provisions of this chapter shall be filed in the Department of Agriculture, another copy shall be delivered to the owner or shipper, and when the amenable species, or their carcasses and products are sent abroad, a third copy shall be delivered to the chief officer of the vessel on which the shipment shall be made.
(Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907, title I, § 18, formerly 16th par., 34 Stat. 1263; renumbered § 18 and amended Pub. L. 90–201, §§ 1, 12(a), (h), Dec. 15, 1967, 81 Stat. 584, 592; Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10418(b)(4), May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 508; Pub. L. 109–97, title VII, § 798[(a)](1), Nov. 10, 2005, 119 Stat. 2166.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
“Provided for under this subchapter” was in the original “provided for herein”.
Section was formerly classified to section 86 of this title.

Amendments2005—Pub. L. 109–97 substituted “amenable species” for “cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, and other equines” in two places.
2002—Pub. L. 107–171 substituted “of the carcasses and products of cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, and other equines” for “of the cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, and other equines, their carcasses and products as described in this subchapter”.
1967—Pub. L. 90–201, § 12(a), (h), included horses, mules, and other equines in the list of animals and struck out “sound and wholesome” before “conditions”, respectively.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2005 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 109–97 effective the day after 120 days after Nov. 10, 2005, see section 798(b) of Pub. L. 109–97, set out as a note under section 601 of this title.

Effective Date of 1967 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 90–201 effective Dec. 15, 1967, ex</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>