<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/619" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/619/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/619/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_619"><akn:num>619</akn:num><akn:heading>Marking, labeling, or other identification to show kinds of animals from which derived; separate est</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 619. Marking, labeling, or other identification to show kinds of animals from which derived; separate establishments for preparation and slaughtering activities
No person, firm, or corporation shall sell, transport, offer for sale or transportation, or receive for transportation, in commerce, any carcasses of species designated by regulations in effect on the day before November 10, 2005, or parts of such carcasses, or the meat or meat food products thereof, unless they are plainly and conspicuously marked or labeled or otherwise identified as required by regulations prescribed by the Secretary to show the kinds of animals from which they were derived. When required by the Secretary, with respect to establishments at which inspection is maintained under this subchapter, such animals and their carcasses, parts thereof, meat and meat food products shall be prepared in establishments separate from those in which other amenable species are slaughtered or their carcasses, parts thereof, meat or meat food products are prepared.
(Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907, title I, § 19, formerly 17th par., 34 Stat. 1264; renumbered § 19 and amended Pub. L. 90–201, §§ 1, 9, Dec. 15, 1967, 81 Stat. 584, 590; Pub. L. 109–97, title VII, § 798[(a)](3), Nov. 10, 2005, 119 Stat. 2166.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 87 of this title.

Amendments2005—Pub. L. 109–97 substituted “species designated by regulations in effect on the day before November 10, 2005,” for “horses, mules, or other equines” and “other amenable species” for “cattle, sheep, swine, or goats”.
1967—Pub. L. 90–201, § 9, substituted provisions for marking, labeling, or other identification of kinds of animals whence the articles are derived and for separate establishments for preparation and slaughtering activities for prohibition against transportation or sale of meat or meat food products without complying with inspection provisions. See section 610(b) of this title.

Statutory Notes and </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>