<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/620" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/620/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/620/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_620"><akn:num>620</akn:num><akn:heading>Imports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 620. Imports(a) Adulteration or misbranding prohibition; compliance with inspection, building construction standards, and other provisions; humane methods of slaughter; treatment as domestic articles subject to this chapter and food, drug, and cosmetic provisions; marking and labeling; personal consumption exemptionNo carcasses, parts of carcasses, meat or meat food products of cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, or other equines which are capable of use as human food, shall be imported into the United States if such articles are adulterated or misbranded and unless they comply with all the inspection, building, construction standards, and all other provisions of this chapter and regulations issued thereunder applicable to such articles in commerce within the United States. No such carcasses, parts of carcasses, meat or meat food products shall be imported into the United States unless the livestock from which they were produced was slaughtered and handled in connection with slaughter in accordance with the Act of August 27, 1958 (72 Stat. 862; 7 U.S.C. 1901–1906). All such imported articles shall, upon entry into the United States, be deemed and treated as domestic articles subject to the other provisions of this chapter and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.]: Provided, That they shall be marked and labeled as required by such regulations for imported articles: Provided further, That nothing in this section shall apply to any individual who purchases meat or meat products outside the United States for his own consumption except that the total amount of such meat or meat products shall not exceed fifty pounds.


(b) Terms and conditions for destructionThe Secretary may prescribe the terms and conditions for the destruction of all such articles which are imported contrary to this section, unless (1) they are exported by the consignee within the time fixed therefor by the Secretary, or (2) in the case of articles which are not i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adulteration or misbranding prohibition; compliance with inspection, building construction standards, and other provisions; humane methods of slaughter; treatment as domestic articles subject to this chapter and food, drug, and cosmetic provisions; marking and labeling; personal consumption exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Adulteration or misbranding prohibition; compliance with inspection, building construction standards, and other provisions; humane methods of slaughter; treatment as domestic articles subject to this chapter and food, drug, and cosmetic provisions; marking and labeling; personal consumption exemption No carcasses, parts of carcasses, meat or meat food products of cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, or other equines which are capable of use as human food, shall be imported into the United States if such articles are adulterated or misbranded and unless they comply with all the inspection, building, construction standards, and all other provisions of this chapter and regulations issued thereunder applicable to such articles in commerce within the United States. No such carcasses, parts of carcasses, meat or meat food products shall be imported into the United States unless the livestock from which they were produced was slaughtered and handled in connection with slaughter in </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions for destruction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions for destruction The Secretary may prescribe the terms and conditions for the destruction of all such articles which are imported contrary to this section, unless (1) they are exported by the consignee within the time fixed therefor by the Secretary, or (2) in the case of articles which are not in compliance with the chapter solely because of misbranding, such articles are brought into compliance with the chapter under supervision of authorized representatives of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of storage, cartage, and labor charges by owner or consignee; liens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of storage, cartage, and labor charges by owner or consignee; liens All charges for storage, cartage, and labor with respect to any article which is imported contrary to this section shall be paid by the owner or consignee, and in default of such payment shall constitute a lien against such article and any other article thereafter imported under this chapter by or for such owner or consignee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition The knowing importation of any article contrary to this section is prohibited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection and other standards; applicability, enforcement, etc.; certifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Inspection and other standards; applicability, enforcement, etc.; certifications Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all carcasses, parts of carcasses, meat, and meat food products of cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules, or other equines, capable of use as human food, offered for importation into the United States shall be subject to the inspection, sanitary, quality, species verification, and residue standards applied to products produced in the United States. Any such imported meat articles that do not meet such standards shall not be permitted entry in to the United States. The Secretary shall enforce this provision through (1) the imposition of random inspections for such species verification and for residues, and (2) random sampling and testing of internal organs and fat of the carcasses for residues at the point of slaughter by the exporting country in accordance with methods approved by the Secretary. Each foreign country from which such meat articles are offe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of animal drugs or antibiotics; terms and conditions; entry order violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Administration of animal drugs or antibiotics; terms and conditions; entry order violations The Secretary may prescribe terms and conditions under which amenable species that have been administered an animal drug or antibiotic banned for use in the United States may be imported for slaughter and human consumption. No person shall enter amenable species into the United States in violation of any order issued under this subsection by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_620_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reciprocal meat inspection requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reciprocal meat inspection requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>