<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/661" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/661/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/661/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_661"><akn:num>661</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal and State cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 661. Federal and State cooperation(a) Congressional statement of policyIt is the policy of the Congress to protect the consuming public from meat and meat food products that are adulterated or misbranded and to assist in efforts by State and other Government agencies to accomplish this objective. In furtherance of this policy—(1) Development and administration of State meat inspection program equal to subchapter I ante and post mortem inspection, reinspection, and sanitation requirementsThe Secretary is authorized, whenever he determines that it would effectuate the purposes of this chapter, to cooperate with the appropriate State agency in developing and administering a State meat inspection program in any State which has enacted a State meat inspection law that imposes mandatory ante mortem and post mortem inspection, reinspection and sanitation requirements that are at least equal to those under subchapter I of this chapter, with respect to all or certain classes of persons engaged in the State in slaughtering cattle, sheep, swine, goats, or equines, or preparing the carcasses, parts thereof, meat or meat food products, of any such animals for use as human food solely for distribution within such State.


(2) Development and administration of State program with authorities equal to subchapter II authorities; cooperation with Federal agenciesThe Secretary is further authorized, whenever he determines that it would effectuate the purposes of this chapter, to cooperate with appropriate State agencies in developing and administering State programs under State laws containing authorities at least equal to those provided in subchapter II of this chapter; and to cooperate with other agencies of the United States in carrying out any provisions of this chapter.


(3) Scope of cooperation: advisory assistance, technical and laboratory assistance and training, and financial and other aid; limitation on amount; equitable allocation of Federal funds; adequacy of State progr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional statement of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional statement of policy It is the policy of the Congress to protect the consuming public from meat and meat food products that are adulterated or misbranded and to assist in efforts by State and other Government agencies to accomplish this objective. In furtherance of this policy—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Single State agency; subordinate governmental unit as part of State agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Single State agency; subordinate governmental unit as part of State agency The appropriate State agency with which the Secretary may cooperate under this chapter shall be a single agency in the State which is primarily responsible for the coordination of the State programs having objectives similar to those under this chapter. When the State program includes performance of certain functions by a municipality or other subordinate governmental unit, such unit shall be deemed to be a part of the State agency for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State meat inspection requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State meat inspection requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_661_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“State” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “State” defined As used in this section, the term “State” means any State (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico) or organized Territory.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>