<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/7...14" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/7...14/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/7...14/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7___14"><akn:num>7...14</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 1002(a), formerly § 902(a), 52 Stat. 1059; renumbered § 1002(a),</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 7 to 14. Repealed. June 25, 1938, ch. 675, § 1002(a), formerly § 902(a), 52 Stat. 1059; renumbered § 1002(a), Pub. L. 111–31, div. A, title I, § 101(b)(2), June 22, 2009, 123 Stat. 1784

Section 7, act June 30, 1906, ch. 3915, § 6, 34 Stat. 769, defined “drug” and “food”. See section 321 of this title.


Section 8, act June 30, 1906, ch. 3915, § 7, 34 Stat. 769, deemed drugs to be adulterated when sold having a difference from recognized standards, except where there is an explanatory statement on or in container, and when sold below professed standard; confectioneries, when containing mineral substances, poisonous color or flavors, other deleterious ingredients, liquors or narcotics; food, when concerned with injurious mixtures, use of substitutes, abstraction of valuable constituents, concealment of damage or inferiority, deleterious ingredients, preservatives in shipment conditionally excepted, animal or vegetable substances unfit for food and products of animals diseased or having died otherwise than by slaughter. See sections 342 and 351 of this title.


Section 9, act June 30, 1906, ch. 3915, § 8, 34 Stat. 771, defined “misbranded” and provided for its application to drugs and food. See sections 343 and 352 of this title.


Section 10, acts June 30, 1906, ch. 3915, § 8, 34 Stat. 771; Aug. 23, 1912, ch. 352, 37 Stat. 416; Mar. 3, 1913, ch. 117, 37 Stat. 732; July 24, 1919, ch. 26, 41 Stat. 271; July 8, 1930, ch. 874, 46 Stat. 1019, deemed drugs to be misbranded when there is an imitation or use of name of other article, when there is removal and substitution of contents of package or failure to state on label quantity or proportion of narcotics therein, and when there is a false statement of curative or therapeutic effect; and food, when there is an imitation or use of name of other article, when there is a false label or brand removal and substitution of contents of package, or failure to state or label quantity or proportion of narcotics therein, when the </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>