<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/811" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/811/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/811/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_811"><akn:num>811</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority and criteria for classification of substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 811. Authority and criteria for classification of substances(a) Rules and regulations of Attorney General; hearingThe Attorney General shall apply the provisions of this subchapter to the controlled substances listed in the schedules established by section 812 of this title and to any other drug or other substance added to such schedules under this subchapter. Except as provided in subsections (d) and (e), the Attorney General may by rule—(1) add to such a schedule or transfer between such schedules any drug or other substance if he—(A) finds that such drug or other substance has a potential for abuse, and

(B) makes with respect to such drug or other substance the findings prescribed by subsection (b) of section 812 of this title for the schedule in which such drug is to be placed; or


(2) remove any drug or other substance from the schedules if he finds that the drug or other substance does not meet the requirements for inclusion in any schedule.


Rules of the Attorney General under this subsection shall be made on the record after opportunity for a hearing pursuant to the rulemaking procedures prescribed by subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5. Proceedings for the issuance, amendment, or repeal of such rules may be initiated by the Attorney General (1) on his own motion, (2) at the request of the Secretary, or (3) on the petition of any interested party.

(b) Evaluation of drugs and other substancesThe Attorney General shall, before initiating proceedings under subsection (a) to control a drug or other substance or to remove a drug or other substance entirely from the schedules, and after gathering the necessary data, request from the Secretary a scientific and medical evaluation, and his recommendations, as to whether such drug or other substance should be so controlled or removed as a controlled substance. In making such evaluation and recommendations, the Secretary shall consider the factors listed in paragraphs (2), (3), (6), (7), and (8) of subsection (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations of Attorney General; hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules and regulations of Attorney General; hearing The Attorney General shall apply the provisions of this subchapter to the controlled substances listed in the schedules established by section 812 of this title and to any other drug or other substance added to such schedules under this subchapter. Except as provided in subsections (d) and (e), the Attorney General may by rule— Rules of the Attorney General under this subsection shall be made on the record after opportunity for a hearing pursuant to the rulemaking procedures prescribed by subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5. Proceedings for the issuance, amendment, or repeal of such rules may be initiated by the Attorney General (1) on his own motion, (2) at the request of the Secretary, or (3) on the petition of any interested party.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of drugs and other substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation of drugs and other substances The Attorney General shall, before initiating proceedings under subsection (a) to control a drug or other substance or to remove a drug or other substance entirely from the schedules, and after gathering the necessary data, request from the Secretary a scientific and medical evaluation, and his recommendations, as to whether such drug or other substance should be so controlled or removed as a controlled substance. In making such evaluation and recommendations, the Secretary shall consider the factors listed in paragraphs (2), (3), (6), (7), and (8) of subsection (c) and any scientific or medical considerations involved in paragraphs (1), (4), and (5) of such subsection. The recommendations of the Secretary shall include recommendations with respect to the appropriate schedule, if any, under which such drug or other substance should be listed. The evaluation and the recommendations of the Secretary shall be made in writing and submitted to th</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors determinative of control or removal from schedules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Factors determinative of control or removal from schedules In making any finding under subsection (a) of this section or under subsection (b) of section 812 of this title, the Attorney General shall consider the following factors with respect to each drug or other substance proposed to be controlled or removed from the schedules:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>International treaties, conventions, and protocols requiring control; procedures respecting changes in drug schedules of Convention on Psychotropic Substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) International treaties, conventions, and protocols requiring control; procedures respecting changes in drug schedules of Convention on Psychotropic Substances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immediate precursors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Immediate precursors The Attorney General may, without regard to the findings required by subsection (a) of this section or section 812(b) of this title and without regard to the procedures prescribed by subsections (a) and (b) of this section, place an immediate precursor in the same schedule in which the controlled substance of which it is an immediate precursor is placed or in any other schedule with a higher numerical designation. If the Attorney General designates a substance as an immediate precursor and places it in a schedule, other substances shall not be placed in a schedule solely because they are its precursors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Abuse potential</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Abuse potential If, at the time a new-drug application is submitted to the Secretary for any drug having a stimulant, depressant, or hallucinogenic effect on the central nervous system, it appears that such drug has an abuse potential, such information shall be forwarded by the Secretary to the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of non-narcotic substances sold over the counter without a prescription; dextromethorphan; exemption of substances lacking abuse potential</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exclusion of non-narcotic substances sold over the counter without a prescription; dextromethorphan; exemption of substances lacking abuse potential</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary scheduling to avoid imminent hazards to public safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Temporary scheduling to avoid imminent hazards to public safety</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary and permanent scheduling of recently emerged anabolic steroids</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Temporary and permanent scheduling of recently emerged anabolic steroids</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_811_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim final rule; date of issuance; procedure for final rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Interim final rule; date of issuance; procedure for final rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>