<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/825" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/825/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/825/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_825"><akn:num>825</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling and packaging</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 825. Labeling and packaging(a) SymbolIt shall be unlawful to distribute a controlled substance in a commercial container unless such container, when and as required by regulations of the Attorney General, bears a label (as defined in section 321(k) of this title) containing an identifying symbol for such substance in accordance with such regulations. A different symbol shall be required for each schedule of controlled substances.


(b) Unlawful distribution without identifying symbolIt shall be unlawful for the manufacturer of any controlled substance to distribute such substance unless the labeling (as defined in section 321(m) of this title) of such substance contains, when and as required by regulations of the Attorney General, the identifying symbol required under subsection (a).


(c) Warning on labelThe Secretary shall prescribe regulations under section 353(b) of this title which shall provide that the label of a drug listed in schedule II, III, or IV shall, when dispensed to or for a patient, contain a clear, concise warning that it is a crime to transfer the drug to any person other than the patient.


(d) Containers to be securely sealedIt shall be unlawful to distribute controlled substances in schedule I or II, and narcotic drugs in schedule III or IV, unless the bottle or other container, stopper, covering, or wrapper thereof is securely sealed as required by regulations of the Attorney General.


(e) False labeling of anabolic steroids(1) It shall be unlawful to import, export, manufacture, distribute, dispense, or possess with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense, an anabolic steroid or product containing an anabolic steroid, unless the steroid or product bears a label clearly identifying an anabolic steroid or product containing an anabolic steroid by the nomenclature used by the International Union of Pure and Applied Chemistry (IUPAC).

(2)(A) A product described in subparagraph (B) is exempt from the International Union of Pure and App</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_825_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Symbol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Symbol It shall be unlawful to distribute a controlled substance in a commercial container unless such container, when and as required by regulations of the Attorney General, bears a label (as defined in section 321(k) of this title) containing an identifying symbol for such substance in accordance with such regulations. A different symbol shall be required for each schedule of controlled substances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_825_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful distribution without identifying symbol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Unlawful distribution without identifying symbol It shall be unlawful for the manufacturer of any controlled substance to distribute such substance unless the labeling (as defined in section 321(m) of this title) of such substance contains, when and as required by regulations of the Attorney General, the identifying symbol required under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_825_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Warning on label</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Warning on label The Secretary shall prescribe regulations under section 353(b) of this title which shall provide that the label of a drug listed in schedule II, III, or IV shall, when dispensed to or for a patient, contain a clear, concise warning that it is a crime to transfer the drug to any person other than the patient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_825_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Containers to be securely sealed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Containers to be securely sealed It shall be unlawful to distribute controlled substances in schedule I or II, and narcotic drugs in schedule III or IV, unless the bottle or other container, stopper, covering, or wrapper thereof is securely sealed as required by regulations of the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_825_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>False labeling of anabolic steroids</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) False labeling of anabolic steroids</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>