<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/827" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/827/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/827/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_827"><akn:num>827</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and reports of registrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 827. Records and reports of registrants(a) InventoryExcept as provided in subsection (c)—(1) every registrant under this subchapter shall, on May 1, 1971, or as soon thereafter as such registrant first engages in the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of controlled substances, and every second year thereafter, make a complete and accurate record of all stocks thereof on hand, except that the regulations prescribed under this section shall permit each such biennial inventory (following the initial inventory required by this paragraph) to be prepared on such registrant’s regular general physical inventory date (if any) which is nearest to and does not vary by more than six months from the biennial date that would otherwise apply;

(2) on the effective date of each regulation of the Attorney General controlling a substance that immediately prior to such date was not a controlled substance, each registrant under this subchapter manufacturing, distributing, or dispensing such substance shall make a complete and accurate record of all stocks thereof on hand; and

(3) on and after May 1, 1971, every registrant under this subchapter manufacturing, distributing, or dispensing a controlled substance or substances shall maintain, on a current basis, a complete and accurate record of each such substance manufactured, received, sold, delivered, or otherwise disposed of by him, except that this paragraph shall not require the maintenance of a perpetual inventory.


(b) Availability of recordsEvery inventory or other record required under this section (1) shall be in accordance with, and contain such relevant information as may be required by, regulations of the Attorney General, (2) shall (A) be maintained separately from all other records of the registrant, or (B) alternatively, in the case of nonnarcotic controlled substances, be in such form that information required by the Attorney General is readily retrievable from the ordinary business records of the registrant, an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inventory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Inventory Except as provided in subsection (c)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of records Every inventory or other record required under this section (1) shall be in accordance with, and contain such relevant information as may be required by, regulations of the Attorney General, (2) shall (A) be maintained separately from all other records of the registrant, or (B) alternatively, in the case of nonnarcotic controlled substances, be in such form that information required by the Attorney General is readily retrievable from the ordinary business records of the registrant, and (3) shall be kept and be available, for at least two years, for inspection and copying by officers or employees of the United States authorized by the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nonapplicability The foregoing provisions of this section shall not apply— Nothing in the Convention on Psychotropic Substances shall be construed as superseding or otherwise affecting the provisions of paragraph (1)(B), (2), or (3) of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic reports to Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Periodic reports to Attorney General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting and recordkeeping requirements of drug conventions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporting and recordkeeping requirements of drug conventions In addition to the reporting and recordkeeping requirements under any other provision of this subchapter, each manufacturer registered under section 823 of this title shall, with respect to narcotic and nonnarcotic controlled substances manufactured by it, make such reports to the Attorney General, and maintain such records, as the Attorney General may require to enable the United States to meet its obligations under articles 19 and 20 of the Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs and article 16 of the Convention on Psychotropic Substances. The Attorney General shall administer the requirements of this subsection in such a manner as to avoid the unnecessary imposition of duplicative requirements under this subchapter on manufacturers subject to the requirements of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and reports of registrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Records and reports of registrants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigational uses of drugs; procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Investigational uses of drugs; procedures Regulations under sections 355(i) and 360(j) of this title, relating to investigational use of drugs, shall include such procedures as the Secretary, after consultation with the Attorney General, determines are necessary to insure the security and accountability of controlled substances used in research to which such regulations apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change of address</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Change of address Every registrant under this subchapter shall be required to report any change of professional or business address in such manner as the Attorney General shall by regulation require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements for GHB</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reporting requirements for GHB In the case of a drug product containing gamma hydroxybutyric acid for which an application has been approved under section 355 of this title, the Attorney General may, in addition to any other requirements that apply under this section with respect to such a drug product, establish any of the following as reporting requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_827_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic reporting format</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Electronic reporting format All of the reports required under this section shall be provided in an electronic format.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>