<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/831" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/831/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/831/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_831"><akn:num>831</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements relating to online pharmacies and telemedicine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 831. Additional requirements relating to online pharmacies and telemedicine(a) In generalAn online pharmacy shall display in a visible and clear manner on its homepage a statement that it complies with the requirements of this section with respect to the delivery or sale or offer for sale of controlled substances and shall at all times display on the homepage of its Internet site a declaration of compliance in accordance with this section.


(b) LicensureEach online pharmacy shall comply with the requirements of State law concerning the licensure of pharmacies in each State from which it, and in each State to which it, delivers, distributes, or dispenses or offers to deliver, distribute, or dispense controlled substances by means of the Internet, pursuant to applicable licensure requirements, as determined by each such State.


(c) Internet pharmacy site disclosure informationEach online pharmacy shall post in a visible and clear manner on the homepage of each Internet site it operates, or on a page directly linked thereto in which the hyperlink is also visible and clear on the homepage, the following information for each pharmacy that delivers, distributes, or dispenses controlled substances pursuant to orders made on, through, or on behalf of, that website:(1) The name and address of the pharmacy as it appears on the pharmacy’s Drug Enforcement Administration certificate of registration.

(2) The pharmacy’s telephone number and email address.

(3) The name, professional degree, and States of licensure of the pharmacist-in-charge, and a telephone number at which the pharmacist-in-charge can be contacted.

(4) A list of the States in which the pharmacy is licensed to dispense controlled substances.

(5) A certification that the pharmacy is registered under this part to deliver, distribute, or dispense by means of the Internet controlled substances.

(6) The name, address, telephone number, professional degree, and States of licensure of any practitioner who has a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general An online pharmacy shall display in a visible and clear manner on its homepage a statement that it complies with the requirements of this section with respect to the delivery or sale or offer for sale of controlled substances and shall at all times display on the homepage of its Internet site a declaration of compliance in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Licensure Each online pharmacy shall comply with the requirements of State law concerning the licensure of pharmacies in each State from which it, and in each State to which it, delivers, distributes, or dispenses or offers to deliver, distribute, or dispense controlled substances by means of the Internet, pursuant to applicable licensure requirements, as determined by each such State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Internet pharmacy site disclosure information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Internet pharmacy site disclosure information Each online pharmacy shall post in a visible and clear manner on the homepage of each Internet site it operates, or on a page directly linked thereto in which the hyperlink is also visible and clear on the homepage, the following information for each pharmacy that delivers, distributes, or dispenses controlled substances pursuant to orders made on, through, or on behalf of, that website:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Declaration of compliance On and after the date on which it makes the notification under subsection (d), each online pharmacy shall display on the homepage of its Internet site, in such form as the Attorney General shall by regulation require, a declaration that it has made such notification to the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports Any statement, declaration, notification, or disclosure required under this section shall be considered a report required to be kept under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and designations concerning Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notice and designations concerning Indian tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special registration for telemedicine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special registration for telemedicine</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting of telemedicine by VHA during medical emergency situations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reporting of telemedicine by VHA during medical emergency situations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_831_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification concerning prescription transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Clarification concerning prescription transfers Any transfer between pharmacies of information relating to a prescription for a controlled substance shall meet the applicable requirements under regulations promulgated by the Attorney General under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>