<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/851" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/851/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/851/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_851"><akn:num>851</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceedings to establish prior convictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 851. Proceedings to establish prior convictions(a) Information filed by United States Attorney(1) No person who stands convicted of an offense under this part shall be sentenced to increased punishment by reason of one or more prior convictions, unless before trial, or before entry of a plea of guilty, the United States attorney files an information with the court (and serves a copy of such information on the person or counsel for the person) stating in writing the previous convictions to be relied upon. Upon a showing by the United States attorney that facts regarding prior convictions could not with due diligence be obtained prior to trial or before entry of a plea of guilty, the court may postpone the trial or the taking of the plea of guilty for a reasonable period for the purpose of obtaining such facts. Clerical mistakes in the information may be amended at any time prior to the pronouncement of sentence.

(2) An information may not be filed under this section if the increased punishment which may be imposed is imprisonment for a term in excess of three years unless the person either waived or was afforded prosecution by indictment for the offense for which such increased punishment may be imposed.


(b) Affirmation or denial of previous convictionIf the United States attorney files an information under this section, the court shall after conviction but before pronouncement of sentence inquire of the person with respect to whom the information was filed whether he affirms or denies that he has been previously convicted as alleged in the information, and shall inform him that any challenge to a prior conviction which is not made before sentence is imposed may not thereafter be raised to attack the sentence.


(c) Denial; written response; hearing(1) If the person denies any allegation of the information of prior conviction, or claims that any conviction alleged is invalid, he shall file a written response to the information. A copy of the response shall be se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_851_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information filed by United States Attorney</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information filed by United States Attorney</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_851_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affirmation or denial of previous conviction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Affirmation or denial of previous conviction If the United States attorney files an information under this section, the court shall after conviction but before pronouncement of sentence inquire of the person with respect to whom the information was filed whether he affirms or denies that he has been previously convicted as alleged in the information, and shall inform him that any challenge to a prior conviction which is not made before sentence is imposed may not thereafter be raised to attack the sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_851_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial; written response; hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Denial; written response; hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_851_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of sentence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Imposition of sentence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_851_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statute of limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Statute of limitations No person who stands convicted of an offense under this part may challenge the validity of any prior conviction alleged under this section which occurred more than five years before the date of the information alleging such prior conviction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>