<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/862" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/862/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/862/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_862"><akn:num>862</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of Federal benefits to drug traffickers and possessors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 862. Denial of Federal benefits to drug traffickers and possessors(a) Drug traffickers(1) Any individual who is convicted of any Federal or State offense consisting of the distribution of controlled substances shall—(A) at the discretion of the court, upon the first conviction for such an offense be ineligible for any or all Federal benefits for up to 5 years after such conviction;

(B) at the discretion of the court, upon a second conviction for such an offense be ineligible for any or all Federal benefits for up to 10 years after such conviction; and

(C) upon a third or subsequent conviction for such an offense be permanently ineligible for all Federal benefits.


(2) The benefits which are denied under this subsection shall not include benefits relating to long-term drug treatment programs for addiction for any person who, if there is a reasonable body of evidence to substantiate such declaration, declares himself to be an addict and submits himself to a long-term treatment program for addiction, or is deemed to be rehabilitated pursuant to rules established by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.


(b) Drug possessors(1) Any individual who is convicted of any Federal or State offense involving the possession of a controlled substance (as such term is defined for purposes of this subchapter) shall—(A) upon the first conviction for such an offense and at the discretion of the court—(i) be ineligible for any or all Federal benefits for up to one year;

(ii) be required to successfully complete an approved drug treatment program which includes periodic testing to insure that the individual remains drug free;

(iii) be required to perform appropriate community service; or

(iv) any combination of clause (i), (ii), or (iii); and


(B) upon a second or subsequent conviction for such an offense be ineligible for all Federal benefits for up to 5 years after such conviction as determined by the court. The court shall continue to have the discretion in subparagra</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_862_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug traffickers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Drug traffickers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_862_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug possessors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Drug possessors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_862_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of period of ineligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Suspension of period of ineligibility The period of ineligibility referred to in subsections (a) and (b) shall be suspended if the individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_862_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_862_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of this section to Government witnesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Inapplicability of this section to Government witnesses The penalties provided by this section shall not apply to any individual who cooperates or testifies with the Government in the prosecution of a Federal or State offense or who is in a Government witness protection program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_862_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Indian provision Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the obligation of the United States to any Indian or Indian tribe arising out of any treaty, statute, Executive order, or the trust responsibility of the United States owing to such Indian or Indian tribe. Nothing in this subsection shall exempt any individual Indian from the sanctions provided for in this section, provided that no individual Indian shall be denied any benefit under Federal Indian programs comparable to those described in subsection (d)(1)(B) or (d)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_862_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Presidential report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_862_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effective date The denial of Federal benefits set forth in this section shall take effect for convictions occurring after September 1, 1989.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>