<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/952" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/952/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/952/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_952"><akn:num>952</akn:num><akn:heading>Importation of controlled substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 952. Importation of controlled substances(a) Controlled substances in schedule I or II and narcotic drugs in schedule III, IV, or V; exceptionsIt shall be unlawful to import into the customs territory of the United States from any place outside thereof (but within the United States), or to import into the United States from any place outside thereof, any controlled substance in schedule I or II of subchapter I, or any narcotic drug in schedule III, IV, or V of subchapter I, or ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, or phenylpropanolamine, except that—(1) such amounts of crude opium, poppy straw, concentrate of poppy straw, and coca leaves, and of ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, and phenylpropanolamine, as the Attorney General finds to be necessary to provide for medical, scientific, or other legitimate purposes, and

(2) such amounts of any controlled substance in schedule I or II or any narcotic drug in schedule III, IV, or V that the Attorney General finds to be necessary to provide for the medical, scientific, or other legitimate needs of the United States—(A) during an emergency in which domestic supplies of such substance or drug are found by the Attorney General to be inadequate,

(B) in any case in which the Attorney General finds that competition among domestic manufacturers of the controlled substance is inadequate and will not be rendered adequate by the registration of additional manufacturers under section 823 of this title, or

(C) in any case in which the Attorney General finds that such controlled substance is in limited quantities exclusively for scientific, analytical, or research uses,



may be so imported under such regulations as the Attorney General shall prescribe. No crude opium may be so imported for the purpose of manufacturing heroin or smoking opium.

(b) Nonnarcotic controlled substances in schedule III, IV, or VIt shall be unlawful to import into the customs territory of the United States from any place outside thereof (but within the United States)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_952_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Controlled substances in schedule I or II and narcotic drugs in schedule III, IV, or V; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Controlled substances in schedule I or II and narcotic drugs in schedule III, IV, or V; exceptions It shall be unlawful to import into the customs territory of the United States from any place outside thereof (but within the United States), or to import into the United States from any place outside thereof, any controlled substance in schedule I or II of subchapter I, or any narcotic drug in schedule III, IV, or V of subchapter I, or ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, or phenylpropanolamine, except that— may be so imported under such regulations as the Attorney General shall prescribe. No crude opium may be so imported for the purpose of manufacturing heroin or smoking opium.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_952_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonnarcotic controlled substances in schedule III, IV, or V</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nonnarcotic controlled substances in schedule III, IV, or V It shall be unlawful to import into the customs territory of the United States from any place outside thereof (but within the United States), or to import into the United States from  any  place  outside  thereof,  any  non­narcotic controlled substance in schedule III, IV, or V, unless such nonnarcotic controlled substance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_952_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coca leaves</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coca leaves In addition to the amount of coca leaves authorized to be imported into the United States under subsection (a), the Attorney General may permit the importation of additional amounts of coca leaves. All cocaine and ecgonine (and all salts, derivatives, and preparations from which cocaine or ecgonine may be synthesized or made) contained in such additional amounts of coca leaves imported under this subsection shall be destroyed under the supervision of an authorized representative of the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_952_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for increased importation of ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, or phenylpropanolamine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application for increased importation of ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, or phenylpropanolamine</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_952_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reference to ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, or phenylpropanolamine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reference to ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, or phenylpropanolamine Each reference in this section to ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, or phenylpropanolamine includes each of the salts, optical isomers, and salts of optical isomers of such chemical.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>