<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/960" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/960/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/960/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_960"><akn:num>960</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited acts A</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 960. Prohibited acts A(a) Unlawful actsAny person who—(1) contrary to section 825, 952, 953, or 957 of this title, knowingly or intentionally imports or exports a controlled substance,

(2) contrary to section 955 of this title, knowingly or intentionally brings or possesses on board a vessel, aircraft, or vehicle a controlled substance, or

(3) contrary to section 959 of this title, manufactures, possesses with intent to distribute, or distributes a controlled substance,


shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).

(b) Penalties(1) In the case of a violation of subsection (a) of this section involving—(A) 1 kilogram or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectable amount of heroin;

(B) 5 kilograms or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectable amount of—(i) coca leaves, except coca leaves and extracts of coca leaves from which cocaine, ecgonine, and derivatives of ecgonine or their salts have been removed;

(ii) cocaine, its salts, optical and geometric isomers, and salts or isomers;

(iii) ecgonine, its derivatives, their salts, isomers, and salts of isomers; or

(iv) any compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of any of the substances referred to in clauses (i) through (iii);


(C) 280 grams or more of a mixture or substance described in subparagraph (B) which contains cocaine base;

(D) 100 grams or more of phencyclidine (PCP) or 1 kilogram or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectable amount of phencyclidine (PCP);

(E) 10 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectable amount of lysergic acid diethylamide (LSD);

(F) 400 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectable amount of N-phenyl-N- [1- ( 2-phenylethyl ) -4-piperidinyl] propanamide or 100 grams or more of a mixture or substance containing a detectable amount of any analogue of N-phenyl-N-[1-(2-phenylethyl)-4-piperidinyl] propanamide or a fentanyl-related substance;

(G) 1000 kilograms or more of a mixture or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unlawful acts Any person who— shall be punished as provided in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 225, formerly § 225(a), Oct. 12, 1984, 98 Stat. 2030, as amended by Pub. L. 99–570, title I, § 1005(c), Oct. 27, 1986, 100 Stat. 3207–6</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for importation or exportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Penalty for importation or exportation A person who knowingly or intentionally— shall be fined in accordance with title 18, imprisoned not more than 20 years in the case of a violation of paragraph (1) or (3) involving a list I chemical or not more than 10 years in the case of a violation of this subsection other than a violation of paragraph (1) or (3) involving a list I chemical, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>