<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/971" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/971/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/21/971/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_971"><akn:num>971</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification, suspension of shipment, and penalties with respect to importation and exportation of l</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 971. Notification, suspension of shipment, and penalties with respect to importation and exportation of listed chemicals(a) Notification prior to transactionEach regulated person who imports or exports a listed chemical shall notify the Attorney General of the importation or exportation not later than 15 days before the transaction is to take place.


(b) Regular customers or importers(1) The Attorney General shall provide by regulation for circumstances in which the requirement of subsection (a) does not apply to a transaction between a regulated person and a regular customer or to a transaction that is an importation by a regular importer. At the time of any importation or exportation constituting a transaction referred to in the preceding sentence, the regulated person shall notify the Attorney General of the transaction.

(2) The regulations under this subsection shall provide that the initial notification under subsection (a) with respect to a customer of a regulated person or to an importer shall, upon the expiration of the 15-day period, qualify the customer as a regular customer or the importer as a regular importer, unless the Attorney General otherwise notifies the regulated person in writing.


(c) Suspension of importation or exportation; disqualification of regular customers or importers; hearing(1) The Attorney General may order the suspension of any importation or exportation of a listed chemical (other than a regulated transaction to which the requirement of subsection (a) does not apply by reason of subsection (b)) or may disqualify any regular customer or regular importer on the ground that the chemical may be diverted to the clandestine manufacture of a controlled substance (without regard to the form of the chemical that may be diverted, including the diversion of a finished drug product to be manufactured from bulk chemicals to be transferred). From and after the time when the Attorney General provides written notice of the order (including a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification prior to transaction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notification prior to transaction Each regulated person who imports or exports a listed chemical shall notify the Attorney General of the importation or exportation not later than 15 days before the transaction is to take place.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regular customers or importers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regular customers or importers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of importation or exportation; disqualification of regular customers or importers; hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Suspension of importation or exportation; disqualification of regular customers or importers; hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information required in notice; updated notice for change in circumstances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information required in notice; updated notice for change in circumstances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Broker or trader for international transaction in listed chemical</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Broker or trader for international transaction in listed chemical A person located in the United States who is a broker or trader for an international transaction in a listed chemical that is a regulated transaction solely because of that person’s involvement as a broker or trader shall, with respect to that transaction, be subject to all of the notification, reporting, recordkeeping, and other requirements placed upon exporters of listed chemicals by this subchapter and subchapter I.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of notification requirement to exports of listed chemical; waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application of notification requirement to exports of listed chemical; waiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return declaration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Return declaration Within 30 days after a transaction covered by this section is completed, the importer or exporter shall send the Attorney General a return declaration containing particulars of the transaction, including the date, quantity, chemical, container, name of transferees, and such other information as the Attorney General may specify in regulations. For importers, a single return declaration may include the particulars of both the importation and distribution. If the importer has not distributed all chemicals imported by the end of the initial 30-day period, the importer shall file supplemental return declarations no later than 30 days from the date of any further distribution, until the distribution or other disposition of all chemicals imported pursuant to the import notification or any update are accounted for.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_971_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Importation and distribution of ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, or phenylpropanolamine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Importation and distribution of ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, or phenylpropanolamine</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>