<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/1103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/1103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/1103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1103"><akn:num>1103</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate of necessity; estimate of cost</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1103. Certificate of necessity; estimate of cost
When a department, the Supreme Court, or the Library of Congress requires printing or binding to be done, it shall certify that it is necessary for the public service. The Director of the Government Publishing Office shall then furnish an estimate of cost by principal items, after which requisitions may be made upon him for the printing or binding by the head of the department, the Clerk of the Supreme Court, or the Librarian of Congress, respectively. The Director of the Government Publishing Office shall place the cost to the debit of the department in its annual appropriation for printing and binding.
(Pub. L. 90–620, Oct. 22, 1968, 82 Stat. 1261; Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 159, Apr. 2, 1982, 96 Stat. 48; Pub. L. 113–235, div. H, title I, § 1301(c)(1), Dec. 16, 2014, 128 Stat. 2537.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on 44 U.S. Code, 1964 ed., § 117 (Jan. 12, 1895, ch. 23, § 93, 28 Stat. 623; June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32(a), 62 Stat. 991; May 24, 1949, ch. 139, sec. 127, 63 Stat. 107).

Editorial Notes
Amendments2014—Pub. L. 113–235 substituted “Director of the Government Publishing Office” for “Public Printer” in two places.
1982—Pub. L. 97–164 struck out the Court of Claims from the enumeration of entities for which printing or binding may be done for the public service and struck out the chief judge of the Court of Claims from the enumeration of officials who make requisitions upon the Public Printer for printing or binding.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1982 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 97–164 effective Oct. 1, 1982, see section 402 of Pub. L. 97–164, set out as a note under section 171 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>