<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/2102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/2102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/2102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2102"><akn:num>2102</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2102. Establishment
There shall be an independent establishment in the executive branch of the Government to be known as the National Archives and Records Administration. The Administration shall be administered under the supervision and direction of the Archivist.
(Pub. L. 90–620, Oct. 22, 1968, 82 Stat. 1287; Pub. L. 98–497, title I, § 101, Oct. 19, 1984, 98 Stat. 2280.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on 44 U.S. Code, 1964 ed., § 391(a) (June 30, 1949, ch. 288, title I, § 104, 63 Stat. 381).
This section incorporates only the last sentence of paragraph (a) of former section 391. The balance of that section will be found in sections 1506, 2301, 2501, and 2902 of the revision.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1984—Pub. L. 98–497 substituted provisions directing that there shall be an independent establishment in the executive branch of the Government to be known as the National Archives and Records Administration and that the Administration shall be administered under the supervision and direction of the Archivist for provisions which had formerly directed only that the Administrator of General Services appoint the Archivist of the United States.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1984 AmendmentPub. L. 98–497, title III, § 301, Oct. 19, 1984, 98 Stat. 2295, provided that: “The provisions of this Act [enacting sections 2103 to 2106 of this title and provisions set out as notes under this section and section 101 of this title, redesignating existing sections 2103 to 2114 as sections 2107 to 2118 of this title, amending this section, sections 710, 711, 729, 1501 to 1503, 1506, 1714, 2101, 2107 to 2118, 2204, 2205, 2301 to 2305, 2307, 2501, 2504, 2506, 2901 to 2909, 3102 to 3106, 3302 to 3303a, 3308, 3310, 3311, 3504, and 3513 of this title, provisions set out as a note under section 2111 of this title, sections 106a, 106b, 112, 113, and 201 of Title 1, General Provisions, sections 6 and 11 to 13 of Title 3, The President, sections 141 to 145 o</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>