<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/2109" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/2109/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/2109/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2109"><akn:num>2109</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation, arrangement, duplication, exhibition of records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2109. Preservation, arrangement, duplication, exhibition of records
The Archivist shall provide for the preservation, arrangement, repair and rehabilitation, duplication and reproduction (including microcopy publications), description, and exhibition of records or other documentary material transferred to him as may be needful or appropriate, including the preparation and publication of inventories, indexes, catalogs, and other finding aids or guides to facilitate their use. He may also prepare guides and other finding aids to Federal records and, when approved by the National Historical Publications and Records Commission, publish such historical works and collections of sources as seem appropriate for printing or otherwise recording at the public expense.
(Pub. L. 90–620, Oct. 22, 1968, 82 Stat. 1288, § 2105; renumbered § 2109 and amended Pub. L. 98–497, title I, §§ 102(a)(1), 107(a)(3), Oct. 19, 1984, 98 Stat. 2280, 2285.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on 44 U.S. Code, 1964 ed., § 397(c) (June 30, 1949, ch. 288, title V, § 507, as added Sept. 5, 1950, ch. 849, § 6(d), 64 Stat. 583; July 12, 1952, ch. 703, § 1(o), 66 Stat. 594).

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 2109 was renumbered section 2113 of this title.

Amendments1984—Pub. L. 98–497, § 107(a)(3), substituted “Archivist” for “Administrator of General Services” and inserted “and Records” after “National Historical Publications”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1984 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 98–497 effective Apr. 1, 1985, see section 301 of Pub. L. 98–497, set out as a note under section 2102 of this title.

Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 11440. Supplemental Use of Exhibits and Displays Created in Furtherance of Authorized Programs of Executive Departments and Agencies
Ex. Ord. No. 11440, Dec. 11, 1968, 33 F.R. 18475, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 12608, Sept. 9, 1987, 52 F.R. 34617, provided:
WHEREAS the executive departments and agencies of the Governmen</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>