<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3506" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3506/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3506/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3506"><akn:num>3506</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agency responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3506. Federal agency responsibilities(a)(1) The head of each agency shall be responsible for—(A) carrying out the agency’s information resources management activities to improve agency productivity, efficiency, and effectiveness; and

(B) complying with the requirements of this subchapter and related policies established by the Director.


(2)(A) Except as provided under subparagraph (B), the head of each agency shall designate a Chief Information Officer who shall report directly to such agency head to carry out the responsibilities of the agency under this subchapter.

(B) The Secretary of the Department of Defense and the Secretary of each military department may each designate Chief Information Officers who shall report directly to such Secretary to carry out the responsibilities of the department under this subchapter. If more than one Chief Information Officer is designated, the respective duties of the Chief Information Officers shall be clearly delineated.


(3) The Chief Information Officer designated under paragraph (2) shall head an office responsible for ensuring agency compliance with and prompt, efficient, and effective implementation of the information policies and information resources management responsibilities established under this subchapter, including the reduction of information collection burdens on the public. The Chief Information Officer and employees of such office shall be selected with special attention to the professional qualifications required to administer the functions described under this subchapter.

(4) Each agency program official shall be responsible and accountable for information resources assigned to and supporting the programs under such official. In consultation with the Chief Information Officer designated under paragraph (2) and the agency Chief Financial Officer (or comparable official), each agency program official shall define program information needs and develop strategies, systems, and capabilities to meet those</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3506_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3506_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) With respect to general information resources management, each agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3506_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) With respect to the collection of information and the control of paperwork, each agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3506_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) With respect to information dissemination, each agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3506_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) With respect to statistical policy and coordination, each agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3506_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) With respect to records management, each agency shall implement and enforce applicable policies and procedures, including requirements for archiving information maintained in electronic format, particularly in the planning, design and operation of information systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3506_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) With respect to privacy and security, each agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3506_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) With respect to Federal information technology, each agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3506_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>