<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3561" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3561/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3561/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3561"><akn:num>3561</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3561. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Agency.—The term “agency” means any entity that falls within the definition of the term “executive agency”, as defined in section 102 of title 31, or “agency”, as defined in section 3502.

(2) Agent.—The term “agent” means an individual—(A)(i) who is an employee of a private organization or a researcher affiliated with an institution of higher learning (including a person granted special sworn status by the Bureau of the Census under section 23(c) of title 13), and with whom a contract or other agreement is executed, on a temporary basis, by an executive agency to perform exclusively statistical activities under the control and supervision of an officer or employee of that agency;

(ii) who is working under the authority of a government entity with which a contract or other agreement is executed by an executive agency to perform exclusively statistical activities under the control of an officer or employee of that agency;

(iii) who is a self-employed researcher, a consultant, a contractor, or an employee of a contractor, and with whom a contract or other agreement is executed by an executive agency to perform a statistical activity under the control of an officer or employee of that agency; or

(iv) who is a contractor or an employee of a contractor, and who is engaged by the agency to design or maintain the systems for handling or storage of data received under this subchapter; and


(B) who agrees in writing to comply with all provisions of law that affect information acquired by that agency.


(3) Business data.—The term “business data” means operating and financial data and information about businesses, tax-exempt organizations, and government entities.

(4) Data asset.—The term “data asset” has the meaning given that term in section 3502.

(5) Director.—The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.

(6) Evidence.—The term “evidence” means information produced as a result of statistical</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “agency” means any entity that falls within the definition of the term “executive agency”, as defined in section 102 of title 31, or “agency”, as defined in section 3502.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “agent” means an individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Business data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “business data” means operating and financial data and information about businesses, tax-exempt organizations, and government entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data asset.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “data asset” has the meaning given that term in section 3502.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “Director” means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evidence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “evidence” means information produced as a result of statistical activities conducted for a statistical purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identifiable form.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “identifiable form” means any representation of information that permits the identity of the respondent to whom the information applies to be reasonably inferred by either direct or indirect means.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonstatistical purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “nonstatistical purpose”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Respondent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “respondent” means a person who, or organization that, is requested or required to supply information to an agency, is the subject of information requested or required to be supplied to an agency, or provides that information to an agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3561_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statistical activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “statistical activities”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>