<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3572" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3572/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3572/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3572"><akn:num>3572</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidential information protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3572. Confidential information protection(a) Purposes.—The purposes of this section are the following:(1) To ensure that information supplied by individuals or organizations to an agency for statistical purposes under a pledge of confidentiality is used exclusively for statistical purposes.

(2) To ensure that individuals or organizations who supply information under a pledge of confidentiality to agencies for statistical purposes will neither have that information disclosed in identifiable form to anyone not authorized by this subchapter nor have that information used for any purpose other than a statistical purpose.

(3) To safeguard the confidentiality of individually identifiable information acquired under a pledge of confidentiality for statistical purposes by controlling access to, and uses made of, such information.


(b) Use of Statistical Data or Information.—Data or information acquired by an agency under a pledge of confidentiality and for exclusively statistical purposes shall be used by officers, employees, or agents of the agency exclusively for statistical purposes and protected in accordance with such pledge.

(c) Disclosure of Statistical Data or Information.—(1) Data or information acquired by an agency under a pledge of confidentiality for exclusively statistical purposes shall not be disclosed by an agency in identifiable form, for any use other than an exclusively statistical purpose, except with the informed consent of the respondent.

(2) A disclosure pursuant to paragraph (1) is authorized only when the head of the agency approves such disclosure and the disclosure is not prohibited by any other law.

(3) This section does not restrict or diminish any confidentiality protections in law that otherwise apply to data or information acquired by an agency under a pledge of confidentiality for exclusively statistical purposes.


(d) Rule for Use of Data or Information for Nonstatistical Purposes.—A statistical agency or unit shall clearly disting</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The purposes of this section are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Statistical Data or Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Data or information acquired by an agency under a pledge of confidentiality and for exclusively statistical purposes shall be used by officers, employees, or agents of the agency exclusively for statistical purposes and protected in accordance with such pledge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of Statistical Data or Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule for Use of Data or Information for Nonstatistical Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A statistical agency or unit shall clearly distinguish any data or information it collects for nonstatistical purposes (as authorized by law) and provide notice to the public, before the data or information is collected, that the data or information could be used for nonstatistical purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Agents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A statistical agency or unit may designate agents, by contract or by entering into a special agreement containing the provisions required under section 3561(2) for treatment as an agent under that section, who may perform exclusively statistical activities, subject to the limitations and penalties described in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3572_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fines and Penalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Whoever, being an officer, employee, or agent of an agency acquiring information for exclusively statistical purposes, having taken and subscribed the oath of office, or having sworn to observe the limitations imposed by this section, comes into possession of such information by reason of his or her being an officer, employee, or agent and, knowing that the disclosure of the specific information is prohibited under the provisions of this subchapter, willfully discloses the information in any manner to a person or agency not entitled to receive it, shall be guilty of a class E felony and imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or fined not more than $250,000, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>