<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3576" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3576/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3576/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3576"><akn:num>3576</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated statistical agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3576. Designated statistical agencies(a) Purposes.—The purposes of this section are the following:(1) To authorize the sharing of business data among the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics for exclusively statistical purposes.

(2) To reduce the paperwork burdens imposed on businesses that provide requested information to the Federal Government.

(3) To improve the comparability and accuracy of Federal economic statistics by allowing the Bureau of the Census, the Bureau of Economic Analysis, and the Bureau of Labor Statistics to update sample frames, develop consistent classifications of establishments and companies into industries, improve coverage, and reconcile significant differences in data produced by the three agencies.

(4) To increase understanding of the United States economy, especially for key industry and regional statistics, to develop more accurate measures of the impact of technology on productivity growth, and to enhance the reliability of the Nation’s most important economic indicators, such as the National Income and Product Accounts.


(b) Responsibilities of Designated Statistical Agencies.—The head of each of the Designated Statistical Agencies shall—(1) identify opportunities to eliminate duplication and otherwise reduce reporting burden and cost imposed on the public in providing information for statistical purposes;

(2) enter into joint statistical projects to improve the quality and reduce the cost of statistical programs; and

(3) protect the confidentiality of individually identifiable information acquired for statistical purposes by adhering to safeguard principles, including—(A) emphasizing to their officers, employees, and agents the importance of protecting the confidentiality of information in cases where the identity of individual respondents can reasonably be inferred by either direct or indirect means;

(B) training their officers, employees, and agents in their legal oblig</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3576_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The purposes of this section are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3576_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Designated Statistical Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The head of each of the Designated Statistical Agencies shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3576_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of Business Data Among Designated Statistical Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3576_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Use of Business Data Provided by Designated Statistical Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3576_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated Statistical Agency Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section, the term “Designated Statistical Agency” means each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>