<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3610" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3610/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/44/3610/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3610"><akn:num>3610</akn:num><akn:heading>FedRAMP Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3610. FedRAMP Board(a) Establishment.—There is established a FedRAMP Board to provide input and recommendations to the Administrator regarding the requirements and guidelines for, and the prioritization of, security assessments of cloud computing products and services.

(b) Membership.—The FedRAMP Board shall consist of not more than 7 senior officials or experts from agencies appointed by the Director, in consultation with the Administrator, from each of the following:(1) The Department of Defense.

(2) The Department of Homeland Security.

(3) The General Services Administration.

(4) Such other agencies as determined by the Director, in consultation with the Administrator.


(c) Qualifications.—Members of the FedRAMP Board appointed under subsection (b) shall have technical expertise in domains relevant to FedRAMP, such as—(1) cloud computing;

(2) cybersecurity;

(3) privacy;

(4) risk management; and

(5) other competencies identified by the Director to support the secure authorization of cloud services and products.


(d) Duties.—The FedRAMP Board shall—(1) in consultation with the Administrator, serve as a resource for best practices to accelerate the process for obtaining a FedRAMP authorization;

(2) establish and regularly update requirements and guidelines for security authorizations of cloud computing products and services, consistent with standards and guidelines established by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to be used in the determination of FedRAMP authorizations;

(3) monitor and oversee, to the greatest extent practicable, the processes and procedures by which agencies determine and validate requirements for a FedRAMP authorization, including periodic review of the agency determinations described in section 3613(b);

(4) ensure consistency and transparency between agencies and cloud service providers in a manner that minimizes confusion and engenders trust; and

(5) perform such other roles and responsibilities</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established a FedRAMP Board to provide input and recommendations to the Administrator regarding the requirements and guidelines for, and the prioritization of, security assessments of cloud computing products and services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The FedRAMP Board shall consist of not more than 7 senior officials or experts from agencies appointed by the Director, in consultation with the Administrator, from each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Members of the FedRAMP Board appointed under subsection (b) shall have technical expertise in domains relevant to FedRAMP, such as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The FedRAMP Board shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations of Demand for Cloud Computing Products and Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The FedRAMP Board may consult with the Chief Information Officers Council to establish a process, which may be made available on the website maintained under section 3609(b), for prioritizing and accepting the cloud computing products and services to be granted a FedRAMP authorization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>