<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/1009" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/1009/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/1009/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1009"><akn:num>1009</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1009. Civil remedies(a) Civil Actions.—Any interested copyright party injured by a violation of section 1002 or 1003 may bring a civil action in an appropriate United States district court against any person for such violation.

(b) Other Civil Actions.—Any person injured by a violation of this chapter may bring a civil action in an appropriate United States district court for actual damages incurred as a result of such violation.

(c) Powers of the Court.—In an action brought under subsection (a), the court—(1) may grant temporary and permanent injunctions on such terms as it deems reasonable to prevent or restrain such violation;

(2) in the case of a violation of section 1002, or in the case of an injury resulting from a failure to make royalty payments required by section 1003, shall award damages under subsection (d);

(3) in its discretion may allow the recovery of costs by or against any party other than the United States or an officer thereof; and

(4) in its discretion may award a reasonable attorney’s fee to the prevailing party.


(d) Award of Damages.—(1) Damages for section 1002 or 1003 violations.—(A) Actual damages.—(i) In an action brought under subsection (a), if the court finds that a violation of section 1002 or 1003 has occurred, the court shall award to the complaining party its actual damages if the complaining party elects such damages at any time before final judgment is entered.

(ii) In the case of section 1003, actual damages shall constitute the royalty payments that should have been paid under section 1004 and deposited under section 1005. In such a case, the court, in its discretion, may award an additional amount of not to exceed 50 percent of the actual damages.


(B) Statutory damages for section 1002 violations.—(i) Device.—A complaining party may recover an award of statutory damages for each violation of section 1002(a) or (c) in the sum of not more than $2,500 per device involved in such violation or per device on which a servi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1009_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Actions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any interested copyright party injured by a violation of section 1002 or 1003 may bring a civil action in an appropriate United States district court against any person for such violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1009_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Civil Actions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any person injured by a violation of this chapter may bring a civil action in an appropriate United States district court for actual damages incurred as a result of such violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1009_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of the Court.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In an action brought under subsection (a), the court—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1009_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of Damages.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1009_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Damages.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Any award of damages under subsection (d) shall be deposited with the Register pursuant to section 1005 for distribution to interested copyright parties as though such funds were royalty payments made pursuant to section 1003.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1009_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impounding of Articles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) At any time while an action under subsection (a) is pending, the court may order the impounding, on such terms as it deems reasonable, of any digital audio recording device, digital musical recording, or device specified in section 1002(c) that is in the custody or control of the alleged violator and that the court has reasonable cause to believe does not comply with, or was involved in a violation of, section 1002.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1009_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedial Modification and Destruction of Articles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In an action brought under subsection (a), the court may, as part of a final judgment or decree finding a violation of section 1002, order the remedial modification or the destruction of any digital audio recording device, digital musical recording, or device specified in section 1002(c) that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>