<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/104A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/104A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/104A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_104A"><akn:num>104A</akn:num><akn:heading>Copyright in restored works</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 104A. Copyright in restored works(a) Automatic Protection and Term.—(1) Term.—(A) Copyright subsists, in accordance with this section, in restored works, and vests automatically on the date of restoration.

(B) Any work in which copyright is restored under this section shall subsist for the remainder of the term of copyright that the work would have otherwise been granted in the United States if the work never entered the public domain in the United States.


(2) Exception.—Any work in which the copyright was ever owned or administered by the Alien Property Custodian and in which the restored copyright would be owned by a government or instrumentality thereof, is not a restored work.


(b) Ownership of Restored Copyright.—A restored work vests initially in the author or initial rightholder of the work as determined by the law of the source country of the work.

(c) Filing of Notice of Intent to Enforce Restored Copyright Against Reliance Parties.—On or after the date of restoration, any person who owns a copyright in a restored work or an exclusive right therein may file with the Copyright Office a notice of intent to enforce that person’s copyright or exclusive right or may serve such a notice directly on a reliance party. Acceptance of a notice by the Copyright Office is effective as to any reliance parties but shall not create a presumption of the validity of any of the facts stated therein. Service on a reliance party is effective as to that reliance party and any other reliance parties with actual knowledge of such service and of the contents of that notice.

(d) Remedies for Infringement of Restored Copyrights.—(1) Enforcement of copyright in restored works in the absence of a reliance party.—As against any party who is not a reliance party, the remedies provided in chapter 5 of this title shall be available on or after the date of restoration of a restored copyright with respect to an act of infringement of the restored copyright that is commenced on or aft</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_104A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Automatic Protection and Term.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_104A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ownership of Restored Copyright.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A restored work vests initially in the author or initial rightholder of the work as determined by the law of the source country of the work.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_104A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of Notice of Intent to Enforce Restored Copyright Against Reliance Parties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) On or after the date of restoration, any person who owns a copyright in a restored work or an exclusive right therein may file with the Copyright Office a notice of intent to enforce that person’s copyright or exclusive right or may serve such a notice directly on a reliance party. Acceptance of a notice by the Copyright Office is effective as to any reliance parties but shall not create a presumption of the validity of any of the facts stated therein. Service on a reliance party is effective as to that reliance party and any other reliance parties with actual knowledge of such service and of the contents of that notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_104A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies for Infringement of Restored Copyrights.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_104A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notices of Intent To Enforce a Restored Copyright.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_104A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity From Warranty and Related Liability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_104A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proclamation of Copyright Restoration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Whenever the President finds that a particular foreign nation extends, to works by authors who are nationals or domiciliaries of the United States, restored copyright protection on substantially the same basis as provided under this section, the President may by proclamation extend restored protection provided under this section to any work— The President may revise, suspend, or revoke any such proclamation or impose any conditions or limitations on protection under such a proclamation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_104A_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) For purposes of this section and section 109(a):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>