<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/122" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/122/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/122/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_122"><akn:num>122</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on exclusive rights: Secondary transmissions of local television programming by satellit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 122. Limitations on exclusive rights: Secondary transmissions of local television programming by satellite(a) Secondary Transmissions Into Local Markets.—(1) Secondary transmissions of television broadcast stations within a local market.—A secondary transmission of a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission of a television broadcast station into the station’s local market shall be subject to statutory licensing under this section if—(A) the secondary transmission is made by a satellite carrier to the public;

(B) with regard to secondary transmissions, the satellite carrier is in compliance with the rules, regulations, or authorizations of the Federal Communications Commission governing the carriage of television broadcast station signals; and

(C) the satellite carrier makes a direct or indirect charge for the secondary transmission to—(i) each subscriber receiving the secondary transmission; or

(ii) a distributor that has contracted with the satellite carrier for direct or indirect delivery of the secondary transmission to the public.



(2) Significantly viewed stations.—(A) In general.—A secondary transmission of a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission of a television broadcast station to subscribers who receive secondary transmissions of primary transmissions under paragraph (1) shall be subject to statutory licensing under this paragraph if the secondary transmission is of the primary transmission of a network station or a non-network station to a subscriber who resides outside the station’s local market but within a community in which the signal has been determined by the Federal Communications Commission to be significantly viewed in such community, pursuant to the rules, regulations, and authorizations of the Federal Communications Commission in effect on April 15, 1976, applicable to determining with respect to a cable system whether signals are significantly viewed in a community.

(B) Waiver.—A </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secondary Transmissions Into Local Markets.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Royalty Fee Required for Certain Secondary Transmissions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A satellite carrier whose secondary transmissions are subject to statutory licensing under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (a) shall have no royalty obligation for such secondary transmissions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncompliance With Reporting and Regulatory Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notwithstanding subsection (a), the willful or repeated secondary transmission to the public by a satellite carrier into the local market of a television broadcast station of a primary transmission embodying a performance or display of a work made by that television broadcast station is actionable as an act of infringement under section 501, and is fully subject to the remedies provided under sections 502 through 506, if the satellite carrier has not complied with the reporting requirements of subsection (b) or with the rules, regulations, and authorizations of the Federal Communications Commission concerning the carriage of television broadcast signals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Willful Alterations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notwithstanding subsection (a), the secondary transmission to the public by a satellite carrier into the local market of a television broadcast station of a performance or display of a work embodied in a primary transmission made by that television broadcast station is actionable as an act of infringement under section 501, and is fully subject to the remedies provided by sections 502 through 506 and section 510, if the content of the particular program in which the performance or display is embodied, or any commercial advertising or station announcement transmitted by the primary transmitter during, or immediately before or after, the transmission of such program, is in any way willfully altered by the satellite carrier through changes, deletions, or additions, or is combined with programming from any other broadcast signal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violation of Territorial Restrictions on Statutory License for Television Broadcast Stations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Burden of Proof.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In any action brought under subsection (f), the satellite carrier shall have the burden of proving that its secondary transmission of a primary transmission by a television broadcast station is made only to subscribers located within that station’s local market or subscribers being served in compliance with section 119, paragraph (2)(A), (3), or (4) of subsection (a), or a private licensing agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geographic Limitations on Secondary Transmissions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The statutory license created by this section shall apply to secondary transmissions to locations in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusivity With Respect to Secondary Transmissions of Broadcast Stations by Satellite to Members of the Public.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) No provision of section 111 or any other law (other than this section and section 119) shall be construed to contain any authorization, exemption, or license through which secondary transmissions by satellite carriers of programming contained in a primary transmission made by a television broadcast station may be made without obtaining the consent of the copyright owner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_122_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>