<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/1502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/1502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/17/1502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1502"><akn:num>1502</akn:num><akn:heading>Copyright Claims Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1502. Copyright Claims Board(a) In General.—There is established in the Copyright Office the Copyright Claims Board, which shall serve as an alternative forum in which parties may voluntarily seek to resolve certain copyright claims regarding any category of copyrighted work, as provided in this chapter.

(b) Officers and Staff.—(1) Copyright claims officers.—The Register of Copyrights shall recommend 3 full-time Copyright Claims Officers to serve on the Copyright Claims Board in accordance with paragraph (3)(A). The Officers shall be appointed by the Librarian of Congress to such positions after consultation with the Register of Copyrights.

(2) Copyright claims attorneys.—The Register of Copyrights shall hire not fewer than 2 full-time Copyright Claims Attorneys to assist in the administration of the Copyright Claims Board.

(3) Qualifications.—(A) Copyright claims officers.—(i) In general.—Each Copyright Claims Officer shall be an attorney who has not fewer than 7 years of legal experience.

(ii) Experience.—Two of the Copyright Claims Officers shall—(I) have substantial experience in the evaluation, litigation, or adjudication of copyright infringement claims; and

(II) between those 2 Officers, have represented or presided over a diversity of copyright interests, including those of both owners and users of copyrighted works.


(iii) Alternative dispute resolution.—The Copyright Claims Officer not described in clause (ii) shall have substantial familiarity with copyright law and experience in the field of alternative dispute resolution, including the resolution of litigation matters through that method of resolution.


(B) Copyright claims attorneys.—Each Copyright Claims Attorney shall be an attorney who has not fewer than 3 years of substantial experience in copyright law.


(4) Compensation.—(A) Copyright claims officers.—(i) Definition.—In this subparagraph, the term “senior level employee of the Federal Government” means an employee, other than an employe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established in the Copyright Office the Copyright Claims Board, which shall serve as an alternative forum in which parties may voluntarily seek to resolve certain copyright claims regarding any category of copyrighted work, as provided in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers and Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>