<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1021"><akn:num>1021</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of disclosure and reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1021. Duty of disclosure and reporting(a) Summary plan description and information to be furnished to participants and beneficiariesThe administrator of each employee benefit plan shall cause to be furnished in accordance with section 1024(b) of this title to each participant covered under the plan and to each beneficiary who is receiving benefits under the plan—(1) a summary plan description described in section 1022(a)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title; and

(2) the information described in subsection (f) and sections 1024(b)(3) and 1025(a) and (c) of this title.


(b) Reports to be filed with Secretary of LaborThe administrator shall, in accordance with section 1024(a) of this title, file with the Secretary—(1) the annual report containing the information required by section 1023 of this title; and

(2) terminal and supplementary reports as required by subsection (c) of this section.


(c) Terminal and supplementary reports(1) Each administrator of an employee pension benefit plan which is winding up its affairs (without regard to the number of participants remaining in the plan) shall, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, file such terminal reports as the Secretary may consider necessary. A copy of such report shall also be filed with the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation.

(2) The Secretary may require terminal reports to be filed with regard to any employee welfare benefit plan which is winding up its affairs in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary.

(3) The Secretary may require that a plan described in paragraph (1) or (2) file a supplementary or terminal report with the annual report in the year such plan is terminated and that a copy of such supplementary or terminal report in the case of a plan described in paragraph (1) be also filed with the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation.


(d) Notice of failure to meet minimum funding standards(1) In generalIf an employer maintaining a plan oth</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Summary plan description and information to be furnished to participants and beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Summary plan description and information to be furnished to participants and beneficiaries The administrator of each employee benefit plan shall cause to be furnished in accordance with section 1024(b) of this title to each participant covered under the plan and to each beneficiary who is receiving benefits under the plan—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to be filed with Secretary of Labor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports to be filed with Secretary of Labor The administrator shall, in accordance with section 1024(a) of this title, file with the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terminal and supplementary reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terminal and supplementary reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of failure to meet minimum funding standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice of failure to meet minimum funding standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of transfer of excess pension assets to health benefits accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice of transfer of excess pension assets to health benefits accounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defined benefit plan funding notices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Defined benefit plan funding notices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting by certain arrangements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reporting by certain arrangements The Secretary shall, by regulation, require multiple employer welfare arrangements providing benefits consisting of medical care (within the meaning of section 1191b(a)(2) of this title) which are not group health plans to register with the Secretary prior to operating in a State and may, by regulation, require such multiple employer welfare arrangements to report, not more frequently than annually, in such form and such manner as the Secretary may require for the purpose of determining the extent to which the requirements of part 7 are being carried out in connection with such benefits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Simple retirement accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Simple retirement accounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of blackout periods to participant or beneficiary under individual account plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Notice of blackout periods to participant or beneficiary under individual account plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1021_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of funding-based limitation on certain forms of distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Notice of funding-based limitation on certain forms of distribution The plan administrator of a single-employer plan shall provide a written notice to plan participants and beneficiaries within 30 days— The notice required to be provided under this subsection shall be in writing, except that such notice may be in electronic or other form to the extent that such form is reasonably accessible to the recipient. The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary, shall have the authority to prescribe rules applicable to the notices required under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>