<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1024" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1024/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1024/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1024"><akn:num>1024</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing with Secretary and furnishing information to participants and certain employers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1024. Filing with Secretary and furnishing information to participants and certain employers(a) Filing of annual report with Secretary(1) The administrator of any employee benefit plan subject to this part shall file with the Secretary the annual report for a plan year within 210 days after the close of such year (or within such time as may be required by regulations promulgated by the Secretary in order to reduce duplicative filing). The Secretary shall make copies of such annual reports available for inspection in the public document room of the Department of Labor.

(2)(A) With respect to annual reports required to be filed with the Secretary under this part, the Secretary may by regulation prescribe simplified annual reports for any pension plan that—(i) covers fewer than 100 participants; or

(ii) is a plan described in section 1060(a) of this title that covers fewer than 1,000 participants, but only if no single employer in the plan has 100 or more participants covered by the plan.


(B) Nothing contained in this paragraph shall preclude the Secretary from requiring any information or data from any such plan to which this part applies where he finds such data or information is necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter nor shall the Secretary be precluded from revoking provisions for simplified reports for any such plan if he finds it necessary to do so in order to carry out the objectives of this subchapter.


(3) The Secretary may by regulation exempt any welfare benefit plan from all or part of the reporting and disclosure requirements of this subchapter, or may provide for simplified reporting and disclosure if he finds that such requirements are inappropriate as applied to welfare benefit plans.

(4) The Secretary may reject any filing under this section—(A) if he determines that such filing is incomplete for purposes of this part; or

(B) if he determines that there is any material qualification by an accountant or actuary contained in an o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1024_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of annual report with Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Filing of annual report with Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1024_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of summary plan description and annual report to participants and beneficiaries of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Publication of summary plan description and annual report to participants and beneficiaries of plan Publication of the summary plan descriptions and annual reports shall be made to participants and beneficiaries of the particular plan as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1024_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statement of rights The Secretary may by regulation require that the administrator of any employee benefit plan furnish to each participant and to each beneficiary receiving benefits under the plan a statement of the rights of participants and beneficiaries under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1024_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing summary plan information to employers and employee representatives of multiemployer plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Furnishing summary plan information to employers and employee representatives of multiemployer plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1024_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cross references For regulations respecting coordination of reports to the Secretaries of Labor and the Treasury, see section 1204 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>