<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1054" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1054/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1054/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1054"><akn:num>1054</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefit accrual requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1054. Benefit accrual requirements(a) Satisfaction of requirements by pension plansEach pension plan shall satisfy the requirements of subsection (b)(3), and—(1) in the case of a defined benefit plan, shall satisfy the requirements of subsection (b)(1); and

(2) in the case of a defined contribution plan, shall satisfy the requirements of subsection (b)(2).


(b) Enumeration of plan requirements(1)(A) A defined benefit plan satisfies the requirements of this paragraph if the accrued benefit to which each participant is entitled upon his separation from the service is not less than—(i) 3 percent of the normal retirement benefit to which he would be entitled at the normal retirement age if he commenced participation at the earliest possible entry age under the plan and served continuously until the earlier of age 65 or the normal retirement age specified under the plan, multiplied by

(ii) the number of years (not in excess of 33⅓) of his participation in the plan.


In the case of a plan providing retirement benefits based on compensation during any period, the normal retirement benefit to which a participant would be entitled shall be determined as if he continued to earn annually the average rate of compensation which he earned during consecutive years of service, not in excess of 10, for which his compensation was the highest. For purposes of this subparagraph, social security benefits and all other relevant factors used to compute benefits shall be treated as remaining constant as of the current year for all years after such current year.

(B) A defined benefit plan satisfies the requirements of this paragraph of a particular plan year if under the plan the accrued benefit payable at the normal retirement age is equal to the normal retirement benefit and the annual rate at which any individual who is or could be a participant can accrue the retirement benefits payable at normal retirement age under the plan for any later plan year is not more than 133⅓ percent </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Satisfaction of requirements by pension plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Satisfaction of requirements by pension plans Each pension plan shall satisfy the requirements of subsection (b)(3), and—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enumeration of plan requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enumeration of plan requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee’s accrued benefits derived from employer and employee contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Employee’s accrued benefits derived from employer and employee contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee service which may be disregarded in determining employee’s accrued benefits under plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Employee service which may be disregarded in determining employee’s accrued benefits under plan Notwithstanding section 1053(b)(1) of this title, for purposes of determining the employee’s accrued benefit under the plan, the plan may disregard service performed by the employee with respect to which he has received— Paragraph (1) shall apply only if such distribution was made on termination of the employee’s participation in the plan. Paragraph (2) shall apply only if such distribution was made on termination of the employee’s participation in the plan or under such other circumstances as may be provided under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity to repay full amount of distributions which have been reduced through disregarded employee service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Opportunity to repay full amount of distributions which have been reduced through disregarded employee service For purposes of determining the employee’s accrued benefit, the plan shall not disregard service as provided in subsection (d) unless the plan provides an opportunity for the participant to repay the full amount of a distribution described in subsection (d) with, in the case of a defined benefit plan, interest at the rate determined for purposes of subsection (c)(2)(C) and provides that upon such repayment the employee’s accrued benefit shall be recomputed by taking into account service so disregarded. This subsection shall apply only in the case of a participant who— The plan provision required under this subsection may provide that such repayment must be made (A) in the case of a withdrawal on account of separation from service, before the earlier of 5 years after the first date on which the participant is subsequently re-employed by the employer, or the close of the fir</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer treated as maintaining a plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employer treated as maintaining a plan For the purposes of this part, an employer shall be treated as maintaining a plan if any employee of such employer accrues benefits under such plan by reason of service with such employer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decrease of accrued benefits through amendment of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Decrease of accrued benefits through amendment of plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of significant reduction in benefit accruals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notice of significant reduction in benefit accruals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on benefit increases where plan sponsor is in bankruptcy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Prohibition on benefit increases where plan sponsor is in bankruptcy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1054_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diversification requirements for certain individual account plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Diversification requirements for certain individual account plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>