<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1104"><akn:num>1104</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiduciary duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1104. Fiduciary duties(a) Prudent man standard of care(1) Subject to sections 1103(c) and (d), 1342, and 1344 of this title, a fiduciary shall discharge his duties with respect to a plan solely in the interest of the participants and beneficiaries and—(A) for the exclusive purpose of:(i) providing benefits to participants and their beneficiaries; and

(ii) defraying reasonable expenses of administering the plan;


(B) with the care, skill, prudence, and diligence under the circumstances then prevailing that a prudent man acting in a like capacity and familiar with such matters would use in the conduct of an enterprise of a like character and with like aims;

(C) by diversifying the investments of the plan so as to minimize the risk of large losses, unless under the circumstances it is clearly prudent not to do so; and

(D) in accordance with the documents and instruments governing the plan insofar as such documents and instruments are consistent with the provisions of this subchapter and subchapter III.


(2) In the case of an eligible individual account plan (as defined in section 1107(d)(3) of this title), the diversification requirement of paragraph (1)(C) and the prudence requirement (only to the extent that it requires diversification) of paragraph (1)(B) is not violated by acquisition or holding of qualifying employer real property or qualifying employer securities (as defined in section 1107(d)(4) and (5) of this title).


(b) Indicia of ownership of assets outside jurisdiction of district courtsExcept as authorized by the Secretary by regulations, no fiduciary may maintain the indicia of ownership of any assets of a plan outside the jurisdiction of the district courts of the United States.


(c) Control over assets by participant or beneficiary(1)(A) In the case of a pension plan which provides for individual accounts and permits a participant or beneficiary to exercise control over the assets in his account, if a participant or beneficiary exercises contr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prudent man standard of care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prudent man standard of care</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indicia of ownership of assets outside jurisdiction of district courts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Indicia of ownership of assets outside jurisdiction of district courts Except as authorized by the Secretary by regulations, no fiduciary may maintain the indicia of ownership of any assets of a plan outside the jurisdiction of the district courts of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control over assets by participant or beneficiary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Control over assets by participant or beneficiary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan terminations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Plan terminations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safe harbor for annuity selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Safe harbor for annuity selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>