<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1135" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1135/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1135/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1135"><akn:num>1135</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1135. Regulations
Subject to subchapter II and section 1029 of this title, the Secretary may prescribe such regulations as he finds necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of this subchapter. Among other things, such regulations may define accounting, technical and trade terms used in such provisions; may prescribe forms; and may provide for the keeping of books and records, and for the inspection of such books and records (subject to section 1134(a) and (b) of this title).
(Pub. L. 93–406, title I, § 505, Sept. 2, 1974, 88 Stat. 894.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
RegulationsPub. L. 99–272, title XI, § 11018, Apr. 7, 1986, 100 Stat. 277, provided that:
“(a) Regulatory Treatment of Assets of Real Estate Entities.—“(1) In general.—Except as a defense, no rule or regulation adopted pursuant to the Secretary’s proposed regulation defining ‘plan assets’ for purposes of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.] (50 Fed. Reg. 961, January 8, 1985, as modified by 50 Fed. Reg. 6361, February 15, 1985), or any reproposal thereof prior to the adoption of the regulations required to be issued in accordance with subsection (d), shall apply to any asset of a real estate entity in which a plan, account, or arrangement subject to such Act invests if—“(A) any interest in the entity is first offered to a plan, account, or arrangement subject to such Act investing in the entity (hereinafter in this section referred to as a ‘plan investor’) on or before the date which is 120 days after the date of publication of such rule or regulation as a final rule or regulation;

“(B) no plan investor acquires an interest in the entity from an issuer or underwriter at any time on or after the date which is 270 days after the date of publication of such rule or regulation as a final rule or regulation (except pursuant to a contract or subscription binding on the plan investor and entered into, or tendered, before the expiration of such 2</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>