<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1142" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1142/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1142/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1142"><akn:num>1142</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council on Employee Welfare and Pension Benefit Plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1142. Advisory Council on Employee Welfare and Pension Benefit Plans(a) Establishment; membership; terms; appointment and reappointment; vacancies; quorum(1) There is hereby established an Advisory Council on Employee Welfare and Pension Benefit Plans (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Council”) consisting of fifteen members appointed by the Secretary. Not more than eight members of the Council shall be members of the same political party.

(2) Members shall be persons qualified to appraise the programs instituted under this chapter.

(3) Of the members appointed, three shall be representatives of employee organizations (at least one of whom shall be representative of any organization members of which are participants in a multiemployer plan); three shall be representatives of employers (at least one of whom shall be representative of employers maintaining or contributing to multi-employer plans); three representatives shall be appointed from the general public, one of whom shall be a person representing those receiving benefits from a pension plan; and there shall be one representative each from the fields of insurance, corporate trust, actuarial counseling, investment counseling, investment management, and the accounting field.

(4) Members shall serve for terms of three years except that of those first appointed, five shall be appointed for terms of one year, five shall be appointed for terms of two years, and five shall be appointed for terms of three years. A member may be reappointed. A member appointed to fill a vacancy shall be appointed only for the remainder of such term. A majority of members shall constitute a quorum and action shall be taken only by a majority vote of those present and voting.


(b) Duties and functionsIt shall be the duty of the Council to advise the Secretary with respect to the carrying out of his functions under this chapter and to submit to the Secretary recommendations with respect thereto. The Council shall meet a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1142_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; membership; terms; appointment and reappointment; vacancies; quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; membership; terms; appointment and reappointment; vacancies; quorum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1142_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties and functions It shall be the duty of the Council to advise the Secretary with respect to the carrying out of his functions under this chapter and to submit to the Secretary recommendations with respect thereto. The Council shall meet at least four times each year and at such other times as the Secretary requests. In his annual report submitted pursuant to section 1143(b) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, the Secretary shall include each recommendation which he has received from the Council during the preceding calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1142_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive secretary; secretarial and clerical services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Executive secretary; secretarial and clerical services The Secretary shall furnish to the Council an executive secretary and such secretarial, clerical, and other services as are deemed necessary to conduct its business. The Secretary may call upon other agencies of the Government for statistical data, reports, and other information which will assist the Council in the performance of its duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1142_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1142_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination Section 1013(a) of title 5 (relating to termination) shall not apply to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>