<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1143" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1143/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1143/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1143"><akn:num>1143</akn:num><akn:heading>Research, studies, and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1143. Research, studies, and reports(a) Authorization to undertake research and surveys(1) The Secretary is authorized to undertake research and surveys and in connection therewith to collect, compile, analyze and publish data, information, and statistics relating to employee benefit plans, including retirement, deferred compensation, and welfare plans, and types of plans not subject to this chapter.

(2) The Secretary is authorized and directed to undertake research studies relating to pension plans, including but not limited to (A) the effects of this subchapter upon the provisions and costs of pension plans, (B) the role of private pensions in meeting the economic security needs of the Nation, and (C) the operation of private pension plans including types and levels of benefits, degree of reciprocity or portability, and financial and actuarial characteristics and practices, and methods of encouraging the growth of the private pension system.

(3) The Secretary may, as he deems appropriate or necessary, undertake other studies relating to employee benefit plans, the matters regulated by this subchapter, and the enforcement procedures provided for under this subchapter.

(4) The research, surveys, studies, and publications referred to in this subsection may be conducted directly, or indirectly through grant or contract arrangements.


(b) Omitted

(c) Cooperation with CongressThe Secretary is authorized and directed to cooperate with the Congress and its appropriate committees, subcommittees, and staff in supplying data and any other information, and personnel and services, required by the Congress in any study, examination, or report by the Congress relating to pension benefit plans established or maintained by States or their political subdivisions.


(Pub. L. 93–406, title I, § 513, Sept. 2, 1974, 88 Stat. 896.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 93–406, known as the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1143_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization to undertake research and surveys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization to undertake research and surveys</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1143_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1143_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperation with Congress The Secretary is authorized and directed to cooperate with the Congress and its appropriate committees, subcommittees, and staff in supplying data and any other information, and personnel and services, required by the Congress in any study, examination, or report by the Congress relating to pension benefit plans established or maintained by States or their political subdivisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>