<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1147" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1147/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1147/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1147"><akn:num>1147</akn:num><akn:heading>National Summit on Retirement Savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1147. National Summit on Retirement Savings(a) Authority to call SummitNot later than July 15, 1998, the President shall convene a National Summit on Retirement Income Savings at the White House, to be co-hosted by the President and the Speaker and the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives and the Majority Leader and Minority Leader of the Senate. Such a National Summit shall be convened thereafter in 2001 and 2005 on or after September 1 of each year involved. Such a National Summit shall—(1) advance the public’s knowledge and understanding of retirement savings and its critical importance to the future well-being of American workers and their families;

(2) facilitate the development of a broad-based, public education program to encourage and enhance individual commitment to a personal retirement savings strategy;

(3) develop recommendations for additional research, reforms, and actions in the field of private pensions and individual retirement savings; and

(4) disseminate the report of, and information obtained by, the National Summit and exhibit materials and works of the National Summit.


(b) Planning and directionThe National Summit shall be planned and conducted under the direction of the Secretary, in consultation with, and with the assistance of, the heads of such other Federal departments and agencies as the President may designate. Such assistance may include the assignment of personnel. The Secretary shall, in planning and conducting the National Summit, consult with the congressional leaders specified in subsection (e)(2). The Secretary shall also, in carrying out the Secretary’s duties under this subsection, consult and coordinate with at least one organization made up of private sector businesses and associations partnered with Government entities to promote long-term financial security in retirement through savings.


(c) Purpose of National SummitThe purpose of the National Summit shall be—(1) to increase the public awareness of the v</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to call Summit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to call Summit Not later than July 15, 1998, the President shall convene a National Summit on Retirement Income Savings at the White House, to be co-hosted by the President and the Speaker and the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives and the Majority Leader and Minority Leader of the Senate. Such a National Summit shall be convened thereafter in 2001 and 2005 on or after September 1 of each year involved. Such a National Summit shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning and direction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Planning and direction The National Summit shall be planned and conducted under the direction of the Secretary, in consultation with, and with the assistance of, the heads of such other Federal departments and agencies as the President may designate. Such assistance may include the assignment of personnel. The Secretary shall, in planning and conducting the National Summit, consult with the congressional leaders specified in subsection (e)(2). The Secretary shall also, in carrying out the Secretary’s duties under this subsection, consult and coordinate with at least one organization made up of private sector businesses and associations partnered with Government entities to promote long-term financial security in retirement through savings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of National Summit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purpose of National Summit The purpose of the National Summit shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of National Summit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Scope of National Summit The scope of the National Summit shall consist of issues relating to individual and employer-based retirement savings and shall not include issues relating to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program under title II of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Summit participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) National Summit participants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Summit administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) National Summit administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report The Secretary shall prepare a report describing the activities of the National Summit and shall submit the report to the President, the Speaker and Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate, and the chief executive officers of the States not later than 90 days after the date on which the National Summit is adjourned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“State” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “State” defined For purposes of this section, the term “State” means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1147_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial obligation for fiscal year 1998</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Financial obligation for fiscal year 1998 The financial obligation for the Department of Labor for fiscal year 1998 shall not exceed the lesser of— The private sector organization described in subsection (b) and contracted with by the Secretary shall be obligated for the balance of the cost of the National Summit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>