<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1162" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1162/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1162/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1162"><akn:num>1162</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1162. Continuation coverage
For purposes of section 1161 of this title, the term “continuation coverage” means coverage under the plan which meets the following requirements:(1) Type of benefit coverageThe coverage must consist of coverage which, as of the time the coverage is being provided, is identical to the coverage provided under the plan to similarly situated beneficiaries under the plan with respect to whom a qualifying event has not occurred. If coverage is modified under the plan for any group of similarly situated beneficiaries, such coverage shall also be modified in the same manner for all individuals who are qualified beneficiaries under the plan pursuant to this part in connection with such group.


(2) Period of coverageThe coverage must extend for at least the period beginning on the date of the qualifying event and ending not earlier than the earliest of the following:(A) Maximum required period(i) General rule for terminations and reduced hoursIn the case of a qualifying event described in section 1163(2) of this title, except as provided in clause (ii), the date which is 18 months after the date of the qualifying event.


(ii) Special rule for multiple qualifying eventsIf a qualifying event (other than a qualifying event described in section 1163(6) of this title) occurs during the 18 months after the date of a qualifying event described in section 1163(2) of this title, the date which is 36 months after the date of the qualifying event described in section 1163(2) of this title.


(iii) Special rule for certain bankruptcy proceedingsIn the case of a qualifying event described in section 1163(6) of this title (relating to bankruptcy proceedings), the date of the death of the covered employee or qualified beneficiary (described in section 1167(3)(C)(iii) of this title), or in the case of the surviving spouse or dependent children of the covered employee, 36 months after the date of the death of the covered employee.


(iv) General rule for other</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Type of benefit coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Type of benefit coverage The coverage must consist of coverage which, as of the time the coverage is being provided, is identical to the coverage provided under the plan to similarly situated beneficiaries under the plan with respect to whom a qualifying event has not occurred. If coverage is modified under the plan for any group of similarly situated beneficiaries, such coverage shall also be modified in the same manner for all individuals who are qualified beneficiaries under the plan pursuant to this part in connection with such group.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Period of coverage The coverage must extend for at least the period beginning on the date of the qualifying event and ending not earlier than the earliest of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premium requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Premium requirements The plan may require payment of a premium for any period of continuation coverage, except that such premium— In no event may the plan require the payment of any premium before the day which is 45 days after the day on which the qualified beneficiary made the initial election for continuation coverage. In the case of an individual described in the last sentence of paragraph (2)(A),22 See References in Text note below. any reference in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph to “102 percent” is deemed a reference to “150 percent” for any month after the 18th month of continuation coverage described in clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (2)(A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>No requirement of insurability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) No requirement of insurability The coverage may not be conditioned upon, or discriminate on the basis of lack of, evidence of insurability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion option</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Conversion option In the case of a qualified beneficiary whose period of continuation coverage expires under paragraph (2)(A), the plan must, during the 180-day period ending on such expiration date, provide to the qualified beneficiary the option of enrollment under a conversion health plan otherwise generally available under the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>