<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1185l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1185l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1185l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1185l"><akn:num>1185l</akn:num><akn:heading>Air ambulance report requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1185l. Air ambulance report requirements(a) In generalEach group health plan and health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall submit to the Secretary, jointly with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of the Treasury—(1) not later than the date that is 90 days after the last day of the first calendar year beginning on or after the date on which a final rule is promulgated pursuant to the rulemaking described in section 106(d) of the No Surprises Act, the information described in subsection (b) with respect to such plan year; and

(2) not later than the date that is 90 days after the last day of the plan year immediately succeeding the calendar year described in paragraph (1), such information with respect to such immediately succeeding plan year.


(b) Information describedFor purposes of subsection (a), information described in this subsection, with respect to a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, is each of the following:(1) Claims data for air ambulance services furnished by providers of such services, disaggregated by each of the following factors:(A) Whether such services were furnished on an emergent or nonemergent basis.

(B) Whether the provider of such services is part of a hospital-owned or sponsored program, municipality-sponsored program, hospital independent partnership (hybrid) program, independent program, or tribally operated program in Alaska.

(C) Whether the transport in which the services were furnished originated in a rural or urban area.

(D) The type of aircraft (such as rotor transport or fixed wing transport) used to furnish such services.

(E) Whether the provider of such services has a contract with the plan or issuer, as applicable, to furnish such services under the plan or coverage, respectively.


(2) Such other information regarding providers of air ambulance services as the Secretary may specify.


(Pub. L. 93–406, title I, § 723,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1185l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each group health plan and health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall submit to the Secretary, jointly with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of the Treasury—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1185l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information described For purposes of subsection (a), information described in this subsection, with respect to a group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, is each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>