<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1191d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1191d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1191d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1191d"><akn:num>1191d</akn:num><akn:heading>Standardized reporting format</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1191d. Standardized reporting format(a) In generalNot later than 1 year after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall establish (and periodically update) a standardized reporting format for the voluntary reporting, by group health plans to State All Payer Claims Databases, of medical claims, pharmacy claims, dental claims, and eligibility and provider files that are collected from private and public payers, and shall provide guidance to States on the process by which States may collect such data from such plans in the standardized reporting format.


(b) Consultation(1) Advisory CommitteeNot later than 90 days after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall convene an Advisory Committee (referred to in this section as the “Committee”), consisting of 15 members to advise the Secretary regarding the format and guidance described in paragraph (1).11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (a).”


(2) Membership(A) AppointmentIn accordance with subparagraph (B), not later than 90 days after December 27, 2020, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall appoint under subparagraph (B)(iii), and the Comptroller General of the United States shall appoint under subparagraph (B)(iv), members who have distinguished themselves in the fields of health services research, health economics, health informatics, data privacy and security, or the governance of State All Payer Claims Databases, or who represent organizations likely to submit data to or use the database, including patients, employers, or employee organizations that sponsor group health plans, health care providers, health insurance issuers, or third-party administrators of group health plans. Such members shall serve 3-year terms on a staggered basis. Vacancies on the Committee shall be filled by appointment consistent with this paragraph not later than 3 months after the vacancy arises.


(B) CompositionThe Committee shall be comprised of—(i) the Assistant Secretary of Emp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1191d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 1 year after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall establish (and periodically update) a standardized reporting format for the voluntary reporting, by group health plans to State All Payer Claims Databases, of medical claims, pharmacy claims, dental claims, and eligibility and provider files that are collected from private and public payers, and shall provide guidance to States on the process by which States may collect such data from such plans in the standardized reporting format.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1191d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1191d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State All Payer Claims Database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State All Payer Claims Database In this section, the term “State All Payer Claims Database” means, with respect to a State, a database that may include medical claims, pharmacy claims, dental claims, and eligibility and provider files, which are collected from private and public payers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1191d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2021, to remain available until expended or, if sooner, until the date described in subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1191d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sunset Beginning on the date on which the report is submitted under subsection (b)(3), subsection (b) shall have no force or effect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>