<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1232" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1232/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1232/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1232"><akn:num>1232</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection for employees under Federal procurement, construction, and research contracts and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1232. Protection for employees under Federal procurement, construction, and research contracts and grants(a) Study and investigation by Secretary of LaborThe Secretary of Labor shall, during the 2–year period beginning on September 2, 1974, conduct a full and complete study and investigation of the steps necessary to be taken to insure that professional, scientific, and technical personnel and others working in associated occupations employed under Federal procurement, construction, or research contracts or grants will, to the extent feasible, be protected against forfeitures of pension or retirement rights or benefits, otherwise provided, as a consequence of job transfers or loss of employment resulting from terminations or modifications of Federal contracts, grants, or procurement policies. The Secretary of Labor shall report the results of his study and investigation to the Congress within 2 years after September 2, 1974. The Secretary of Labor is authorized, to the extent provided by law, to obtain the services of private research institutions and such other persons by contract or other arrangement as he determines necessary in carrying out the provisions of this section.


(b) ConsultationIn the course of conducting the study and investigation described in subsection (a), and in developing the regulations referred to in subsection (c), the Secretary of Labor shall consult—(1) with appropriate professional societies, business organizations, and labor organizations, and

(2) with the heads of interested Federal departments and agencies.


(c) RegulationsWithin 1 year after the date on which he submits his report to the Congress under subsection (a), the Secretary of Labor shall, if he determines it to be feasible, develop regulations, which will provide the protection of pension and retirement rights and benefits referred to in subsection (a).


(d) Congressional review of regulations; resolution of disapproval(1) Any regulations developed pursuant to subsectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and investigation by Secretary of Labor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Study and investigation by Secretary of Labor The Secretary of Labor shall, during the 2–year period beginning on September 2, 1974, conduct a full and complete study and investigation of the steps necessary to be taken to insure that professional, scientific, and technical personnel and others working in associated occupations employed under Federal procurement, construction, or research contracts or grants will, to the extent feasible, be protected against forfeitures of pension or retirement rights or benefits, otherwise provided, as a consequence of job transfers or loss of employment resulting from terminations or modifications of Federal contracts, grants, or procurement policies. The Secretary of Labor shall report the results of his study and investigation to the Congress within 2 years after September 2, 1974. The Secretary of Labor is authorized, to the extent provided by law, to obtain the services of private research institutions and such other persons by contract or ot</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation In the course of conducting the study and investigation described in subsection (a), and in developing the regulations referred to in subsection (c), the Secretary of Labor shall consult—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations Within 1 year after the date on which he submits his report to the Congress under subsection (a), the Secretary of Labor shall, if he determines it to be feasible, develop regulations, which will provide the protection of pension and retirement rights and benefits referred to in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional review of regulations; resolution of disapproval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Congressional review of regulations; resolution of disapproval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>