<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1304"><akn:num>1304</akn:num><akn:heading>Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1304. Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate(a) In generalThe board of directors of the corporation shall select a Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate from the candidates nominated by the advisory committee to the corporation under section 1302(h)(1) of this title and without regard to the provisions of title 5 relating to appointments in the competitive service or Senior Executive Service.


(b) DutiesThe Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate shall—(1) act as a liaison between the corporation, sponsors of defined benefit pension plans insured by the corporation, and participants in pension plans trusteed by the corporation;

(2) advocate for the full attainment of the rights of participants in plans trusteed by the corporation;

(3) assist pension plan sponsors and participants in resolving disputes with the corporation;

(4) identify areas in which participants and plan sponsors have persistent problems in dealings with the corporation;

(5) to the extent possible, propose changes in the administrative practices of the corporation to mitigate problems;

(6) identify potential legislative changes which may be appropriate to mitigate problems; and

(7) refer instances of fraud, waste, and abuse, and violations of law to the Office of the Inspector General of the corporation.


(c) RemovalIf the Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate is removed from office or is transferred to another position or location within the corporation or the Department of Labor, the board of the 11 So in original. The word “the” probably should not appear. directors of the corporation shall communicate in writing the reasons for any such removal or transfer to Congress not less than 30 days before the removal or transfer. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a personnel action otherwise authorized by law, other than transfer or removal.


(d) CompensationThe annual rate of basic pay for the Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate shall be the same rate as the highest rate of basic pay </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The board of directors of the corporation shall select a Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate from the candidates nominated by the advisory committee to the corporation under section 1302(h)(1) of this title and without regard to the provisions of title 5 relating to appointments in the competitive service or Senior Executive Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Removal If the Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate is removed from office or is transferred to another position or location within the corporation or the Department of Labor, the board of the 11 So in original. The word “the” probably should not appear. directors of the corporation shall communicate in writing the reasons for any such removal or transfer to Congress not less than 30 days before the removal or transfer. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a personnel action otherwise authorized by law, other than transfer or removal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1304_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation The annual rate of basic pay for the Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate shall be the same rate as the highest rate of basic pay established for the Senior Executive Service under section 5382 of title 5 or, if the board of directors of the corporation so determines, at a rate fixed under section 9503 of such title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1304_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>