<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1305"><akn:num>1305</akn:num><akn:heading>Pension benefit guaranty funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1305. Pension benefit guaranty funds(a) Establishment of four revolving funds on books of Treasury of the United StatesThere are established on the books of the Treasury of the United States four revolving funds to be used by the corporation in carrying out its duties under this subchapter. One of the funds shall be used with respect to basic benefits guaranteed under section 1322 of this title, one of the funds shall be used with respect to basic benefits guaranteed under section 1322a of this title, one of the funds shall be used with respect to nonbasic benefits guaranteed under section 1322 of this title (if any), and the remaining fund shall be used with respect to nonbasic benefits guaranteed under section 1322a of this title (if any), other than subsection (g)(2) thereof (if any). Whenever in this subchapter reference is made to the term “fund” the reference shall be considered to refer to the appropriate fund established under this subsection.


(b) Credits to funds; availability of funds; investment of moneys in excess of current needs(1) Each fund established under this section shall be credited with the appropriate portion of—(A) premiums, penalties, interest, and charges collected under this subchapter,

(B) the value of the assets of a plan administered under section 1342 of this title by a trustee to the extent that they exceed the liabilities of such plan,

(C) the amount of any employer liability payments under subtitle D, to the extent that such payments exceed liabilities of the plan (taking into account all other plan assets),

(D) earnings on investments of the fund or on assets credited to the fund under this subsection,

(E) attorney’s fees awarded to the corporation, and

(F) receipts from any other operations under this subchapter.


(2) Subject to the provisions of subsection (a), each fund shall be available—(A) for making such payments as the corporation determines are necessary to pay benefits guaranteed under section 1322 or 1322a of t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of four revolving funds on books of Treasury of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of four revolving funds on books of Treasury of the United States There are established on the books of the Treasury of the United States four revolving funds to be used by the corporation in carrying out its duties under this subchapter. One of the funds shall be used with respect to basic benefits guaranteed under section 1322 of this title, one of the funds shall be used with respect to basic benefits guaranteed under section 1322a of this title, one of the funds shall be used with respect to nonbasic benefits guaranteed under section 1322 of this title (if any), and the remaining fund shall be used with respect to nonbasic benefits guaranteed under section 1322a of this title (if any), other than subsection (g)(2) thereof (if any). Whenever in this subchapter reference is made to the term “fund” the reference shall be considered to refer to the appropriate fund established under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credits to funds; availability of funds; investment of moneys in excess of current needs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Credits to funds; availability of funds; investment of moneys in excess of current needs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 112–141, div. D, title II, § 40234(a), July 6, 2012, 126 Stat. 858</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of fifth fund; purpose, availability, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Establishment of fifth fund; purpose, availability, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of sixth fund; purpose, availability, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Establishment of sixth fund; purpose, availability, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of premiums into separate revolving fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Deposit of premiums into separate revolving fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other use of funds; deposits of repayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Other use of funds; deposits of repayments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting by corporation of stock paid as liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Voting by corporation of stock paid as liability Any stock in a person liable to the corporation under this subchapter which is paid to the corporation by such person or a member of such person’s controlled group in satisfaction of such person’s liability under this subchapter may be voted only by the custodial trustees or outside money managers of the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1305_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special financial assistance for multiemployer pension plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Special financial assistance for multiemployer pension plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>