<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1321"><akn:num>1321</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1321. Coverage(a) Plans coveredExcept as provided in subsection (b), this subchapter applies to any plan (including a successor plan) which, for a plan year—(1) is an employee pension benefit plan (as defined in paragraph (2) of section 1002 of this title) established or maintained—(A) by an employer engaged in commerce or in any industry or activity affecting commerce, or

(B) by any employee organization, or organization representing employees, engaged in commerce or in any industry or activity affecting commerce, or

(C) by both,


which has, in practice, met the requirements of part I of subchapter D of chapter 1 of title 26 (as in effect for the preceding 5 plan years of the plan) applicable to the plans described in paragraph (2) for the preceding 5 plan years; or

(2) is, or has been determined by the Secretary of the Treasury to be, a plan described in section 401(a) of title 26, or which meets, or has been determined by the Secretary of the Treasury to meet, the requirements of section 404(a)(2) of title 26.


For purposes of this subchapter, a successor plan is considered to be a continuation of a predecessor plan. For this purpose, unless otherwise specifically indicated in this subchapter, a successor plan is a plan which covers a group of employees which includes substantially the same employees as a previously established plan, and provides substantially the same benefits as that plan provided.

(b) Plans not coveredThis section does not apply to any plan—(1) which is an individual account plan, as defined in paragraph (34) of section 1002 of this title,11 So in original. The comma probably should be a semicolon.

(2) established and maintained for its employees by the Government of the United States, by the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, or by any agency or instrumentality of any of the foregoing, or to which the Railroad Retirement Act of 1935 or 1937 [45 U.S.C. 231 et seq.] applies and which is financed by contributions </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Plans covered Except as provided in subsection (b), this subchapter applies to any plan (including a successor plan) which, for a plan year— For purposes of this subchapter, a successor plan is considered to be a continuation of a predecessor plan. For this purpose, unless otherwise specifically indicated in this subchapter, a successor plan is a plan which covers a group of employees which includes substantially the same employees as a previously established plan, and provides substantially the same benefits as that plan provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans not covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Plans not covered This section does not apply to any plan—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1321_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1321_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantial owner defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Substantial owner defined For purposes of subsection (b)(9), the term “substantial owner” means an individual who, at any time during the 60-month period ending on the date the determination is being made— For purposes of paragraph (3), the constructive ownership rules of section 1563(e) of title 26 (other than paragraph (3)(C) thereof) shall apply, including the application of such rules under section 414(c) of title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>