<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1322a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1322a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1322a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1322a"><akn:num>1322a</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiemployer plan benefits guaranteed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1322a. Multiemployer plan benefits guaranteed(a) Benefits of covered plans subject to guaranteeThe corporation shall guarantee, in accordance with this section, the payment of all nonforfeitable benefits (other than benefits becoming nonforfeitable solely on account of the termination of a plan) under a multiemployer plan—(1) to which this subchapter applies, and

(2) which is insolvent under section 1426(b) or 1441(d)(2) of this title.


(b) Benefits or benefit increases not eligible for guarantee(1)(A) For purposes of this section, a benefit or benefit increase which has been in effect under a plan for less than 60 months is not eligible for the corporation’s guarantee. For purposes of this paragraph, any month of any plan year during which the plan was insolvent or terminated (within the meaning of section 1341a(a)(2) of this title) shall not be taken into account.

(B) For purposes of this section, a benefit or benefit increase which has been in effect under a plan for less than 60 months before the first day of the plan year for which an amendment reducing the benefit or the benefit increase is taken into account under section 1425(a)(2) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title in determining the minimum contribution requirement for the plan year under section 1423(b) 1 of this title is not eligible for the corporation’s guarantee.


(2) For purposes of this section—(A) the date on which a benefit or a benefit increase under a plan is first in effect is the later of—(i) the date on which the documents establishing or increasing the benefit were executed, or

(ii) the effective date of the benefit or benefit increase;


(B) the period of time for which a benefit or a benefit increase has been in effect under a successor plan includes the period of time for which the benefit or benefit increase was in effect under a previously established plan; and

(C) in the case of a plan to which section 1321 of this title did not apply on September 3, 1974, the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits of covered plans subject to guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Benefits of covered plans subject to guarantee The corporation shall guarantee, in accordance with this section, the payment of all nonforfeitable benefits (other than benefits becoming nonforfeitable solely on account of the termination of a plan) under a multiemployer plan—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits or benefit increases not eligible for guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Benefits or benefit increases not eligible for guarantee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations respecting amount of guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determinations respecting amount of guarantee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of guarantee of reduced benefit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of guarantee of reduced benefit In the case of a benefit which has been reduced under section 411(a)(3)(E) of title 26, the corporation shall guarantee the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility of benefits for guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Ineligibility of benefits for guarantee The corporation shall not guarantee benefits under a multiemployer plan which, under section 1322(b)(6) of this title, would not be guaranteed under a single-employer plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study, report, etc., respecting premium increase in existing basic-benefit guarantee levels; Congressional procedures applicable for revision of schedules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Study, report, etc., respecting premium increase in existing basic-benefit guarantee levels; Congressional procedures applicable for revision of schedules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guarantee of payment of other classes of benefits and establishment of terms and conditions of guarantee; promulgation of regulations for establishment of supplemental program to guarantee benefits otherwise ineligible; status of benefits; applicability of revised schedule of premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Guarantee of payment of other classes of benefits and establishment of terms and conditions of guarantee; promulgation of regulations for establishment of supplemental program to guarantee benefits otherwise ineligible; status of benefits; applicability of revised schedule of premiums</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to nonforfeitable benefits accrued as of July 30, 1980; manner and extent of guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Applicability to nonforfeitable benefits accrued as of</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>