<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1322"><akn:num>1322</akn:num><akn:heading>Single-employer plan benefits guaranteed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1322. Single-employer plan benefits guaranteed(a) Nonforfeitable benefitsSubject to the limitations contained in subsection (b), the corporation shall guarantee, in accordance with this section, the payment of all nonforfeitable benefits (other than benefits becoming nonforfeitable solely on account of the termination of a plan) under a single-employer plan which terminates at a time when this subchapter applies to it.


(b) Exceptions(1) Except to the extent provided in paragraph (7)—(A) no benefits provided by a plan which has been in effect for less than 60 months at the time the plan terminates shall be guaranteed under this section, and

(B) any increase in the amount of benefits under a plan resulting from a plan amendment which was made, or became effective, whichever is later, within 60 months before the date on which the plan terminates shall be disregarded.


(2) For purposes of this subsection, the time a successor plan (within the meaning of section 1321(a) of this title) has been in effect includes the time a previously established plan (within the meaning of section 1321(a) of this title) was in effect. For purposes of determining what benefits are guaranteed under this section in the case of a plan to which section 1321 of this title does not apply on September 3, 1974, the 60-month period referred to in paragraph (1) shall be computed beginning on the first date on which such section does apply to the plan.

(3) The amount of monthly benefits described in subsection (a) provided by a plan, which are guaranteed under this section with respect to a participant, shall not have an actuarial value which exceeds the actuarial value of a monthly benefit in the form of a life annuity commencing at age 65 equal to the lesser of—(A) his average monthly gross income from his employer during the 5 consecutive calendar year period (or, if less, during the number of calendar years in such period in which he actively participates in the plan) during which his gro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonforfeitable benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nonforfeitable benefits Subject to the limitations contained in subsection (b), the corporation shall guarantee, in accordance with this section, the payment of all nonforfeitable benefits (other than benefits becoming nonforfeitable solely on account of the termination of a plan) under a single-employer plan which terminates at a time when this subchapter applies to it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment by corporation to participants and beneficiaries of recovery percentage of outstanding amount of benefit liabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment by corporation to participants and beneficiaries of recovery percentage of outstanding amount of benefit liabilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization to guarantee other classes of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization to guarantee other classes of benefits The corporation is authorized to guarantee the payment of such other classes of benefits and to establish the terms and conditions under which such other classes of benefits are guaranteed as it determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonforfeitability of preretirement survivor annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nonforfeitability of preretirement survivor annuity For purposes of subsection (a), a qualified preretirement survivor annuity (as defined in section 1055(e)(1) of this title) with respect to a participant under a terminated single-employer plan shall not be treated as forfeitable solely because the participant has not died as of the termination date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of plan amendments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective date of plan amendments For purposes of this section, the effective date of a plan amendment described in section 1054(i)(1) of this title shall be the effective date of the plan of reorganization of the employer described in section 1054(i)(1) of this title or, if later, the effective date stated in such amendment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bankruptcy filing substituted for termination date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Bankruptcy filing substituted for termination date If a contributing sponsor of a plan has filed or has had filed against such person a petition seeking liquidation or reorganization in a case under title 11 or under any similar Federal law or law of a State or political subdivision, and the case has not been dismissed as of the termination date of the plan, then this section shall be applied by treating the date such petition was filed as the termination date of the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1322_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for plans electing certain funding requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rule for plans electing certain funding requirements If any plan makes an election under section 402(a)(1) of the Pension Protection Act of 2006 and is terminated effective before the end of the 10-year period beginning on the first day of the first applicable plan year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>