<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1343" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1343/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1343/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1343"><akn:num>1343</akn:num><akn:heading>Reportable events</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1343. Reportable events(a) Notification that event has occurredWithin 30 days after the plan administrator or the contributing sponsor knows or has reason to know that a reportable event described in subsection (c) has occurred, he shall notify the corporation that such event has occurred, unless a notice otherwise required under this subsection has already been provided with respect to such event. The corporation is authorized to waive the requirement of the preceding sentence with respect to any or all reportable events with respect to any plan, and to require the notification to be made by including the event in the annual report made by the plan.


(b) Notification that event is about to occur(1) The requirements of this subsection shall be applicable to a contributing sponsor if, as of the close of the preceding plan year—(A) the  aggregate  unfunded  vested  benefits (as determined under section 1306(a)(3)(E)(iii) of this title) of plans subject to this subchapter which are maintained by such sponsor and members of such sponsor’s controlled groups (disregarding plans with no unfunded vested benefits) exceed $50,000,000, and

(B) the funded vested benefit percentage for such plans is less than 90 percent.


For purposes of subparagraph (B), the funded vested benefit percentage means the percentage which the aggregate value of the assets of such plans bears to the aggregate vested benefits of such plans (determined in accordance with section 1306(a)(3)(E)(iii) of this title).

(2) This subsection shall not apply to an event if the contributing sponsor, or the member of the contributing sponsor’s controlled group to which the event relates, is—(A) a person subject to the reporting requirements of section 13 or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 [15 U.S.C. 78m, 78o(d)], or

(B) a subsidiary (as defined for purposes of such Act [15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.]) of a person subject to such reporting requirements.


(3) No later than 30 days prior to the effective</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1343_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification that event has occurred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notification that event has occurred Within 30 days after the plan administrator or the contributing sponsor knows or has reason to know that a reportable event described in subsection (c) has occurred, he shall notify the corporation that such event has occurred, unless a notice otherwise required under this subsection has already been provided with respect to such event. The corporation is authorized to waive the requirement of the preceding sentence with respect to any or all reportable events with respect to any plan, and to require the notification to be made by including the event in the annual report made by the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1343_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification that event is about to occur</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification that event is about to occur</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1343_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enumeration of reportable events</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enumeration of reportable events For purposes of this section a reportable event occurs— For purposes of paragraph (7), all distributions to a participant within any 24-month period are treated as a single distribution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1343_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to corporation by Secretary of the Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification to corporation by Secretary of the Treasury The Secretary of the Treasury shall notify the corporation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1343_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to corporation by Secretary of Labor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notification to corporation by Secretary of Labor The Secretary of Labor shall notify the corporation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1343_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosure exemption Any information or documentary material submitted to the corporation pursuant to this section shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, and no such information or documentary material may be made public, except as may be relevant to any administrative or judicial action or proceeding. Nothing in this section is intended to prevent disclosure to either body of Congress or to any duly authorized committee or subcommittee of the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>