<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1344" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1344/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1344/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1344"><akn:num>1344</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1344. Allocation of assets(a) Order of priority of participants and beneficiariesIn the case of the termination of a single-employer plan, the plan administrator shall allocate the assets of the plan (available to provide benefits) among the participants and beneficiaries of the plan in the following order:(1) First, to that portion of each individual’s accrued benefit which is derived from the participant’s contributions to the plan which were not mandatory contributions.

(2) Second, to that portion of each individual’s accrued benefit which is derived from the participant’s mandatory contributions.

(3) Third, in the case of benefits payable as an annuity—(A) in the case of the benefit of a participant or beneficiary which was in pay status as of the beginning of the 3-year period ending on the termination date of the plan, to each such benefit, based on the provisions of the plan (as in effect during the 5-year period ending on such date) under which such benefit would be the least,

(B) in the case of a participant’s or beneficiary’s benefit (other than a benefit described in subparagraph (A)) which would have been in pay status as of the beginning of such 3-year period if the participant had retired prior to the beginning of the 3-year period and if his benefits had commenced (in the normal form of annuity under the plan) as of the beginning of such period, to each such benefit based on the provisions of the plan (as in effect during the 5-year period ending on such date) under which such benefit would be the least.


For purposes of subparagraph (A), the lowest benefit in pay status during a 3-year period shall be considered the benefit in pay status for such period.

(4) Fourth—(A) to all other benefits (if any) of individuals under the plan guaranteed under this subchapter (determined without regard to section 1322b(a) of this title), and

(B) to the additional benefits (if any) which would be determined under subparagraph (A) if section 1322(b)(5)(B) of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of priority of participants and beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Order of priority of participants and beneficiaries In the case of the termination of a single-employer plan, the plan administrator shall allocate the assets of the plan (available to provide benefits) among the participants and beneficiaries of the plan in the following order:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of allocations; reallocations; mandatory contributions; establishment of subclasses and categories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjustment of allocations; reallocations; mandatory contributions; establishment of subclasses and categories For purposes of subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increase or decrease in value of assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Increase or decrease in value of assets Any increase or decrease in the value of the assets of a single-employer plan occurring during the period beginning on the later of (1) the date a trustee is appointed under section 1342(b) of this title or (2) the date on which the plan is terminated is to be allocated between the plan and the corporation in the manner determined by the court (in the case of a court-appointed trustee) or as agreed upon by the corporation and the plan administrator in any other case. Any increase or decrease in the value of the assets of a single-employer plan occurring after the date on which the plan is terminated shall be credited to, or suffered by, the corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of residual assets; restrictions on reversions pursuant to recently amended plans; assets attributable to employee contributions; calculation of remaining assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Distribution of residual assets; restrictions on reversions pursuant to recently amended plans; assets attributable to employee contributions; calculation of remaining assets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bankruptcy filing substituted for termination date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Bankruptcy filing substituted for termination date If a contributing sponsor of a plan has filed or has had filed against such person a petition seeking liquidation or reorganization in a case under title 11 or under any similar Federal law or law of a State or political subdivision, and the case has not been dismissed as of the termination date of the plan, then subsection (a)(3) shall be applied by treating the date such petition was filed as the termination date of the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation of section 1362(c) liability for determining amounts payable by corporation to participants and beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Valuation of section 1362(c) liability for determining amounts payable by corporation to participants and beneficiaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>