<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1368" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1368/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1368/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1368"><akn:num>1368</akn:num><akn:heading>Lien for liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1368. Lien for liability(a) Creation of lienIf any person liable to the corporation under section 1362, 1363, or 1364 of this title neglects or refuses to pay, after demand, the amount of such liability (including interest), there shall be a lien in favor of the corporation in the amount of such liability (including interest) upon all property and rights to property, whether real or personal, belonging to such person, except that such lien may not be in an amount in excess of 30 percent of the collective net worth of all persons described in section 1362(a) of this title 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.


(b) Term of lienThe lien imposed by subsection (a) arises on the date of termination of a plan, and continues until the liability imposed under section 1362, 1363, or 1364 of this title is satisfied or becomes unenforceable by reason of lapse of time.


(c) Priority(1) Except as otherwise provided under this section, the priority of a lien imposed under subsection (a) shall be determined in the same manner as under section 6323 of title 26 (as in effect on April 7, 1986). Such section 6323 shall be applied for purposes of this section by disregarding subsection (g)(4) and by substituting—(A) “lien imposed by section 4068 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [29 U.S.C. 1368]” for “lien imposed by section 6321” each place it appears in subsections (a), (b), (c)(1), (c)(4)(B), (d), (e), and (h)(5);

(B) “the corporation” for “the Secretary” in subsections (a) and (b)(9)(C);

(C) “the payment of the amount on which the section 4068(a) lien is based” for “the collection of any tax under this title” in subsection (b)(3);

(D) “a person whose property is subject to the lien” for “the taxpayer” in subsections (b)(8), (c)(2)(A)(i) (the first place it appears), (c)(2)(A)(ii), (c)(2)(B), (c)(4)(B), and (c)(4)(C) (in the matter preceding clause (i));

(E) “such person” for “the taxpayer” in subsections (c)(2)(A)(i) (the second pla</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation of lien</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation of lien If any person liable to the corporation under section 1362, 1363, or 1364 of this title neglects or refuses to pay, after demand, the amount of such liability (including interest), there shall be a lien in favor of the corporation in the amount of such liability (including interest) upon all property and rights to property, whether real or personal, belonging to such person, except that such lien may not be in an amount in excess of 30 percent of the collective net worth of all persons described in section 1362(a) of this title 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of lien</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Term of lien The lien imposed by subsection (a) arises on the date of termination of a plan, and continues until the liability imposed under section 1362, 1363, or 1364 of this title is satisfied or becomes unenforceable by reason of lapse of time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil action; limitation period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Civil action; limitation period</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release or subordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Release or subordination If the corporation determines that release of the lien or subordination of the lien to any other creditor of the liable person would not adversely affect the collection of the liability imposed under section 1362, 1363, or 1364 of this title, or that the amount realizable by the corporation from the property to which the lien attaches will ultimately be increased by such release or subordination, and that the ultimate collection of the liability will be facilitated by such release or subordination, the corporation may issue a certificate of release or subordination of the lien with respect to such property, or any part thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1368_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>