<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1399" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1399/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1399/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1399"><akn:num>1399</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice, collection, etc., of withdrawal liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1399. Notice, collection, etc., of withdrawal liability(a) Furnishing of information by employer to plan sponsorAn employer shall, within 30 days after a written request from the plan sponsor, furnish such information as the plan sponsor reasonably determines to be necessary to enable the plan sponsor to comply with the requirements of this part.


(b) Notification, demand for payment, and review upon complete or partial withdrawal by employer(1) As soon as practicable after an employer’s complete or partial withdrawal, the plan sponsor shall—(A) notify the employer of—(i) the amount of the liability, and

(ii) the schedule for liability payments, and


(B) demand payment in accordance with the schedule.


(2)(A) No later than 90 days after the employer receives the notice described in paragraph (1), the employer—(i) may ask the plan sponsor to review any specific matter relating to the determination of the employer’s liability and the schedule of payments,

(ii) may identify any inaccuracy in the determination of the amount of the unfunded vested benefits allocable to the employer, and

(iii) may furnish any additional relevant information to the plan sponsor.


(B) After a reasonable review of any matter raised, the plan sponsor shall notify the employer of—(i) the plan sponsor’s decision,

(ii) the basis for the decision, and

(iii) the reason for any change in the determination of the employer’s liability or schedule of liability payments.




(c) Payment requirements; amount, etc.(1)(A)(i) Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (D) of this paragraph and in paragraphs (4) and (5), an employer shall pay the amount determined under section 1391 of this title, adjusted if appropriate first under section 1389 of this title and then under section 1386 of this title over the period of years necessary to amortize the amount in level annual payments determined under subparagraph (C), calculated as if the first payment were made on the first day of the plan year f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1399_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing of information by employer to plan sponsor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Furnishing of information by employer to plan sponsor An employer shall, within 30 days after a written request from the plan sponsor, furnish such information as the plan sponsor reasonably determines to be necessary to enable the plan sponsor to comply with the requirements of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1399_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification, demand for payment, and review upon complete or partial withdrawal by employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification, demand for payment, and review upon complete or partial withdrawal by employer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1399_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment requirements; amount, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment requirements; amount, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1399_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of statutory prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of statutory prohibitions The prohibitions provided in section 1106(a) of this title do not apply to any action required or permitted under this part or to any arrangement relating to withdrawal liability involving the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>