<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1413" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1413/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1413/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1413"><akn:num>1413</akn:num><akn:heading>Partitions of eligible multiemployer plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1413. Partitions of eligible multiemployer plans(a) Authority of corporation(1) Upon the application by the plan sponsor of an eligible multiemployer plan for a partition of the plan, the corporation may order a partition of the plan in accordance with this section. The corporation shall make a determination regarding the application not later than 270 days after the date such application was filed (or, if later, the date such application was completed) in accordance with regulations promulgated by the corporation.

(2) Not later than 30 days after submitting an application for partition of a plan under paragraph (1), the plan sponsor of the plan shall notify the participants and beneficiaries of such application, in the form and manner prescribed by regulations issued by the corporation.


(b) Eligible multiemployer plansFor purposes of this section, a multiemployer plan is an eligible multiemployer plan if—(1) the plan is in critical and declining status (as defined in section 1085(b)(4) of this title);

(2) the corporation determines, after consultation with the Participant and Plan Sponsor Advocate selected under section 1304 of this title, that the plan sponsor has taken (or is taking concurrently with an application for partition) all reasonable measures to avoid insolvency, including the maximum benefit suspensions under section 1085(e)(9) of this title, if applicable;

(3) the corporation reasonably expects that—(A) a partition of the plan will reduce the corporation’s expected long-term loss with respect to the plan; and

(B) a partition of the plan is necessary for the plan to remain solvent;


(4) the corporation certifies to Congress that its ability to meet existing financial assistance obligations to other plans (including any liabilities associated with multiemployer plans that are insolvent or that are projected to become insolvent within 10 years) will not be impaired by such partition; and

(5) the cost to the corporation arising from such partit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1413_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1413_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible multiemployer plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible multiemployer plans For purposes of this section, a multiemployer plan is an eligible multiemployer plan if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1413_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of liabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer of liabilities The corporation’s partition order shall provide for a transfer to the plan referenced in subsection (d)(1) of the minimum amount of the plan’s liabilities necessary for the plan to remain solvent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1413_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans created by partition orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Plans created by partition orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1413_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of benefits and premiums for beneficiaries of partitioned plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment of benefits and premiums for beneficiaries of partitioned plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1413_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of partition orders to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notice of partition orders to Congress Not later than 14 days after the partition order, the corporation shall provide notice of such order to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Finance of the Senate, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and any affected participants or beneficiaries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>