<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1426" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1426/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1426/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1426"><akn:num>1426</akn:num><akn:heading>Insolvent plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1426. Insolvent plans(a) Suspension of payments of benefits; conditions, amount, etc.Notwithstanding sections 1053 and 1054 of this title, in any case in which benefit payments under an insolvent multiemployer plan exceed the resource benefit level, any such payments of benefits which are not basic benefits shall be suspended, in accordance with this section, to the extent necessary to reduce the sum of such payments and the payments of such basic benefits to the greater of the resource benefit level or the level of basic benefits, unless an alternative procedure is prescribed by the corporation under section 1322a(g)(5) of this title.


(b) Determination of insolvency status for plan year; definitionsFor purposes of this section, for a plan year—(1) a multiemployer plan is insolvent if the plan’s available resources are not sufficient to pay benefits under the plan when due for the plan year, or if the plan is determined to be insolvent under subsection (d);

(2) “resource benefit level” means the level of monthly benefits determined under subsections (c)(1) and (3) and (d)(3) to be the highest level which can be paid out of the plan’s available resources;

(3) “available resources” means the plan’s cash, marketable assets, contributions, withdrawal liability payments, and earnings, less reasonable administrative expenses and amounts owed for such plan year to the corporation under section 1431(b)(2) of this title; and

(4) “insolvency year” means a plan year in which a plan is insolvent.


(c) Determination by plan sponsor of plan in critical status of resource benefit level of plan for each insolvency year; uniform application of suspension of benefits; adjustments of benefit payments(1) The plan sponsor of a plan in critical status, as described in subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 1085(b)(2) of this title, shall determine in writing the plan’s resource benefit level for each insolvency year, based on the plan sponsor’s reasonable pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of payments of benefits; conditions, amount, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Suspension of payments of benefits; conditions, amount, etc. Notwithstanding sections 1053 and 1054 of this title, in any case in which benefit payments under an insolvent multiemployer plan exceed the resource benefit level, any such payments of benefits which are not basic benefits shall be suspended, in accordance with this section, to the extent necessary to reduce the sum of such payments and the payments of such basic benefits to the greater of the resource benefit level or the level of basic benefits, unless an alternative procedure is prescribed by the corporation under section 1322a(g)(5) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of insolvency status for plan year; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of insolvency status for plan year; definitions For purposes of this section, for a plan year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination by plan sponsor of plan in critical status of resource benefit level of plan for each insolvency year; uniform application of suspension of benefits; adjustments of benefit payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination by plan sponsor of plan in critical status of resource benefit level of plan for each insolvency year; uniform application of suspension of benefits; adjustments of benefit payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability and determinations respecting plan assets; time for determinations of resource benefit level and level of basic benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability and determinations respecting plan assets; time for determinations of resource benefit level and level of basic benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice, etc., requirements of plan sponsor of plan in critical status regarding insolvency and resource benefit levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice, etc., requirements of plan sponsor of plan in critical status regarding insolvency and resource benefit levels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance from corporation; conditions and criteria applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Financial assistance from corporation; conditions and criteria applicable</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of subsections (a) and (c)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application of subsections (a) and (c) Subsections (a) and (c) shall not apply to a plan that, for the plan year, is operating under section 1085(e)(9) of this title, regarding benefit suspensions by certain multiemployer plans in critical and declining status.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>