<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1432" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1432/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1432/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1432"><akn:num>1432</akn:num><akn:heading>Special financial assistance by the corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1432. Special financial assistance by the corporation(a) Special financial assistance(1) In generalThe corporation shall provide special financial assistance to an eligible multiemployer plan under this section, upon the application of a plan sponsor of such a plan for such assistance.


(2) Inapplicability of certain repayment obligationA plan receiving special financial assistance pursuant to this section shall not be subject to repayment obligations with respect to such special financial assistance.



(b) Eligible multiemployer plans(1) In generalFor purposes of this section, a multiemployer plan is an eligible multiemployer plan if—(A) the plan is in critical and declining status (within the meaning of section 1085(b)(6) of this title) in any plan year beginning in 2020 through 2022;

(B) a suspension of benefits has been approved with respect to the plan under section 1085(e)(9) of this title as of March 11, 2021;

(C) in any plan year beginning in 2020 through 2022, the plan is certified by the plan actuary to be in critical status (within the meaning of section 1085(b)(2) of this title), has a modified funded percentage of less than 40 percent, and has a ratio of active to inactive participants which is less than 2 to 3; or

(D) the plan became insolvent for purposes of section 418E of title 26 after December 16, 2014, and has remained so insolvent and has not been terminated as of March 11, 2021.


(2) Modified funded percentageFor purposes of paragraph (1)(C), the term “modified funded percentage” means the percentage equal to a fraction the numerator of which is current value of plan assets (as defined in section 1002(26) of this title) and the denominator of which is current liabilities (as defined in section 431(c)(6)(D) of title 26 and section 1084(c)(6)(D) of this title).



(c) Applications for special financial assistanceWithin 120 days of March 11, 2021, the corporation shall issue regulations or guidance setting forth requirements for special fi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Special financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible multiemployer plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible multiemployer plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for special financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications for special financial assistance Within 120 days of March 11, 2021, the corporation shall issue regulations or guidance setting forth requirements for special financial assistance applications under this section. In such regulations or guidance, the corporation shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary priority consideration of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Temporary priority consideration of applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actuarial assumptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Actuarial assumptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application deadline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application deadline Any application by a plan for special financial assistance under this section shall be submitted to the corporation (and, in the case of a plan to which section 432(k)(1)(D) of title 26 applies, to the Secretary of the Treasury) no later than December 31, 2025, and any revised application for special financial assistance shall be submitted no later than December 31, 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations on applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Determinations on applications A plan’s application for special financial assistance under this section that is timely filed in accordance with the regulations or guidance issued under subsection (c) shall be deemed approved unless the corporation notifies the plan within 120 days of the filing of the application that the application is incomplete, any proposed change or assumption is unreasonable, or the plan is not eligible under this section. Such notice shall specify the reasons the plan is ineligible for special financial assistance, any proposed change or assumption is unreasonable, or information is needed to complete the application. If a plan is denied assistance under this subsection, the plan may submit a revised application under this section. Any revised application for special financial assistance submitted by a plan shall be deemed approved unless the corporation notifies the plan within 120 days of the filing of the revised application that the application is incomp</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Manner of payment The payment made by the corporation to an eligible multiemployer plan under this section shall be made as a single, lump sum payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount and manner of special financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Amount and manner of special financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1432_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of amount of special financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Determination of amount of special financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>