<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1441" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1441/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1441/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1441"><akn:num>1441</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits under certain terminated plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1441. Benefits under certain terminated plans(a) Amendment of plan by plan sponsor to reduce benefits, and suspension of benefit paymentsNotwithstanding sections 1053 and 1054 of this title, the plan sponsor of a terminated multiemployer plan to which section 1341a(d) of this title applies shall amend the plan to reduce benefits, and shall suspend benefit payments, as required by this section.


(b) Determinations respecting value of nonforfeitable benefits under terminated plan and value of assets of plan(1) The value of nonforfeitable benefits under a terminated plan referred to in subsection (a), and the value of the plan’s assets, shall be determined in writing, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the corporation, as of the end of the plan year during which section 1341a(d) of this title becomes applicable to the plan, and each plan year thereafter.

(2) For purposes of this section, plan assets include outstanding claims for withdrawal liability (within the meaning of section 1301(a)(12) of this title).


(c) Amendment of plan by plan sponsor to reduce benefits for conservation of assets; factors applicable(1) If, according to the determination made under subsection (b), the value of nonforfeitable benefits exceeds the value of the plan’s assets, the plan sponsor shall amend the plan to reduce benefits under the plan to the extent necessary to ensure that the plan’s assets are sufficient, as determined and certified in accordance with regulations prescribed by the corporation, to discharge when due all of the plan’s obligations with respect to nonforfeitable benefits.

(2) Any plan amendment required by this subsection shall, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury—(A) reduce benefits only to the extent necessary to comply with paragraph (1);

(B) reduce accrued benefits only to the extent that those benefits are not eligible for the corporation’s guarantee under section 1322a(b) of this title;

(C) comply with the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of plan by plan sponsor to reduce benefits, and suspension of benefit payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amendment of plan by plan sponsor to reduce benefits, and suspension of benefit payments Notwithstanding sections 1053 and 1054 of this title, the plan sponsor of a terminated multiemployer plan to which section 1341a(d) of this title applies shall amend the plan to reduce benefits, and shall suspend benefit payments, as required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations respecting value of nonforfeitable benefits under terminated plan and value of assets of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determinations respecting value of nonforfeitable benefits under terminated plan and value of assets of plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of plan by plan sponsor to reduce benefits for conservation of assets; factors applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amendment of plan by plan sponsor to reduce benefits for conservation of assets; factors applicable</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1441_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of benefit payments; determinative factors; powers and duties of plan sponsor; retroactive benefit payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Suspension of benefit payments; determinative factors; powers and duties of plan sponsor; retroactive benefit payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>