<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1451" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1451/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1451/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1451"><akn:num>1451</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1451. Civil actions(a) Persons entitled to maintain actions(1) A plan fiduciary, employer, plan participant, or beneficiary, who is adversely affected by the act or omission of any party under this subtitle with respect to a multiemployer plan, or an employee organization which represents such a plan participant or beneficiary for purposes of collective bargaining, may bring an action for appropriate legal or equitable relief, or both.

(2) Notwithstanding paragraph (1), this section does not authorize an action against the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Labor, or the corporation.


(b) Failure of employer to make withdrawal liability payment within prescribed timeIn any action under this section to compel an employer to pay withdrawal liability, any failure of the employer to make any withdrawal liability payment within the time prescribed shall be treated in the same manner as a delinquent contribution (within the meaning of section 1145 of this title).


(c) Jurisdiction of Federal and State courtsThe district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction of an action under this section without regard to the amount in controversy, except that State courts of competent jurisdiction shall have concurrent jurisdiction over an action brought by a plan fiduciary to collect withdrawal liability.


(d) Venue and service of processAn action under this section may be brought in the district where the plan is administered or where a defendant resides or does business, and process may be served in any district where a defendant resides, does business, or may be found.


(e) Costs and expensesIn any action under this section, the court may award all or a portion of the costs and expenses incurred in connection with such action, including reasonable attorney’s fees, to the prevailing party.


(f) Time limitationsAn action under this section may not be brought after the later of—(1) 6 years after the date on which the cause of action arose, or

(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons entitled to maintain actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Persons entitled to maintain actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure of employer to make withdrawal liability payment within prescribed time</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Failure of employer to make withdrawal liability payment within prescribed time In any action under this section to compel an employer to pay withdrawal liability, any failure of the employer to make any withdrawal liability payment within the time prescribed shall be treated in the same manner as a delinquent contribution (within the meaning of section 1145 of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of Federal and State courts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Jurisdiction of Federal and State courts The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction of an action under this section without regard to the amount in controversy, except that State courts of competent jurisdiction shall have concurrent jurisdiction over an action brought by a plan fiduciary to collect withdrawal liability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venue and service of process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Venue and service of process An action under this section may be brought in the district where the plan is administered or where a defendant resides or does business, and process may be served in any district where a defendant resides, does business, or may be found.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Costs and expenses In any action under this section, the court may award all or a portion of the costs and expenses incurred in connection with such action, including reasonable attorney’s fees, to the prevailing party.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Time limitations An action under this section may not be brought after the later of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of complaint on corporation; intervention by corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Service of complaint on corporation; intervention by corporation A copy of the complaint in any action under this section or section 1401 of this title shall be served upon the corporation by certified mail. The corporation may intervene in any such action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>