<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/175a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/175a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/175a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_175a"><akn:num>175a</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to plant, area, and industrywide labor management committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 175a. Assistance to plant, area, and industrywide labor management committees(a) Establishment and operation of plant, area, and industrywide committees(1) The Service is authorized and directed to provide assistance in the establishment and operation of plant, area and industrywide labor management committees which—(A) have been organized jointly by employers and labor organizations representing employees in that plant, area, or industry; and

(B) are established for the purpose of improving labor management relationships, job security, organizational effectiveness, enhancing economic development or involving workers in decisions affecting their jobs including improving communication with respect to subjects of mutual interest and concern.


(2) The Service is authorized and directed to enter into contracts and to make grants, where necessary or appropriate, to fulfill its responsibilities under this section.


(b) Restrictions on grants, contracts, or other assistance(1) No grant may be made, no contract may be entered into and no other assistance may be provided under the provisions of this section to a plant labor management committee unless the employees in that plant are represented by a labor organization and there is in effect at that plant a collective bargaining agreement.

(2) No grant may be made, no contract may be entered into and no other assistance may be provided under the provisions of this section to an area or industrywide labor management committee unless its participants include any labor organizations certified or recognized as the representative of the employees of an employer participating in such committee. Nothing in this clause shall prohibit participation in an area or industrywide committee by an employer whose employees are not represented by a labor organization.

(3) No grant may be made under the provisions of this section to any labor management committee which the Service finds to have as one of its purposes the discouragement o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_175a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and operation of plant, area, and industrywide committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and operation of plant, area, and industrywide committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_175a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on grants, contracts, or other assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Restrictions on grants, contracts, or other assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_175a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of office The Service shall carry out the provisions of this section through an office established for that purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_175a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section $10,000,000 for the fiscal year 1979, and such sums as may be necessary thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>