<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/178" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/178/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/178/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_178"><akn:num>178</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctions during national emergency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 178. Injunctions during national emergency(a) Petition to district court by Attorney General on direction of PresidentUpon receiving a report from a board of inquiry the President may direct the Attorney General to petition any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the parties to enjoin such strike or lock-out or the continuing thereof, and if the court finds that such threatened or actual strike or lock-out—(i) affects an entire industry or a substantial part thereof engaged in trade, commerce, transportation, transmission, or communication among the several States or with foreign nations, or engaged in the production of goods for commerce; and

(ii) if permitted to occur or to continue, will imperil the national health or safety, it shall have jurisdiction to enjoin any such strike or lockout, or the continuing thereof, and to make such other orders as may be appropriate.


(b) Inapplicability of chapter 6In any case, the provisions of chapter 6 of this title shall not be applicable.


(c) Review of ordersThe order or orders of the court shall be subject to review by the appropriate United States court of appeals and by the Supreme Court upon writ of certiorari or certification as provided in section 1254 of title 28.


(June 23, 1947, ch. 120, title II, § 208, 61 Stat. 155; June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 32(a), 62 Stat. 991; May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 127, 63 Stat. 107.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextChapter 6 (§ 101 et seq.) of this title, referred to in subsec. (b), is a reference to act Mar. 23, 1932, ch. 90, 47 Stat. 70, popularly known as the Norris-LaGuardia Act.

Codification
In subsec. (c), “court of appeals” substituted for “circuit court of appeals” on authority of act June 25, 1948, as amended by act May 24, 1949. The words “United States” immediately preceding “Court of appeals” were inserted on authority of section 43 of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.
In subsec. (c), “section 1254 of title 28” substituted for “secti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_178_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition to district court by Attorney General on direction of President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Petition to district court by Attorney General on direction of President Upon receiving a report from a board of inquiry the President may direct the Attorney General to petition any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the parties to enjoin such strike or lock-out or the continuing thereof, and if the court finds that such threatened or actual strike or lock-out—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_178_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of chapter 6</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inapplicability of chapter 6 In any case, the provisions of chapter 6 of this title shall not be applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_178_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review of orders The order or orders of the court shall be subject to review by the appropriate United States court of appeals and by the Supreme Court upon writ of certiorari or certification as provided in section 1254 of title 28.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>