<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1803"><akn:num>1803</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1803. Applicability of chapter(a) The following persons are not subject to this chapter:(1) Family business exemption.—Any individual who engages in a farm labor contracting activity on behalf of a farm, processing establishment, seed conditioning establishment, cannery, gin, packing shed, or nursery, which is owned or operated exclusively by such individual or an immediate family member of such individual, if such activities are performed only for such operation and exclusively by such individual or an immediate family member, but without regard to whether such individual has incorporated or otherwise organized for business purposes.

(2) Small business exemption.—Any person, other than a farm labor contractor, for whom the man-days exemption for agricultural labor provided under section 13(a)(6)(A) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 213(a)(6)(A)) is applicable.

(3) Other exemptions.—(A) Any common carrier which would be a farm labor contractor solely because the carrier is engaged in the farm labor contracting activity of transporting any migrant or seasonal agricultural worker.

(B) Any labor organization, as defined in section 2(5) of the Labor Management Relations Act (29 U.S.C. 152(5)) (without regard to the exclusion of agricultural employees in that Act [29 U.S.C. 141 et seq.]) or as defined under applicable State labor relations law.

(C) Any nonprofit charitable organization or public or private nonprofit educational institution.

(D) Any person who engages in any farm labor contracting activity solely within a twenty-five mile intrastate radius of such person’s permanent place of residence and for not more than thirteen weeks per year.

(E) Any custom combine, hay harvesting, or sheep shearing operation.

(F) Any custom poultry harvesting, breeding, debeaking, desexing, or health service operation provided the employees of the operation are not regularly required to be away from their permanent place of residence other than during their</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The following persons are not subject to this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subchapter I of this chapter does not apply to any agricultural employer or agricultural association or to any employee of such an employer or association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>