<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1821" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1821/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1821/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1821"><akn:num>1821</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and recordkeeping requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1821. Information and recordkeeping requirements(a) Written disclosure requirements imposed upon recruitersEach farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, and agricultural association which recruits any migrant agricultural worker shall ascertain and disclose in writing to each such worker who is recruited for employment the following information at the time of the worker’s recruitment:(1) the place of employment;

(2) the wage rates to be paid;

(3) the crops and kinds of activities on which the worker may be employed;

(4) the period of employment;

(5) the transportation, housing, and any other employee benefit to be provided, if any, and any costs to be charged for each of them;

(6) the existence of any strike or other concerted work stoppage, slowdown, or interruption of operations by employees at the place of employment;

(7) the existence of any arrangements with any owner or agent of any establishment in the area of employment under which the farm labor contractor, the agricultural employer, or the agricultural association is to receive a commission or any other benefit resulting from any sales by such establishment to the workers; and

(8) whether State workers’ compensation insurance is provided, and, if so, the name of the State workers’ compensation insurance carrier, the name of the policyholder of such insurance, the name and the telephone number of each person who must be notified of an injury or death, and the time period within which such notice must be given.


Compliance with the disclosure requirement of paragraph (8) for a migrant agricultural worker may be met if such worker is given a photocopy of any notice regarding workers’ compensation insurance required by law of the State in which such worker is employed. Such worker shall be given such disclosure regarding workers’ compensation at the time of recruitment or if sufficient information is unavailable at that time, at the earliest practicable time but in no event later than the commen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written disclosure requirements imposed upon recruiters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Written disclosure requirements imposed upon recruiters Each farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, and agricultural association which recruits any migrant agricultural worker shall ascertain and disclose in writing to each such worker who is recruited for employment the following information at the time of the worker’s recruitment: Compliance with the disclosure requirement of paragraph (8) for a migrant agricultural worker may be met if such worker is given a photocopy of any notice regarding workers’ compensation insurance required by law of the State in which such worker is employed. Such worker shall be given such disclosure regarding workers’ compensation at the time of recruitment or if sufficient information is unavailable at that time, at the earliest practicable time but in no event later than the commencement of work.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Posting requirements imposed upon employers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Posting requirements imposed upon employers Each farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, and agricultural association which employs any migrant agricultural worker shall, at the place of employment, post in a conspicuous place a poster provided by the Secretary setting forth the rights and protections afforded such workers under this chapter, including the right of a migrant agricultural worker to have, upon request, a written statement provided by the farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, or agricultural association, of the information described in subsection (a). Such employer shall provide upon request, a written statement of the information described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Posting or notice requirements imposed upon housing providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Posting or notice requirements imposed upon housing providers Each farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, and agricultural association which provides housing for any migrant agricultural worker shall post in a conspicuous place or present to such worker a statement of the terms and conditions, if any, of occupancy of such housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping and information requirements imposed upon employers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recordkeeping and information requirements imposed upon employers Each farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, and agricultural association which employs any migrant agricultural worker shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing of records by farm labor contractor; maintenance of records by recipient</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Furnishing of records by farm labor contractor; maintenance of records by recipient Each farm labor contractor shall provide to any other farm labor contractor, and to any agricultural employer and agricultural association to which such farm labor contractor has furnished migrant agricultural workers, copies of all records with respect to each such worker which such farm labor contractor is required to retain by subsection (d)(1). The recipient of such records shall keep them for a period of three years from the end of the period of employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on knowingly providing false or misleading information to workers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition on knowingly providing false or misleading information to workers No farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, or agricultural association shall knowingly provide false or misleading information to any migrant agricultural worker concerning the terms, conditions, or existence of agricultural employment required to be disclosed by subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1821_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and language requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Form and language requirements The information required to be disclosed by subsections (a) through (c) of this section to migrant agricultural workers shall be provided in written form. Such information shall be provided in English or, as necessary and reasonable, in Spanish or other language common to migrant agricultural workers who are not fluent or literate in English. The Department of Labor shall make forms available in English, Spanish, and other languages, as necessary, which may be used in providing workers with information required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>