<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1832" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1832/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1832/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1832"><akn:num>1832</akn:num><akn:heading>Wages, supplies, and other working arrangements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1832. Wages, supplies, and other working arrangements(a) Payment of wagesEach farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, and agricultural association which employs any seasonal agricultural worker shall pay the wages owed to such worker when due.


(b) Purchase of goods or services by workerNo farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, or agricultural association shall require any seasonal agricultural worker to purchase any goods or services solely from such farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, or agricultural association.


(c) Violation of terms of working arrangementNo farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, or agricultural association shall, without justification, violate the terms of any working arrangement made by that contractor, employer, or association with any seasonal agricultural worker.


(Pub. L. 97–470, title III, § 302, Jan. 14, 1983, 96 Stat. 2593.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective 90 days from Jan. 14, 1983, see section 524 of Pub. L. 97–470, set out as a note under section 1801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1832_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of wages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payment of wages Each farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, and agricultural association which employs any seasonal agricultural worker shall pay the wages owed to such worker when due.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1832_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of goods or services by worker</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purchase of goods or services by worker No farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, or agricultural association shall require any seasonal agricultural worker to purchase any goods or services solely from such farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, or agricultural association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1832_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violation of terms of working arrangement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Violation of terms of working arrangement No farm labor contractor, agricultural employer, or agricultural association shall, without justification, violate the terms of any working arrangement made by that contractor, employer, or association with any seasonal agricultural worker.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>