<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/1902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1902"><akn:num>1902</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued operation of Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1902. Continued operation of Center(a) Administration by Secretary of EducationThe Secretary of Education shall continue to administer and support the Helen Keller National Center for Youths and Adults who are Deaf-Blind in the same manner as such Center was administered prior to February 22, 1984, to the extent such manner of administration is not inconsistent with any purpose described in subsection (b) or any other requirement of this chapter.


(b) Purposes of CenterThe purposes of the Center are to—(1) provide specialized intensive services, or any other services, at the Center or anywhere else in the United States, which are necessary to encourage the maximum personal development of any individual who is deaf-blind;

(2) train family members of individuals who are deaf-blind at the Center or anywhere else in the United States, in order to assist family members in providing and obtaining appropriate services for the individual who is deaf-blind;

(3) train professionals and allied personnel at the Center or anywhere else in the United States to provide services to individuals who are deaf-blind; and

(4) conduct applied research, development programs, and demonstrations with respect to communication techniques, teaching methods, aids and devices, and delivery of services.


(Pub. L. 98–221, title II, § 203, Feb. 22, 1984, 98 Stat. 33; Pub. L. 102–569, title IX, §§ 902, 908, Oct. 29, 1992, 106 Stat. 4482, 4485.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of Pub. L. 98–221, Feb. 22, 1984, 98 Stat. 32, which is classified generally to this chapter (§ 1901 et seq.). For complete classification of this title to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1901 of this title and Tables. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1984 Amendment note set out under section 701 of this title and Tables.

Amendments1992—Pub. L. 102–569, § 908(c)(2),</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration by Secretary of Education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administration by Secretary of Education The Secretary of Education shall continue to administer and support the Helen Keller National Center for Youths and Adults who are Deaf-Blind in the same manner as such Center was administered prior to February 22, 1984, to the extent such manner of administration is not inconsistent with any purpose described in subsection (b) or any other requirement of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes of Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purposes of Center The purposes of the Center are to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>