<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2001" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2001/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2001/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2001"><akn:num>2001</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2001. Definitions
As used in this chapter:(1) CommerceThe term “commerce” has the meaning provided by section 203(b) of this title.


(2) EmployerThe term “employer” includes any person acting directly or indirectly in the interest of an employer in relation to an employee or prospective employee.


(3) Lie detectorThe term “lie detector” includes a polygraph, deceptograph, voice stress analyzer, psychological stress evaluator, or any other similar device (whether mechanical or electrical) that is used, or the results of which are used, for the purpose of rendering a diagnostic opinion regarding the honesty or dishonesty of an individual.


(4) PolygraphThe term “polygraph” means an instrument that—(A) records continuously, visually, permanently, and simultaneously changes in cardiovascular, respiratory, and electrodermal patterns as minimum instrumentation standards; and

(B) is used, or the results of which are used, for the purpose of rendering a diagnostic opinion regarding the honesty or dishonesty of an individual.


(5) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.


(Pub. L. 100–347, § 2, June 27, 1988, 102 Stat. 646.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 100–347, § 11, June 27, 1988, 102 Stat. 653, provided that:
“(a) In General.—Except as provided in subsection (b), this Act [enacting this chapter] shall become effective 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act [June 27, 1988].

“(b) Regulations.—Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue such rules and regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out this Act.”




Short TitlePub. L. 100–347, § 1, June 27, 1988, 102 Stat. 646, provided that: “This Act [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988’.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2001_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Commerce The term “commerce” has the meaning provided by section 203(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2001_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Employer The term “employer” includes any person acting directly or indirectly in the interest of an employer in relation to an employee or prospective employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2001_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lie detector</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Lie detector The term “lie detector” includes a polygraph, deceptograph, voice stress analyzer, psychological stress evaluator, or any other similar device (whether mechanical or electrical) that is used, or the results of which are used, for the purpose of rendering a diagnostic opinion regarding the honesty or dishonesty of an individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2001_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Polygraph</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Polygraph The term “polygraph” means an instrument that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2001_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>