<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2005" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2005/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2005/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2005"><akn:num>2005</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2005. Enforcement provisions(a) Civil penalties(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), any employer who violates any provision of this chapter may be assessed a civil penalty of not more than $10,000.


(2) Determination of amountIn determining the amount of any penalty under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall take into account the previous record of the person in terms of compliance with this chapter and the gravity of the violation.


(3) CollectionAny civil penalty assessed under this subsection shall be collected in the same manner as is required by subsections (b) through (e) of section 1853 of this title with respect to civil penalties assessed under subsection (a) of such section.



(b) Injunctive actions by SecretaryThe Secretary may bring an action under this section to restrain violations of this chapter. The Solicitor of Labor may appear for and represent the Secretary in any litigation brought under this chapter. In any action brought under this section, the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown, to issue temporary or permanent restraining orders and injunctions to require compliance with this chapter, including such legal or equitable relief incident thereto as may be appropriate, including, but not limited to, employment, reinstatement, promotion, and the payment of lost wages and benefits.


(c) Private civil actions(1) LiabilityAn employer who violates this chapter shall be liable to the employee or prospective employee affected by such violation. Such employer shall be liable for such legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate, including, but not limited to, employment, reinstatement, promotion, and the payment of lost wages and benefits.


(2) CourtAn action to recover the liability prescribed in paragraph (1) may be maintained against the employer in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction by an employee or prospective employee for or on behalf of such employee, prospective employee, and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Civil penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctive actions by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Injunctive actions by Secretary The Secretary may bring an action under this section to restrain violations of this chapter. The Solicitor of Labor may appear for and represent the Secretary in any litigation brought under this chapter. In any action brought under this section, the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction, for cause shown, to issue temporary or permanent restraining orders and injunctions to require compliance with this chapter, including such legal or equitable relief incident thereto as may be appropriate, including, but not limited to, employment, reinstatement, promotion, and the payment of lost wages and benefits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Private civil actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of rights prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver of rights prohibited The rights and procedures provided by this chapter may not be waived by contract or otherwise, unless such waiver is part of a written settlement agreed to and signed by the parties to the pending action or complaint under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>