<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2006" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2006/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2006/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2006"><akn:num>2006</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2006. Exemptions(a) No application to governmental employersThis chapter shall not apply with respect to the United States Government, any State or local government, or any political subdivision of a State or local government.


(b) National defense and security exemption(1) National defenseNothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the administration, by the Federal Government, in the performance of any counterintelligence function, of any lie detector test to—(A) any expert or consultant under contract to the Department of Defense or any employee of any contractor of such Department; or

(B) any expert or consultant under contract with the Department of Energy in connection with the atomic energy defense activities of such Department or any employee of any contractor of such Department in connection with such activities.


(2) SecurityNothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the administration, by the Federal Government, in the performance of any intelligence or counterintelligence function, of any lie detector test to—(A)(i) any individual employed by, assigned to, or detailed to, the National Security Agency, the Defense Intelligence Agency, the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency, or the Central Intelligence Agency,

(ii) any expert or consultant under contract to any such agency,

(iii) any employee of a contractor to any such agency,

(iv) any individual applying for a position in any such agency, or

(v) any individual assigned to a space where sensitive cryptologic information is produced, processed, or stored for any such agency; or


(B) any expert, or consultant (or employee of such expert or consultant) under contract with any Federal Government department, agency, or program whose duties involve access to information that has been classified at the level of top secret or designated as being within a special access program under section 4.2(a) of Executive Order 12356 (or a successor Executive order).



(c) FBI contracto</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>No application to governmental employers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) No application to governmental employers This chapter shall not apply with respect to the United States Government, any State or local government, or any political subdivision of a State or local government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National defense and security exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National defense and security exemption</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>FBI contractors exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) FBI contractors exemption Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit the administration, by the Federal Government, in the performance of any counterintelligence function, of any lie detector test to an employee of a contractor of the Federal Bureau of Investigation of the Department of Justice who is engaged in the performance of any work under the contract with such Bureau.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited exemption for ongoing investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limited exemption for ongoing investigations Subject to sections 2007 and 2009 of this title, this chapter shall not prohibit an employer from requesting an employee to submit to a polygraph test if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for security services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemption for security services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for drug security, drug theft, or drug diversion investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemption for drug security, drug theft, or drug diversion investigations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>