<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/204" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/204/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/204/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_204"><akn:num>204</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 204. Administration(a) Creation of Wage and Hour Division in Department of Labor; AdministratorThere is created in the Department of Labor a Wage and Hour Division which shall be under the direction of an Administrator, to be known as the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division (in this chapter referred to as the “Administrator”). The Administrator shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(b) Appointment, selection, classification, and promotion of employees by AdministratorThe Administrator may, subject to the civil-service laws, appoint such employees as he deems necessary to carry out his functions and duties under this chapter and shall fix their compensation in accordance with chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5. The Administrator may establish and utilize such regional, local, or other agencies, and utilize such voluntary and uncompensated services, as may from time to time be needed. Attorneys appointed under this section may appear for and represent the Administrator in any litigation, but all such litigation shall be subject to the direction and control of the Attorney General. In the appointment, selection, classification, and promotion of officers and employees of the Administrator, no political test or qualification shall be permitted or given consideration, but all such appointments and promotions shall be given and made on the basis of merit and efficiency.


(c) Principal office of Administrator; jurisdictionThe principal office of the Administrator shall be in the District of Columbia, but he or his duly authorized representative may exercise any or all of his powers in any place.


(d) Biennial report to Congress; studies of exemptions to hour and wage provisions and means to prevent curtailment of employment opportunities(1) The Secretary shall submit biennially in January a report to the Congress covering his activities for the preceding two years and including such informati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_204_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation of Wage and Hour Division in Department of Labor; Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation of Wage and Hour Division in Department of Labor; Administrator There is created in the Department of Labor a Wage and Hour Division which shall be under the direction of an Administrator, to be known as the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division (in this chapter referred to as the “Administrator”). The Administrator shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_204_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment, selection, classification, and promotion of employees by Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment, selection, classification, and promotion of employees by Administrator The Administrator may, subject to the civil-service laws, appoint such employees as he deems necessary to carry out his functions and duties under this chapter and shall fix their compensation in accordance with chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5. The Administrator may establish and utilize such regional, local, or other agencies, and utilize such voluntary and uncompensated services, as may from time to time be needed. Attorneys appointed under this section may appear for and represent the Administrator in any litigation, but all such litigation shall be subject to the direction and control of the Attorney General. In the appointment, selection, classification, and promotion of officers and employees of the Administrator, no political test or qualification shall be permitted or given consideration, but all such appointments and promotions shall be given and made on the basis of </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_204_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal office of Administrator; jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Principal office of Administrator; jurisdiction The principal office of the Administrator shall be in the District of Columbia, but he or his duly authorized representative may exercise any or all of his powers in any place.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_204_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biennial report to Congress; studies of exemptions to hour and wage provisions and means to prevent curtailment of employment opportunities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Biennial report to Congress; studies of exemptions to hour and wage provisions and means to prevent curtailment of employment opportunities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_204_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of effects of foreign production on un­employment; report to President and Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Study of effects of foreign production on un­employment; report to President and Congress Whenever the Secretary has reason to believe that in any industry under this chapter the competition of foreign producers in United States markets or in markets abroad, or both, has resulted, or is likely to result, in increased unemployment in the United States, he shall undertake an investigation to gain full information with respect to the matter. If he determines such increased unemployment has in fact resulted, or is in fact likely to result, from such competition, he shall make a full and complete report of his findings and determinations to the President and to the Congress: Provided, That he may also include in such report information on the increased employment resulting from additional exports in any industry under this chapter as he may determine to be pertinent to such report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_204_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees of Library of Congress; administration of provisions by Office of Personnel Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employees of Library of Congress; administration of provisions by Office of Personnel Management The Secretary is authorized to enter into an agreement with the Librarian of Congress with respect to individuals employed in the Library of Congress to provide for the carrying out of the Secretary’s functions under this chapter with respect to such individuals. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, or any other law, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management is authorized to administer the provisions of this chapter with respect to any individual employed by the United States (other than an individual employed in the Library of Congress, United States Postal Service, Postal Regulatory Commission, or the Tennessee Valley Authority). Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect the right of an employee to bring an action for unpaid minimum wages, or unpaid overtime compensation, and liquidated damages under section 216(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>