<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/206" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/206/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/206/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_206"><akn:num>206</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum wage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 206. Minimum wage(a) Employees engaged in commerce; home workers in Puerto Rico and Virgin Islands; employees in American Samoa; seamen on American vessels; agricultural employeesEvery employer shall pay to each of his employees who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, wages at the following rates:(1) except as otherwise provided in this section, not less than—(A) $5.85 an hour, beginning on the 60th day after May 25, 2007;

(B) $6.55 an hour, beginning 12 months after that 60th day; and

(C) $7.25 an hour, beginning 24 months after that 60th day;


(2) if such employee is a home worker in Puerto Rico or the Virgin Islands, not less than the minimum piece rate prescribed by regulation or order; or, if no such minimum piece rate is in effect, any piece rate adopted by such employer which shall yield, to the proportion or class of employees prescribed by regulation or order, not less than the applicable minimum hourly wage rate. Such minimum piece rates or employer piece rates shall be commensurate with, and shall be paid in lieu of, the minimum hourly wage rate applicable under the provisions of this section. The Administrator, or his authorized representative, shall have power to make such regulations or orders as are necessary or appropriate to carry out any of the provisions of this paragraph, including the power without limiting the generality of the foregoing, to define any operation or occupation which is performed by such home work employees in Puerto Rico or the Virgin Islands; to establish minimum piece rates for any operation or occupation so defined; to prescribe the method and procedure for ascertaining and promulgating minimum piece rates; to prescribe standards for employer piece rates, including the proportion or class of employees who shall receive not less than the minimum hourly wage rate; to define the term</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees engaged in commerce; home workers in Puerto Rico and Virgin Islands; employees in American Samoa; seamen on American vessels; agricultural employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employees engaged in commerce; home workers in Puerto Rico and Virgin Islands; employees in American Samoa; seamen on American vessels; agricultural employees Every employer shall pay to each of his employees who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, wages at the following rates:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional applicability to employees pursuant to subsequent amendatory provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional applicability to employees pursuant to subsequent amendatory provisions Every employer shall pay to each of his employees (other than an employee to whom subsection (a)(5) 11 See References in Text note below. applies) who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, and who in such workweek is brought within the purview of this section by the amendments made to this chapter by the Fair Labor Standards Amendments of 1966, title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 [20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.], or the Fair Labor Standards Amendments of 1974, wages at the following rate: Effective after December 31, 1977, not less than the minimum wage rate in effect under subsection (a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–188, [title II], § 2104(c), Aug. 20, 1996, 110 Stat. 1929</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of sex discrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition of sex discrimination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees of employers providing contract services to United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Employees of employers providing contract services to United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees in domestic service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employees in domestic service Any employee— shall be paid wages for such employment in such workweek at a rate not less than the wage rate in effect under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_206_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Newly hired employees who are less than 20 years old</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Newly hired employees who are less than 20 years old</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>