<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/207" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/207/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/207/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_207"><akn:num>207</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum hours</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 207. Maximum hours(a) Employees engaged in interstate commerce; additional applicability to employees pursuant to subsequent amendatory provisions(1) Except as otherwise provided in this section, no employer shall employ any of his employees who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, for a workweek longer than forty hours unless such employee receives compensation for his employment in excess of the hours above specified at a rate not less than one and one-half times the regular rate at which he is employed.

(2) No employer shall employ any of his employees who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, and who in such workweek is brought within the purview of this subsection by the amendments made to this chapter by the Fair Labor Standards Amendments of 1966—(A) for a workweek longer than forty-four hours during the first year from the effective date of the Fair Labor Standards Amendments of 1966,

(B) for a workweek longer than forty-two hours during the second year from such date, or

(C) for a workweek longer than forty hours after the expiration of the second year from such date,


unless such employee receives compensation for his employment in excess of the hours above specified at a rate not less than one and one-half times the regular rate at which he is employed.


(b) Employment pursuant to collective bargaining agreement; employment by independently owned and controlled local enterprise engaged in distribution of petroleum productsNo employer shall be deemed to have violated subsection (a) by employing any employee for a workweek in excess of that specified in such subsection without paying the compensation for overtime employment prescribed therein if such employee is so employe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees engaged in interstate commerce; additional applicability to employees pursuant to subsequent amendatory provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employees engaged in interstate commerce; additional applicability to employees pursuant to subsequent amendatory provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment pursuant to collective bargaining agreement; employment by independently owned and controlled local enterprise engaged in distribution of petroleum products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Employment pursuant to collective bargaining agreement; employment by independently owned and controlled local enterprise engaged in distribution of petroleum products No employer shall be deemed to have violated subsection (a) by employing any employee for a workweek in excess of that specified in such subsection without paying the compensation for overtime employment prescribed therein if such employee is so employed— and if such employee receives compensation for employment in excess of twelve hours in any workday, or for employment in excess of fifty-six hours in any workweek, as the case may be, at a rate not less than one and one-half times the regular rate at which he is employed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (d) Repealed. Pub. L. 93–259, § 19(e), Apr. 8, 1974, 88 Stat. 66</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) , (d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Regular rate” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Regular rate” defined As used in this section the “regular rate” at which an employee is employed shall be deemed to include all remuneration for employment paid to, or on behalf of, the employee, but shall not be deemed to include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment necessitating irregular hours of work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employment necessitating irregular hours of work No employer shall be deemed to have violated subsection (a) by employing any employee for a workweek in excess of the maximum workweek applicable to such employee under subsection (a) if such employee is employed pursuant to a bona fide individual contract, or pursuant to an agreement made as a result of collective bargaining by representatives of employees, if the duties of such employee necessitate irregular hours of work, and the contract or agreement (1) specifies a regular rate of pay of not less than the minimum hourly rate provided in subsection (a) or (b) of section 206 of this title (whichever may be applicable) and compensation at not less than one and one-half times such rate for all hours worked in excess of such maximum workweek, and (2) provides a weekly guaranty of pay for not more than sixty hours based on the rates so specified.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment at piece rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Employment at piece rates No employer shall be deemed to have violated subsection (a) by employing any employee for a workweek in excess of the maximum workweek applicable to such employee under such subsection if, pursuant to an agreement or understanding arrived at between the employer and the employee before performance of the work, the amount paid to the employee for the number of hours worked by him in such workweek in excess of the maximum workweek applicable to such employee under such subsection— and if (i) the employee’s average hourly earnings for the workweek exclusive of payments described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (e) are not less than the minimum hourly rate required by applicable law, and (ii) extra overtime compensation is properly computed and paid on other forms of additional pay required to be included in computing the regular rate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit toward minimum wage or overtime compensation of amounts excluded from regular rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Credit toward minimum wage or overtime compensation of amounts excluded from regular rate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment by retail or service establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Employment by retail or service establishment No employer shall be deemed to have violated subsection (a) by employing any employee of a retail or service establishment for a workweek in excess of the applicable workweek specified therein, if (1) the regular rate of pay of such employee is in excess of one and one-half times the minimum hourly rate applicable to him under section 206 of this title, and (2) more than half his compensation for a representative period (not less than one month) represents commissions on goods or services. In determining the proportion of compensation representing commissions, all earnings resulting from the application of a bona fide commission rate shall be deemed commissions on goods or services without regard to whether the computed commissions exceed the draw or guarantee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment in hospital or establishment engaged in care of sick, aged, or mentally ill</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Employment in hospital or establishment engaged in care of sick, aged, or mentally ill No employer engaged in the operation of a hospital or an establishment which is an institution primarily engaged in the care of the sick, the aged, or the mentally ill or defective who reside on the premises shall be deemed to have violated subsection (a) if, pursuant to an agreement or understanding arrived at between the employer and the employee before performance of the work, a work period of fourteen consecutive days is accepted in lieu of the workweek of seven consecutive days for purposes of overtime computation and if, for his employment in excess of eight hours in any workday and in excess of eighty hours in such fourteen-day period, the employee receives compensation at a rate not less than one and one-half times the regular rate at which he is employed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment by public agency engaged in fire protection or law enforcement activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) Employment by public agency engaged in fire protection or law enforcement activities No public agency shall be deemed to have violated subsection (a) with respect to the employment of any employee in fire protection activities or any employee in law enforcement activities (including security personnel in correctional institutions) if— compensation at a rate not less than one and one-half times the regular rate at which he is employed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>