<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/213" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/213/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/213/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_213"><akn:num>213</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 213. Exemptions(a) Minimum wage and maximum hour requirementsThe provisions of sections 206 (except subsection (d) in the case of paragraph (1) of this subsection) and 207 of this title shall not apply with respect to—(1) any employee employed in a bona fide executive, administrative, or professional capacity (including any employee employed in the capacity of academic administrative personnel or teacher in elementary or secondary schools), or in the capacity of outside salesman (as such terms are defined and delimited from time to time by regulations of the Secretary, subject to the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5, except that an employee of a retail or service establishment shall not be excluded from the definition of employee employed in a bona fide executive or administrative capacity because of the number of hours in his workweek which he devotes to activities not directly or closely related to the performance of executive or administrative activities, if less than 40 per centum of his hours worked in the workweek are devoted to such activities); or

(2) Repealed. Pub. L. 101–157, § 3(c)(1), Nov. 17, 1989, 103 Stat. 939.

(3) any employee employed by an establishment which is an amusement or recreational establishment, organized camp, or religious or non-profit educational conference center, if (A) it does not operate for more than seven months in any calendar year, or (B) during the preceding calendar year, its average receipts for any six months of such year were not more than 33⅓ per centum of its average receipts for the other six months of such year, except that the exemption from sections 206 and 207 of this title provided by this paragraph does not apply with respect to any employee of a private entity engaged in providing services or facilities (other than, in the case of the exemption from section 206 of this title, a private entity engaged in providing services and facilities directly related to skiing) in a national park or a na</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum wage and maximum hour requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Minimum wage and maximum hour requirements The provisions of sections 206 (except subsection (d) in the case of paragraph (1) of this subsection) and 207 of this title shall not apply with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum hour requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Maximum hour requirements The provisions of section 207 of this title shall not apply with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Child labor requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Child labor requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of newspapers and wreathmaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Delivery of newspapers and wreathmaking The provisions of sections 206, 207, and 212 of this title shall not apply with respect to any employee engaged in the delivery of newspapers to the consumer or to any homeworker engaged in the making of wreaths composed principally of natural holly, pine, cedar, or other evergreens (including the harvesting of the evergreens or other forest products used in making such wreaths).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum hour requirements and minimum wage employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Maximum hour requirements and minimum wage employees The provisions of section 207 of this title shall not apply with respect to employees for whom the Secretary of Labor is authorized to establish minimum wage rates as provided in section 206(a)(3) 1 of this title, except with respect to employees for whom such rates are in effect; and with respect to such employees the Secretary may make rules and regulations providing reasonable limitations and allowing reasonable variations, tolerances, and exemptions to and from any or all of the provisions of section 207 of this title if he shall find, after a public hearing on the matter, and taking into account the factors set forth in section 206(a)(3) 1 of this title, that economic conditions warrant such action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment in foreign countries and certain United States territories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employment in foreign countries and certain United States territories The provisions of sections 206, 207, 211, and 212 of this title shall not apply with respect to any employee whose services during the workweek are performed in a workplace within a foreign country or within territory under the jurisdiction of the United States other than the following: a State of the United States; the District of Columbia; Puerto Rico; the Virgin Islands; outer Continental Shelf lands defined in the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (ch. 345, 67 Stat. 462) [43 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.]; American Samoa; Guam; Wake Island; Eniwetok Atoll; Kwajalein Atoll; and Johnston Island.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain employment in retail or service establishments, agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certain employment in retail or service establishments, agriculture The exemption from section 206 of this title provided by paragraph (6) of subsection (a) of this section shall not apply with respect to any employee employed by an establishment (1) which controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with, another establishment the activities of which are not related for a common business purpose to, but materially support the activities of the establishment employing such employee; and (2) whose annual gross volume of sales made or business done, when combined with the annual gross volume of sales made or business done by each establishment which controls, is controlled by, or is under common control with, the establishment employing such employee, exceeds $10,000,000 (exclusive of excise taxes at the retail level which are separately stated).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum hour requirement: fourteen workweek limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Maximum hour requirement: fourteen workweek limitation The provisions of section 207 of this title shall not apply for a period or periods of not more than fourteen workweeks in the aggregate in any calendar year to any employee who— Any employer who receives an exemption under this subsection shall not be eligible for any other exemption under this section or section 207 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cotton ginning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Cotton ginning The provisions of section 207 of this title shall not apply for a period or periods of not more than fourteen workweeks in the aggregate in any period of fifty-two consecutive weeks to any employee who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_213_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Processing of sugar beets, sugar beet molasses, or sugar cane</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Processing of sugar beets, sugar beet molasses, or sugar cane The provisions of section 207 of this title shall not apply for a period or periods of not more than fourteen workweeks in the aggregate in any period of fifty-two consecutive weeks to any employee who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>