<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/218d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/218d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/218d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_218d"><akn:num>218d</akn:num><akn:heading>Breastfeeding accommodations in the workplace</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 218d. Breastfeeding accommodations in the workplace(a) In generalAn employer shall provide—(1) a reasonable break time for an employee to express breast milk for such employee’s nursing child for 1 year after the child’s birth each time such employee has need to express the milk; and

(2) a place, other than a bathroom, that is shielded from view and free from intrusion from coworkers and the public, which may be used by an employee to express breast milk.


(b) Compensation(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), an employer shall not be required to compensate an employee receiving reasonable break time under subsection (a)(1) for any time spent during the workday for such purpose unless otherwise required by Federal or State law or municipal ordinance.


(2) Relief from dutiesBreak time provided under subsection (a)(1) shall be considered hours worked if the employee is not completely relieved from duty during the entirety of such break.



(c) Exemption for small employersAn employer that employs less than 50 employees shall not be subject to the requirements of this section, if such requirements would impose an undue hardship by causing the employer significant difficulty or expense when considered in relation to the size, financial resources, nature, or structure of the employer’s business.


(d) Exemption for crewmembers of air carriers(1) In generalAn employer that is an air carrier shall not be subject to the requirements of this section with respect to an employee of such air carrier who is a crewmember 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.


(2) DefinitionsIn this subsection:(A) Air carrierThe term “air carrier” has the meaning given such term in section 40102 of title 49.


(B) CrewmemberThe term “crewmember” has the meaning given such term in section 1.1 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).




(e) Applicability to rail carriers(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), an employer that is a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general An employer shall provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for small employers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exemption for small employers An employer that employs less than 50 employees shall not be subject to the requirements of this section, if such requirements would impose an undue hardship by causing the employer significant difficulty or expense when considered in relation to the size, financial resources, nature, or structure of the employer’s business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for crewmembers of air carriers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemption for crewmembers of air carriers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to rail carriers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability to rail carriers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to motorcoach services operators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicability to motorcoach services operators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification prior to commencement of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notification prior to commencement of action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_218d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interaction with State and Federal law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Interaction with State and Federal law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>