<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/253" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/253/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/253/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_253"><akn:num>253</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise and waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 253. Compromise and waiver(a) Compromise of certain existing claims under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, the Walsh-Healey Act, or the Bacon-Davis Act; limitationsAny cause of action under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended [29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.], the Walsh-Healey Act, or the Bacon-Davis Act,11 See References in Text note below. which accrued prior to May 14, 1947, or any action (whether instituted prior to or on or after May 14, 1947) to enforce such a cause of action, may hereafter be compromised in whole or in part, if there exists a bona fide dispute as to the amount payable by the employer to his employee; except that no such action or cause of action may be so compromised to the extent that such compromise is based on an hourly wage rate less than the minimum required under such Act, or on a payment for overtime at a rate less than one and one-half times such minimum hourly wage rate.


(b) Waiver of liquidated damages under Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938Any employee may hereafter waive his right under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended [29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.], to liquidated damages, in whole or in part, with respect to activities engaged in prior to May 14, 1947.


(c) SatisfactionAny such compromise or waiver, in the absence of fraud or duress, shall, according to the terms thereof, be a complete satisfaction of such cause of action and a complete bar to any action based on such cause of action.


(d) Retroactive effect of sectionThe provisions of this section shall also be applicable to any compromise or waiver heretofore so made or given.


(e) “Compromise” definedAs used in this section, the term “compromise” includes “adjustment”, “settlement”, and “release”.


(May 14, 1947, ch. 52, § 3, 61 Stat. 86.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is act June 25, 1938, ch. 676, 52 Stat. 1060, which is classified generally to chapter 8 (§ 20</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_253_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise of certain existing claims under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, the Walsh-Healey Act, or the Bacon-Davis Act; limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compromise of certain existing claims under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, the Walsh-Healey Act, or the Bacon-Davis Act; limitations Any cause of action under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended [29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.], the Walsh-Healey Act, or the Bacon-Davis Act,11 See References in Text note below. which accrued prior to May 14, 1947, or any action (whether instituted prior to or on or after May 14, 1947) to enforce such a cause of action, may hereafter be compromised in whole or in part, if there exists a bona fide dispute as to the amount payable by the employer to his employee; except that no such action or cause of action may be so compromised to the extent that such compromise is based on an hourly wage rate less than the minimum required under such Act, or on a payment for overtime at a rate less than one and one-half times such minimum hourly wage rate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_253_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of liquidated damages under Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Waiver of liquidated damages under Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 Any employee may hereafter waive his right under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, as amended [29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.], to liquidated damages, in whole or in part, with respect to activities engaged in prior to May 14, 1947.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_253_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Satisfaction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Satisfaction Any such compromise or waiver, in the absence of fraud or duress, shall, according to the terms thereof, be a complete satisfaction of such cause of action and a complete bar to any action based on such cause of action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_253_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retroactive effect of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Retroactive effect of section The provisions of this section shall also be applicable to any compromise or waiver heretofore so made or given.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_253_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Compromise” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Compromise” defined As used in this section, the term “compromise” includes “adjustment”, “settlement”, and “release”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>