<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2611" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2611/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2611/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2611"><akn:num>2611</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2611. Definitions
As used in this subchapter:(1) CommerceThe terms “commerce” and “industry or activity affecting commerce” mean any activity, business, or industry in commerce or in which a labor dispute would hinder or obstruct commerce or the free flow of commerce, and include “commerce” and any “industry affecting commerce”, as defined in paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 142 of this title.


(2) Eligible employee(A) In generalThe term “eligible employee” means an employee who has been employed—(i) for at least 12 months by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under section 2612 of this title; and

(ii) for at least 1,250 hours of service with such employer during the previous 12-month period.


(B) ExclusionsThe term “eligible employee” does not include—(i) any Federal officer or employee covered under subchapter V of chapter 63 of title 5; or

(ii) any employee of an employer who is employed at a worksite at which such employer employs less than 50 employees if the total number of employees employed by that employer within 75 miles of that worksite is less than 50.


(C) DeterminationFor purposes of determining whether an employee meets the hours of service requirement specified in subparagraph (A)(ii), the legal standards established under section 207 of this title shall apply.


(D) Airline flight crews(i) DeterminationFor purposes of determining whether an employee who is a flight attendant or flight crewmember (as such terms are defined in regulations of the Federal Aviation Administration) meets the hours of service requirement specified in subparagraph (A)(ii), the employee will be considered to meet the requirement if—(I) the employee has worked or been paid for not less than 60 percent of the applicable total monthly guarantee, or the equivalent, for the previous 12-month period, for or by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under section 2612 of this title; and

(II) the employee has worked or been paid for not less </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Commerce The terms “commerce” and “industry or activity affecting commerce” mean any activity, business, or industry in commerce or in which a labor dispute would hinder or obstruct commerce or the free flow of commerce, and include “commerce” and any “industry affecting commerce”, as defined in paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 142 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible employee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Eligible employee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employ; employee; State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Employ; employee; State The terms “employ”, “employee”, and “State” have the same meanings given such terms in subsections (c), (e), and (g) of section 203 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Employer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Employment benefits The term “employment benefits” means all benefits provided or made available to employees by an employer, including group life insurance, health insurance, disability insurance, sick leave, annual leave, educational benefits, and pensions, regardless of whether such benefits are provided by a practice or written policy of an employer or through an “employee benefit plan”, as defined in section 1002(3) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care provider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Health care provider The term “health care provider” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Parent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Parent The term “parent” means the biological parent of an employee or an individual who stood in loco parentis to an employee when the employee was a son or daughter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Person The term “person” has the same meaning given such term in section 203(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduced leave schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Reduced leave schedule The term “reduced leave schedule” means a leave schedule that reduces the usual number of hours per workweek, or hours per workday, of an employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2611_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>