<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2613" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2613/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2613/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2613"><akn:num>2613</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2613. Certification(a) In generalAn employer may require that a request for leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) or paragraph (3) of section 2612(a) of this title be supported by a certification issued by the health care provider of the eligible employee or of the son, daughter, spouse, or parent of the employee, or of the next of kin of an individual in the case of leave taken under such paragraph (3), as appropriate. The employee shall provide, in a timely manner, a copy of such certification to the employer.


(b) Sufficient certificationCertification provided under subsection (a) shall be sufficient if it states—(1) the date on which the serious health condition commenced;

(2) the probable duration of the condition;

(3) the appropriate medical facts within the knowledge of the health care provider regarding the condition;

(4)(A) for purposes of leave under section 2612(a)(1)(C) of this title, a statement that the eligible employee is needed to care for the son, daughter, spouse, or parent and an estimate of the amount of time that such employee is needed to care for the son, daughter, spouse, or parent; and

(B) for purposes of leave under section 2612(a)(1)(D) of this title, a statement that the employee is unable to perform the functions of the position of the employee;


(5) in the case of certification for intermittent leave, or leave on a reduced leave schedule, for planned medical treatment, the dates on which such treatment is expected to be given and the duration of such treatment;

(6) in the case of certification for intermittent leave, or leave on a reduced leave schedule, under section 2612(a)(1)(D) of this title, a statement of the medical necessity for the intermittent leave or leave on a reduced leave schedule, and the expected duration of the intermittent leave or reduced leave schedule; and

(7) in the case of certification for intermittent leave, or leave on a reduced leave schedule, under section 2612(a)(1)(C) of this titl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general An employer may require that a request for leave under subparagraph (C) or (D) of paragraph (1) or paragraph (3) of section 2612(a) of this title be supported by a certification issued by the health care provider of the eligible employee or of the son, daughter, spouse, or parent of the employee, or of the next of kin of an individual in the case of leave taken under such paragraph (3), as appropriate. The employee shall provide, in a timely manner, a copy of such certification to the employer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sufficient certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sufficient certification Certification provided under subsection (a) shall be sufficient if it states—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Second opinion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Second opinion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolution of conflicting opinions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Resolution of conflicting opinions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent recertification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subsequent recertification The employer may require that the eligible employee obtain subsequent recertifications on a reasonable basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification related to covered active duty or call to covered active duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certification related to covered active duty or call to covered active duty An employer may require that a request for leave under section 2612(a)(1)(E) of this title be supported by a certification issued at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe. If the Secretary issues a regulation requiring such certification, the employee shall provide, in a timely manner, a copy of such certification to the employer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>