<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2620" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2620/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2620/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2620"><akn:num>2620</akn:num><akn:heading>Public health emergency leave</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2620. Public health emergency leave(a) DefinitionsThe following shall apply with respect to leave under section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title:(1) Application of certain termsThe definitions in section 2611 of this title shall apply, except as follows:(A) Eligible employee(i) In generalIn lieu of the definition in sections 2611(2)(A) and 2611(2)(B)(ii) of this title, the term “eligible employee” means an employee who has been employed for at least 30 calendar days by the employer with respect to whom leave is requested under section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title.


(ii) 11 So in original. Two cls. (ii) have been enacted. Rule regarding rehired employeesFor purposes of clause (i), the term “employed for at least 30 calendar days”, used with respect to an employee and an employer described in clause (i), includes an employee who was laid off by that employer not earlier than March 1, 2020, had worked for the employer for not less than 30 of the last 60 calendar days prior to the employee’s layoff, and was rehired by the employer.


(ii) 1 Special ruleFor purposes of applying section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title and this section under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 [2 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.], in lieu of the definition in section 202(a)(2)(B) of that Act (2 U.S.C. 1312(a)(2)(B)), the term “eligible employee” means a covered employee (as defined in section 101 of that Act (2 U.S.C. 1301)) who has been employed for at least 30 calendar days by the employing office (as so defined) with respect to whom leave is requested under section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title.



(B) Employer thresholdSection 2611(4)(A)(i) of this title shall be applied by substituting “fewer than 500 employees” for “50 or more employees for each working day during each of 20 or more calendar workweeks in the current or preceding calendar year”.



(2) Additional definitionsIn addition to the definitions described in paragraph (1), the following definitions shall apply with respect to leave under </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2620_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions The following shall apply with respect to leave under section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2620_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to paid leave</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relationship to paid leave</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2620_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice In any case where the necessity for leave under section 2612(a)(1)(F) of this title for the purpose described in subsection (a)(2)(A) is foreseeable, an employee shall provide the employer with such notice of leave as is practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2620_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restoration to position</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Restoration to position</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>