<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/2701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2701"><akn:num>2701</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2701. Findings
The Congress finds and declares the following:(1) In an increasingly competitive world economy, the companies and nations that lead in the rapid development, commercialization, and application of new and advanced technologies, and in the high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services, will lead in economic growth, employment, and high living standards.

(2) While the United States remains the world leader in science and invention, it has not done well in rapidly making the transition from achievement in its research laboratories to high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services. This lag and the unprecedented competitive challenge that the United States has faced from abroad have contributed to a drop in real wages and living standards.

(3) Companies that are successfully competitive in the rapid development, commercialization, application, and implementation of advanced technologies, and in the successful delivery of goods and services, recognize that worker participation and labor-management cooperation in the deployment, application, and implementation of advanced workplace technologies make an important contribution to high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services and in maintaining and improving real wages for workers.

(4) The Federal Government has an important role in encouraging and augmenting private sector efforts relating to the development, application, manufacture, and deployment of new and advanced technologies. The role should be to—(A) work with private companies, States, worker organizations, nonprofit organizations, and institutions of higher education to ensure the development, application, production, and implementation of new and advanced technologies to promote the improvement of workers’ skills, wages, job security, and working conditions, and a healthy environment;

(B) encourage worker and worker organization participation in the development, commercialization</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2701_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) In an increasingly competitive world economy, the companies and nations that lead in the rapid development, commercialization, and application of new and advanced technologies, and in the high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services, will lead in economic growth, employment, and high living standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2701_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) While the United States remains the world leader in science and invention, it has not done well in rapidly making the transition from achievement in its research laboratories to high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services. This lag and the unprecedented competitive challenge that the United States has faced from abroad have contributed to a drop in real wages and living standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2701_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Companies that are successfully competitive in the rapid development, commercialization, application, and implementation of advanced technologies, and in the successful delivery of goods and services, recognize that worker participation and labor-management cooperation in the deployment, application, and implementation of advanced workplace technologies make an important contribution to high-quality, competitively priced production of goods and services and in maintaining and improving real wages for workers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2701_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The Federal Government has an important role in encouraging and augmenting private sector efforts relating to the development, application, manufacture, and deployment of new and advanced technologies. The role should be to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2701_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) In working with the private sector to promote the technological leadership and economic growth of the United States, the Federal Government has a responsibility to ensure that Federal technology programs help the United States to remain competitive and to maintain and improve living standards and to create and retain secure jobs in economically stable communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>