<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3001" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3001/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3001/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3001"><akn:num>3001</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3001. Purposes
The purposes of this chapter are to—(1) to 11 So in original. The word “to” probably should not appear. support State efforts to improve the provision of assistive technology to individuals with disabilities of all ages, including underrepresented populations, through comprehensive statewide programs of technology-related assistance that are designed to—(A) increase the availability of, funding for, access to, provision of, and education about assistive technology devices and assistive technology services;

(B) increase the ability of individuals with disabilities to secure and maintain possession of assistive technology devices as such individuals make the transition between services offered by educational or human service agencies or between settings of daily living (for example, between home and work);

(C) increase the capacity of public agencies and private entities to provide and pay for assistive technology devices and assistive technology services on a statewide basis for individuals with disabilities;

(D) increase the involvement of individuals with disabilities and, if appropriate, their family members, guardians, advocates, and authorized representatives, in decisions related to the provision of assistive technology devices and assistive technology services;

(E) increase and promote coordination among and between State and local agencies and private entities (such as managed care providers), that are involved in carrying out activities under this chapter;

(F) increase the awareness and facilitate the change of laws, regulations, policies, practices, procedures, and organizational structures that facilitate the availability or provision of assistive technology devices and assistive technology services; and

(G) increase awareness and knowledge of the benefits of assistive technology devices and assistive technology services among targeted individuals and entities and the general population; and


(2) to 1 provide States and protection a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) to 11 So in original. The word “to” probably should not appear. support State efforts to improve the provision of assistive technology to individuals with disabilities of all ages, including underrepresented populations, through comprehensive statewide programs of technology-related assistance that are designed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) to 1 provide States and protection and advocacy systems with financial assistance that supports programs designed to maximize the ability of individuals with disabilities and their family members, guardians, advocates, and authorized representatives to obtain assistive technology devices and assistive technology services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>