<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3112"><akn:num>3112</akn:num><akn:heading>Unified State plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3112. Unified State plan(a) PlanFor a State to be eligible to receive allotments for the core programs, the Governor shall submit to the Secretary of Labor for the approval process described under subsection (c)(2), a unified State plan. The unified State plan shall outline a 4-year strategy for the core programs of the State and meet the requirements of this section.


(b) Contents(1) Strategic planning elementsThe unified State plan shall include strategic planning elements consisting of a strategic vision and goals for preparing an educated and skilled workforce, that include—(A) an analysis of the economic conditions in the State, including—(i) existing and emerging in-demand industry sectors and occupations; and

(ii) the employment needs of employers, including a description of the knowledge, skills, and abilities, needed in those industries and occupations;


(B) an analysis of the current workforce, employment and unemployment data, labor market trends, and the educational and skill levels of the workforce, including individuals with barriers to employment (including individuals with disabilities), in the State;

(C) an analysis of the workforce development activities (including education and training) in the State, including an analysis of the strengths and weaknesses of such activities, and the capacity of State entities to provide such activities, in order to address the identified education and skill needs of the workforce and the employment needs of employers in the State;

(D) a description of the State’s strategic vision and goals for preparing an educated and skilled workforce (including preparing youth and individuals with barriers to employment) and for meeting the skilled workforce needs of employers, including goals relating to performance accountability measures based on primary indicators of performance described in section 3141(b)(2)(A) of this title, in order to support economic growth and economic self-sufficiency, and of how the State wil</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Plan For a State to be eligible to receive allotments for the core programs, the Governor shall submit to the Secretary of Labor for the approval process described under subsection (c)(2), a unified State plan. The unified State plan shall outline a 4-year strategy for the core programs of the State and meet the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan submission and approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Plan submission and approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>