<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3141" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3141/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3141/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3141"><akn:num>3141</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance accountability system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3141. Performance accountability system(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to establish performance accountability measures that apply across the core programs to assess the effectiveness of States and local areas (for core programs described in part B) in achieving positive outcomes for individuals served by those programs.


(b) State performance accountability measures(1) In generalFor each State, the performance accountability measures for the core programs shall consist of—(A)(i) the primary indicators of performance described in paragraph (2)(A); and

(ii) the additional indicators of performance (if any) identified by the State under paragraph (2)(B); and


(B) a State adjusted level of performance for each indicator described in subparagraph (A).


(2) Indicators of performance(A) Primary indicators of performance(i) In generalThe State primary indicators of performance for activities provided under the adult and dislocated worker programs authorized under subpart 3 of part B, the program of adult education and literacy activities authorized under subchapter II, the employment services program authorized under sections 1 through 13 of the Wagner-Peyser Act (29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.) (except that subclauses (IV) and (V) shall not apply to such program), and the program authorized under title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (29 U.S.C. 720 et seq.), other than section 112 or part C of that title (29 U.S.C. 732, 741), shall consist of—(I) the percentage of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the second quarter after exit from the program;

(II) the percentage of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the fourth quarter after exit from the program;

(III) the median earnings of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the second quarter after exit from the program;

(IV) the percentage of program participants who obtain a recognized postsecondary credential, or a secondary school dip</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3141_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to establish performance accountability measures that apply across the core programs to assess the effectiveness of States and local areas (for core programs described in part B) in achieving positive outcomes for individuals served by those programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3141_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State performance accountability measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State performance accountability measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3141_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local performance accountability measures for part B</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Local performance accountability measures for part B</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3141_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Performance reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3141_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of State programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation of State programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3141_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions for State failure to meet State performance accountability measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sanctions for State failure to meet State performance accountability measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3141_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions for local area failure to meet local performance accountability measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sanctions for local area failure to meet local performance accountability measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3141_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishing pay-for-performance contract strategy incentives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Establishing pay-for-performance contract strategy incentives Using non-Federal funds, the Governor may establish incentives for local boards to implement pay-for-performance contract strategies for the delivery of training services described in section 3174(c)(3) of this title or activities described in section 3164(c)(2) of this title in the local areas served by the local boards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3141_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal and management accountability information systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Fiscal and management accountability information systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>