<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3194" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3194/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3194/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3194"><akn:num>3194</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals eligible for the Job Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3194. Individuals eligible for the Job Corps(a) In generalTo be eligible to become an enrollee, an individual shall be—(1) not less than age 16 and not more than age 21 on the date of enrollment, except that—(A) not more than 20 percent of the individuals enrolled in the Job Corps may be not less than age 22 and not more than age 24 on the date of enrollment; and

(B) either such maximum age limitation may be waived by the Secretary, in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, in the case of an individual with a disability;


(2) a low-income individual; and

(3) an individual who is one or more of the following:(A) Basic skills deficient.

(B) A school dropout.

(C) A homeless individual (as defined in section 12473(6) of title 34), a homeless child or youth (as defined in section 11434a(2) of title 42), a runaway, an individual in foster care, or an individual who was in foster care and has aged out of the foster care system.

(D) A parent.

(E) An individual who requires additional education, career and technical education or training, or workforce preparation skills to be able to obtain and retain employment that leads to economic self-sufficiency.

(F) A victim of a severe form of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 7102 of title 22). Notwithstanding paragraph (2), an individual described in this subparagraph shall not be required to demonstrate eligibility under such paragraph.



(b) Special rule for veteransNotwithstanding the requirement of subsection (a)(2), a veteran shall be eligible to become an enrollee under subsection (a) if the individual—(1) meets the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (3) of such subsection; and

(2) does not meet the requirement of subsection (a)(2) because the military income earned by such individual within the 6-month period prior to the individual’s application for Job 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “the”. Corps prevents the individual from meeting such requirement.


(Pub. L. 113–128, titl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3194_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To be eligible to become an enrollee, an individual shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3194_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rule for veterans Notwithstanding the requirement of subsection (a)(2), a veteran shall be eligible to become an enrollee under subsection (a) if the individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>