<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3197" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3197/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3197/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3197"><akn:num>3197</akn:num><akn:heading>Job Corps centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3197. Job Corps centers(a) Operators and service providers(1) Eligible entities(A) OperatorsThe Secretary shall enter into an agreement with a Federal, State, or local agency, an area career and technical education school, a residential career and technical education school, or a private organization, for the operation of each Job Corps center.


(B) ProvidersThe Secretary may enter into an agreement with a local entity, or other entity with the necessary capacity, to provide activities described in this part to a Job Corps center.



(2) Selection process(A) Competitive basisExcept as provided in subsections (a) and (b) of section 3304 of title 41, the Secretary shall select on a competitive basis an entity to operate a Job Corps center and entities to provide activities described in this part to the Job Corps center. In developing a solicitation for an operator or service provider, the Secretary shall consult with the Governor of the State in which the center is located, the workforce council for the Job Corps center (if established), and the applicable local board regarding the contents of such solicitation, including elements that will promote the consistency of the activities carried out through the center with the objectives set forth in the State plan or in a local plan.


(B) Recommendations and considerations(i) OperatorsIn selecting an entity to operate a Job Corps center, the Secretary shall consider—(I) the ability of the entity to coordinate the activities carried out through the Job Corps center with activities carried out under the appropriate State plan and local plans;

(II) the ability of the entity to offer career and technical education and training that has been proposed by the workforce council under section 3204(c) of this title, and the degree to which such education and training reflects employment opportunities in the local areas in which enrollees at the center intend to seek employment;

(III) the degree to which the entity demonstrates</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3197_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operators and service providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Operators and service providers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3197_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-performing centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) High-performing centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3197_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Character and activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Character and activities Job Corps centers may be residential or nonresidential in character, and shall be designed and operated so as to provide enrollees, in a well-supervised setting, with access to activities described in this part. In any year, no more than 20 percent of the individuals enrolled in the Job Corps may be nonresidential participants in the Job Corps.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3197_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civilian Conservation Centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Civilian Conservation Centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3197_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Indian tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3197_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Length of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Length of agreement The agreement described in subsection (a)(1)(A) shall be for not more than a 2-year period. The Secretary may exercise any contractual option to renew the agreement in 1-year increments for not more than 3 additional years, consistent with the requirements of subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3197_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewal conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Renewal conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>