<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3198" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3198/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3198/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3198"><akn:num>3198</akn:num><akn:heading>Program activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3198. Program activities(a) Activities provided by Job Corps centers(1) In generalEach Job Corps center shall provide enrollees with an intensive, well organized, and fully supervised program of education, including English language acquisition programs, career and technical education and training, work experience, work-based learning, recreational activities, physical rehabilitation and development, driver’s education, and counseling, which may include information about financial literacy. Each Job Corps center shall provide enrollees assigned to the center with access to career services described in clauses (i) through (xi) of section 3174(c)(2)(A) of this title.


(2) Relationship to opportunitiesThe activities provided under this subsection shall be targeted to helping enrollees, on completion of their enrollment—(A) secure and maintain meaningful unsubsidized employment;

(B) enroll in and complete secondary education or postsecondary education or training programs, including other suitable career and technical education and training, and apprenticeship programs; or

(C) satisfy Armed Forces requirements.


(3) Link to employment opportunitiesThe career and technical education and training provided shall be linked to employment opportunities in in-demand industry sectors and occupations in the State or local area in which the Job Corps center is located and, to the extent practicable, in the State or local area in which the enrollee intends to seek employment after graduation.



(b) Academic and career and technical education and trainingThe Secretary may arrange for career and technical education and training of enrollees through local public or private educational agencies, career and technical educational institutions, technical institutes, or national service providers, whenever such entities provide education and training substantially equivalent in cost and quality to that which the Secretary could provide through other means.


(c) Advanced career tra</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities provided by Job Corps centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Activities provided by Job Corps centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Academic and career and technical education and training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Academic and career and technical education and training The Secretary may arrange for career and technical education and training of enrollees through local public or private educational agencies, career and technical educational institutions, technical institutes, or national service providers, whenever such entities provide education and training substantially equivalent in cost and quality to that which the Secretary could provide through other means.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced career training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Advanced career training programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Graduate services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Graduate services In order to promote the retention of graduates in employment or postsecondary education, the Secretary shall arrange for the provision of job placement and support services to graduates for up to 12 months after the date of graduation. Multiple resources, including one-stop partners, may support the provision of these services, including services from the State vocational rehabilitation agency, to supplement job placement and job development efforts for Job Corps graduates who are individuals with disabilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3198_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Child care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Child care The Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, provide child care at or near Job Corps centers, for individuals who require child care for their children in order to participate in the Job Corps.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>