<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3199" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3199/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3199/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3199"><akn:num>3199</akn:num><akn:heading>Counseling and job placement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3199. Counseling and job placement(a) Assessment and counselingThe Secretary shall arrange for assessment and counseling for each enrollee at regular intervals to measure progress in the academic and career and technical education and training programs carried out through the Job Corps.


(b) PlacementThe Secretary shall arrange for assessment and counseling for enrollees prior to their scheduled graduations to determine their capabilities and, based on their capabilities, shall place the enrollees in employment leading to economic self-sufficiency for which the enrollees are trained or assist the enrollees in participating in further activities described in this part. In arranging for the placement of graduates in jobs, the Secretary shall utilize the one-stop delivery system to the maximum extent practicable.


(c) Status and progressThe Secretary shall determine the status and progress of enrollees scheduled for graduation and make every effort to assure that their needs for further activities described in this part are met.


(d) Services to former enrolleesThe Secretary may provide such services as the Secretary determines to be appropriate under this part to former enrollees.


(Pub. L. 113–128, title I, § 149, July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1548.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on the first day of the first full program year after July 22, 2014 (July 1, 2015), see section 506 of Pub. L. 113–128, set out as a note under section 3101 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3199_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment and counseling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessment and counseling The Secretary shall arrange for assessment and counseling for each enrollee at regular intervals to measure progress in the academic and career and technical education and training programs carried out through the Job Corps.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3199_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Placement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Placement The Secretary shall arrange for assessment and counseling for enrollees prior to their scheduled graduations to determine their capabilities and, based on their capabilities, shall place the enrollees in employment leading to economic self-sufficiency for which the enrollees are trained or assist the enrollees in participating in further activities described in this part. In arranging for the placement of graduates in jobs, the Secretary shall utilize the one-stop delivery system to the maximum extent practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3199_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status and progress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Status and progress The Secretary shall determine the status and progress of enrollees scheduled for graduation and make every effort to assure that their needs for further activities described in this part are met.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3199_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services to former enrollees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Services to former enrollees The Secretary may provide such services as the Secretary determines to be appropriate under this part to former enrollees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>