<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3200" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3200/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3200/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3200"><akn:num>3200</akn:num><akn:heading>Support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3200. Support(a) Personal allowancesThe Secretary may provide enrollees assigned to Job Corps centers with such personal allowances as the Secretary may determine to be necessary or appropriate to meet the needs of the enrollees.


(b) Transition allowancesThe Secretary shall arrange for a transition allowance to be paid to graduates. The transition allowance shall be incentive-based to reflect a graduate’s completion of academic, career and technical education or training, and attainment of recognized postsecondary credentials.


(c) Transition supportThe Secretary may arrange for the provision of 3 months of employment services for former enrollees.


(Pub. L. 113–128, title I, § 150, July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1549.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on the first day of the first full program year after July 22, 2014 (July 1, 2015), see section 506 of Pub. L. 113–128, set out as a note under section 3101 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3200_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Personal allowances The Secretary may provide enrollees assigned to Job Corps centers with such personal allowances as the Secretary may determine to be necessary or appropriate to meet the needs of the enrollees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3200_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transition allowances The Secretary shall arrange for a transition allowance to be paid to graduates. The transition allowance shall be incentive-based to reflect a graduate’s completion of academic, career and technical education or training, and attainment of recognized postsecondary credentials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3200_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transition support The Secretary may arrange for the provision of 3 months of employment services for former enrollees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>