<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3208" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3208/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3208/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3208"><akn:num>3208</akn:num><akn:heading>Special provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3208. Special provisions(a) EnrollmentThe Secretary shall ensure that women and men have an equal opportunity to participate in the Job Corps program, consistent with section 3195 of this title.


(b) Studies, evaluations, proposals, and dataThe Secretary shall assure that all studies, evaluations, proposals, and data produced or developed with Federal funds in the course of carrying out the Job Corps program shall become the property of the United States.


(c) Transfer of property(1) In generalNotwithstanding chapter 5 of title 40, and any other provision of law, the Secretary and the Secretary of Education shall receive priority by the Secretary of Defense for the direct transfer, on a nonreimbursable basis, of the property described in paragraph (2) for use in carrying out programs under this Act or under any other Act.


(2) PropertyThe property described in this paragraph is real and personal property under the control of the Department of Defense that is not used by such Department, including property that the Secretary of Defense determines is in excess of current and projected requirements of such Department.



(d) Gross receiptsTransactions conducted by a private for-profit or nonprofit entity that is an operator or service provider for a Job Corps center shall not be considered to be generating gross receipts. Such an operator or service provider shall not be liable, directly or indirectly, to any State or subdivision of a State (nor to any person acting on behalf of such a State or subdivision) for any gross receipts taxes, business privilege taxes measured by gross receipts, or any similar taxes imposed on, or measured by, gross receipts in connection with any payments made to or by such entity for operating or providing services to a Job Corps center. Such an operator or service provider shall not be liable to any State or subdivision of a State to collect or pay any sales, excise, use, or similar tax imposed on the sale to or use by such operator o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enrollment The Secretary shall ensure that women and men have an equal opportunity to participate in the Job Corps program, consistent with section 3195 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies, evaluations, proposals, and data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Studies, evaluations, proposals, and data The Secretary shall assure that all studies, evaluations, proposals, and data produced or developed with Federal funds in the course of carrying out the Job Corps program shall become the property of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer of property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gross receipts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Gross receipts Transactions conducted by a private for-profit or nonprofit entity that is an operator or service provider for a Job Corps center shall not be considered to be generating gross receipts. Such an operator or service provider shall not be liable, directly or indirectly, to any State or subdivision of a State (nor to any person acting on behalf of such a State or subdivision) for any gross receipts taxes, business privilege taxes measured by gross receipts, or any similar taxes imposed on, or measured by, gross receipts in connection with any payments made to or by such entity for operating or providing services to a Job Corps center. Such an operator or service provider shall not be liable to any State or subdivision of a State to collect or pay any sales, excise, use, or similar tax imposed on the sale to or use by such operator or service provider of any property, service, or other item in connection with the operation of or provision of services to a Job Corps cente</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Management fee The Secretary shall provide each operator and (in an appropriate case, as determined by the Secretary) service provider with an equitable and negotiated management fee of not less than 1 percent of the amount of the funding provided under the appropriate agreement specified in section 3197 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Donations The Secretary may accept on behalf of the Job Corps or individual Job Corps centers charitable donations of cash or other assistance, including equipment and materials, if such donations are available for appropriate use for the purposes set forth in this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3208_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sale of property Notwithstanding any other provision of law, if the Administrator of General Services sells a Job Corps center facility, the Administrator shall transfer the proceeds from the sale to the Secretary, who shall use the proceeds to carry out the Job Corps program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>