<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3209" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3209/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3209/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3209"><akn:num>3209</akn:num><akn:heading>Management information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3209. Management information(a) Financial management information system(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish procedures to ensure that each operator, and each service provider, maintains a financial management information system that will provide—(A) accurate, complete, and current disclosures of the costs of Job Corps operations; and

(B) sufficient data for the effective evaluation of activities carried out through the Job Corps program.


(2) AccountsEach operator and service provider shall maintain funds received under this part in accounts in a manner that ensures timely and accurate reporting as required by the Secretary.


(3) Fiscal responsibilityOperators shall remain fiscally responsible and control costs, regardless of whether the funds made available for Job Corps centers are incrementally increased or decreased between fiscal years.



(b) Audit(1) AccessThe Secretary, the Inspector General of the Department of Labor, the Comptroller General of the United States, and any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access to any books, documents, papers, and records of the operators and service providers described in subsection (a) that are pertinent to the Job Corps program, for purposes of conducting surveys, audits, and evaluations of the operators and service providers.


(2) Surveys, audits, and evaluationsThe Secretary shall survey, audit, or evaluate, or arrange for the survey, audit, or evaluation of, the operators and service providers, using Federal auditors or independent public accountants. The Secretary shall conduct such surveys, audits, or evaluations not less often than once every 3 years.



(c) Information on indicators of performance(1) Levels of performance and indicatorsThe Secretary shall annually establish expected levels of performance for a Job Corps center and the Job Corps program relating to each of the primary indicators of performance for eligible youth described in section 3141(b)(2)(A)(ii) of this title.

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial management information system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Financial management information system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Audit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on indicators of performance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information on indicators of performance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Methods The Secretary shall collect the information described in subsections (c) and (d), using methods described in section 3141(i)(2) of this title and consistent with State law, by entering into agreements with the States to access such data for Job Corps enrollees, former enrollees, and graduates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance assessments and improvements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Performance assessments and improvements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participant health and safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Participant health and safety</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Buildings and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Buildings and facilities The Secretary shall collect, and submit in the report described in subsection (c)(4), information regarding the state of Job Corps buildings and facilities. Such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>National and community service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) National and community service The Secretary shall include in the report described in subsection (c)(4) available information regarding the national and community service activities of enrollees, particularly those enrollees at Civilian Conservation Centers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3209_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Closure of Job Corps center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Closure of Job Corps center Prior to the closure of any Job Corps center, the Secretary shall ensure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>