<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3210" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3210/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3210/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3210"><akn:num>3210</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3210. General provisions
The Secretary is authorized to—(1) disseminate, with regard to the provisions of section 3204 of title 39, data and information in such forms as the Secretary shall determine to be appropriate, to public agencies, private organizations, and the general public;

(2) subject to section 3207(b) of this title, collect or compromise all obligations to or held by the Secretary and exercise all legal or equitable rights accruing to the Secretary in connection with the payment of obligations until such time as such obligations may be referred to the Attorney General for suit or collection; and

(3) expend funds made available for purposes of this part—(A) for printing and binding, in accordance with applicable law (including regulation); and

(B) without regard to any other law (including regulation), for rent of buildings and space in buildings and for repair, alteration, and improvement of buildings and space in buildings rented by the Secretary, except that the Secretary shall not expend funds under the authority of this subparagraph—(i) except when necessary to obtain an item, service, or facility, that is required in the proper administration of this part, and that otherwise could not be obtained, or could not be obtained in the quantity or quality needed, or at the time, in the form, or under the conditions in which the item, service, or facility is needed; and

(ii) prior to having given written notification to the Administrator of General Services (if the expenditure would affect an activity that otherwise would be under the jurisdiction of the General Services Administration) of the intention of the Secretary to make the expenditure, and the reasons and justifications for the expenditure.



(Pub. L. 113–128, title I, § 160, July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1558.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on the first day of the first full program year after July 22, 2014 (July 1, 2015), see section 506 of Pub. L. </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3210_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) disseminate, with regard to the provisions of section 3204 of title 39, data and information in such forms as the Secretary shall determine to be appropriate, to public agencies, private organizations, and the general public;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3210_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) subject to section 3207(b) of this title, collect or compromise all obligations to or held by the Secretary and exercise all legal or equitable rights accruing to the Secretary in connection with the payment of obligations until such time as such obligations may be referred to the Attorney General for suit or collection; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3210_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) expend funds made available for purposes of this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>