<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3241" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3241/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3241/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3241"><akn:num>3241</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements and restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3241. Requirements and restrictions(a) Benefits(1) Wages(A) In generalIndividuals in on-the-job training or individuals employed in activities under this subchapter shall be compensated at the same rates, including periodic increases, as trainees or employees who are similarly situated in similar occupations by the same employer and who have similar training, experience, and skills, and such rates shall be in accordance with applicable law, but in no event less than the higher of the rate specified in section 206(a)(1) of this title or the applicable State or local minimum wage law.


(B) Rule of constructionThe reference in subparagraph (A) to section 206(a)(1) of this title shall not be applicable for individuals in territorial jurisdictions in which section 206(a)(1) of this title does not apply.



(2) Treatment of allowances, earnings, and paymentsAllowances, earnings, and payments to individuals participating in programs under this subchapter shall not be considered as income for the purposes of determining eligibility for and the amount of income transfer and in-kind aid furnished under any Federal or federally assisted program based on need, other than as provided under the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.).



(b) Labor standards(1) Limitations on activities that impact wages of employeesNo funds provided under this subchapter shall be used to pay the wages of incumbent employees during their participation in economic development activities provided through a statewide workforce development system.


(2) Displacement(A) ProhibitionA participant in a program or activity authorized under this subchapter (referred to in this section as a “specified activity”) shall not displace (including a partial displacement, such as a reduction in the hours of nonovertime work, wages, or employment benefits) any currently employed employee (as of the date of the participation).


(B) Prohibition on impairment of contractsA specified activity shall not impair an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labor standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Labor standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grievance procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grievance procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Relocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on use of funds No funds available to carry out an activity under this subchapter shall be used for employment generating activities, investment in revolving loan funds, capitalization of businesses, investment in contract bidding resource centers, economic development activities, or similar activities, that are not directly related to training for eligible individuals under this subchapter. No funds received to carry out an activity under part B shall be used for foreign travel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing and sanctioning for use of controlled substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Testing and sanctioning for use of controlled substances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subgrant authority A recipient of grant funds under this subchapter shall have the authority to enter into subgrants in order to carry out the grant, subject to such conditions as the Secretary may establish.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>