<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3247" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3247/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3247/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3247"><akn:num>3247</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3247. Judicial review(a) Review(1) PetitionWith respect to any final order by the Secretary under section 3246 of this title by which the Secretary awards, declines to award, or only conditionally awards, financial assistance under this subchapter, or any final order of the Secretary under section 3246 of this title with respect to a corrective action or sanction imposed under section 3244 of this title, any party to a proceeding that resulted in such final order may obtain review of such final order in the United States Court of Appeals having jurisdiction over the applicant for or recipient of the funds involved, by filing a review petition within 30 days after the date of issuance of such final order.


(2) Action on petitionThe clerk of the court shall transmit a copy of the review petition to the Secretary, who shall file the record on which the final order was entered as provided in section 2112 of title 28. The filing of a review petition shall not stay the order of the Secretary, unless the court orders a stay. Petitions filed under this subsection shall be heard expeditiously, if possible within 10 days after the date of filing of a reply to the petition.


(3) Standard and scope of reviewNo objection to the order of the Secretary shall be considered by the court unless the objection was specifically urged, in a timely manner, before the Secretary. The review shall be limited to questions of law and the findings of fact of the Secretary shall be conclusive if supported by substantial evidence.



(b) JudgmentThe court shall have jurisdiction to make and enter a decree affirming, modifying, or setting aside the order of the Secretary in whole or in part. The judgment of the court regarding the order shall be final, subject to certiorari review by the Supreme Court as provided in section 1254(1) of title 28.


(Pub. L. 113–128, title I, § 187, July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1597.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on the fi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3247_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3247_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judgment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Judgment The court shall have jurisdiction to make and enter a decree affirming, modifying, or setting aside the order of the Secretary in whole or in part. The judgment of the court regarding the order shall be final, subject to certiorari review by the Supreme Court as provided in section 1254(1) of title 28.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>