<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3249" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3249/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3249/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3249"><akn:num>3249</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial administrative authorities and responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3249. Secretarial administrative authorities and responsibilities(a) In generalIn accordance with chapter 5 of title 5, the Secretary may prescribe rules and regulations to carry out this subchapter, only to the extent necessary to administer and ensure compliance with the requirements of this subchapter. Such rules and regulations may include provisions making adjustments authorized by section 6504 of title 31. All such rules and regulations shall be published in the Federal Register at least 30 days prior to their effective dates. Copies of each such rule or regulation shall be transmitted to the appropriate committees of Congress on the date of such publication and shall contain, with respect to each material provision of such rule or regulation, a citation to the particular substantive section of law that is the basis for the provision.


(b) Acquisition of certain property and servicesThe Secretary is authorized, in carrying out this subchapter, to accept, purchase, or lease in the name of the Department of Labor, and employ or dispose of in furtherance of the purposes of this subchapter, any money or property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible, received by gift, devise, bequest, or otherwise, and to accept voluntary and uncompensated services notwithstanding the provisions of section 1342 of title 31.


(c) Authority to enter into certain agreements and to make certain expendituresThe Secretary may make such grants, enter into such contracts or agreements, establish such procedures, and make such payments, in installments and in advance or by way of reimbursement, or otherwise allocate or expend such funds under this subchapter, as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter, including making expenditures for construction, repairs, and capital improvements, and including making necessary adjustments in payments on account of over-payments or underpayments.


(d) Annual reportThe Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Educatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3249_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In accordance with chapter 5 of title 5, the Secretary may prescribe rules and regulations to carry out this subchapter, only to the extent necessary to administer and ensure compliance with the requirements of this subchapter. Such rules and regulations may include provisions making adjustments authorized by section 6504 of title 31. All such rules and regulations shall be published in the Federal Register at least 30 days prior to their effective dates. Copies of each such rule or regulation shall be transmitted to the appropriate committees of Congress on the date of such publication and shall contain, with respect to each material provision of such rule or regulation, a citation to the particular substantive section of law that is the basis for the provision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3249_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of certain property and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acquisition of certain property and services The Secretary is authorized, in carrying out this subchapter, to accept, purchase, or lease in the name of the Department of Labor, and employ or dispose of in furtherance of the purposes of this subchapter, any money or property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible, received by gift, devise, bequest, or otherwise, and to accept voluntary and uncompensated services notwithstanding the provisions of section 1342 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3249_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to enter into certain agreements and to make certain expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority to enter into certain agreements and to make certain expenditures The Secretary may make such grants, enter into such contracts or agreements, establish such procedures, and make such payments, in installments and in advance or by way of reimbursement, or otherwise allocate or expend such funds under this subchapter, as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter, including making expenditures for construction, repairs, and capital improvements, and including making necessary adjustments in payments on account of over-payments or underpayments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3249_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual report The Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate an annual report regarding the programs and activities funded under this subchapter. The Secretary shall include in such report—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3249_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of services and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Utilization of services and facilities The Secretary is authorized, in carrying out this subchapter, under the same procedures as are applicable under subsection (c) or to the extent permitted by law other than this subchapter, to accept and use the services and facilities of departments, agencies, and establishments of the United States. The Secretary is also authorized, in carrying out this subchapter, to accept and use the services and facilities of the agencies of any State or political subdivision of a State, with the consent of the State or political subdivision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3249_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligational authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Obligational authority Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Secretary shall have no authority to enter into contracts, grant agreements, or other financial assistance agreements under this subchapter, except to such extent and in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriations Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3249_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Program year</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3249_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of Military Selective Service Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Enforcement of Military Selective Service Act The Secretary shall ensure that each individual participating in any program or activity established under this subchapter, or receiving any assistance or benefit under this subchapter, has not violated section 3 of the Military Selective Service Act (50 U.S.C. App. 453) [now 50 U.S.C. 3802] by not presenting and submitting to registration as required pursuant to such section. The Director of the Selective Service System shall cooperate with the Secretary to enable the Secretary to carry out this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3249_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Waivers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>