<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3251" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3251/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3251/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3251"><akn:num>3251</akn:num><akn:heading>State legislative authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3251. State legislative authority(a) Authority of State legislatureNothing in this subchapter shall be interpreted to preclude the enactment of State legislation providing for the implementation, consistent with the provisions of this subchapter, of the activities assisted under this subchapter. Any funds received by a State under this subchapter shall be subject to appropriation by the State legislature, consistent with the terms and conditions required under this subchapter.


(b) Interstate compacts and cooperative agreementsIn the event that compliance with provisions of this subchapter would be enhanced by compacts and cooperative agreements between States, the consent of Congress is given to States to enter into such compacts and agreements to facilitate such compliance, subject to the approval of the Secretary.


(Pub. L. 113–128, title I, § 191, July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1603.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on the first day of the first full program year after July 22, 2014 (July 1, 2015), see section 506 of Pub. L. 113–128, set out as a note under section 3101 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3251_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of State legislature</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of State legislature Nothing in this subchapter shall be interpreted to preclude the enactment of State legislation providing for the implementation, consistent with the provisions of this subchapter, of the activities assisted under this subchapter. Any funds received by a State under this subchapter shall be subject to appropriation by the State legislature, consistent with the terms and conditions required under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3251_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate compacts and cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interstate compacts and cooperative agreements In the event that compliance with provisions of this subchapter would be enhanced by compacts and cooperative agreements between States, the consent of Congress is given to States to enter into such compacts and agreements to facilitate such compliance, subject to the approval of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>