<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3342" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3342/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3342/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3342"><akn:num>3342</akn:num><akn:heading>Buy-American requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3342. Buy-American requirements(a) Compliance with Buy American ActNone of the funds made available under subchapter I or II or under the Wagner-Peyser Act (29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.) may be expended by an entity unless the entity agrees that in expending the funds the entity will comply with sections 8301 through 8303 of title 41 (commonly known as the “Buy American Act”).


(b) Sense of Congress; requirement regarding notice(1) Purchase of American-made equipment and productsIn the case of any equipment or product that may be authorized to be purchased with financial assistance provided using funds made available under subchapter I or II or under the Wagner-Peyser Act (29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.), it is the sense of Congress that entities receiving the assistance should, in expending the assistance, purchase only American-made equipment and products.


(2) Notice to recipients of assistanceIn providing financial assistance using funds made available under subchapter I or II or under the Wagner-Peyser Act, the head of each Federal agency shall provide to each recipient of the assistance a notice describing the statement made in paragraph (1) by Congress.



(c) Prohibition of contracts with persons falsely labeling products as Made in AmericaIf it has been finally determined by a court or Federal agency that any person intentionally affixed a label bearing a “Made in America” inscription, or any inscription with the same meaning, to any product sold in or shipped to the United States that is not made in the United States, the person shall be ineligible to receive any contract or subcontract made with funds made available under subchapter I or II or under the Wagner-Peyser Act (29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.), pursuant to the debarment, suspension, and ineligibility procedures described in sections 9.400 through 9.409 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations, as such sections were in effect on August 7, 1998, or pursuant to any successor regulations.


(Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 502</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3342_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with Buy American Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compliance with Buy American Act None of the funds made available under subchapter I or II or under the Wagner-Peyser Act (29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.) may be expended by an entity unless the entity agrees that in expending the funds the entity will comply with sections 8301 through 8303 of title 41 (commonly known as the “Buy American Act”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3342_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress; requirement regarding notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sense of Congress; requirement regarding notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3342_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of contracts with persons falsely labeling products as Made in America</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition of contracts with persons falsely labeling products as Made in America If it has been finally determined by a court or Federal agency that any person intentionally affixed a label bearing a “Made in America” inscription, or any inscription with the same meaning, to any product sold in or shipped to the United States that is not made in the United States, the person shall be ineligible to receive any contract or subcontract made with funds made available under subchapter I or II or under the Wagner-Peyser Act (29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.), pursuant to the debarment, suspension, and ineligibility procedures described in sections 9.400 through 9.409 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations, as such sections were in effect on August 7, 1998, or pursuant to any successor regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>