<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3361" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3361/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/3361/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3361"><akn:num>3361</akn:num><akn:heading>References</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3361. References(a) Workforce Investment Act of 1998 referencesExcept as otherwise specified, a reference in a Federal law to a provision of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (29 U.S.C. 2801 et seq.) shall be deemed to refer to the corresponding provision of this Act.


(b) Wagner-Peyser Act referencesExcept as otherwise specified, a reference in a Federal law to a provision of the Wagner-Peyser Act (29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.) shall be deemed to refer to the corresponding provision of such Act, as amended by this Act.


(c) Disability-related referencesExcept as otherwise specified, a reference in a Federal law to a provision of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.) shall be deemed to refer to the corresponding provision of such Act, as amended by this Act.


(Pub. L. 113–128, title V, § 513, July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1722.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 113–128, July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1425, known as the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, which enacted this chapter, repealed chapter 30 (§ 2801 et seq.) of this title and chapter 73 (§ 9201 et seq.) of Title 20, Education, and made amendments to numerous other sections and notes in the Code. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 3101 of this title and Tables.
The Workforce Investment Act of 1998, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 105–220, Aug. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 936, and was repealed by Pub. L. 113–128, title V, §§ 506, 511(a), July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1703, 1705, effective July 1, 2015. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
The Wagner-Peyser Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is act June 6, 1933, ch. 49, 48 Stat. 113, which is classified generally to chapter 4B (§ 49 et seq.) of this title and was amended extensively by title III of Pub. L. 113–128. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 49 of this titl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3361_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Workforce Investment Act of 1998 references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Workforce Investment Act of 1998 references Except as otherwise specified, a reference in a Federal law to a provision of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (29 U.S.C. 2801 et seq.) shall be deemed to refer to the corresponding provision of this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3361_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wagner-Peyser Act references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Wagner-Peyser Act references Except as otherwise specified, a reference in a Federal law to a provision of the Wagner-Peyser Act (29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.) shall be deemed to refer to the corresponding provision of such Act, as amended by this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3361_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disability-related references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disability-related references Except as otherwise specified, a reference in a Federal law to a provision of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.) shall be deemed to refer to the corresponding provision of such Act, as amended by this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>