<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4"><akn:num>4</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Commissioner in general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4. Duties of Commissioner in general
It shall be the duty of the Commissioner of Labor Statistics to ascertain the effect of the customs laws, and the effect thereon of the state of the currency, in the United States, on the agricultural industry, especially as to its effect on mortgage indebtedness of farmers. He shall also establish a system of reports by which, at intervals of not less than two years, he can report the general condition, so far as production is concerned, of the leading industries of the country. He is also specially charged to investigate the causes of, and facts relating to, all controversies and disputes between employers and employees as they may occur, and which may tend to interfere with the welfare of the people of the different States. He shall also obtain such information upon the various subjects committed to him as he may deem desirable from different foreign nations, and what, if any, convict-made goods are imported into this country, and if so from whence.
(June 13, 1888, ch. 389, § 7, 25 Stat. 183; Aug. 23, 1912, ch. 350, § 1, 37 Stat. 407; Mar. 4, 1913, ch. 141, § 3, 37 Stat. 737; May 29, 1928, ch. 901, § 1(110), (111), 45 Stat. 994.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section is from act June 13, 1888. Act June 13, 1888, also contained other provisions relating to duties of former Commissioner of Labor to ascertain cost of producing, in leading countries, articles dutiable in United States, comparative cost of living, etc., which have been omitted from this section because of act Aug. 23, 1912, transferring those duties to Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce.
Act Aug. 23, 1912, transferred the duty of former Commissioner of Labor to ascertain the cost of producing, in leading countries, articles dutiable in the United States, the profits of the manufacturers and producers of such articles, the comparative cost of such articles, comparative cost of living in such countries, what articles are controlled by trusts and the effect the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>