<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/49b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/49b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/49b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_49b"><akn:num>49b</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 49b. Duties of Secretary(a) Assistance to State public employment service officesThe Secretary shall assist in coordinating the State public employment service offices throughout the country and in increasing their usefulness by developing and prescribing minimum standards of efficiency, assisting them in meeting problems peculiar to their localities, promoting uniformity in their administrative and statistical procedure, furnishing and publishing information as to opportunities for employment and other information of value in the operation of the system, and maintaining a system for clearing labor between the States.


(b) Provision of unemployment compensation informationIt shall be the duty of the Secretary to assure that unemployment insurance and employment service offices in each State, as appropriate, upon request of a public agency administering or supervising the administration of a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.], of a public agency charged with any duty or responsibility under any program or activity authorized or required under part D of title IV of such Act [42 U.S.C. 651 et seq.], or of a State agency charged with the administration of the supplemental nutrition assistance program in a State under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.), shall (and, notwithstanding any other provision of law, is authorized to) furnish to such agency making the request, from any data contained in the files of any such office, information with respect to any individual specified in the request as to (1) whether such individual is receiving, has received, or has made application for, unemployment compensation, and the amount of any such compensation being received by such individual, (2) the current (or most recent) home address of such individual, and (3) whether such individual has refused an offer of employment and, if so, a description of the employment so offered and the terms, cond</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to State public employment service offices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assistance to State public employment service offices The Secretary shall assist in coordinating the State public employment service offices throughout the country and in increasing their usefulness by developing and prescribing minimum standards of efficiency, assisting them in meeting problems peculiar to their localities, promoting uniformity in their administrative and statistical procedure, furnishing and publishing information as to opportunities for employment and other information of value in the operation of the system, and maintaining a system for clearing labor between the States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of unemployment compensation information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Provision of unemployment compensation information It shall be the duty of the Secretary to assure that unemployment insurance and employment service offices in each State, as appropriate, upon request of a public agency administering or supervising the administration of a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.], of a public agency charged with any duty or responsibility under any program or activity authorized or required under part D of title IV of such Act [42 U.S.C. 651 et seq.], or of a State agency charged with the administration of the supplemental nutrition assistance program in a State under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.), shall (and, notwithstanding any other provision of law, is authorized to) furnish to such agency making the request, from any data contained in the files of any such office, information with respect to any individual specified in the request as to (1) whether such indivi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public labor exchange services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public labor exchange services The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Colocation of employment service offices and one-stop centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Colocation of employment service offices and one-stop centers In order to improve service delivery, avoid duplication of services, and enhance coordination of services, including location of staff to ensure access to services under section 49f(a) of this title statewide in underserved areas, employment service offices in each State shall be colocated with one-stop centers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of national electronic tools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Development of national electronic tools The Secretary, in consultation with States, is authorized to assist the States in the development of national electronic tools that may be used to improve access to workforce information for individuals through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>