<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/49e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/49e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/49e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_49e"><akn:num>49e</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 49e. Allotment of funds(a) From the funds appropriated and (except for Guam) certified under section 49d of this title and made available for allotments under this section for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall first allot to Guam and the Virgin Islands an amount which, in relation to the total amount available for the fiscal year, is equal to the allotment percentage which each received of amounts available under this chapter in fiscal year 1983.

(b)(1) Subject to paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, after making the allotments required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall allot the remainder of the funds described in subsection (a) for each fiscal year among the States as follows:(A) two-thirds of such remainder shall be allotted on the basis of the relative number of individuals in the civilian labor force in each State as compared to the total number of such individuals in all States; and

(B) one-third of such remainder shall be allotted on the basis of the relative number of unemployed individuals in each State as compared to the total number of such individuals in all States.


For purposes of this paragraph, the number of individuals in the civilian labor force and the number of unemployed individuals shall be based on data for the most recent calendar year available, as determined by the Secretary. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “State” does not include Guam or the Virgin Islands.

(2) No State’s allotment under this section for any fiscal year shall be less than 90 percent of its allotment percentage for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the determination is made. For the purpose of this section, the Secretary shall determine the allotment percentage for each State (including Guam and the Virgin Islands) for fiscal year 1984 which is the percentage that the State received under this chapter for fiscal year 1983 of the total amounts available for payments to all States for such fiscal year. For each succeeding</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) From the funds appropriated and (except for Guam) certified under section 49d of this title and made available for allotments under this section for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall first allot to Guam and the Virgin Islands an amount which, in relation to the total amount available for the fiscal year, is equal to the allotment percentage which each received of amounts available under this chapter in fiscal year 1983.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>