<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/566" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/566/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/566/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_566"><akn:num>566</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee drug and alcohol abuse assistance programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 566. Employee drug and alcohol abuse assistance programs(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary of Labor shall establish a program through which the Secretary shall provide grants to, or enter into contracts with, employers to enable such employers to develop employee drug and alcohol abuse assistance programs.


(b) ApplicationsEmployers desiring to receive a grant or contract under this section shall submit to the Secretary of Labor, an application, in such form and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(c) RegulationsThe Secretary of Labor shall promulgate regulations necessary to carry out this section.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $4,000,000 for fiscal year 1989, and $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1990 and 1991.


(Pub. L. 100–690, title II, § 2101, Nov. 18, 1988, 102 Stat. 4216.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_566_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary of Labor shall establish a program through which the Secretary shall provide grants to, or enter into contracts with, employers to enable such employers to develop employee drug and alcohol abuse assistance programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_566_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications Employers desiring to receive a grant or contract under this section shall submit to the Secretary of Labor, an application, in such form and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_566_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations The Secretary of Labor shall promulgate regulations necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_566_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $4,000,000 for fiscal year 1989, and $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1990 and 1991.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>