<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/623" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/623/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/623/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_623"><akn:num>623</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of age discrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 623. Prohibition of age discrimination(a) Employer practicesIt shall be unlawful for an employer—(1) to fail or refuse to hire or to discharge any individual or otherwise discriminate against any individual with respect to his compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment, because of such individual’s age;

(2) to limit, segregate, or classify his employees in any way which would deprive or tend to deprive any individual of employment opportunities or otherwise adversely affect his status as an employee, because of such individual’s age; or

(3) to reduce the wage rate of any employee in order to comply with this chapter.


(b) Employment agency practicesIt shall be unlawful for an employment agency to fail or refuse to refer for employment, or otherwise to discriminate against, any individual because of such individual’s age, or to classify or refer for employment any individual on the basis of such individual’s age.


(c) Labor organization practicesIt shall be unlawful for a labor organization—(1) to exclude or to expel from its membership, or otherwise to discriminate against, any individual because of his age;

(2) to limit, segregate, or classify its membership, or to classify or fail or refuse to refer for employment any individual, in any way which would deprive or tend to deprive any individual of employment opportunities, or would limit such employment opportunities or otherwise adversely affect his status as an employee or as an applicant for employment, because of such individual’s age;

(3) to cause or attempt to cause an employer to discriminate against an individual in violation of this section.


(d) Opposition to unlawful practices; participation in investigations, proceedings, or litigationIt shall be unlawful for an employer to discriminate against any of his employees or applicants for employment, for an employment agency to discriminate against any individual, or for a labor organization to discriminate against any member thereo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employer practices It shall be unlawful for an employer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment agency practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Employment agency practices It shall be unlawful for an employment agency to fail or refuse to refer for employment, or otherwise to discriminate against, any individual because of such individual’s age, or to classify or refer for employment any individual on the basis of such individual’s age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labor organization practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Labor organization practices It shall be unlawful for a labor organization—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opposition to unlawful practices; participation in investigations, proceedings, or litigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Opposition to unlawful practices; participation in investigations, proceedings, or litigation It shall be unlawful for an employer to discriminate against any of his employees or applicants for employment, for an employment agency to discriminate against any individual, or for a labor organization to discriminate against any member thereof or applicant for membership, because such individual, member or applicant for membership has opposed any practice made unlawful by this section, or because such individual, member or applicant for membership has made a charge, testified, assisted, or participated in any manner in an investigation, proceeding, or litigation under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Printing or publication of notice or advertisement indicating preference, limitation, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Printing or publication of notice or advertisement indicating preference, limitation, etc. It shall be unlawful for an employer, labor organization, or employment agency to print or publish, or cause to be printed or published, any notice or advertisement relating to employment by such an employer or membership in or any classification or referral for employment by such a labor organization, or relating to any classification or referral for employment by such an employment agency, indicating any preference, limitation, specification, or discrimination, based on age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lawful practices; age an occupational qualification; other reasonable factors; laws of foreign workplace; seniority system; employee benefit plans; discharge or discipline for good cause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Lawful practices; age an occupational qualification; other reasonable factors; laws of foreign workplace; seniority system; employee benefit plans; discharge or discipline for good cause It shall not be unlawful for an employer, employment agency, or labor organization—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 101–239, title VI, § 6202(b)(3)(C)(i), Dec. 19, 1989, 103 Stat. 2233</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Practices of foreign corporations controlled by American employers; foreign employers not controlled by American employers; factors determining control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Practices of foreign corporations controlled by American employers; foreign employers not controlled by American employers; factors determining control</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee pension benefit plans; cessation or reduction of benefit accrual or of allocation to employee account; distribution of benefits after attainment of normal retirement age; compliance; highly compensated employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Employee pension benefit plans; cessation or reduction of benefit accrual or of allocation to employee account; distribution of benefits after attainment of normal retirement age; compliance; highly compensated employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_623_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment as firefighter or law enforcement officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Employment as firefighter or law enforcement officer It shall not be unlawful for an employer which is a State, a political subdivision of a State, an agency or instrumentality of a State or a political subdivision of a State, or an interstate agency to fail or refuse to hire or to discharge any individual because of such individual’s age if such action is taken—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>