<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/625" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/625/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/625/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_625"><akn:num>625</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 625. Administration
The Secretary shall have the power—(a) Delegation of functions; appointment of personnel; technical assistanceto make delegations, to appoint such agents and employees, and to pay for technical assistance on a fee for service basis, as he deems necessary to assist him in the performance of his functions under this chapter;


(b) Cooperation with other agencies, employers, labor organizations, and employment agenciesto cooperate with regional, State, local, and other agencies, and to cooperate with and furnish technical assistance to employers, labor organizations, and employment agencies to aid in effectuating the purposes of this chapter.


(Pub. L. 90–202, § 6, Dec. 15, 1967, 81 Stat. 604.)

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Functions relating to age discrimination administration and enforcement vested by this section in Secretary of Labor or Civil Service Commission transferred to Equal Employment Opportunity Commission by Reorg. Plan No. 1 of 1978, § 2, 43 F.R. 19807, 92 Stat. 3781, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, effective Jan. 1, 1979, as provided by section 1–101 of Ex. Ord. No. 12106, Dec. 28, 1978, 44 F.R. 1053.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_625_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of functions; appointment of personnel; technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Delegation of functions; appointment of personnel; technical assistance to make delegations, to appoint such agents and employees, and to pay for technical assistance on a fee for service basis, as he deems necessary to assist him in the performance of his functions under this chapter;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_625_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with other agencies, employers, labor organizations, and employment agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cooperation with other agencies, employers, labor organizations, and employment agencies to cooperate with regional, State, local, and other agencies, and to cooperate with and furnish technical assistance to employers, labor organizations, and employment agencies to aid in effectuating the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>