<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/626" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/626/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/626/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_626"><akn:num>626</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping, investigation, and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 626. Recordkeeping, investigation, and enforcement(a) Attendance of witnesses; investigations, inspections, records, and homework regulationsThe Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall have the power to make investigations and require the keeping of records necessary or appropriate for the administration of this chapter in accordance with the powers and procedures provided in sections 209 and 211 of this title.


(b) Enforcement; prohibition of age discrimination under fair labor standards; unpaid minimum wages and unpaid overtime compensation; liquidated damages; judicial relief; conciliation, conference, and persuasionThe provisions of this chapter shall be enforced in accordance with the powers, remedies, and procedures provided in sections 211(b), 216 (except for subsection (a) thereof), and 217 of this title, and subsection (c) of this section. Any act prohibited under section 623 of this title shall be deemed to be a prohibited act under section 215 of this title. Amounts owing to a person as a result of a violation of this chapter shall be deemed to be unpaid minimum wages or unpaid overtime compensation for purposes of sections 216 and 217 of this title: Provided, That liquidated damages shall be payable only in cases of willful violations of this chapter. In any action brought to enforce this chapter the court shall have jurisdiction to grant such legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate to effectuate the purposes of this chapter, including without limitation judgments compelling employment, reinstatement or promotion, or enforcing the liability for amounts deemed to be unpaid minimum wages or unpaid overtime compensation under this section. Before instituting any action under this section, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall attempt to eliminate the discriminatory practice or practices alleged, and to effect voluntary compliance with the requirements of this chapter through informal methods of conciliation, conference, and pers</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_626_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attendance of witnesses; investigations, inspections, records, and homework regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Attendance of witnesses; investigations, inspections, records, and homework regulations The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall have the power to make investigations and require the keeping of records necessary or appropriate for the administration of this chapter in accordance with the powers and procedures provided in sections 209 and 211 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_626_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement; prohibition of age discrimination under fair labor standards; unpaid minimum wages and unpaid overtime compensation; liquidated damages; judicial relief; conciliation, conference, and persuasion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enforcement; prohibition of age discrimination under fair labor standards; unpaid minimum wages and unpaid overtime compensation; liquidated damages; judicial relief; conciliation, conference, and persuasion The provisions of this chapter shall be enforced in accordance with the powers, remedies, and procedures provided in sections 211(b), 216 (except for subsection (a) thereof), and 217 of this title, and subsection (c) of this section. Any act prohibited under section 623 of this title shall be deemed to be a prohibited act under section 215 of this title. Amounts owing to a person as a result of a violation of this chapter shall be deemed to be unpaid minimum wages or unpaid overtime compensation for purposes of sections 216 and 217 of this title: Provided, That liquidated damages shall be payable only in cases of willful violations of this chapter. In any action brought to enforce this chapter the court shall have jurisdiction to grant such legal or equitable relief as may be a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_626_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions; persons aggrieved; jurisdiction; judicial relief; termination of individual action upon commencement of action by Commission; jury trial</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Civil actions; persons aggrieved; jurisdiction; judicial relief; termination of individual action upon commencement of action by Commission; jury trial</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_626_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of charge with Commission; timeliness; conciliation, conference, and persuasion; unlawful practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Filing of charge with Commission; timeliness; conciliation, conference, and persuasion; unlawful practice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_626_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reliance on administrative rulings; notice of dismissal or termination; civil action after receipt of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reliance on administrative rulings; notice of dismissal or termination; civil action after receipt of notice Section 259 of this title shall apply to actions under this chapter. If a charge filed with the Commission under this chapter is dismissed or the proceedings of the Commission are otherwise terminated by the Commission, the Commission shall notify the person aggrieved. A civil action may be brought under this section by a person defined in section 630(a) of this title against the respondent named in the charge within 90 days after the date of the receipt of such notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_626_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Waiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>