<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/633a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/633a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/633a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_633a"><akn:num>633a</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination on account of age in Federal Government employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 633a. Nondiscrimination on account of age in Federal Government employment(a) Federal agencies affectedAll personnel actions affecting employees or applicants for employment who are at least 40 years of age (except personnel actions with regard to aliens employed outside the limits of the United States) in military departments as defined in section 102 of title 5, in executive agencies as defined in section 105 of title 5 (including employees and applicants for employment who are paid from nonappropriated funds), in the United States Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission, in those units in the government of the District of Columbia having positions in the competitive service, and in those units of the judicial branch of the Federal Government having positions in the competitive service, in the Smithsonian Institution, and in the Government Publishing Office, the Government Accountability Office, and the Library of Congress shall be made free from any discrimination based on age.


(b) Enforcement by Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and by Librarian of Congress in the Library of Congress; remedies; rules, regulations, orders, and instructions of Commission: compliance by Federal agencies; powers and duties of Commission; notification of final action on complaint of discrimination; exemptions: bona fide occupational qualificationExcept as otherwise provided in this subsection, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission is authorized to enforce the provisions of subsection (a) through appropriate remedies, including reinstatement or hiring of employees with or without backpay, as will effectuate the policies of this section. The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall issue such rules, regulations, orders, and instructions as it deems necessary and appropriate to carry out its responsibilities under this section. The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall—(1) be responsible for the review and evaluation of the operation of all agenc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agencies affected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal agencies affected All personnel actions affecting employees or applicants for employment who are at least 40 years of age (except personnel actions with regard to aliens employed outside the limits of the United States) in military departments as defined in section 102 of title 5, in executive agencies as defined in section 105 of title 5 (including employees and applicants for employment who are paid from nonappropriated funds), in the United States Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission, in those units in the government of the District of Columbia having positions in the competitive service, and in those units of the judicial branch of the Federal Government having positions in the competitive service, in the Smithsonian Institution, and in the Government Publishing Office, the Government Accountability Office, and the Library of Congress shall be made free from any discrimination based on age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and by Librarian of Congress in the Library of Congress; remedies; rules, regulations, orders, and instructions of Commission: compliance by Federal agencies; powers and duties of Commission; notification of final action on complaint of discrimination; exemptions: bona fide occupational qualification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enforcement by Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and by Librarian of Congress in the Library of Congress; remedies; rules, regulations, orders, and instructions of Commission: compliance by Federal agencies; powers and duties of Commission; notification of final action on complaint of discrimination; exemptions: bona fide occupational qualification Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission is authorized to enforce the provisions of subsection (a) through appropriate remedies, including reinstatement or hiring of employees with or without backpay, as will effectuate the policies of this section. The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall issue such rules, regulations, orders, and instructions as it deems necessary and appropriate to carry out its responsibilities under this section. The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission shall— The head of each such department, agency, or unit shall comply with such rules, regulati</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions; jurisdiction; relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Civil actions; jurisdiction; relief Any person aggrieved may bring a civil action in any Federal district court of competent jurisdiction for such legal or equitable relief as will effectuate the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Commission; time of notice; Commission notification of prospective defendants; Commission elimination of unlawful practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice to Commission; time of notice; Commission notification of prospective defendants; Commission elimination of unlawful practices When the individual has not filed a complaint concerning age discrimination with the Commission, no civil action may be commenced by any individual under this section until the individual has given the Commission not less than thirty days’ notice of an intent to file such action. Such notice shall be filed within one hundred and eighty days after the alleged unlawful practice occurred. Upon receiving a notice of intent to sue, the Commission shall promptly notify all persons named therein as prospective defendants in the action and take any appropriate action to assure the elimination of any unlawful practice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of Government agency or official</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duty of Government agency or official Nothing contained in this section shall relieve any Government agency or official of the responsibility to assure nondiscrimination on account of age in employment as required under any provision of Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of statutory provisions to personnel action of Federal departments, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicability of statutory provisions to personnel action of Federal departments, etc. Any personnel action of any department, agency, or other entity referred to in subsection (a) of this section shall not be subject to, or affected by, any provision of this chapter, other than the provisions of sections 626(d)(3) and 631(b) of this title and the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_633a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report to President and Congress by Equal Employment Opportunity Commission; scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Study and report to President and Congress by Equal Employment Opportunity Commission; scope</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>