<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/657" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/657/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/657/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_657"><akn:num>657</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections, investigations, and recordkeeping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 657. Inspections, investigations, and recordkeeping(a) Authority of Secretary to enter, inspect, and investigate places of employment; time and mannerIn order to carry out the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary, upon presenting appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, is authorized—(1) to enter without delay and at reasonable times any factory, plant, establishment, construction site, or other area, workplace or environment where work is performed by an employee of an employer; and

(2) to inspect and investigate during regular working hours and at other reasonable times, and within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner, any such place of employment and all pertinent conditions, structures, machines, apparatus, devices, equipment, and materials therein, and to question privately any such employer, owner, operator, agent, or employee.


(b) Attendance and testimony of witnesses and production of evidence; enforcement of subpoenaIn making his inspections and investigations under this chapter the Secretary may require the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of evidence under oath. Witnesses shall be paid the same fees and mileage that are paid witnesses in the courts of the United States. In case of a contumacy, failure, or refusal of any person to obey such an order, any district court of the United States or the United States courts of any territory or possession, within the jurisdiction of which such person is found, or resides or transacts business, upon the application by the Secretary, shall have jurisdiction to issue to such person an order requiring such person to appear to produce evidence if, as, and when so ordered, and to give testimony relating to the matter under investigation or in question, and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by said court as a contempt thereof.


(c) Maintenance, preservation, and availability of rec­ords; issuance of regulations; scope of records</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary to enter, inspect, and investigate places of employment; time and manner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary to enter, inspect, and investigate places of employment; time and manner In order to carry out the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary, upon presenting appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, is authorized—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attendance and testimony of witnesses and production of evidence; enforcement of subpoena</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Attendance and testimony of witnesses and production of evidence; enforcement of subpoena In making his inspections and investigations under this chapter the Secretary may require the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of evidence under oath. Witnesses shall be paid the same fees and mileage that are paid witnesses in the courts of the United States. In case of a contumacy, failure, or refusal of any person to obey such an order, any district court of the United States or the United States courts of any territory or possession, within the jurisdiction of which such person is found, or resides or transacts business, upon the application by the Secretary, shall have jurisdiction to issue to such person an order requiring such person to appear to produce evidence if, as, and when so ordered, and to give testimony relating to the matter under investigation or in question, and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by said court as a contempt t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance, preservation, and availability of rec­ords; issuance of regulations; scope of records; periodic inspections by employer; posting of notices by employer; notification of employee of corrective action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maintenance, preservation, and availability of rec­ords; issuance of regulations; scope of records; periodic inspections by employer; posting of notices by employer; notification of employee of corrective action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obtaining of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Obtaining of information Any information obtained by the Secretary, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, or a State agency under this chapter shall be obtained with a minimum burden upon employers, especially those operating small businesses. Unnecessary duplication of efforts in obtaining information shall be reduced to the maximum extent feasible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer and authorized employee representatives to accompany Secretary or his authorized representative on inspection of workplace; consultation with employees where no authorized employee representative is present</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Employer and authorized employee representatives to accompany Secretary or his authorized representative on inspection of workplace; consultation with employees where no authorized employee representative is present Subject to regulations issued by the Secretary, a representative of the employer and a representative authorized by his employees shall be given an opportunity to accompany the Secretary or his authorized representative during the physical inspection of any workplace under subsection (a) for the purpose of aiding such inspection. Where there is no authorized employee representative, the Secretary or his authorized representative shall consult with a reasonable number of employees concerning matters of health and safety in the workplace.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for inspection by employees or representative of employees; grounds; procedure; determination of request; notification of Secretary or representative prior to or during any inspection of violations; procedure for review of refusal by representative of Secretary to issue citation for alleged violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Request for inspection by employees or representative of employees; grounds; procedure; determination of request; notification of Secretary or representative prior to or during any inspection of violations; procedure for review of refusal by representative of Secretary to issue citation for alleged violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compilation, analysis, and publication of reports and information; rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compilation, analysis, and publication of reports and information; rules and regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_657_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of results of enforcement activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of results of enforcement activities The Secretary shall not use the results of enforcement activities, such as the number of citations issued or penalties assessed, to evaluate employees directly involved in enforcement activities under this chapter or to impose quotas or goals with regard to the results of such activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>