<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/710" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/710/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/710/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_710"><akn:num>710</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 710. Reports(a) Annual reports requiredNot later than one hundred and eighty days after the close of each fiscal year, the Commissioner shall prepare and submit to the President and to the Congress a full and complete report on the activities carried out under this chapter, including the activities and staffing of the information clearinghouse under section 712 of this title.


(b) Collection of informationThe Commissioner shall collect information to determine whether the purposes of this chapter are being met and to assess the performance of programs carried out under this chapter. The Commissioner shall take whatever action is necessary to assure that the identity of each individual for which information is supplied under this section is kept confidential, except as otherwise required by law (including regulation).


(c) Information to be included in reports(1) 11 So in original. There is no par. (2). In preparing the report, the Commissioner shall annually collect and include in the report information based on the information submitted by States in accordance with section 721(a)(10) of this title, including information on administrative costs as required by section 721(a)(10)(D) of this title. The Commissioner shall, to the maximum extent appropriate, include in the report all information that is required to be submitted in the reports described in section 3141(d)(2) of this title and that pertains to the employment of individuals with disabilities.


(d) Availability to publicThe Commissioner shall ensure that the report described in this section is made publicly available in a timely manner, including through electronic means, in order to inform the public about the administration and performance of programs under this chapter.


(Pub. L. 93–112, § 13, formerly § 11, as added Pub. L. 105–220, title IV, § 403, Aug. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1111; renumbered § 13, Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title VIII, § 402(a)(1)], Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–337, 2681–412</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_710_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual reports required Not later than one hundred and eighty days after the close of each fiscal year, the Commissioner shall prepare and submit to the President and to the Congress a full and complete report on the activities carried out under this chapter, including the activities and staffing of the information clearinghouse under section 712 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_710_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Collection of information The Commissioner shall collect information to determine whether the purposes of this chapter are being met and to assess the performance of programs carried out under this chapter. The Commissioner shall take whatever action is necessary to assure that the identity of each individual for which information is supplied under this section is kept confidential, except as otherwise required by law (including regulation).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_710_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information to be included in reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information to be included in reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_710_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability to public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability to public The Commissioner shall ensure that the report described in this section is made publicly available in a timely manner, including through electronic means, in order to inform the public about the administration and performance of programs under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>