<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_711"><akn:num>711</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 711. Evaluation(a) Statement of purpose; standards; persons eligible to conduct evaluationsFor the purpose of improving program management and effectiveness, the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Commissioner, shall evaluate all the programs authorized by this chapter, their general effectiveness in relation to their cost, their impact on related programs, and their structure and mechanisms for delivery of services, using appropriate methodology and evaluative research designs. The Secretary of Education shall establish and use standards for the evaluations required by this subsection. Such an evaluation shall be conducted by a person not immediately involved in the administration of the program evaluated.


(b) Opinions of participants; data as property of United States; availability of information(1) In carrying out evaluations under this section, the Secretary of Education shall obtain the opinions of program and project participants about the strengths and weaknesses of the programs and projects.

(2) The Secretary of Education shall take the necessary action to assure that all studies, evaluations, proposals, and data produced or developed with Federal funds under this chapter shall become the property of the United States.

(3) Such information as the Secretary of Education may determine to be necessary for purposes of the evaluations conducted under this section shall be made available upon request of the Secretary of Education, by the departments and agencies of the executive branch.


(c) Longitudinal study(1) To assess the linkages between vocational rehabilitation services and economic and noneconomic outcomes, the Secretary of Education shall continue to conduct a longitudinal study of a national sample of applicants for the services.

(2) The study shall address factors related to attrition and completion of the program through which the services are provided and factors within and outside the program affecting results. Appropriate comp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of purpose; standards; persons eligible to conduct evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Statement of purpose; standards; persons eligible to conduct evaluations For the purpose of improving program management and effectiveness, the Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Commissioner, shall evaluate all the programs authorized by this chapter, their general effectiveness in relation to their cost, their impact on related programs, and their structure and mechanisms for delivery of services, using appropriate methodology and evaluative research designs. The Secretary of Education shall establish and use standards for the evaluations required by this subsection. Such an evaluation shall be conducted by a person not immediately involved in the administration of the program evaluated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opinions of participants; data as property of United States; availability of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Opinions of participants; data as property of United States; availability of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Longitudinal study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Longitudinal study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on exemplary practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information on exemplary practices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities and responsibilities of Secretary of Education and Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorities and responsibilities of Secretary of Education and Commissioner</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>References to “this chapter”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) References to “this chapter”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>