<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/718" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/718/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/718/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_718"><akn:num>718</akn:num><akn:heading>Traditionally underserved populations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 718. Traditionally underserved populations(a) FindingsWith respect to the programs authorized in subchapters II through VII, the Congress finds as follows:(1) Racial profileThe demographic profile of America is rapidly changing. While the percentage increase from 2000 to 2010 for white Americans was 9.7 percent, the percentage increase for racial and ethnic minorities was much higher: 43.0 percent for Latinos, 12.3 percent for African-Americans, and 43.2 percent for Asian-Americans.


(2) Rate of disabilityEthnic and racial minorities tend to have disabling conditions at a disproportionately high rate. In 2011—(A) among Americans ages 16 through 64, the rate of disability was 12.1 percent;

(B) among African-Americans in that age range, the disability rate was more than twice as high, at 27.1 percent; and

(C) for American Indians and Alaska Natives in the same age range, the disability rate was also more than twice as high, at 27.0 percent.


(3) Inequitable treatmentPatterns of inequitable treatment of minorities have been documented in all major junctures of the vocational rehabilitation process. As compared to white Americans, a larger percentage of African-American applicants to the vocational rehabilitation system is denied acceptance. Of applicants accepted for service, a larger percentage of African-American cases is closed without being rehabilitated. Minorities are provided less training than their white counterparts. Consistently, less money is spent on minorities than on their white counterparts.


(4) RecruitmentRecruitment efforts within vocational rehabilitation at the level of preservice training, continuing education, and in-service training must focus on bringing larger numbers of minorities into the profession in order to provide appropriate practitioner knowledge, role models, and sufficient manpower to address the clearly changing demography of vocational rehabilitation.



(b) Outreach to minorities(1) In generalFor each fiscal year, the Comm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings With respect to the programs authorized in subchapters II through VII, the Congress finds as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach to minorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Outreach to minorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Demonstration In awarding grants, or entering into contracts or cooperative agreements under subchapters I, II, III, VI, and VII of this chapter, and section 794e of this title, the Commissioner and the Director of the National Institute on Disability, Independent Living, and Rehabilitation Research, in appropriate cases, shall require applicants to demonstrate how the applicants will address, in whole or in part, the needs of individuals with disabilities from minority backgrounds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>