<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/721" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/721/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/721/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_721"><akn:num>721</akn:num><akn:heading>State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 721. State plans(a) Plan requirements(1) In general(A) SubmissionTo be eligible to receive funds under this subchapter for a fiscal year, a State shall submit, and have approved by the Secretary and the Secretary of Labor, a unified State plan in accordance with section 102, or a combined State plan in accordance with section 103, of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act [29 U.S.C. 3112, 3113]. The unified or combined State plan shall include, in the portion of the plan described in section 102(b)(2)(D) of such Act [29 U.S.C. 3112(b)(2)(D)] (referred to in this subsection as the “vocational rehabilitation services portion”), the provisions of a State plan for vocational rehabilitation services, described in this subsection.


(B) NonduplicationThe State shall not be required to submit, as part of the vocational rehabilitation services portion of the unified or combined State plan submitted in accordance with subparagraph (A), policies, procedures, or descriptions required under this subchapter that have been previously submitted to the Commissioner and that demonstrate that such State meets the requirements of this subchapter, including any policies, procedures, or descriptions submitted under this subchapter as in effect on the day before the effective date of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.


(C) DurationThe vocational rehabilitation services portion of the unified or combined State plan submitted in accordance with subparagraph (A) shall remain in effect until the State submits and receives approval of a new State plan in accordance with subparagraph (A), or until the submission of such modifications as the State determines to be necessary or as the Commissioner may require based on a change in State policy, a change in Federal law (including regulations), an interpretation of this chapter by a Federal court or the highest court of the State, or a finding by the Commissioner of State noncompliance with the requirements of this chapter.



(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Plan requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission; approval; modification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submission; approval; modification The State plan for vocational rehabilitation services shall be subject to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Construction Nothing in this part shall be construed to reduce the obligation under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.) of a local educational agency or any other agency to provide or pay for any transition services that are also considered special education or related services and that are necessary for ensuring a free appropriate public education to children with disabilities within the State involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>