<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/730" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/730/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/730/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_730"><akn:num>730</akn:num><akn:heading>State allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 730. State allotments(a) Computation; additional amount; minimum amount; adjustments(1) Subject to the provisions of subsections (c) and (d),,11 So in original. for each fiscal year beginning before October 1, 1978, each State shall be entitled to an allotment of an amount bearing the same ratio to the amount authorized to be appropriated under section 720(b)(1) of this title for allotment under this section as the product of—(A) the population of the State; and

(B) the square of its allotment percentage,


bears to the sum of the corresponding products for all the States.

(2)(A) For each fiscal year beginning on or after October 1, 1978, each State shall be entitled to an allotment in an amount equal to the amount such State received under paragraph (1) for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1978, and an additional amount determined pursuant to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph.

(B) For each fiscal year beginning on or after October 1, 1978, each State shall be entitled to an allotment, from any amount authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year under section 720(b)(1) of this title for allotment under this section in excess of the amount appropriated under section 720(b)(1)(A) 22 See References in Text note below. of this title for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1978, in an amount equal to the sum of—(i) an amount bearing the same ratio to 50 percent of such excess amount as the product of the population of the State and the square of its allotment percentage bears to the sum of the corresponding products for all the States; and

(ii) an amount bearing the same ratio to 50 percent of such excess amount as the product of the population of the State and its allotment percentage bears to the sum of the corresponding products for all the States.



(3) The sum of the payment to any State (other than Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands) under this subsection for any fiscal year which is les</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_730_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation; additional amount; minimum amount; adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Computation; additional amount; minimum amount; adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_730_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unused funds; redistribution; increase in amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Unused funds; redistribution; increase in amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_730_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds for American Indian vocational rehabilitation services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funds for American Indian vocational rehabilitation services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_730_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds for pre-employment transition services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funds for pre-employment transition services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>