<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/732" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/732/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/732/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_732"><akn:num>732</akn:num><akn:heading>Client assistance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 732. Client assistance program(a) Establishment of grant programFrom funds appropriated under subsection (h), the Secretary shall, in accordance with this section, make grants to States to establish and carry out client assistance programs to provide assistance in informing and advising all clients and client applicants of all available benefits under this chapter, including under sections 733 and 794g of this title, and, upon request of such clients or client applicants, to assist and advocate for such clients or applicants in their relationships with projects, programs, and services provided under this chapter, including assistance and advocacy in pursuing legal, administrative, or other appropriate remedies to ensure the protection of the rights of such individuals under this chapter and to facilitate access to the services funded under this chapter through individual and systemic advocacy. The client assistance program shall provide information on the available services and benefits under this chapter and title I of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (42 U.S.C. 12111 et seq.) to individuals with disabilities in the State, especially with regard to individuals with disabilities who have traditionally been unserved or underserved by vocational rehabilitation programs. In providing assistance and advocacy under this subsection with respect to services under this subchapter, a client assistance program may provide the assistance and advocacy with respect to services that are directly related to facilitating the employment of the individual.


(b) Existence of State program as requisite to receiving paymentsNo State may receive payments from its allotment under this chapter in any fiscal year unless the State has in effect a client assistance program which—(1) has the authority to pursue legal, administrative, and other appropriate remedies to ensure the protection of rights of individuals with disabilities who are receiving treatments, services, or rehabi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of grant program From funds appropriated under subsection (h), the Secretary shall, in accordance with this section, make grants to States to establish and carry out client assistance programs to provide assistance in informing and advising all clients and client applicants of all available benefits under this chapter, including under sections 733 and 794g of this title, and, upon request of such clients or client applicants, to assist and advocate for such clients or applicants in their relationships with projects, programs, and services provided under this chapter, including assistance and advocacy in pursuing legal, administrative, or other appropriate remedies to ensure the protection of the rights of such individuals under this chapter and to facilitate access to the services funded under this chapter through individual and systemic advocacy. The client assistance program shall provide information on the available services and benefits under this chapter and titl</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existence of State program as requisite to receiving payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Existence of State program as requisite to receiving payments No State may receive payments from its allotment under this chapter in any fiscal year unless the State has in effect a client assistance program which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of agency to conduct program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designation of agency to conduct program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Class action by designated agency prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Class action by designated agency prohibited The agency designated under subsection (c) of this section may not bring any class action in carrying out its responsibilities under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment and reallotment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allotment and reallotment of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application by State for grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application by State for grant funds No grant may be made under this section unless the State submits an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Secretary deems necessary to meet the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; minimum requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations; minimum requirements The Secretary shall prescribe regulations applicable to the client assistance program which shall include the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_732_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>