<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/765" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/765/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/765/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_765"><akn:num>765</akn:num><akn:heading>Disability, Independent Living, and Rehabilitation Research Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 765. Disability, Independent Living, and Rehabilitation Research Advisory Council(a) EstablishmentSubject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall establish in the Department of Health and Human Services a Disability, Independent Living, and Rehabilitation Research Advisory Council (referred to in this section as the “Council”) composed of not less than 12 members appointed by the Secretary.


(b) DutiesThe Council shall advise the Director with respect to research priorities and the development and revision of the 5-year plan required by section 762(h) of this title.


(c) QualificationsMembers of the Council shall be generally representative of the community of disability, independent living, and rehabilitation professionals, the community of disability, independent living, and rehabilitation researchers, the directors of independent living centers and community rehabilitation programs, the business community (including a representative of the small business community) that has experience with the system of vocational rehabilitation services and independent living services carried out under this chapter and with hiring individuals with disabilities, the community of stakeholders involved in assistive technology, the community of covered school professionals, and the community of individuals with disabilities, and the individuals’ representatives. At least one-half of the members shall be individuals with disabilities or the individuals’ representatives.


(d) Terms of appointment(1) Length of termEach member of the Council shall serve for a term of up to 3 years, determined by the Secretary, except that—(A) a member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which a predecessor was appointed, shall be appointed for the remainder of such term; and

(B) the terms of service of the members initially appointed shall be (as specified by the Secretary) for such fewer number of years as will provide for the expiratio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall establish in the Department of Health and Human Services a Disability, Independent Living, and Rehabilitation Research Advisory Council (referred to in this section as the “Council”) composed of not less than 12 members appointed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Council shall advise the Director with respect to research priorities and the development and revision of the 5-year plan required by section 762(h) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualifications Members of the Council shall be generally representative of the community of disability, independent living, and rehabilitation professionals, the community of disability, independent living, and rehabilitation researchers, the directors of independent living centers and community rehabilitation programs, the business community (including a representative of the small business community) that has experience with the system of vocational rehabilitation services and independent living services carried out under this chapter and with hiring individuals with disabilities, the community of stakeholders involved in assistive technology, the community of covered school professionals, and the community of individuals with disabilities, and the individuals’ representatives. At least one-half of the members shall be individuals with disabilities or the individuals’ representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms of appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Vacancies Any vacancy occurring in the membership of the Council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment for the position being vacated. The vacancy shall not affect the power of the remaining members to execute the duties of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Payment and expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail of Federal employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Detail of Federal employees On the request of the Council, the Secretary may detail, with or without reimbursement, any of the personnel of the Department of Health and Human Services to the Council to assist the Council in carrying out its duties. Any detail shall not interrupt or otherwise affect the civil service status or privileges of the Federal employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Technical assistance On the request of the Council, the Secretary shall provide such technical assistance to the Council as the Council determines to be necessary to carry out its duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_765_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination Section 1013 of title 5 shall not apply with respect to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>