<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/780a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/780a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/780a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_780a"><akn:num>780a</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent status of National Council on the Handicapped</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 780a. Independent status of National Council on the Handicapped(1) Council as independent agency within Federal GovernmentEffective on February 22, 1984, the National Council on the Handicapped shall be an independent agency within the Federal Government and shall not be an agency within the Department of Education or any other department or agency of the United States.


(2) Transfer of functions to Council ChairmanThere are transferred to the Chairman of the National Council on the Handicapped all functions relating to the Council which were vested in the Secretary of Education on the day before February 22, 1984. The Chairman of the National Council on the Handicapped shall continue to exercise all the functions under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.] or any other law or authority which the Chairman was performing before February 22, 1984.


(3) Changes in statutory and other referencesReferences in any statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, regulation, or other official document or proceeding to the Department of Education or the Secretary of Education with respect to functions or activities relating to the National Council on the Handicapped shall be deemed to refer to the National Council on the Handicapped or the Chairman of the National Council on the Handicapped, respectively.


(Pub. L. 98–221, title I, § 141(b), Feb. 22, 1984, 98 Stat. 26.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Rehabilitation Act of 1973, referred to in par. (2), is Pub. L. 93–112, Sept. 26, 1973, 87 Stat. 355, which is classified generally to this chapter (§ 701 et seq.). For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 701 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Rehabilitation Amendments of 1984, and not as part of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
The National Council on the Handicapped wa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_780a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Council as independent agency within Federal Government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Council as independent agency within Federal Government Effective on February 22, 1984, the National Council on the Handicapped shall be an independent agency within the Federal Government and shall not be an agency within the Department of Education or any other department or agency of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_780a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of functions to Council Chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Transfer of functions to Council Chairman There are transferred to the Chairman of the National Council on the Handicapped all functions relating to the Council which were vested in the Secretary of Education on the day before February 22, 1984. The Chairman of the National Council on the Handicapped shall continue to exercise all the functions under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.] or any other law or authority which the Chairman was performing before February 22, 1984.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_780a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes in statutory and other references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Changes in statutory and other references References in any statute, reorganization plan, Executive order, regulation, or other official document or proceeding to the Department of Education or the Secretary of Education with respect to functions or activities relating to the National Council on the Handicapped shall be deemed to refer to the National Council on the Handicapped or the Chairman of the National Council on the Handicapped, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>