<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/792" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/792/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/792/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_792"><akn:num>792</akn:num><akn:heading>Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 792. Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board(a) Establishment; membership; chairperson; vice-chairperson; term of office; termination of membership; reappointment; compensation and travel expenses; bylaws; quorum requirements(1) There is established within the Federal Government the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board (hereinafter referred to as the “Access Board”) which shall be composed as follows:(A) Thirteen members shall be appointed by the President from among members of the general public of whom at least a majority shall be individuals with disabilities.

(B) The remaining members shall be the heads of each of the following departments or agencies (or their designees whose positions are executive level IV or higher):(i) Department of Health and Human Services.

(ii) Department of Transportation.

(iii) Department of Housing and Urban Development.

(iv) Department of Labor.

(v) Department of the Interior.

(vi) Department of Defense.

(vii) Department of Justice.

(viii) General Services Administration.

(ix) Department of Veterans Affairs.

(x) United States Postal Service.

(xi) Department of Education.

(xii) Department of Commerce.



The chairperson and vice-chairperson of the Access Board shall be elected by majority vote of the members of the Access Board to serve for terms of one year. When the chairperson is a member of the general public, the vice-chairperson shall be a Federal official; and when the chairperson is a Federal official, the vice-chairperson shall be a member of the general public. Upon the expiration of the term as chairperson of a member who is a Federal official, the subsequent chairperson shall be a member of the general public; and vice versa.

(2)(A)(i) The term of office of each appointed member of the Access Board shall be 4 years, except as provided in clause (ii). Each year, the terms of office of at least three appointed members of the board 11 So in original. Probably should be “</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; membership; chairperson; vice-chairperson; term of office; termination of membership; reappointment; compensation and travel expenses; bylaws; quorum requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; membership; chairperson; vice-chairperson; term of office; termination of membership; reappointment; compensation and travel expenses; bylaws; quorum requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions It shall be the function of the Access Board to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional functions; transportation barriers and housing needs; transportation and housing plans and proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional functions; transportation barriers and housing needs; transportation and housing plans and proposals The Access Board shall also (1)(A) determine how and to what extent transportation barriers impede the mobility of individuals with disabilities and aged individuals with disabilities and consider ways in which travel expenses in connection with transportation to and from work for individuals with disabilities can be met or subsidized when such individuals are unable to use mass transit systems or need special equipment in private transportation, and (B) consider the housing needs of individuals with disabilities; (2) determine what measures are being taken, especially by public and other nonprofit agencies and groups having an interest in and a capacity to deal with such problems, (A) to eliminate barriers from public transportation systems (including vehicles used in such systems), and to prevent their incorporation in new or expanded transportation systems, and (B) to </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic and information technology accessibility training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Electronic and information technology accessibility training Beginning in fiscal year 2000, the Access Board, after consultation with the Secretary, representatives of such public and private entities as the Access Board determines to be appropriate (including the electronic and information technology industry), targeted individuals and entities (as defined in section 3002 of this title), and State information technology officers, shall provide training for Federal and State employees on any obligations related to section 794d of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations; hearings; orders; administrative procedure applicable; final orders; judicial review; civil action; intervention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Investigations; hearings; orders; administrative procedure applicable; final orders; judicial review; civil action; intervention</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of executive director, administrative law judges, and other personnel; provisions applicable to administrative law judges; authority and duties of executive director; finality of orders of compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appointment of executive director, administrative law judges, and other personnel; provisions applicable to administrative law judges; authority and duties of executive director; finality of orders of compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical, administrative, or other assistance; appointment, compensation, and travel expenses of advisory and technical experts and consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Technical, administrative, or other assistance; appointment, compensation, and travel expenses of advisory and technical experts and consultants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and contracts to aid Access Board in carrying out its functions; acceptance of gifts, devises, and bequests of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Grants and contracts to aid Access Board in carrying out its functions; acceptance of gifts, devises, and bequests of property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_792_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out the duties and functions of the Access Board under this section $7,448,000 for fiscal year 2015, $8,023,000 for fiscal year 2016, $8,190,000 for fiscal year 2017, $8,371,000 for fiscal year 2018, $8,568,000 for fiscal year 2019, and $8,750,000 for fiscal year 2020.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>