<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/794e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/794e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/794e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_794e"><akn:num>794e</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection and advocacy of individual rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 794e. Protection and advocacy of individual rights(a) Purpose and construction(1) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to support a system in each State to protect the legal and human rights of individuals with disabilities who—(A) need services that are beyond the scope of services authorized to be provided by the client assistance program under section 732 of this title; and

(B)(i) are ineligible for protection and advocacy programs under subtitle C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [42 U.S.C. 15041 et seq.] because the individuals do not have a developmental disability, as defined in section 102 of such Act [42 U.S.C. 15002]; and

(ii) are ineligible for services under the Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals Act of 1986 11 See References in Text note below. (42 U.S.C. 10801 et seq.) because the individuals are not individuals with mental illness, as defined in section 102 of such Act (42 U.S.C. 10802).



(2) ConstructionThis section shall not be construed to require the provision of protection and advocacy services that can be provided under the Assistive Technology Act of 1998 [29 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.].



(b) Appropriations less than $5,500,000For any fiscal year in which the amount appropriated to carry out this section is less than $5,500,000, the Commissioner may make grants from such amount to eligible systems within States to plan for, develop outreach strategies for, and carry out protection and advocacy programs authorized under this section for individuals with disabilities who meet the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1).


(c) Appropriations of $5,500,000 or more(1) Reservations(A) Technical assistanceFor any fiscal year in which the amount appropriated to carry out this section equals or exceeds $5,500,000, the Commissioner shall set aside not less than 1.8 percent and not more than 2.2 percent of the amount to provide a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose and construction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations less than $5,500,000</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appropriations less than $5,500,000 For any fiscal year in which the amount appropriated to carry out this section is less than $5,500,000, the Commissioner may make grants from such amount to eligible systems within States to plan for, develop outreach strategies for, and carry out protection and advocacy programs authorized under this section for individuals with disabilities who meet the requirements of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations of $5,500,000 or more</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appropriations of $5,500,000 or more</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proportional reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Proportional reduction To provide minimum allotments to systems within States (as increased under subsection (c)(5)) under subsection (c)(3)(B), or to provide minimum allotments to systems within States (as increased under subsection (c)(5)) under subsection (c)(4)(B), the Commissioner shall proportionately reduce the allotments of the remaining systems within States under subsection (c)(3), with such adjustments as may be necessary to prevent the allotment of any such remaining system within a State from being reduced to less than the minimum allotment for a system within a State (as increased under subsection (c)(5)) under subsection (c)(3)(B), or the minimum allotment for a State (as increased under subsection (c)(5)) under subsection (c)(4)(B), as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reallotment Whenever the Commissioner determines that any amount of an allotment to a system within a State for any fiscal year described in subsection (c)(1) will not be expended by such system in carrying out the provisions of this section, the Commissioner shall make such amount available for carrying out the provisions of this section to one or more of the systems that the Commissioner determines will be able to use additional amounts during such year for carrying out such provisions. Any amount made available to a system for any fiscal year pursuant to the preceding sentence shall, for the purposes of this section, be regarded as an increase in the allotment of the system (as determined under the preceding provisions of this section) for such year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application In order to receive assistance under this section, an eligible system shall submit an application to the Commissioner, at such time, in such form and manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Commissioner determines necessary to meet the requirements of this section, including assurances that the eligible system will—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryover and direct payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Carryover and direct payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on disclosure requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitation on disclosure requirements For purposes of any audit, report, or evaluation of the performance of the program established under this section, the Commissioner shall not require such a program to disclose the identity of, or any other personally identifiable information related to, any individual requesting assistance under such program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative cost</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Administrative cost In any State in which an eligible system is located within a State agency, a State may use a portion of any allotment under subsection (c) for the cost of the administration of the system required by this section. Such portion may not exceed 5 percent of the allotment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794e_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Delegation The Commissioner may delegate the administration of this program to the Commissioner of the Administration on Developmental Disabilities within the Department of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>