<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/794g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/794g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/794g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_794g"><akn:num>794g</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on use of subminimum wage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 794g. Limitations on use of subminimum wage(a) In generalNo entity, including a contractor or subcontractor of the entity, which holds a special wage certificate as described in section 14(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 214(c)) may compensate an individual with a disability who is age 24 or younger at a wage (referred to in this section as a “subminimum wage”) that is less than the Federal minimum wage unless 1 of the following conditions is met:(1) The individual is currently employed, as of the effective date of this section, by an entity that holds a valid certificate pursuant to section 14(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938.

(2) The individual, before beginning work that is compensated at a subminimum wage, has completed, and produces documentation indicating completion of, each of the following actions:(A) The individual has received pre-employment transition services that are available to the individual under section 733 of this title, or transition services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.) such as transition services available to the individual under section 614(d) of that Act (20 U.S.C. 1414(d)).

(B) The individual has applied for vocational rehabilitation services under subchapter I, with the result that—(i)(I) the individual has been found ineligible for such services pursuant to that subchapter and has documentation consistent with section 722(a)(5)(C) of this title regarding the determination of ineligibility; or

(II)(aa) the individual has been determined to be eligible for vocational rehabilitation services;

(bb) the individual has an individualized plan for employment under section 722 of this title;

(cc) the individual has been working toward an employment outcome specified in such individualized plan for employment, with appropriate supports and services, including supported employment services, for a reasonable period of time without success; and

(dd) the individua</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general No entity, including a contractor or subcontractor of the entity, which holds a special wage certificate as described in section 14(c) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 214(c)) may compensate an individual with a disability who is age 24 or younger at a wage (referred to in this section as a “subminimum wage”) that is less than the Federal minimum wage unless 1 of the following conditions is met:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Construction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>During employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) During employment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documentation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Documentation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Verification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_794g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal minimum wage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal minimum wage In this section, the term “Federal minimum wage” means the rate applicable under section 6(a)(1) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (29 U.S.C. 206(a)(1)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>