<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/795k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/795k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/795k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_795k"><akn:num>795k</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 795k. State plan(a) State plan supplementsTo be eligible for an allotment under this subchapter, a State shall submit to the Commissioner, as part of the State plan under section 721 of this title, a State plan supplement for providing supported employment services authorized under this chapter to individuals, including youth with the most significant disabilities, who are eligible under this chapter to receive the services. Each State shall make such annual revisions in the plan supplement as may be necessary.


(b) ContentsEach such plan supplement shall—(1) designate each designated State agency as the agency to administer the program assisted under this subchapter;

(2) summarize the results of the comprehensive, statewide assessment conducted under section 721(a)(15)(A)(i) of this title, with respect to the rehabilitation needs of individuals, including youth, with significant disabilities and the need for supported employment services, including needs related to coordination;

(3) describe the quality, scope, and extent of supported employment services authorized under this chapter to be provided to individuals, including youth with the most significant disabilities, who are eligible under this chapter to receive the services and specify the goals and plans of the State with respect to the distribution of funds received under section 795h of this title;

(4) demonstrate evidence of the efforts of the designated State agency to identify and make arrangements (including entering into cooperative agreements) with other State agencies and other appropriate entities to assist in the provision of supported employment services;

(5) demonstrate evidence of the efforts of the designated State agency to identify and make arrangements (including entering into cooperative agreements) with other public or nonprofit agencies or organizations within the State, employers, natural supports, and other entities with respect to the provision of extended services;

(6) describe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_795k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan supplements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State plan supplements To be eligible for an allotment under this subchapter, a State shall submit to the Commissioner, as part of the State plan under section 721 of this title, a State plan supplement for providing supported employment services authorized under this chapter to individuals, including youth with the most significant disabilities, who are eligible under this chapter to receive the services. Each State shall make such annual revisions in the plan supplement as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_795k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents Each such plan supplement shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>