<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_796c"><akn:num>796c</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 796c. State plan(a) In general(1) RequirementTo be eligible to receive financial assistance under this part, a State shall submit to the Administrator, and obtain approval of, a State plan developed and signed in accordance with paragraph (2), containing such provisions as the Administrator may require, including, at a minimum, the provisions required in this section.


(2) Joint developmentThe plan under paragraph (1) shall be jointly—(A) developed by the chairperson of the Statewide Independent Living Council, and the directors of the centers for independent living in the State, after receiving public input from individuals with disabilities and other stakeholders throughout the State; and

(B) signed by—(i) the chairperson of the Statewide Independent Living Council, acting on behalf of and at the direction of the Council;

(ii) the director of the designated State entity described in subsection (c); and

(iii) not less than 51 percent of the directors of the centers for independent living in the State.



(3) Periodic review and revisionThe plan shall provide for the review and revision of the plan, not less than once every 3 years, to ensure the existence of appropriate planning, financial support and coordination, and other assistance to appropriately address, on a statewide and comprehensive basis, needs in the State for—(A) the provision of independent living services in the State;

(B) the development and support of a statewide network of centers for independent living; and

(C) working relationships and collaboration between—(i) centers for independent living; and

(ii)(I) entities carrying out programs that provide independent living services, including those serving older individuals;

(II) other community-based organizations that provide or coordinate the provision of housing, transportation, employment, information and referral assistance, services, and supports for individuals with significant disabilities; and

(III) entities carrying out other pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statewide Independent Living Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Statewide Independent Living Council The plan shall provide for the establishment of a Statewide Independent Living Council in accordance with section 796d of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of State entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designation of State entity The plan shall designate a State entity of such State (referred to in this subchapter as the “designated State entity”) as the agency that, on behalf of the State, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Objectives The plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent living services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Independent living services The plan shall provide that the State will provide independent living services under this part to individuals with significant disabilities, and will provide the services to such an individual in accordance with an independent living plan mutually agreed upon by an appropriate staff member of the service provider and the individual, unless the individual signs a waiver stating that such a plan is unnecessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope and arrangements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Scope and arrangements The plan shall describe the extent and scope of independent living services to be provided under this part to meet such objectives. If the State makes arrangements, by grant or contract, for providing such services, such arrangements shall be described in the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Network</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Network The plan shall set forth a design for the establishment of a statewide network of centers for independent living that comply with the standards and assurances set forth in section 796f–4 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Centers In States in which State funding for centers for independent living equals or exceeds the amount of funds allotted to the State under subpart 3, as provided in section 796f–2 of this title, the plan shall include policies, practices, and procedures governing the awarding of grants to centers for independent living and oversight of such centers consistent with section 796f–2 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation, coordination, and working relationships among various entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Cooperation, coordination, and working relationships among various entities The plan shall set forth the steps that will be taken to maximize the cooperation, coordination, and working relationships among—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Coordination of services The plan shall describe how services funded under this part will be coordinated with, and complement, other services, in order to avoid unnecessary duplication with other Federal, State, and local programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>