<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_796d"><akn:num>796d</akn:num><akn:heading>Statewide Independent Living Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 796d. Statewide Independent Living Council(a) EstablishmentTo be eligible to receive financial assistance under this part, each State shall establish and maintain a Statewide Independent Living Council (referred to in this section as the “Council”). The Council shall not be established as an entity within a State agency.


(b) Composition and appointment(1) AppointmentMembers of the Council shall be appointed by the Governor or, in the case of a State that, under State law, vests authority for the administration of the activities carried out under this chapter in an entity other than the Governor (such as one or more houses of the State legislature or an independent board), the chief officer of that entity. The appointing authority shall select members after soliciting recommendations from representatives of organizations representing a broad range of individuals with disabilities and organizations interested in individuals with disabilities.


(2) CompositionThe Council shall include—(A) among its voting members, at least 1 director of a center for independent living chosen by the directors of centers for independent living within the State;

(B) among its voting members, for a State in which 1 or more centers for independent living are run by, or in conjunction with, the governing bodies of American Indian tribes located on Federal or State reservations, at least 1 representative of the directors of such centers; and

(C) as ex officio, nonvoting members, a representative of the designated State entity, and representatives from State agencies that provide services for individuals with disabilities.


(3) Additional membersThe Council may include—(A) other representatives from centers for independent living;

(B) individuals with disabilities;

(C) parents and guardians of individuals with disabilities;

(D) advocates of and for individuals with disabilities;

(E) representatives from private businesses;

(F) representatives from organizations that provide servic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment To be eligible to receive financial assistance under this part, each State shall establish and maintain a Statewide Independent Living Council (referred to in this section as the “Council”). The Council shall not be established as an entity within a State agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition and appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Composition and appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings and forums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hearings and forums The Council is authorized to hold such hearings and forums as the Council may determine to be necessary to carry out the duties of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compensation and expenses The Council may use available resources to reimburse members of the Council for reasonable and necessary expenses of attending Council meetings and performing Council duties (such as personal assistance services), and to pay reasonable compensation to a member of the Council, if such member is not employed or must forfeit wages from other employment, for each day the member is engaged in performing Council duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>