<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796f–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796f–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796f–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_796f_4"><akn:num>796f–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards and assurances for centers for independent living</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 796f–4. Standards and assurances for centers for independent living(a) In generalEach center for independent living that receives assistance under this subpart shall comply with the standards set out in subsection (b) and provide and comply with the assurances set out in subsection (c) in order to ensure that all programs and activities under this subpart are planned, conducted, administered, and evaluated in a manner consistent with the purposes of this part and the objective of providing assistance effectively and efficiently.


(b) Standards(1) PhilosophyThe center shall promote and practice the independent living philosophy of—(A) consumer control of the center regarding decisionmaking, service delivery, management, and establishment of the policy and direction of the center;

(B) self-help and self-advocacy;

(C) development of peer relationships and peer role models; and

(D) equal access for individuals with significant disabilities, within their communities, to all services, programs, activities, resources, and facilities, whether public or private and regardless of the funding source.


(2) Provision of servicesThe center shall provide services to individuals with a range of significant disabilities. The center shall provide services on a cross-disability basis (for individuals with all different types of significant disabilities, including individuals with significant disabilities who are members of populations that are unserved or underserved by programs under this subchapter). Eligibility for services at any center for independent living shall be determined by the center, and shall not be based on the presence of any one or more specific significant disabilities.


(3) Independent living goalsThe center shall facilitate the development and achievement of independent living goals selected by individuals with significant disabilities who seek such assistance by the center.


(4) Community optionsThe center shall work to increase the availability and impr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796f_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each center for independent living that receives assistance under this subpart shall comply with the standards set out in subsection (b) and provide and comply with the assurances set out in subsection (c) in order to ensure that all programs and activities under this subpart are planned, conducted, administered, and evaluated in a manner consistent with the purposes of this part and the objective of providing assistance effectively and efficiently.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796f_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796f_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assurances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assurances The eligible agency shall provide at such time and in such manner as the Administrator may require, such satisfactory assurances as the Administrator may require, including satisfactory assurances that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>