<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796j–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796j–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796j–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_796j_1"><akn:num>796j–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 796j–1. Training and technical assistance(a) In generalFrom the funds appropriated and made available to carry out this part for any fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 2015, the Commissioner shall first reserve not less than 1.8 percent and not more than 2 percent of the funds to provide, either directly or through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements, training and technical assistance to designated State agencies, or other providers of independent living services for older individuals who are blind, that are funded under this part for such fiscal year.


(b) SurveyThe Commissioner shall conduct a survey of designated State agencies that receive grants under section 796k of this title regarding training and technical assistance needs in order to determine funding priorities for such training and technical assistance.


(c) Application for grantTo be eligible to receive a grant or enter into a contract or cooperative agreement under this section, an entity shall submit an application to the Commissioner at such time, in such manner, containing a proposal to provide such training and technical assistance, and containing such additional information, as the Commissioner may require. The Commissioner shall provide for peer review of applications by panels that include persons who are not government employees and who have experience in the provision of services to older individuals who are blind.


(Pub. L. 93–112, title VII, § 751A, as added Pub. L. 113–128, title IV, § 486, July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1693.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796j_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general From the funds appropriated and made available to carry out this part for any fiscal year, beginning with fiscal year 2015, the Commissioner shall first reserve not less than 1.8 percent and not more than 2 percent of the funds to provide, either directly or through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements, training and technical assistance to designated State agencies, or other providers of independent living services for older individuals who are blind, that are funded under this part for such fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796j_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Survey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Survey The Commissioner shall conduct a survey of designated State agencies that receive grants under section 796k of this title regarding training and technical assistance needs in order to determine funding priorities for such training and technical assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796j_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application for grant To be eligible to receive a grant or enter into a contract or cooperative agreement under this section, an entity shall submit an application to the Commissioner at such time, in such manner, containing a proposal to provide such training and technical assistance, and containing such additional information, as the Commissioner may require. The Commissioner shall provide for peer review of applications by panels that include persons who are not government employees and who have experience in the provision of services to older individuals who are blind.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>