<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/29/796k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_796k"><akn:num>796k</akn:num><akn:heading>Program of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 796k. Program of grants(a) In general(1) Authority for grantsSubject to subsections (b) and (c), the Commissioner may make grants to States for the purpose of providing the services described in subsection (d) to older individuals who are blind.


(2) Designated State agencyThe Commissioner may not make a grant under this subsection unless the State involved agrees that the grant will be administered solely by the agency described in section 721(a)(2)(A)(i) of this title.



(b) Contingent competitive grantsBeginning with fiscal year 1993, in the case of any fiscal year for which the amount appropriated under section 796l of this title is less than $13,000,000, grants made under subsection (a) shall be—(1) discretionary grants made on a competitive basis to States; or

(2) grants made on a noncompetitive basis to pay for the continuation costs of activities for which a grant was awarded—(A) under this part; or

(B) under part C, as in effect on the day before October 29, 1992.



(c) Contingent formula grants(1) In generalIn the case of any fiscal year for which the amount appropriated under section 796l of this title is equal to or greater than $13,000,000, grants under subsection (a) shall be made only to States and shall be made only from allotments under paragraph (2).


(2) AllotmentsFor grants under subsection (a) for a fiscal year described in paragraph (1), the Commissioner shall make an allotment to each State in an amount determined in accordance with subsection (i), and shall make a grant to the State of the allotment made for the State if the State submits to the Commissioner an application in accordance with subsection (h).



(d) Services generallyThe Commissioner may not make a grant under subsection (a) unless the State involved agrees that the grant will be expended only for purposes of—(1) providing independent living services to older individuals who are blind;

(2) conducting activities that will improve or expand services for such individuals;</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contingent competitive grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contingent competitive grants Beginning with fiscal year 1993, in the case of any fiscal year for which the amount appropriated under section 796l of this title is less than $13,000,000, grants made under subsection (a) shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contingent formula grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contingent formula grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Services generally The Commissioner may not make a grant under subsection (a) unless the State involved agrees that the grant will be expended only for purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796k_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent living services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Independent living services Independent living services for purposes of subsection (d)(1) include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796k_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Matching funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796k_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain expenditures of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certain expenditures of grants A State may expend a grant under subsection (a) to carry out the purposes specified in subsection (d) through grants to, or contracts or cooperative agreements with, public and nonprofit private agencies or organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796k_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Application for grant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_796k_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of formula grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Amount of formula grant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>