<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_103"><akn:num>103</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Railroad Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 103. Federal Railroad Administration(a) In General.—The Federal Railroad Administration is an administration in the Department of Transportation.

(b) Safety.—To carry out all railroad safety laws of the United States, the Administration is divided on a geographical basis into at least 8 safety offices. The Secretary of Transportation is responsible for all acts taken under those laws and for ensuring that the laws are uniformly administered and enforced among the safety offices.

(c) Safety as Highest Priority.—In carrying out its duties, the Administration shall consider the assignment and maintenance of safety as the highest priority, recognizing the clear intent, encouragement, and dedication of Congress to the furtherance of the highest degree of safety in railroad transportation.

(d) Administrator.—The head of the Administration shall be the Administrator who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall be an individual with professional experience in railroad safety, hazardous materials safety, or other transportation safety. The Administrator shall report directly to the Secretary of Transportation.

(e) Deputy Administrator.—The Administration shall have a Deputy Administrator who shall be appointed by the Secretary. The Deputy Administrator shall carry out duties and powers prescribed by the Administrator.

(f) Chief Safety Officer.—The Administration shall have an Associate Administrator for Railroad Safety appointed in the career service by the Secretary. The Associate Administrator shall be the Chief Safety Officer of the Administration. The Associate Administrator shall carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Administrator.

(g) Duties and Powers of the Administrator.—The Administrator shall carry out—(1) duties and powers related to railroad safety vested in the Secretary by section 20134(c) and chapters 203 through 211 of this title, and by chapter 213 of this title for carrying out cha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Federal Railroad Administration is an administration in the Department of Transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safety.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To carry out all railroad safety laws of the United States, the Administration is divided on a geographical basis into at least 8 safety offices. The Secretary of Transportation is responsible for all acts taken under those laws and for ensuring that the laws are uniformly administered and enforced among the safety offices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safety as Highest Priority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out its duties, the Administration shall consider the assignment and maintenance of safety as the highest priority, recognizing the clear intent, encouragement, and dedication of Congress to the furtherance of the highest degree of safety in railroad transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The head of the Administration shall be the Administrator who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall be an individual with professional experience in railroad safety, hazardous materials safety, or other transportation safety. The Administrator shall report directly to the Secretary of Transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administration shall have a Deputy Administrator who shall be appointed by the Secretary. The Deputy Administrator shall carry out duties and powers prescribed by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Safety Officer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Administration shall have an Associate Administrator for Railroad Safety appointed in the career service by the Secretary. The Associate Administrator shall be the Chief Safety Officer of the Administration. The Associate Administrator shall carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and Powers of the Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Administrator shall carry out—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) A duty or power specified in subsection (g)(1) may be transferred to another part of the Department of Transportation or another Federal Government entity only when specifically provided by law. A decision of the Administrator in carrying out the duties or powers of the Administration and involving notice and hearing required by law is administratively final.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Subject to the provisions of subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, the Secretary of Transportation may make, enter into, and perform such contracts, grants, leases, cooperative agreements, and other similar transactions with Federal or other public agencies (including State and local governments) and private organizations and persons, and make such payments, by way of advance or reimbursement, as the Secretary may determine to be necessary or appropriate to carry out functions at the Administration. The authority of the Secretary granted by this subsection shall be carried out by the Administrator. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, no authority to enter into contracts or to make payments under this subsection shall be effective, except as provided for in appropriations Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_103_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Duties of the Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>