<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/10908" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/10908/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/10908/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10908"><akn:num>10908</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of solid waste rail transfer facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10908. Regulation of solid waste rail transfer facilities(a) In General.—Each solid waste rail transfer facility shall be subject to and shall comply with all applicable Federal and State requirements, both substantive and procedural, including judicial and administrative orders and fines, respecting the prevention and abatement of pollution, the protection and restoration of the environment, and the protection of public health and safety, including laws governing solid waste, to the same extent as required for any similar solid waste management facility, as defined in section 1004(29) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (42 U.S.C. 6903(29)) 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. that is not owned or operated by or on behalf of a rail carrier, except as provided for in section 10909 of this chapter.

(b) Existing Facilities.—(1) State laws and standards.—Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the Clean Railroads Act of 2008, a solid waste rail transfer facility operating as of such date of enactment shall comply with all Federal and State requirements pursuant to subsection (a) other than those provisions requiring permits.

(2) Permit requirements.—(A) State non-siting permits.—Any solid waste rail transfer facility operating as of the date of enactment of the Clean Railroads Act of 2008 that does not possess a permit required pursuant to subsection (a), other than a siting permit for the facility, as of the date of enactment of the Clean Railroads Act of 2008 shall not be required to possess any such permits in order to operate the facility—(i) if, within 180 days after such date of enactment, the solid waste rail transfer facility has submitted, in good faith, a complete application for all permits, except siting permits, required pursuant to subsection (a) to the appropriate permitting agency authorized to grant such permits; and

(ii) until the permitting agency has either approved or denied the solid waste rail transfer facilit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10908_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each solid waste rail transfer facility shall be subject to and shall comply with all applicable Federal and State requirements, both substantive and procedural, including judicial and administrative orders and fines, respecting the prevention and abatement of pollution, the protection and restoration of the environment, and the protection of public health and safety, including laws governing solid waste, to the same extent as required for any similar solid waste management facility, as defined in section 1004(29) of the Solid Waste Disposal Act (42 U.S.C. 6903(29)) 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. that is not owned or operated by or on behalf of a rail carrier, except as provided for in section 10909 of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10908_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing Facilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10908_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common Carrier Obligation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No prospective or current rail carrier customer may demand solid waste rail transfer service from a rail carrier at a solid waste rail transfer facility that does not already possess the necessary Federal land-use exemption and State permits at the location where service is requested.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10908_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Waste Commodities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nothing in this section or section 10909 of this chapter shall affect a rail carrier’s ability to conduct transportation-related activities with respect to commodities other than solid waste.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10908_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>