<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_113"><akn:num>113</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 113. Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration(a) In General.—The Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration shall be an administration of the Department of Transportation.

(b) Safety as Highest Priority.—In carrying out its duties, the Administration shall consider the assignment and maintenance of safety as the highest priority, recognizing the clear intent, encouragement, and dedication of Congress to the furtherance of the highest degree of safety in motor carrier transportation.

(c) Administrator.—The head of the Administration shall be the Administrator who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall be an individual with professional experience in motor carrier safety. The Administrator shall report directly to the Secretary of Transportation.

(d) Deputy Administrator.—The Administration shall have a Deputy Administrator appointed by the Secretary, with the approval of the President. The Deputy Administrator shall carry out duties and powers prescribed by the Administrator.

(e) Chief Safety Officer.—The Administration shall have an Assistant Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administrator appointed in the competitive service by the Secretary, with the approval of the President. The Assistant Administrator shall be the Chief Safety Officer of the Administration. The Assistant Administrator shall carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Administrator.

(f) Powers and Duties.—The Administrator shall carry out—(1) duties and powers related to motor carriers or motor carrier safety vested in the Secretary by chapters 5, 51, 55, 57, 59, 133 through 149, 311, 313, 315, and 317 and by section 18 of the Noise Control Act of 1972 (42 U.S.C. 4917; 86 Stat. 1249–1250); except as otherwise delegated by the Secretary to any agency of the Department of Transportation other than the Federal Highway Administration, as of October 8, 1999; and

(2) additional duties and powers prescribed by the Secretary.


(g) L</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration shall be an administration of the Department of Transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safety as Highest Priority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In carrying out its duties, the Administration shall consider the assignment and maintenance of safety as the highest priority, recognizing the clear intent, encouragement, and dedication of Congress to the furtherance of the highest degree of safety in motor carrier transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The head of the Administration shall be the Administrator who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall be an individual with professional experience in motor carrier safety. The Administrator shall report directly to the Secretary of Transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Administration shall have a Deputy Administrator appointed by the Secretary, with the approval of the President. The Deputy Administrator shall carry out duties and powers prescribed by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Safety Officer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administration shall have an Assistant Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administrator appointed in the competitive service by the Secretary, with the approval of the President. The Assistant Administrator shall be the Chief Safety Officer of the Administration. The Assistant Administrator shall carry out the duties and powers prescribed by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Administrator shall carry out—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Transfer of Powers and Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A duty or power specified in subsection (f)(1) may only be transferred to another part of the Department when specifically provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Certain Decisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) A decision of the Administrator involving a duty or power specified in subsection (f)(1) and involving notice and hearing required by law is administratively final.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Administrator shall consult with the Federal Highway Administrator and with the National Highway Traffic Safety Administrator on matters related to highway and motor carrier safety.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>