<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/1136" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/1136/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/1136/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1136"><akn:num>1136</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to passengers involved in aircraft accidents and families of such passengers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1136. Assistance to passengers involved in aircraft accidents and families of such passengers(a) In General.—As soon as practicable after being notified of an aircraft accident within United States airspace or airspace delegated to the United States involving an air carrier or foreign air carrier, resulting in any loss of life, and for which the National Transportation Safety Board will serve as the lead investigative agency, the Chairman of the Board shall—(1) designate and publicize the name and phone number of a director of family support services who shall be an employee of the Board and shall be responsible for acting as a point of contact within the Federal Government for the families of passengers involved in the accident and a liaison between the air carrier or foreign air carrier and the families; and

(2) designate an independent nonprofit organization, with experience in disasters and posttrauma communication with families, which shall have primary responsibility for coordinating the emotional care, psychological care, and family support services of passengers involved in the accident and the families of such passengers.


(b) Responsibilities of the Board.—The Board shall have primary Federal responsibility for facilitating the recovery and identification of fatally-injured passengers involved in an accident described in subsection (a).

(c) Responsibilities of Designated Organization.—The organization designated for an accident under subsection (a)(2) shall have the following responsibilities with respect to passengers involved in the accident and the families of such passengers:(1) To provide emotional care, psychological care, and family support services, in coordination with the disaster response team of the air carrier or foreign air carrier involved.

(2) To take such actions as may be necessary to provide an environment in which the families may grieve in private.

(3) To meet with passengers involved in the accident and the families of such pas</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) As soon as practicable after being notified of an aircraft accident within United States airspace or airspace delegated to the United States involving an air carrier or foreign air carrier, resulting in any loss of life, and for which the National Transportation Safety Board will serve as the lead investigative agency, the Chairman of the Board shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of the Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Board shall have primary Federal responsibility for facilitating the recovery and identification of fatally-injured passengers involved in an accident described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Designated Organization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The organization designated for an accident under subsection (a)(2) shall have the following responsibilities with respect to passengers involved in the accident and the families of such passengers:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Passenger Lists.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing Responsibilities of the Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In the course of its investigation of an accident described in subsection (a), the Board shall, to the maximum extent practicable, ensure that the families of passengers involved in the accident—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Air Carrier Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) To the extent practicable, the organization designated for an accident under subsection (a)(2) shall coordinate its activities with the air carrier or foreign air carrier involved in the accident so that the resources of the carrier can be used to the greatest extent possible to carry out the organization’s responsibilities under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited Actions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nothing in this section may be construed as limiting the actions that an air carrier may take, or the obligations that an air carrier may have, in providing assistance to passengers involved in the aircraft accident and the families of such passengers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1136_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relinquishment of Investigative Priority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>