<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13703" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13703/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13703/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13703"><akn:num>13703</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain collective activities; exemption from antitrust laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13703. Certain collective activities; exemption from antitrust laws(a) Agreements.—(1) Authority to enter.—A motor carrier providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 may enter into an agreement with one or more such carriers to establish—(A) through routes and joint rates;

(B) rates for the transportation of household goods;

(C) classifications;

(D) mileage guides;

(E) rules;

(F) divisions;

(G) rate adjustments of general application based on industry average carrier costs (so long as there is no discussion of individual markets or particular single-line rates); or

(H) procedures for joint consideration, initiation, or establishment of matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (G).


(2) Submission of agreement to board; approval.—An agreement entered into under paragraph (1) may be submitted by any carrier or carriers that are parties to such agreement to the Board for approval and may be approved by the Board only if it finds that such agreement is in the public interest.

(3) Conditions.—The Board may require compliance with reasonable conditions consistent with this part to assure that the agreement furthers the transportation policy set forth in section 13101.

(4) Independently established rates.—Any carrier which is a party to an agreement under paragraph (1) is not, and may not be, precluded from independently establishing its own rates, classification, and mileages or from adopting and using a noncollectively made classification or mileage guide.

(5) Investigations.—(A) Reasonableness.—The Board may suspend and investigate the reasonableness of any rate, rule, classification, or rate adjustment of general application made pursuant to an agreement under this section.

(B) Actions not in the public interest.—The Board may investigate any action taken pursuant to an agreement approved under this section. If the Board finds that the action is not in the public interest, the Board may take such measures as may be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13703_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13703_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Board may require an organization established or continued under an agreement approved under this section to maintain records and submit reports. The Board, or its delegate, may inspect a record maintained under this section, or monitor any organization’s compliance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13703_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13703_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13703_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Statutory Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13703_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry Standard Guides.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13703_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Single Line Rate Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section, the term “single line rate” means a rate, charge, or allowance proposed by a single motor carrier that is applicable only over its line and for which the transportation can be provided by that carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>