<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13905"><akn:num>13905</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective periods of registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13905. Effective periods of registration(a) Person Holding ICC Authority.—Any person having authority to provide transportation or service as a motor carrier, freight forwarder, or broker under this title, as in effect on December 31, 1995, shall be deemed, for purposes of this part, to be registered to provide such transportation or service under this part.

(b) Person Registered With Secretary.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), any person having registered with the Secretary to provide transportation or service as a motor carrier or motor private carrier under this title, as in effect on January 1, 2005, but not having registered pursuant to section 13902(a), shall be treated, for purposes of this part, to be registered to provide such transportation or service for purposes of sections 13908 and 14504a.

(2) Exclusively intrastate operators.—Paragraph (1) does not apply to a motor carrier or motor private carrier (including a transporter of waste or recyclable materials) engaged exclusively in intrastate transportation operations.


(c) Effective Period.—(1) In general.—Except as otherwise provided in this part, each registration issued under section 13902, 13903, or 13904—(A) shall be effective beginning on the date specified by the Secretary; and

(B) shall remain in effect for such period as the Secretary determines appropriate by regulation.


(2) Reissuance of registration.—(A) Requirement.—Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Enhancement Act of 2012, the Secretary shall require a freight forwarder or broker to renew its registration issued under this chapter.

(B) Effective period.—Each registration renewal under subparagraph (A)—(i) shall expire not later than 5 years after the date of such renewal; and

(ii) may be further renewed as provided under this chapter.




(d) Suspension, Amendments, and Revocations.—(1) Applications.—On application of the registrant, the Secretary may amen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person Holding ICC Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any person having authority to provide transportation or service as a motor carrier, freight forwarder, or broker under this title, as in effect on December 31, 1995, shall be deemed, for purposes of this part, to be registered to provide such transportation or service under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person Registered With Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Period.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension, Amendments, and Revocations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Except on application of the registrant, or if the Secretary determines that the registrant failed to disclose a material fact in an application for registration in accordance with subsection (d)(2)(C), the Secretary may revoke a registration of a motor carrier, freight forwarder, or broker, only after—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13905_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited Procedure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13905_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mexico-Domiciled Motor Carriers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, upon an order in accordance with section 324(a) of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement Implementation Act, the Secretary shall carry out the relief specified by revoking or imposing limitations on existing registrations of Mexico-domiciled motor carriers of cargo to operate beyond the municipalities along the United States-Mexico international border and the commercial zones of those municipalities as directed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>