<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13903"><akn:num>13903</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of freight forwarders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13903. Registration of freight forwarders(a) In General.—The Secretary shall register a person to provide service subject to jurisdiction under subchapter III of chapter 135 as a freight forwarder if the Secretary determines that the person—(1) has sufficient experience to qualify the person to act as a freight forwarder; and

(2) is fit, willing, and able to provide the service and to comply with this part and applicable regulations of the Secretary.


(b) Duration.—A registration issued under subsection (a) shall only remain in effect while the freight forwarder is in compliance with section 13906(c).

(c) Experience or Training Requirement.—Each freight forwarder shall employ, as an officer, an individual who—(1) has at least 3 years of relevant experience; or

(2) provides the Secretary with satisfactory evidence of the individual’s knowledge of related rules, regulations, and industry practices.


(d) Registration as Motor Carrier Required.—A freight forwarder may not provide transportation as a motor carrier unless the freight forwarder has registered separately under this chapter to provide transportation as a motor carrier.

(e) Update of Registration.—The Secretary shall require a freight forwarder to update its registration under this section not later than 30 days after a change in the freight forwarder’s address, other contact information, officers, process agent, or other essential information, as determined by the Secretary.

(Added Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103, Dec. 29, 1995, 109 Stat. 884; amended Pub. L. 109–59, title IV, § 4142(b), Aug. 10, 2005, 119 Stat. 1747; Pub. L. 110–244, title III, § 305(d), June 6, 2008, 122 Stat. 1620; Pub. L. 112–141, div. C, title II, §§ 32107(b), 32916(a), July 6, 2012, 126 Stat. 782, 820; Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title V, § 5508(a)(2), Dec. 4, 2015, 129 Stat. 1554.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2015—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 114–94 struck out par. (1) designation and heading before “A freight forwarder”.
2012—Subsec. (a).</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall register a person to provide service subject to jurisdiction under subchapter III of chapter 135 as a freight forwarder if the Secretary determines that the person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A registration issued under subsection (a) shall only remain in effect while the freight forwarder is in compliance with section 13906(c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Experience or Training Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each freight forwarder shall employ, as an officer, an individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration as Motor Carrier Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A freight forwarder may not provide transportation as a motor carrier unless the freight forwarder has registered separately under this chapter to provide transportation as a motor carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Update of Registration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall require a freight forwarder to update its registration under this section not later than 30 days after a change in the freight forwarder’s address, other contact information, officers, process agent, or other essential information, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>