<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/13906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13906"><akn:num>13906</akn:num><akn:heading>Security of motor carriers, motor private carriers, brokers, and freight forwarders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13906. Security of motor carriers, motor private carriers, brokers, and freight forwarders(a) Motor Carrier Requirements.—(1) Liability insurance requirement.—The Secretary may register a motor carrier under section 13902 only if the registrant files with the Secretary a bond, insurance policy, or other type of security approved by the Secretary, in an amount not less than such amount as the Secretary prescribes pursuant to, or as is required by, sections 31138 and 31139, and the laws of the State or States in which the registrant is operating, to the extent applicable. The security must be sufficient to pay, not more than the amount of the security, for each final judgment against the registrant for bodily injury to, or death of, an individual resulting from the negligent operation, maintenance, or use of motor vehicles, or for loss or damage to property (except property referred to in paragraph (3) 11 See References in Text note below. of this subsection), or both. A registration remains in effect only as long as the registrant continues to satisfy the security requirements of this paragraph.

(2) Security requirement.—Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of the Unified Carrier Registration Act of 2005, any person, other than a motor private carrier, registered with the Secretary to provide transportation or service as a motor carrier under section 13905(b) shall file with the Secretary a bond, insurance policy, or other type of security approved by the Secretary, in an amount not less than required by sections 31138 and 31139.

(3) Agency requirement.—A motor carrier shall comply with the requirements of sections 13303 and 13304. To protect the public, the Secretary may require any such motor carrier to file the type of security that a motor carrier is required to file under paragraph (1) of this subsection. This paragraph only applies to a foreign motor private carrier and foreign motor carrier operating in the United States to the extent that s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motor Carrier Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Broker Financial Security Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13906_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Freight Forwarder Financial Security Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13906_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Type of Insurance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may determine the type and amount of security filed under this section. A motor carrier may submit proof of qualifications as a self-insurer to satisfy the security requirements of this section. The Secretary shall adopt regulations governing the standards for approval as a self-insurer. Motor carriers which have been granted authority to self-insure as of January 1, 1996, shall retain that authority unless, for good cause shown and after notice and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary finds that the authority must be revoked.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13906_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of Cancellation of Insurance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall issue regulations requiring the submission to the Secretary of notices of insurance cancellation sufficiently in advance of actual cancellation so as to enable the Secretary to promptly revoke or suspend the registration of any carrier or broker after the effective date of the cancellation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13906_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of Endorsement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall also prescribe the appropriate form of endorsement to be appended to policies of insurance and surety bonds which will subject the insurance policy or surety bond to the full security limits of the coverage required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>