<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/14504a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/14504a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/14504a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14504a"><akn:num>14504a</akn:num><akn:heading>Unified Carrier Registration System plan and agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14504a. Unified Carrier Registration System plan and agreement(a) Definitions.—In this section and section 14506 (except as provided in paragraph (5)), the following definitions apply:(1) Commercial motor vehicle.—(A) In general.—Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “commercial motor vehicle”—(i) for calendar years 2008 and 2009, has the meaning given the term in section 31101; and

(ii) for years beginning after December 31, 2009, means a self-propelled vehicle described in section 31101.


(B) Exception.—With respect to determining the size of a motor carrier or motor private carrier’s fleet in calculating the fee to be paid by a motor carrier or motor private carrier pursuant to subsection (f)(1), the motor carrier or motor private carrier shall have the option to include, in addition to commercial motor vehicles as defined in subparagraph (A), any self-propelled vehicle used on the highway in commerce to transport passengers or property for compensation regardless of the gross vehicle weight rating of the vehicle or the number of passengers transported by such vehicle.


(2) Base-state.—(A) In general.—Subject to subparagraph (B), the term “base-State” means, with respect to a unified carrier registration agreement, a State—(i) that is in compliance with the requirements of subsection (e); and

(ii) in which the motor carrier, motor private carrier, broker, freight forwarder, or leasing company to which the agreement applies maintains its principal place of business.


(B) Designation of base-state.—A motor carrier, motor private carrier, broker, freight forwarder, or leasing company may designate another State in which it maintains an office or operating facility to be its base-State in the event that—(i) the State in which the motor carrier, motor private carrier, broker, freight forwarder, or leasing company maintains its principal place of business is not in compliance with the requirements of subsection (e); or

(ii) the motor carrier, motor p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section and section 14506 (except as provided in paragraph (5)), the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Provisions to Freight Forwarders.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A freight forwarder that operates commercial motor vehicles and is not required to register as a carrier pursuant to section 13903(b) 11 See References in Text note below. shall be subject to the provisions of this section as if the freight forwarder is a motor carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unreasonable Burden.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) For purposes of this section, it shall be considered an unreasonable burden upon interstate commerce for any State or any political subdivision of a State, or any political authority of two or more States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unified Carrier Registration Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State Participation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of Unified Carrier Registration Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The unified carrier registration agreement shall provide the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Revenues derived under the UCR Agreement shall be allocated to participating States as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of UCR Agreement Revenues.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14504a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to Intrastate Carriers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a State may elect to apply the provisions of the UCR agreement to motor carriers and motor private carriers and freight forwarders subject to its jurisdiction that operate solely in intrastate commerce within the borders of the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>