<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/14903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/14903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/14903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14903"><akn:num>14903</akn:num><akn:heading>Tariff violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14903. Tariff violations(a) Civil Penalty for Undercharging and Overcharging.—A person that offers, grants, gives, solicits, accepts, or receives by any means transportation or service provided for property by a carrier subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 at a rate different than the rate in effect under section 13702 is liable to the United States for a civil penalty of not more than $100,000 for each violation.

(b) General Criminal Penalty.—A carrier providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 or an officer, director, receiver, trustee, lessee, agent, or employee of a corporation that is subject to jurisdiction under that chapter, that willfully does not observe its tariffs as required under section 13702, shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned not more than 2 years, or both.

(c) Actions of Agents and Employees.—When acting in the scope of their employment, the actions and omissions of persons acting for or employed by a carrier or shipper that is subject to this section are considered to be the actions and omissions of that carrier or shipper as well as that person.

(d) Venue.—Trial in a criminal action under this section is in the judicial district in which any part of the violation is committed or through which the transportation is conducted.

(Added Pub. L. 104–88, title I, § 103, Dec. 29, 1995, 109 Stat. 915; amended Pub. L. 105–102, § 2(12), Nov. 20, 1997, 111 Stat. 2205.)

Historical and Revision Notes
Pub. L. 105–102This amends 49:14903(a) to correct a grammatical error.

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in section 11903 of this title prior to the general amendment of this subtitle by Pub. L. 104–88, § 102(a).

Amendments1997—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 105–102 inserted “a” before “civil penalty of not more than”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Jan. 1, 1996, except as otherwise provided in Pub. L. 104–88, see sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Penalty for Undercharging and Overcharging.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A person that offers, grants, gives, solicits, accepts, or receives by any means transportation or service provided for property by a carrier subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 at a rate different than the rate in effect under section 13702 is liable to the United States for a civil penalty of not more than $100,000 for each violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Criminal Penalty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A carrier providing transportation or service subject to jurisdiction under chapter 135 or an officer, director, receiver, trustee, lessee, agent, or employee of a corporation that is subject to jurisdiction under that chapter, that willfully does not observe its tariffs as required under section 13702, shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned not more than 2 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions of Agents and Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) When acting in the scope of their employment, the actions and omissions of persons acting for or employed by a carrier or shipper that is subject to this section are considered to be the actions and omissions of that carrier or shipper as well as that person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venue.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Trial in a criminal action under this section is in the judicial district in which any part of the violation is committed or through which the transportation is conducted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>