<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20109" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20109/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20109/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20109"><akn:num>20109</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20109. Employee protections(a) In General.—A railroad carrier engaged in interstate or foreign commerce, a contractor or a subcontractor of such a railroad carrier, or an officer or employee of such a railroad carrier, may not discharge, demote, suspend, reprimand, or in any other way discriminate against an employee if such discrimination is due, in whole or in part, to the employee’s lawful, good faith act done, or perceived by the employer to have been done or about to be done—(1) to provide information, directly cause information to be provided, or otherwise directly assist in any investigation regarding any conduct which the employee reasonably believes constitutes a violation of any Federal law, rule, or regulation relating to railroad safety or security, or gross fraud, waste, or abuse of Federal grants or other public funds intended to be used for railroad safety or security, if the information or assistance is provided to or an investigation stemming from the provided information is conducted by—(A) a Federal, State, or local regulatory or law enforcement agency (including an office of the Inspector General under chapter 4 of title 5; 11 So in original. A closing parenthesis probably should precede the semicolon.

(B) any Member of Congress, any committee of Congress, or the Government Accountability Office; or

(C) a person with supervisory authority over the employee or such other person who has the authority to investigate, discover, or terminate the misconduct;


(2) to refuse to violate or assist in the violation of any Federal law, rule, or regulation relating to railroad safety or security;

(3) to file a complaint, or directly cause to be brought a proceeding related to the enforcement of this part or, as applicable to railroad safety or security, chapter 51 or 57 of this title, or to testify in that proceeding;

(4) to notify, or attempt to notify, the railroad carrier or the Secretary of Transportation of a work-related personal injury or work-r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A railroad carrier engaged in interstate or foreign commerce, a contractor or a subcontractor of such a railroad carrier, or an officer or employee of such a railroad carrier, may not discharge, demote, suspend, reprimand, or in any other way discriminate against an employee if such discrimination is due, in whole or in part, to the employee’s lawful, good faith act done, or perceived by the employer to have been done or about to be done—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous Safety or Security Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt Medical Attention.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement Action.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of Remedies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) An employee may not seek protection under both this section and another provision of law for the same allegedly unlawful act of the railroad carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Preemption.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nothing in this section preempts or diminishes any other safeguards against discrimination, demotion, discharge, suspension, threats, harassment, reprimand, retaliation, or any other manner of discrimination provided by Federal or State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights Retained by Employee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Nothing in this section shall be deemed to diminish the rights, privileges, or remedies of any employee under any Federal or State law or under any collective bargaining agreement. The rights and remedies in this section may not be waived by any agreement, policy, form, or condition of employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of Identity.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20109_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Process for Reporting Security Problems to the Department of Homeland Security.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>