<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20108"><akn:num>20108</akn:num><akn:heading>Research, development, testing, and training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20108. Research, development, testing, and training(a) General.—The Secretary of Transportation shall carry out, as necessary, research, development, testing, evaluation, and training for every area of railroad safety.

(b) Contracts.—To carry out this part, the Secretary may make contracts for, and carry out, research, development, testing, evaluation, and training (particularly for those areas of railroad safety found to need prompt attention).

(c) Amounts From Non-Government Sources for Training Safety Employees.—The Secretary may request, receive, and expend amounts received from non-United States Government sources for expenses incurred in training safety employees of private industry, State and local authorities, or other public authorities, except State rail safety inspectors participating in training under section 20105 of this title.

(d) Facilities.—The Secretary may erect, alter, and repair buildings and make other public improvements to carry out necessary railroad research, safety, and training activities at the Transportation Technology Center in Pueblo, Colorado.

(e) Offsetting Collections.—The Secretary may collect fees or rents from facility users to offset appropriated amounts for the cost of providing facilities or research, development, testing, training, or other services, including long-term sustainment of the on-site physical plant.

(f) Revolving Fund.—Amounts appropriated to carry out subsection (d) and all fees and rents collected pursuant to subsection (e) shall be credited to a revolving fund and remain available until expended. The Secretary may use such fees and rents for operation, maintenance, repair, or improvement of the Transportation Technology Center.

(g) Leases and Contracts.—Notwithstanding section 1302 of title 40, the Secretary may lease to others or enter into contracts for terms of up to 20 years, for such consideration and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be in the best interests of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation shall carry out, as necessary, research, development, testing, evaluation, and training for every area of railroad safety.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To carry out this part, the Secretary may make contracts for, and carry out, research, development, testing, evaluation, and training (particularly for those areas of railroad safety found to need prompt attention).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts From Non-Government Sources for Training Safety Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may request, receive, and expend amounts received from non-United States Government sources for expenses incurred in training safety employees of private industry, State and local authorities, or other public authorities, except State rail safety inspectors participating in training under section 20105 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may erect, alter, and repair buildings and make other public improvements to carry out necessary railroad research, safety, and training activities at the Transportation Technology Center in Pueblo, Colorado.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offsetting Collections.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may collect fees or rents from facility users to offset appropriated amounts for the cost of providing facilities or research, development, testing, training, or other services, including long-term sustainment of the on-site physical plant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revolving Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Amounts appropriated to carry out subsection (d) and all fees and rents collected pursuant to subsection (e) shall be credited to a revolving fund and remain available until expended. The Secretary may use such fees and rents for operation, maintenance, repair, or improvement of the Transportation Technology Center.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leases and Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notwithstanding section 1302 of title 40, the Secretary may lease to others or enter into contracts for terms of up to 20 years, for such consideration and subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines to be in the best interests of the Government of the United States, for the operation, maintenance, repair, and improvement of the Transportation Technology Center.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Property and Casualty Loss Insurance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary may allow its lessees and contractors to purchase property and casualty loss insurance for its assets and activities at the Transportation Technology Center to mitigate the lessee’s or contractor’s risk associated with operating a facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Notwithstanding section 1341 of title 31, the Secretary may enter into contracts or agreements, or commit to obligations in connection with third-party contracts or agreements, including contingent liability for the purchase of electric power in connection with such contracts or agreements, for terms not to exceed 20 years, to enable the use of the land at the Transportation Technology Center for projects to produce energy from renewable sources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20108_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rail Research and Development Center of Excellence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>