<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20120" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20120/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20120/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20120"><akn:num>20120</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20120. Enforcement report(a) 11 So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted. In General.—Beginning not later than December 31, 2009, the Secretary of Transportation shall make available to the public and publish on its public Web site an annual report that—(1) provides a summary of railroad safety and hazardous materials compliance inspections and audits that Federal or State inspectors conducted in the prior fiscal year organized by type of alleged violation, including track, motive power and equipment, signal, grade crossing, operating practices, accident and incident reporting, and hazardous materials;

(2) provides a summary of all enforcement actions taken by the Secretary or the Federal Railroad Administration during the prior fiscal year, including—(A) the number of civil penalties assessed;

(B) the initial amount of civil penalties assessed;

(C) the number of civil penalty cases settled;

(D) the final amount of civil penalties assessed;

(E) the difference between the initial and final amounts of civil penalties assessed;

(F) the number of administrative hearings requested and completed related to hazardous materials transportation law violations or enforcement actions against individuals;

(G) the number of cases referred to the Attorney General for civil or criminal prosecution; and

(H) the number and subject matter of all compliance orders, emergency orders, or precursor agreements;


(3) analyzes the effect of the number of inspections conducted and enforcement actions taken on the number and rate of reported accidents and incidents and railroad safety;

(4) provide 22 So in original. Probably should be “provides”. the information required by paragraphs (2) and (3)—(A) for each Class I railroad individually; and

(B) in the aggregate for—(i) Class II railroads;

(ii) Class III railroads;

(iii) hazardous materials shippers; and

(iv) individuals;



(5) identifies the number of locomotive engineer certification denial or revocation cases appea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20120_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted. In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Beginning not later than December 31, 2009, the Secretary of Transportation shall make available to the public and publish on its public Web site an annual report that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>