<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20153" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20153/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20153/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20153"><akn:num>20153</akn:num><akn:heading>Audible warnings at highway-rail grade crossings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20153. Audible warnings at highway-rail grade crossings(a) Definitions.—As used in this section—(1) the term “highway-rail grade crossing” includes any street or highway crossing over a line of railroad at grade;

(2) the term “locomotive horn” refers to a train-borne audible warning device meeting standards specified by the Secretary of Transportation; and

(3) the term “supplementary safety measure” refers to a safety system or procedure, provided by the appropriate traffic control authority or law enforcement authority responsible for safety at the highway-rail grade crossing, that is determined by the Secretary to be an effective substitute for the locomotive horn in the prevention of highway-rail casualties. A traffic control arrangement that prevents careless movement over the crossing (e.g., as where adequate median barriers prevent movement around crossing gates extending over the full width of the lanes in the particular direction of travel), and that conforms to standards prescribed by the Secretary under this subsection, shall be deemed to constitute a supplementary safety measure. The following do not, individually or in combination, constitute supplementary safety measures within the meaning of this subsection: standard traffic control devices or arrangements such as reflectorized crossbucks, stop signs, flashing lights, flashing lights with gates that do not completely block travel over the line of railroad, or traffic signals.


(b) Requirement.—The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations requiring that a locomotive horn shall be sounded while each train is approaching and entering upon each public highway-rail grade crossing.

(c) Exception.—(1) In issuing such regulations, the Secretary may except from the requirement to sound the locomotive horn any categories of rail operations or categories of highway-rail grade crossings (by train speed or other factors specified by regulation)—(A) that the Secretary determines not to present a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations requiring that a locomotive horn shall be sounded while each train is approaching and entering upon each public highway-rail grade crossing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for Waiver or Exemption.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Secretary may not entertain an application for waiver or exemption of the regulations issued under this section unless such application shall have been submitted jointly by the railroad carrier owning, or controlling operations over, the crossing and by the appropriate traffic control authority or law enforcement authority. The Secretary shall not grant any such application unless, in the judgment of the Secretary, the application demonstrates that the safety of highway users will not be diminished.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of Supplementary Safety Measures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specific Rules.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary may, by regulation, provide that the following crossings over railroad lines shall be subject, in whole or in part, to the regulations required under this section: Regulations issued under this subsection shall not apply to any location where persons are not authorized to cross the railroad.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall issue regulations required by this section pertaining to categories of highway-rail grade crossings that in the judgment of the Secretary pose the greatest safety hazard to rail and highway users not later than 24 months following November 2, 1994. The Secretary shall issue regulations pertaining to any other categories of crossings not later than 48 months following November 2, 1994.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact of Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary shall include in regulations prescribed under this section a concise statement of the impact of such regulations with respect to the operation of section 20106 of this title (national uniformity of regulation).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In issuing regulations under this section, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20153_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Date of Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Any regulations under this section shall not take effect before the 365th day following the date of publication of the final rule.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>