<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20168" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20168/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/20168/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20168"><akn:num>20168</akn:num><akn:heading>Installation of audio and image recording devices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20168. Installation of audio and image recording devices(a) In General.—Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2015, the Secretary of Transportation shall promulgate regulations to require each railroad carrier that provides regularly scheduled intercity rail passenger or commuter rail passenger transportation to the public to install inward- and outward-facing image recording devices in all controlling locomotive cabs and cab car operating compartments in such passenger trains.

(b) Device Standards.—Each inward- and outward-facing image recording device shall—(1) have a minimum 12-hour continuous recording capability;

(2) have crash and fire protections for any in-cab image recordings that are stored only within a controlling locomotive cab or cab car operating compartment; and

(3) have recordings accessible for review during an accident or incident investigation.


(c) Review.—The Secretary shall establish a process to review and approve or disapprove an inward- or outward-facing image recording device for compliance with the standards described in subsection (b).

(d) Uses.—A railroad carrier subject to the requirements of subsection (a) that has installed an inward- or outward-facing image recording device approved under subsection (c) may use recordings from that inward- or outward-facing image recording device for the following purposes:(1) Verifying that train crew actions are in accordance with applicable safety laws and the railroad carrier’s operating rules and procedures, including a system-wide program for such verification.

(2) Assisting in an investigation into the causation of a reportable accident or incident.

(3) Documenting a criminal act or monitoring unauthorized occupancy of the controlling locomotive cab or car operating compartment.

(4) Other purposes that the Secretary considers appropriate.


(e) Discretion.—(1) In general.—The Secretary may—(A) require in-cab audio recor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Reform and Investment Act of 2015, the Secretary of Transportation shall promulgate regulations to require each railroad carrier that provides regularly scheduled intercity rail passenger or commuter rail passenger transportation to the public to install inward- and outward-facing image recording devices in all controlling locomotive cabs and cab car operating compartments in such passenger trains.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Device Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Each inward- and outward-facing image recording device shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall establish a process to review and approve or disapprove an inward- or outward-facing image recording device for compliance with the standards described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A railroad carrier subject to the requirements of subsection (a) that has installed an inward- or outward-facing image recording device approved under subsection (c) may use recordings from that inward- or outward-facing image recording device for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tampering.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of Data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Each railroad carrier subject to the requirements of subsection (a) shall preserve recording device data for 1 year after the date of a reportable accident or incident.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Protections.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary may not disclose publicly any part of an in-cab audio or image recording or transcript of oral communications by or among train employees or other operating employees responsible for the movement and direction of the train, or between such operating employees and company communication centers, related to an accident or incident investigated by the Secretary. The Secretary may make public any part of a transcript or any written depiction of visual information that the Secretary determines is relevant to the accident at the time a majority of the other factual reports on the accident or incident are released to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) An in-cab audio or image recording obtained by a railroad carrier under this section may not be used to retaliate against an employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20168_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings Clause.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Nothing in this section may be construed as requiring a railroad carrier to cease or restrict operations upon a technical failure of an inward- or outward-facing image recording device or in-cab audio device. Such railroad carrier shall repair or replace the failed inward- or outward-facing image recording device as soon as practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>