<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/21301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/21301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/21301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21301"><akn:num>21301</akn:num><akn:heading>Chapter 201 general violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21301. Chapter 201 general violations(a) Penalty.—(1) A person may not fail to comply with section 20160 or with a regulation prescribed or order issued by the Secretary of Transportation under chapter 201 of this title. Subject to section 21304 of this title, a person violating section 20160 of this title or a regulation prescribed or order issued by the Secretary under chapter 201 is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty. The Secretary shall impose the penalty applicable under paragraph (2) of this subsection. A separate violation occurs for each day the violation continues.

(2) The Secretary shall include in, or make applicable to, each regulation prescribed and order issued under chapter 201 of this title a civil penalty for a violation. The Secretary shall impose a civil penalty for a violation of section 20160 of this title. The amount of the penalty shall be at least $500 but not more than $25,000. However, when a grossly negligent violation or a pattern of repeated violations has caused an imminent hazard of death or injury to individuals, or has caused death or injury, the amount may be not more than $100,000.

(3) The Secretary may find that a person has violated this chapter or a regulation prescribed or order, special permit, or approval issued under this chapter only after notice and an opportunity for a hearing. The Secretary shall impose a penalty under this section by giving the person written notice of the amount of the penalty. The Secretary may compromise the amount of a civil penalty by settlement agreement without issuance of an order. In determining the amount of a compromise, the Secretary shall consider—(A) the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation;

(B) with respect to the violator, the degree of culpability, any history of violations, the ability to pay, and any effect on the ability to continue to do business; and

(C) other matters that justice requires.


(4) The Attorney General may bring a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21301_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21301_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Setoff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Government may deduct the amount of a civil penalty imposed or compromised under this section from amounts it owes the person liable for the penalty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21301_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit in Treasury.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A civil penalty collected under this section or section 20113(b) of this title shall be deposited in the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>