<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_22106"><akn:num>22106</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 22106. Limitations on financial assistance(a) Grants and Loans.—A State shall use financial assistance for projects under this chapter to make a grant or lend money to the owner of rail property, or a rail carrier providing rail transportation, related to a project being assisted.

(b) State Use of Repaid Funds and Contingent Interest Recoveries.—The State shall place the United States Government’s share of money that is repaid and any contingent interest that is recovered in an interest-bearing account. The repaid money, contingent interest, and any interest thereon shall be considered to be State funds. The State shall use such funds to make other grants and loans, consistent with the purposes for which financial assistance may be used under subsection (a), as the State considers to be appropriate.

(c) Encouraging Participation.—To the maximum extent possible, the State shall encourage the participation of shippers, rail carriers, and local communities in paying the State share of assistance costs.

(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 897; Pub. L. 104–287, § 5(55), Oct. 11, 1996, 110 Stat. 3393; Pub. L. 110–432, div. A, title VII, § 701(a), Oct. 16, 2008, 122 Stat. 4905; Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title XI, § 11316(k), Dec. 4, 2015, 129 Stat. 1678.)











Historical and Revision Notes



Pub. L. 103–272


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


22106(a)49 App.:1654(d)(1), (2).Oct. 15, 1966, Pub. L. 89–670, 80 Stat. 931, § 5(d), (i); added Feb. 5, 1976, Pub. L. 94–210, § 803, 90 Stat. 130; Nov. 8, 1978, Pub. L. 95–607, §§ 102–106(a), 107– 109(a), 92 Stat. 3059, 3062; Oct. 12, 1979, Pub. L. 96–86, § 115(b), 93 Stat. 662; Aug. 13, 1981, Pub. L. 97–35, §§ 1191, 1192, 95 Stat. 699; Jan. 14, 1983, Pub. L. 97–468, § 501, 96 Stat. 2551; Apr. 7, 1986, Pub. L. 99–272, § 4018, 100 Stat. 111; restated Dec. 11, 1989, Pub. L. 101–213, § 2(a), (c), 103 Stat. 1843, 1845, 1847.
22106(b)49 App.:1654(d)(3) (1st, 2d sentences).
22106(c)49 App.:</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and Loans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A State shall use financial assistance for projects under this chapter to make a grant or lend money to the owner of rail property, or a rail carrier providing rail transportation, related to a project being assisted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State Use of Repaid Funds and Contingent Interest Recoveries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The State shall place the United States Government’s share of money that is repaid and any contingent interest that is recovered in an interest-bearing account. The repaid money, contingent interest, and any interest thereon shall be considered to be State funds. The State shall use such funds to make other grants and loans, consistent with the purposes for which financial assistance may be used under subsection (a), as the State considers to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Encouraging Participation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To the maximum extent possible, the State shall encourage the participation of shippers, rail carriers, and local communities in paying the State share of assistance costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>