<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22403" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22403/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22403/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_22403"><akn:num>22403</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of direct loans and loan guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 22403. Administration of direct loans and loan guarantees(a) Applications.—(1) In general.—The Secretary shall prescribe the form and contents required of applications for assistance under section 22402, to enable the Secretary to determine the eligibility of the applicant’s proposal, and shall establish terms and conditions for direct loans and loan guarantees made under that section, including a program guide, a standard term sheet, and specific timetables.

(2) Documentation.—An applicant meeting the size standard for small business concerns established under section 3(a)(2) of the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. 632(a)(2)) may provide unaudited financial statements as documentation of historical financial information if such statements are accompanied by the applicant’s Federal tax returns and Internal Revenue Service tax verifications for the corresponding years.


(b) Full Faith and Credit.—All guarantees entered into by the Secretary under section 22402 shall constitute general obligations of the United States of America backed by the full faith and credit of the United States of America.

(c) Assignment of Loan Guarantees.—The holder of a loan guarantee made under section 22402 may assign the loan guarantee in whole or in part, subject to such requirements as the Secretary may prescribe.

(d) Modifications.—The Secretary may approve the modification of any term or condition of a direct loan, loan guarantee, direct loan obligation, or loan guarantee commitment, including the rate of interest, time of payment of interest or principal, or security requirements, if the Secretary finds in writing that—(1) the modification is equitable and is in the overall best interests of the United States;

(2) consent has been obtained from the applicant and, in the case of a loan guarantee or loan guarantee commitment, the holder of the obligation; and

(3) the modification cost has been covered under section 22402(f).


(e) Compliance.—The Secretary shall assure compliance,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Full Faith and Credit.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) All guarantees entered into by the Secretary under section 22402 shall constitute general obligations of the United States of America backed by the full faith and credit of the United States of America.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of Loan Guarantees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The holder of a loan guarantee made under section 22402 may assign the loan guarantee in whole or in part, subject to such requirements as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modifications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may approve the modification of any term or condition of a direct loan, loan guarantee, direct loan obligation, or loan guarantee commitment, including the rate of interest, time of payment of interest or principal, or security requirements, if the Secretary finds in writing that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall assure compliance, by an applicant, any other party to the loan, and any railroad or railroad partner for whose benefit assistance is intended, with the provisions of this chapter, regulations issued hereunder, and the terms and conditions of the direct loan or loan guarantee, including through regular periodic inspections.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial Validity.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) For purposes of claims by any party other than the Secretary, a loan guarantee or loan guarantee commitment shall be conclusive evidence that the underlying obligation is in compliance with the provisions of this chapter, and that such obligation has been approved and is legal as to principal, interest, and other terms. Such a guarantee or commitment shall be valid and incontestable in the hands of a holder thereof, including the original lender or any other holder, as of the date when the Secretary granted the application therefor, except as to fraud or material misrepresentation by such holder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Default.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations setting forth procedures in the event of default on a loan made or guaranteed under section 22402. The Secretary shall ensure that each loan guarantee made under that section contains terms and conditions that provide that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of the Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action Against Obligor.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary may bring a civil action in an appropriate Federal court in the name of the United States in the event of a default on a direct loan made under section 22402, or in the name of the United States or of the holder of the obligation in the event of a default on a loan guaranteed under section 22402. The holder of a guarantee shall make available to the Secretary all records and evidence necessary to prosecute the civil action. The Secretary may accept property in full or partial satisfaction of any sums owed as a result of a default. If the Secretary receives, through the sale or other disposition of such property, an amount greater than the aggregate of— the Secretary shall pay such excess to the obligor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22403_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Breach of Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Attorney General shall commence a civil action in an appropriate Federal court to enjoin any activity which the Secretary finds is in violation of this chapter, regulations issued hereunder, or any conditions which were duly agreed to, and to secure any other appropriate relief.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>