<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_22402"><akn:num>22402</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct loans and loan guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 22402. Direct loans and loan guarantees(a) General Authority.—The Secretary shall provide direct loans and loan guarantees to—(1) State and local governments;

(2) entities implementing interstate compacts consented to by Congress under section 410(a) of the Amtrak Reform and Accountability Act of 1997 (49 U.S.C. 24101 note);

(3) government sponsored authorities and corporations;

(4) railroads;

(5) entities participating in joint ventures that include at least 1 of the entities described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), or (6);

(6) limited option freight shippers that own or operate a plant or other facility, solely for the purpose of constructing a rail connection between a plant or facility and a railroad; and

(7) private entities with controlling ownership in 1 or more freight railroads other than Class I carriers.


(b) Eligible Purposes.—(1) In general.—Direct loans and loan guarantees authorized under this section shall be used—(A) to acquire, improve, or rehabilitate intermodal or rail equipment or facilities, including track, components of track, cuts and fills, stations, tunnels, bridges, yards, buildings, and shops, and to finance costs related to those activities, including pre-construction costs;

(B) to develop or establish new intermodal or railroad facilities;

(C) to develop landside port infrastructure for seaports serviced by rail;

(D) to refinance outstanding debt incurred for the purposes described in subparagraph (A) , (B), or (C);

(E) to reimburse planning, permitting, and design expenses relating to activities described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C); or

(F) to finance economic development, including commercial and residential development, and related infrastructure and activities, that—(i) incorporates private investment of greater than 20 percent of total project costs;

(ii) is physically connected to, or is within ½ mile of, a fixed guideway transit station, an intercity bus station, a passenger rail station, or a multimodal st</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall provide direct loans and loan guarantees to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In granting applications for direct loans or guaranteed loans under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to projects that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extent of Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The aggregate unpaid principal amounts of obligations under direct loans and loan guarantees made under this section shall not exceed $35,000,000,000 at any one time. Of this amount, not less than $7,000,000,000 shall be available solely for projects primarily benefiting freight railroads other than Class I carriers. The Secretary shall not establish any limit on the proportion of the unused amount authorized under this subsection that may be used for 1 loan or loan guarantee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates of Interest.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Infrastructure Partners.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisites for Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall not make a direct loan or loan guarantee under this section unless the Secretary has made a finding in writing that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application Processing Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22402_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment Schedules.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>