<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_22401"><akn:num>22401</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 22401. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Cost.—(A) The term “cost” means the estimated long-term cost to the Government of a direct loan or loan guarantee or modification thereof, calculated on a net present value basis, excluding administrative costs and any incidental effects on governmental receipts or outlays.

(B) The cost of a direct loan shall be the net present value, at the time when the direct loan is disbursed, of the following estimated cash flows:(i) Loan disbursements.

(ii) Repayments of principal.

(iii) Payments of interest and other payments by or to the Government over the life of the loan after adjusting for estimated defaults, prepayments, fees, penalties, and other recoveries.


Calculation of the cost of a direct loan shall include the effects of changes in loan terms resulting from the exercise by the borrower of an option included in the loan contract.

(C) The cost of a loan guarantee shall be the net present value, at the time when the guaranteed loan is disbursed, of the following estimated cash flows:(i) Payments by the Government to cover defaults and delinquencies, interest subsidies, or other payments.

(ii) Payments to the Government, including origination and other fees, penalties, and recoveries.


Calculation of the cost of a loan guarantee shall include the effects of changes in loan terms resulting from the exercise by the guaranteed lender of an option included in the loan guarantee contract, or by the borrower of an option included in the guaranteed loan contract.

(D) The cost of a modification is the difference between the current estimate of the net present value of the remaining cash flows under the terms of a direct loan or loan guarantee contract, and the current estimate of the net present value of the remaining cash flows under the terms of the contract, as modified.

(E) In estimating net present values, the discount rate shall be the average interest rate on marketable Treasury securities of similar maturity to the c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Current.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “current” has the same meaning as in section 250(c)(9) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct loan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “direct loan” means a disbursement of funds by the Government to a non-Federal borrower under a contract that requires the repayment of such funds. The term includes the purchase of, or participation in, a loan made by another lender and financing arrangements that defer payment for more than 90 days, including the sale of a Government asset on credit terms. The term does not include the acquisition of a federally guaranteed loan in satisfaction of default claims.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct loan obligation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “direct loan obligation” means a binding agreement by the Secretary to make a direct loan when specified conditions are fulfilled by the borrower.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intermodal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “intermodal” means of or relating to the connection between rail service and other modes of transportation, including all parts of facilities at which such connection is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment-grade rating.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “investment-grade rating” means a rating of BBB minus, Baa 3, bbb minus, BBB(low), or higher assigned by a rating agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan guarantee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “loan guarantee” means any guarantee, insurance, or other pledge with respect to the payment of all or a part of the principal or interest on any debt obligation of a non-Federal borrower to a non-Federal lender, but does not include the insurance of deposits, shares, or other withdrawable accounts in financial institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan guarantee commitment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “loan guarantee commitment” means a binding agreement by the Secretary to make a loan guarantee when specified conditions are fulfilled by the borrower, the lender, or any other party to the guarantee agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Master credit agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “master credit agreement” means an agreement to make 1 or more direct loans or loan guarantees at future dates for a program of related projects on terms acceptable to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22401_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “modification” means any Government action that alters the estimated cost of an outstanding direct loan (or direct loan obligation) or an outstanding loan guarantee (or loan guarantee commitment) from the current estimate of cash flows. This includes the sale of loan assets, with or without recourse, and the purchase of guaranteed loans. This also includes any action resulting from new legislation, or from the exercise of administrative discretion under existing law, that directly or indirectly alters the estimated cost of outstanding direct loans (or direct loan obligations) or loan guarantees (or loan guarantee commitments) such as a change in collection procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>