<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_22907"><akn:num>22907</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidated rail infrastructure and safety improvements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 22907. Consolidated rail infrastructure and safety improvements(a) General Authority.—The Secretary may make grants under this section to an eligible recipient to assist in financing the cost of improving passenger and freight rail transportation systems in terms of safety, efficiency, or reliability.

(b) Eligible Recipients.—The following entities are eligible to receive a grant under this section:(1) A State (including the District of Columbia).

(2) A group of States.

(3) An Interstate Compact.

(4) A public agency or publicly chartered authority established by 1 or more States.

(5) A political subdivision of a State.

(6) Amtrak or another rail carrier that provides intercity rail passenger transportation (as rail carrier and intercity rail passenger transportation are defined in section 24102).

(7) A Class II railroad or Class III railroad (as those terms are defined in section 20102).

(8) An association representing 1 or more railroads described in paragraph (7).

(9) A federally recognized Indian Tribe.

(10) Any rail carrier or rail equipment manufacturer in partnership with at least 1 of the entities described in paragraphs (1) through (5).

(11) The Transportation Research Board and any entity with which it contracts in the development of rail-related research, including cooperative research programs.

(12) A University transportation center engaged in rail-related research.

(13) A non-profit labor organization representing a class or craft of employees of rail carriers or rail carrier contractors.


(c) Eligible Projects.—The following projects are eligible to receive grants under this section:(1) Deployment of railroad safety technology, including positive train control and rail integrity inspection systems.

(2) A capital project as defined in section 22901(2), except that a project shall not be required to be in a State rail plan developed under chapter 227.

(3) A capital project identified by the Secretary as being necessary to address conges</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary may make grants under this section to an eligible recipient to assist in financing the cost of improving passenger and freight rail transportation systems in terms of safety, efficiency, or reliability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Recipients.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The following entities are eligible to receive a grant under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The following projects are eligible to receive grants under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall prescribe the form and manner of filing an application under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Selection Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance Measures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall establish performance measures for each grant recipient to assess progress in achieving strategic goals and objectives. The Secretary may require a grant recipient to periodically report information related to such performance measures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural Areas.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share of Total Project Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Except as specifically provided in this section, the use of any amounts appropriated for grants under this section shall be subject to the requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22907_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Amounts appropriated for carrying out this section shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>