<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_22903"><akn:num>22903</akn:num><akn:heading>Project management oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 22903. Project management oversight(a) Project Management Plan Requirements.—To receive Federal financial assistance for a major capital project under this chapter, an applicant must prepare and carry out a project management plan approved by the Secretary of Transportation. The plan shall provide for—(1) adequate recipient staff organization with well-defined reporting relationships, statements of functional responsibilities, job descriptions, and job qualifications;

(2) a budget covering the project management organization, appropriate consultants, property acquisition, utility relocation, systems demonstration staff, audits, and miscellaneous payments the recipient may be prepared to justify;

(3) a construction schedule for the project;

(4) a document control procedure and recordkeeping system;

(5) a change order procedure that includes a documented, systematic approach to handling the construction change orders;

(6) organizational structures, management skills, and staffing levels required throughout the construction phase;

(7) quality control and quality assurance functions, procedures, and responsibilities for construction, system installation, and integration of system components;

(8) material testing policies and procedures;

(9) internal plan implementation and reporting requirements;

(10) criteria and procedures to be used for testing the operational system or its major components;

(11) periodic updates of the plan, especially related to project budget and project schedule, financing, and ridership estimates; and

(12) the recipient’s commitment to submit periodically a project budget and project schedule to the Secretary.


[(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title XI, § 11316(p), Dec. 4, 2015, 129 Stat. 1679]

(c) Access to Sites and Records.—Each recipient of assistance under this chapter shall provide the Secretary and a contractor the Secretary chooses under subsection (b) of this section with access to the construction sites and records</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Management Plan Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To receive Federal financial assistance for a major capital project under this chapter, an applicant must prepare and carry out a project management plan approved by the Secretary of Transportation. The plan shall provide for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 114–94, div. A, title XI, § 11316(p), Dec. 4, 2015, 129 Stat. 1679]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to Sites and Records.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each recipient of assistance under this chapter shall provide the Secretary and a contractor the Secretary chooses under subsection (b) of this section with access to the construction sites and records of the recipient when reasonably necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>