<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22909" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22909/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/22909/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_22909"><akn:num>22909</akn:num><akn:heading>Railroad Crossing Elimination Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 22909. Railroad Crossing Elimination Program(a) In General.—The Secretary of Transportation, in cooperation with the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration, shall establish a competitive grant program (referred to in this section as the “Program”) under which the Secretary shall award grants to eligible recipients described in subsection (c) for highway-rail or pathway-rail grade crossing improvement projects that focus on improving the safety and mobility of people and goods.

(b) Goals.—The goals of the Program are—(1) to eliminate highway-rail grade crossings that are frequently blocked by trains;

(2) to improve the health and safety of communities;

(3) to reduce the impacts that freight movement and railroad operations may have on underserved communities; and

(4) to improve the mobility of people and goods.


(c) Eligible Recipients.—The following entities are eligible to receive a grant under this section:(1) A State, including the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and other United States territories and possessions.

(2) A political subdivision of a State.

(3) A federally recognized Indian Tribe.

(4) A unit of local government or a group of local governments.

(5) A public port authority.

(6) A metropolitan planning organization.

(7) A group of entities described in any of paragraphs (1) through (6).


(d) Eligible Projects.—The Secretary may award a grant under the Program for a highway-rail or pathway-rail grade crossing improvement project (including acquiring real property interests) involving—(1) grade separation or closure, including through the use of a bridge, embankment, tunnel, or combination thereof;

(2) track relocation;

(3) the improvement or installation of protective devices, signals, signs, or other measures to improve safety, provided that such activities are related to a separation or relocation project described in paragraph (1) or (2);

(4) other means to improve the safety and mobility of people and goods at highw</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation, in cooperation with the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration, shall establish a competitive grant program (referred to in this section as the “Program”) under which the Secretary shall award grants to eligible recipients described in subsection (c) for highway-rail or pathway-rail grade crossing improvement projects that focus on improving the safety and mobility of people and goods.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The goals of the Program are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Recipients.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The following entities are eligible to receive a grant under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may award a grant under the Program for a highway-rail or pathway-rail grade crossing improvement project (including acquiring real property interests) involving—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Selection Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Except as provided in paragraph (2),11 So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted. the Federal share of the cost of a project carried out using a grant under the Program may not exceed 80 percent of the total cost of the project. Applicants may count costs incurred for preliminary engineering associated with highway-rail and pathway-rail grade crossing improvement projects as part of the total project costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Not later than 3 days before awarding a grant for a project under the Program, the Secretary shall submit written notification of the proposed grant to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Not later than 60 days after each round of award notifications, the Secretary shall post, on the public website of the Department of Transportation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_22909_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commuter Rail Eligibility and Grant Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>