<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_24305"><akn:num>24305</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 24305. General authority(a) Acquisition and Operation of Equipment and Facilities.—(1) Amtrak may acquire, operate, maintain, and make contracts for the operation and maintenance of equipment and facilities necessary for intercity and commuter rail passenger transportation, the transportation of mail and express, and auto-ferry transportation.

(2) Amtrak shall operate and control directly, to the extent practicable, all aspects of the rail passenger transportation it provides.

(3)(A) Except as provided in subsection (d)(2), Amtrak may enter into a contract with a motor carrier of passengers for the intercity transportation of passengers by motor carrier over regular routes only—(i) if the motor carrier is not a public recipient of governmental assistance, as such term is defined in section 13902(b)(8)(A) of this title, other than a recipient of funds under section 5311 of this title;

(ii) for passengers who have had prior movement by rail or will have subsequent movement by rail; and

(iii) if the buses, when used in the provision of such transportation, are used exclusively for the transportation of passengers described in clause (ii).


(B) Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to transportation funded predominantly by a State or local government, or to ticket selling agreements.



(b) Maintenance and Rehabilitation.—Amtrak may maintain and rehabilitate rail passenger equipment and shall maintain a regional maintenance plan that includes—(1) a review panel at the principal office of Amtrak consisting of members the President of Amtrak designates;

(2) a systemwide inventory of spare equipment parts in each operational region;

(3) enough maintenance employees for cars and locomotives in each region;

(4) a systematic preventive maintenance program;

(5) periodic evaluations of maintenance costs, time lags, and parts shortages and corrective actions; and

(6) other elements or activities Amtrak considers appropriate.


(c) Miscellaneous Authority.—Amtrak may—(1) m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition and Operation of Equipment and Facilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance and Rehabilitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amtrak may maintain and rehabilitate rail passenger equipment and shall maintain a regional maintenance plan that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amtrak may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24305_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Through Routes and Joint Fares.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24305_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rail Police.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amtrak may directly employ or contract with rail police to provide security for rail passengers and property of Amtrak. Rail police directly employed by or contracted by Amtrak who have complied with a State law establishing requirements applicable to rail police or individuals employed in a similar position may be directly employed or contracted without regard to the law of another State containing those requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24305_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic Buying Preferences.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>