<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24319" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24319/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24319/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_24319"><akn:num>24319</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant process and reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 24319. Grant process and reporting(a) Procedures for Grant Requests.—The Secretary of Transportation shall—(1) establish and maintain substantive and procedural requirements, including schedules, for grant requests under this section; and

(2) report any changes to such procedures to—(A) the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;

(B) the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;

(C) the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives; and

(D) the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.



(b) Grant Requests.—Amtrak shall transmit to the Secretary a grant request annually, or as additionally required, for Federal funds appropriated to the Secretary of Transportation for the use of Amtrak.

(c) Contents.—(1) In general.—Each grant request under subsection (b) shall, as applicable—(A) categorize and identify, by source, the Federal funds and program income that will be used for the upcoming fiscal year for each of the Northeast Corridor and National Network in 1 of the categories or subcategories set forth in paragraph (2);

(B) describe the operations, services, programs, projects, and other activities to be funded within each of the categories set forth in paragraph (2), including—(i) the estimated scope, schedule, and budget necessary to complete each project and program; and

(ii) the performance measures used to quantify expected and actual project outcomes and benefits, aggregated by fiscal year, project milestone, and any other appropriate grouping; and


(C) describe the status of efforts to improve Amtrak’s safety culture.


(2) Grant categories.—(A) Operating expenses.—Each grant request to use Federal funds for operating expenses shall—(i) include estimated net operating costs not covered by other Amtrak revenue sources;

(ii) specify Federal funding requested for each service line described in section 24320(b)(1); and

(iii) be itemized by route.


(B) Debt service.—A grant</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for Grant Requests.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Requests.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amtrak shall transmit to the Secretary a grant request annually, or as additionally required, for Federal funds appropriated to the Secretary of Transportation for the use of Amtrak.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and Approval.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to Amtrak.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Amounts and Early Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Amounts appropriated to the Secretary for the use of Amtrak shall remain available until expended. Amounts for capital acquisitions and improvements may be appropriated for a fiscal year before the fiscal year in which the amounts will be obligated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Amounts appropriated to the Secretary for the use of Amtrak may not be used to cross-subsidize operating losses or capital costs of commuter rail passenger or freight rail transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable Laws and Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amtrak Grant Reporting.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary of Transportation shall determine the varying levels of detail and information that will be included in reports for operations, services, program, projects, program income, cash on hand, and other activities within each of the grant categories described in subsection (c)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24319_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of Northeast Corridor.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Notwithstanding section 24102, for purposes of this section, the term “Northeast Corridor” means the Northeast Corridor main line between Boston, Massachusetts, and the District of Columbia, and facilities and services used to operate and maintain that line.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>