<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24320" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24320/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24320/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_24320"><akn:num>24320</akn:num><akn:heading>Amtrak 5-year service line and asset line plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 24320. Amtrak 5-year service line and asset line plans(a) In General.—(1) Final plans.—Not later than February 15, 2020, and biennially thereafter, Amtrak shall submit to Congress and the Secretary of Transportation final 5-year service line plans and 5-year asset line plans prepared in accordance with this section. These final plans shall form the basis for Amtrak’s general and legislative annual report to the President and Congress required by section 24315(b). Each plan shall cover a period of 5 fiscal years, beginning with the first fiscal year after the date on which the plan is completed. During each year in which Amtrak is not required to submit a plan under this paragraph, Amtrak shall submit to Congress updated financial sources and uses statements and forecasts with the annual report required under section 24315(b).

(2) Fiscal constraint.—Each plan prepared under this section shall be based on funding levels authorized or otherwise available to Amtrak in a fiscal year. In the absence of an authorization or appropriation of funds for a fiscal year, the plans shall be based on the amount of funding available in the previous fiscal year, plus inflation. Amtrak may include an appendix to the asset line plan required under subsection (c) that describes any funding needs in excess of amounts authorized or otherwise available to Amtrak in a fiscal year.


(b) Amtrak 5-Year Service Line Plans.—(1) Amtrak service lines.—Amtrak shall prepare a 5-year service line plan for each of the following service lines and services:(A) Northeast Corridor train services.

(B) Amtrak State-supported train services.

(C) Long-distance train services operated by Amtrak.

(D) Ancillary services operated by Amtrak, including commuter operations and other revenue generating activities as determined by the Secretary in coordination with Amtrak.

(E) Infrastructure access services for use of Amtrak-owned or Amtrak-controlled infrastructure and facilities.


(2) Contents of 5-year ser</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24320_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24320_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amtrak 5-Year Service Line Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24320_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amtrak 5-Year Asset Line Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24320_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards to Promote Financial Stability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In preparing plans under this section, Amtrak shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>