<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24712" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24712/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24712/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_24712"><akn:num>24712</akn:num><akn:heading>State-supported routes operated by Amtrak</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 24712. State-supported routes operated by Amtrak(a) State-Supported Route Committee.—(1) Establishment.—There is established the State-Supported Route Committee (referred to in this section as the “Committee”) to promote mutual cooperation and planning pertaining to the current and future rail operations of Amtrak and related activities of trains operated by Amtrak on State-supported routes and to further implement section 209 of the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008 (49 U.S.C. 24101 note).

(2) Membership.—(A) In general.—The Committee shall consist of—(i) members representing Amtrak;

(ii) members representing the Department of Transportation, including the Federal Railroad Administration; and

(iii) members representing States.


(B) Non-voting members.—The Committee may invite and accept other non-voting members to participate in Committee activities, as appropriate.


(3) Decisionmaking.—The Committee shall establish a bloc voting system under which, at a minimum—(A) there are 3 separate voting blocs to represent the Committee’s voting members, including—(i) 1 voting bloc to represent the members described in paragraph (2)(A)(i);

(ii) 1 voting bloc to represent the members described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii); and

(iii) 1 voting bloc to represent the members described in paragraph (2)(A)(iii);


(B) each voting bloc has 1 vote;

(C) the vote of the voting bloc representing the members described in paragraph (2)(A)(iii) requires the support of at least two-thirds of that voting bloc’s members; and

(D) the Committee makes decisions by unanimous consent of the 3 voting blocs.


(4) Ability to conduct certain business.—If all of the members of 1 voting bloc described in paragraph (3) abstain from a Committee decision, agreement between the other 2 voting blocs consistent with the procedures set forth in such paragraph shall be deemed sufficient for purpose of achieving unanimous consent.

(5) Meetings; rules and procedures.—The Committee shall</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State-Supported Route Committee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Invoices and Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute Resolution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance Metrics.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In negotiating a contract for operation of a State-supported route, Amtrak and the State or States that sponsor the route shall consider including provisions that provide penalties and incentives for performance, including incentives to increase revenue, reduce costs, finalize contracts by the beginning of the fiscal year, and require States to promptly make payments for services delivered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of Goals and Objectives.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>New State-supported Routes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost Methodology Policy Update Implementation Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Not later than 18 months after the updated cost methodology policy required under subsection (a)(7)(B) is implemented, the Committee shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that assesses the implementation of the updated policy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of State-supported Route Changes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Amtrak shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24712_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic Analysis.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Expansion and Rail Safety Act of 2021, the Committee shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>