<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_24905"><akn:num>24905</akn:num><akn:heading>Northeast Corridor Commission; Safety Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 24905. Northeast Corridor Commission; Safety Committee(a) Northeast Corridor Commission.—(1) Within 180 days after the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Investment and Improvement Act of 2008, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish a Northeast Corridor Commission (referred to in this section as the “Commission”) to promote mutual cooperation and planning pertaining to the rail operations, infrastructure investments, and related activities of the Northeast Corridor. The Commission shall be made up of—(A) members representing Amtrak;

(B) members representing the Department of Transportation, including the Office of the Secretary, the Federal Railroad Administration, and the Federal Transit Administration;

(C) 1 member from each of the States (including the District of Columbia) that constitute the Northeast Corridor as defined in section 24102, designated by, and serving at the pleasure of, the chief executive officer thereof; and

(D) non-voting representatives of freight and commuter railroad carriers authorities using the Northeast Corridor selected by the Secretary.


(2) The Secretary shall ensure that the membership belonging to any of the groups enumerated under paragraph (1) shall not constitute a majority of the Commission’s memberships.

(3) The Commission shall establish a schedule and location for convening meetings, but shall meet no less than four times per fiscal year, and the Commission shall develop rules and procedures to govern the Commission’s proceedings.

(4) A vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.

(5) Members shall serve without pay but shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with sections 5702 and 5703 of title 5.

(6) The members of the Commission shall elect co-chairs consisting of 1 member described in paragraph (1)(B) and 1 member described in paragraph (1)(C).

(7) The Commission may appoint and fix the pay of s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Northeast Corridor Commission.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of Goals and Recommendations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for the use of the Commission and the Northeast Corridor Safety Committee such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section during fiscal years 2022 through 2026, in addition to any amounts withheld under section 22101(e) of the Passenger Rail Expansion and Rail Safety Act of 2021.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Northeast Corridor Safety Committee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>