<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24911" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24911/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/24911/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_24911"><akn:num>24911</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal-State partnership for intercity passenger rail</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 24911. Federal-State partnership for intercity passenger rail(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Applicant.—The term “applicant” means—(A) a State (including the District of Columbia);

(B) a group of States;

(C) an Interstate Compact;

(D) a public agency or publicly chartered authority established by 1 or more States;

(E) a political subdivision of a State;

(F) Amtrak, acting on its own behalf or under a cooperative agreement with 1 or more States;

(G) a federally recognized Indian Tribe; or

(H) any combination of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (G).


(2) Intercity rail passenger transportation.—The term “intercity rail passenger transportation” has the meaning given the term in section 24102.

(3) Northeast corridor.—The term “Northeast Corridor” means—(A) the main rail line between Boston, Massachusetts and the District of Columbia;

(B) the branch rail lines connecting to Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, Springfield, Massachusetts, and Spuyten Duyvil, New York; and

(C) facilities and services used to operate and maintain lines described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).



(b) Grant Program Authorized.—The Secretary of Transportation shall develop and implement a program for issuing grants to applicants, on a competitive basis, to fund capital projects that reduce the state of good repair backlog, improve performance, or expand or establish new intercity passenger rail service, including privately operated intercity passenger rail service if an eligible applicant is involved;.11 So in original. The semicolon preceding the period probably should not appear.

(c) Eligible Projects.—The following capital projects, including acquisition of real property interests, are eligible to receive grants under this section:(1) A project to replace, rehabilitate, or repair infrastructure, equipment, or a facility used for providing intercity passenger rail service to bring such assets into a state of good repair.

(2) A project to improve intercity passenge</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Program Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Transportation shall develop and implement a program for issuing grants to applicants, on a competitive basis, to fund capital projects that reduce the state of good repair backlog, improve performance, or expand or establish new intercity passenger rail service, including privately operated intercity passenger rail service if an eligible applicant is involved;.11 So in original. The semicolon preceding the period probably should not appear.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The following capital projects, including acquisition of real property interests, are eligible to receive grants under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Selection Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In selecting a project for funding under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Long-term Planning.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Expansion and Rail Safety Act of 2021, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall create a predictable project pipeline that will assist Amtrak, States, and the public with long-term capital planning by publishing a Northeast Corridor project inventory that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share of Total Project Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Letters of Intent; Phased Funding Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Amounts appropriated for carrying out this section shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Except as specifically provided in this section, the use of any amounts appropriated for grants under this section shall be subject to the grant conditions under sections 22903 and 22905.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_24911_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report on Phased Funding Agreements and Letters of Intent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Not later than the first Monday in February of each year, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>