<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/25101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/25101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/25101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_25101"><akn:num>25101</akn:num><akn:heading>Corridor Identification and Development Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 25101. Corridor Identification and Development Program(a) In General.—Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Expansion and Rail Safety Act of 2021, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish a program to facilitate the development of intercity passenger rail corridors. The program shall include—(1) a process for eligible entities described in subsection (b) to submit proposals for the development of intercity passenger rail corridors;

(2) a process for the Secretary to review and select proposals in accordance with subsection (c);

(3) criteria for determining the level of readiness for Federal financial assistance of an intercity passenger rail corridor, which shall include—(A) identification of a service operator which may include Amtrak or private rail carriers;

(B) identification of a service sponsor or sponsors;

(C) identification capital project sponsors;

(D) engagement with the host railroads; and

(E) other criteria as determined appropriate by the Secretary;


(4) a process for preparing service development plans in accordance with subsection (d), including the identification of planning funds, such as funds made available under section 24911(k) and interstate rail compact grants established under section 22210; 11 So in original. Probably should be “section 22910;”.

(5) the creation of a pipeline of intercity passenger rail corridor projects under subsection (g);

(6) planning guidance to achieve the purposes of this section, including guidance for intercity passenger rail corridors not selected under this section; and

(7) such other features as the Secretary considers relevant to the successful development of intercity passenger rail corridors.


(b) Eligible Entities.—The Secretary may receive proposals under this section from Amtrak, States, groups of States, entities implementing interstate compacts, regional passenger rail authorities, regional planning organizations, political subdivisions of a State, f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the Passenger Rail Expansion and Rail Safety Act of 2021, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish a program to facilitate the development of intercity passenger rail corridors. The program shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may receive proposals under this section from Amtrak, States, groups of States, entities implementing interstate compacts, regional passenger rail authorities, regional planning organizations, political subdivisions of a State, federally recognized Indian Tribes, and other public entities, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corridor Selection.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In selecting intercity passenger rail corridors pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25101_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service Development Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For each corridor proposal selected for development under this section, the Secretary shall partner with the entity that submitted the proposal, relevant States, and Amtrak, as appropriate, to prepare a service development plan (or to update an existing service development plan), which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25101_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In partnering on the preparation of a service development plan under subsection (d), the Secretary shall consult with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25101_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Every 5 years, after the initial development of the service development plan under subsection (d), if at least 40 percent of the work to implement a service development plan prepared under subsection (d) has not yet been completed, the plan’s sponsor, in consultation with the Secretary, shall determine whether such plan should be updated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25101_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Pipeline.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Not later than 1 year after the establishment of the program under this section, and by February 1st of each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a project pipeline, in accordance with this section, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_25101_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “intercity passenger rail corridor” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>