<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30119" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30119/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30119/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30119"><akn:num>30119</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30119. Notification procedures(a) Contents of Notification.—Notification by a manufacturer required under section 30118 of this title of a defect or noncompliance shall contain—(1) a clear description of the defect or noncompliance;

(2) an evaluation of the risk to motor vehicle safety reasonably related to the defect or noncompliance;

(3) the measures to be taken to obtain a remedy of the defect or noncompliance;

(4) a statement that the manufacturer giving notice will remedy the defect or noncompliance without charge under section 30120 of this title;

(5) the earliest date on which the defect or noncompliance will be remedied without charge, and for tires, the period during which the defect or noncompliance will be remedied without charge under section 30120 of this title;

(6) the procedure the recipient of a notice is to follow to inform the Secretary of Transportation when a manufacturer, distributor, or dealer does not remedy the defect or noncompliance without charge under section 30120 of this title; and

(7) other information the Secretary prescribes by regulation.


(b) Earliest Remedy Date.—The date specified by a manufacturer in a notification under subsection (a)(5) of this section or section 30121(c)(2) of this title is the earliest date that parts and facilities reasonably can be expected to be available to remedy the defect or noncompliance. The Secretary may disapprove the date.

(c) Time for Notification.—Notification required under section 30118 of this title shall be given within a reasonable time—(1) prescribed by the Secretary, after the manufacturer receives notice of a final decision under section 30118(b) of this title; or

(2) after the manufacturer first decides that a safety-related defect or noncompliance exists under section 30118(c) of this title.


(d) Means of Providing Notification.—(1) Notification required under section 30118 of this title about a motor vehicle shall be sent in the manner prescribed by the Secretary, by regu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30119_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notification by a manufacturer required under section 30118 of this title of a defect or noncompliance shall contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30119_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Earliest Remedy Date.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The date specified by a manufacturer in a notification under subsection (a)(5) of this section or section 30121(c)(2) of this title is the earliest date that parts and facilities reasonably can be expected to be available to remedy the defect or noncompliance. The Secretary may disapprove the date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30119_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification required under section 30118 of this title shall be given within a reasonable time—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30119_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Means of Providing Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30119_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30119_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification by Lessor to Lessee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30119_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Regarding Components Involved in Recall.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A manufacturer that is required to furnish a report under section 573.6 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation) for a defect or noncompliance in a motor vehicle or in an item of original or replacement equipment shall, if such defect or noncompliance involves a specific component or components, include in such report, with respect to such component or components, the following information:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>