<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30166" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30166/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30166/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30166"><akn:num>30166</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections, investigations, and records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30166. Inspections, investigations, and records(a) Definition.—In this section, “motor vehicle accident” means an occurrence associated with the maintenance or operation of a motor vehicle or motor vehicle equipment resulting in personal injury, death, or property damage.

(b) Authority To Inspect and Investigate.—(1) The Secretary of Transportation may conduct an inspection or investigation—(A) that may be necessary to enforce this chapter or a regulation prescribed or order issued under this chapter; or

(B) related to a motor vehicle accident and designed to carry out this chapter.


(2) The Secretary of Transportation shall cooperate with State and local officials to the greatest extent possible in an inspection or investigation under paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection.


(c) Matters That Can Be Inspected and Impoundment.—In carrying out this chapter, an officer or employee designated by the Secretary of Transportation—(1) at reasonable times, may inspect and copy any record related to this chapter;

(2) on request, may inspect records of a manufacturer, distributor, dealer, or rental company to decide whether the manufacturer, distributor, dealer, or rental company has complied or is complying with this chapter or a regulation prescribed or order issued under this chapter;

(3) at reasonable times, in a reasonable way, and on display of proper credentials and written notice to an owner, operator, or agent in charge, may—(A) enter and inspect with reasonable promptness premises in which a motor vehicle or motor vehicle equipment is manufactured, held for introduction in interstate commerce (including at United States ports of entry), or held for sale after introduction in interstate commerce;

(B) enter and inspect with reasonable promptness premises at which a vehicle or equipment involved in a motor vehicle accident is located;

(C) inspect with reasonable promptness that vehicle or equipment; and

(D) impound for not more than 72 hours a vehicle or equipme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, “motor vehicle accident” means an occurrence associated with the maintenance or operation of a motor vehicle or motor vehicle equipment resulting in personal injury, death, or property damage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Inspect and Investigate.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters That Can Be Inspected and Impoundment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out this chapter, an officer or employee designated by the Secretary of Transportation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) When a motor vehicle (except a vehicle subject to subchapter I of chapter 135 of this title) or motor vehicle equipment is inspected or temporarily impounded under subsection (c)(3) of this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall pay reasonable compensation to the owner of the vehicle if the inspection or impoundment results in denial of use, or reduction in value, of the vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and Making Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Transportation reasonably may require a manufacturer of a motor vehicle or motor vehicle equipment to keep records, and a manufacturer, distributor, dealer, or rental company to make reports, to enable the Secretary to decide whether the manufacturer, distributor, dealer, or rental company has complied or is complying with this chapter or a regulation prescribed or order issued under this chapter. This subsection does not impose a recordkeeping requirement on a distributor 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. dealer, or rental company in addition to those imposed under subsection (f) of this section and section 30117(b) of this title or a regulation prescribed or order issued under subsection (f) or section 30117(b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Providing Copies of Communications About Defects and Noncompliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative Authority on Reports, Answers, and Hearings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Actions To Enforce and Venue.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) A civil action to enforce a subpena or order under subsection (g) of this section may be brought in the United States district court for any judicial district in which the proceeding is conducted. The court may punish a failure to obey an order of the court to comply with a subpena or order as a contempt of court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governmental Cooperation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary of Transportation may request a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government to provide records the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this chapter. The head of the department, agency, or instrumentality shall provide the record on request, may detail personnel on a reimbursable basis, and otherwise shall cooperate with the Secretary. This subsection does not affect a law limiting the authority of a department, agency, or instrumentality to provide information to another department, agency, or instrumentality.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30166_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation of Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretary of Transportation may advise, assist, and cooperate with departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Government, States, and other public and private agencies in developing a method for inspecting and testing to determine compliance with a motor vehicle safety standard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>