<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30167" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30167/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30167/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30167"><akn:num>30167</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of information by the Secretary of Transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30167. Disclosure of information by the Secretary of Transportation(a) Confidentiality of Information.—Information obtained under this chapter related to a confidential matter referred to in section 1905 of title 18 may be disclosed only in the following ways:(1) to other officers and employees carrying out this chapter.

(2) when relevant to a proceeding under this chapter.

(3) to the public if the confidentiality of the information is preserved.

(4) to the public when the Secretary of Transportation decides that disclosure is necessary to carry out section 30101 of this title.


(b) Defect and Noncompliance Information.—Subject to subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall disclose information obtained under this chapter related to a defect or noncompliance that the Secretary decides will assist in carrying out sections 30117(b) and 30118–30121 of this title or that is required to be disclosed under section 30118(a) of this title. A requirement to disclose information under this subsection is in addition to the requirements of section 552 of title 5.

(c) Information About Manufacturer’s Increased Costs.—A manufacturer opposing an action of the Secretary under this chapter because of increased cost shall submit to the Secretary information about the increased cost, including the manufacturer’s cost and the cost to retail purchasers, that allows the public and the Secretary to evaluate the manufacturer’s statement. The Secretary shall evaluate the information promptly and, subject to subsection (a) of this section, shall make the information and evaluation available to the public. The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register that the information is available.

(d) Withholding Information From Congress.—This section does not authorize information to be withheld from a committee of Congress authorized to have the information.

(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 970.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSection</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30167_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information obtained under this chapter related to a confidential matter referred to in section 1905 of title 18 may be disclosed only in the following ways:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30167_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defect and Noncompliance Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall disclose information obtained under this chapter related to a defect or noncompliance that the Secretary decides will assist in carrying out sections 30117(b) and 30118–30121 of this title or that is required to be disclosed under section 30118(a) of this title. A requirement to disclose information under this subsection is in addition to the requirements of section 552 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30167_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information About Manufacturer’s Increased Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A manufacturer opposing an action of the Secretary under this chapter because of increased cost shall submit to the Secretary information about the increased cost, including the manufacturer’s cost and the cost to retail purchasers, that allows the public and the Secretary to evaluate the manufacturer’s statement. The Secretary shall evaluate the information promptly and, subject to subsection (a) of this section, shall make the information and evaluation available to the public. The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register that the information is available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30167_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding Information From Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) This section does not authorize information to be withheld from a committee of Congress authorized to have the information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>