<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30172" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30172/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/30172/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_30172"><akn:num>30172</akn:num><akn:heading>Whistleblower incentives and protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 30172. Whistleblower incentives and protections(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Covered action.—The term “covered action” means any administrative or judicial action, including any related administrative or judicial action, brought by the Secretary or the Attorney General under this chapter that in the aggregate results in monetary sanctions exceeding $1,000,000.

(2) Monetary sanctions.—The term “monetary sanctions” means monies, including penalties and interest, ordered or agreed to be paid.

(3) Original information.—The term “original information” means information that—(A) is derived from the independent knowledge or analysis of an individual;

(B) is not known to the Secretary from any other source, unless the individual is the original source of the information; and

(C) is not exclusively derived from an allegation made in a judicial or an administrative action, in a governmental report, a hearing, an audit, or an investigation, or from the news media, unless the individual is a source of the information.


(4) Part supplier.—The term “part supplier” means a manufacturer of motor vehicle equipment.

(5) Successful resolution.—The term “successful resolution”, with respect to a covered action, includes any settlement or adjudication of the covered action.

(6) Whistleblower.—The term “whistleblower” means any employee or contractor of a motor vehicle manufacturer, part supplier, or dealership who voluntarily provides to the Secretary original information relating to any motor vehicle defect, noncompliance, or any violation or alleged violation of any notification or reporting requirement of this chapter, which is likely to cause unreasonable risk of death or serious physical injury.


(b) Awards.—(1) In general.—If the original information that a whistleblower provided to the Secretary leads to the successful resolution of a covered action, the Secretary, subject to subsection (c), may pay an award or awards to one or more whistleblowers in an aggregate</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30172_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30172_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30172_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Awards; Denial of Awards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30172_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A whistleblower may be represented by counsel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30172_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Contract Necessary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No contract with the Secretary is necessary for any whistleblower to receive an award under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30172_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of Whistleblowers; Confidentiality.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30172_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of False Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A whistleblower who knowingly and intentionally makes any false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation, or who makes or uses any false writing or document knowing the same to contain any false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or entry, shall not be entitled to an award under this section and shall be subject to prosecution under section 1001 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30172_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_30172_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations on the requirements of this section, consistent with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>