<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31137" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31137/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31137/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_31137"><akn:num>31137</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic logging devices and brake maintenance regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 31137. Electronic logging devices and brake maintenance regulations(a) Use of Electronic Logging Devices.—Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Enhancement Act of 2012, the Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations—(1) requiring a commercial motor vehicle involved in interstate commerce and operated by a driver subject to the hours of service and the record of duty status requirements under part 395 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, be 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “to”. equipped with an electronic logging device to improve compliance by an operator of a vehicle with hours of service regulations prescribed by the Secretary; and

(2) ensuring that an electronic logging device is not used to harass a vehicle operator.


(b) Electronic Logging Device Requirements.—(1) In general.—The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall—(A) require an electronic logging device—(i) to accurately record commercial driver hours of service;

(ii) to record the location of a commercial motor vehicle;

(iii) to be tamper resistant; and

(iv) to be synchronized to the operation of the vehicle engine or be capable of recognizing when the vehicle is being operated;


(B) allow law enforcement to access the data contained in the device during a roadside inspection; and

(C) except as provided in paragraph (3), apply to a commercial motor vehicle beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date that the regulations are published as a final rule.


(2) Performance and design standards.—The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall establish performance standards—(A) defining a standardized user interface to aid vehicle operator compliance and law enforcement review;

(B) establishing a secure process for standardized—(i) and unique vehicle operator identification;

(ii) data access;

(iii) data transfer for vehicle operators between motor vehicles;

(iv) data storage for a motor </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31137_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Electronic Logging Devices.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Enhancement Act of 2012, the Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31137_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic Logging Device Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31137_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31137_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary, in prescribing the regulations described in subsection (a), shall consider how such regulations may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31137_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31137_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31137_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Brakes and Brake Systems Maintenance Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall maintain regulations on improved standards or methods to ensure that brakes and brake systems of commercial motor vehicles are maintained properly and inspected by appropriate employees. At a minimum, the regulations shall establish minimum training requirements and qualifications for employees responsible for maintaining and inspecting the brakes and brake systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>