<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31131" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31131/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31131/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_31131"><akn:num>31131</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes and findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 31131. Purposes and findings(a) Purposes.—The purposes of this subchapter are—(1) to promote the safe operation of commercial motor vehicles;

(2) to minimize dangers to the health of operators of commercial motor vehicles and other employees whose employment directly affects motor carrier safety; and

(3) to ensure increased compliance with traffic laws and with the commercial motor vehicle safety and health regulations and standards prescribed and orders issued under this chapter.


(b) Findings.—Congress finds—(1) it is in the public interest to enhance commercial motor vehicle safety and thereby reduce highway fatalities, injuries, and property damage;

(2) improved, more uniform commercial motor vehicle safety measures and strengthened enforcement would reduce the number of fatalities and injuries and the level of property damage related to commercial motor vehicle operations;

(3) enhanced protection of the health of commercial motor vehicle operators is in the public interest; and

(4) interested State governments can provide valuable assistance to the United States Government in ensuring that commercial motor vehicle operations are conducted safely and healthfully.


(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 999.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


31131(a)49 App.:2501.Oct. 30, 1984, Pub. L. 98–554, §§ 202, 203, 98 Stat. 2832.
31131(b)49 App.:2502.


In subsection (a)(3), the words “this chapter” are substituted for “this Act” because title II of the Act of October 30, 1984 (Public Law 98–554, 98 Stat. 2832), amended and enacted provisions restated in this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Exemptions From Requirements of This Subchapter for Certain Farm VehiclesFor provisions relating to exemptions from certain requirements of this subchapter with respect to certain farm vehicles and individuals operating those vehicles, see section 32934 of Pub. L. 112–141, set o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31131_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The purposes of this subchapter are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31131_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Congress finds—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>