<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31141" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31141/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31141/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_31141"><akn:num>31141</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and preemption of State laws and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 31141. Review and preemption of State laws and regulations(a) Preemption After Decision.—A State may not enforce a State law or regulation on commercial motor vehicle safety that the Secretary of Transportation decides under this section may not be enforced.

(b) Submission of Regulation.—A State receiving funds made available under section 31104 that enacts a State law or issues a regulation on commercial motor vehicle safety shall submit a copy of the law or regulation to the Secretary immediately after the enactment or issuance.

(c) Review and Decisions by Secretary.—(1) Review.—The Secretary shall review State laws and regulations on commercial motor vehicle safety. The Secretary shall decide whether the State law or regulation—(A) has the same effect as a regulation prescribed by the Secretary under section 31136;

(B) is less stringent than such regulation; or

(C) is additional to or more stringent than such regulation.


(2) Regulations with same effect.—If the Secretary decides a State law or regulation has the same effect as a regulation prescribed by the Secretary under section 31136 of this title, the State law or regulation may be enforced.

(3) Less stringent regulations.—If the Secretary decides a State law or regulation is less stringent than a regulation prescribed by the Secretary under section 31136 of this title, the State law or regulation may not be enforced.

(4) Additional or more stringent regulations.—If the Secretary decides a State law or regulation is additional to or more stringent than a regulation prescribed by the Secretary under section 31136 of this title, the State law or regulation may be enforced unless the Secretary also decides that—(A) the State law or regulation has no safety benefit;

(B) the State law or regulation is incompatible with the regulation prescribed by the Secretary; or

(C) enforcement of the State law or regulation would cause an unreasonable burden on interstate commerce.


(5) Consideration of effect on </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31141_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption After Decision.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A State may not enforce a State law or regulation on commercial motor vehicle safety that the Secretary of Transportation decides under this section may not be enforced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31141_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of Regulation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A State receiving funds made available under section 31104 that enacts a State law or issues a regulation on commercial motor vehicle safety shall submit a copy of the law or regulation to the Secretary immediately after the enactment or issuance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31141_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and Decisions by Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31141_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31141_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written Notice of Decisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than 10 days after making a decision under subsection (c) of this section that a State law or regulation may not be enforced, the Secretary shall give written notice to the State of that decision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31141_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial Review and Venue.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31141_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiating Review Proceedings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) To review a State law or regulation on commercial motor vehicle safety under this section, the Secretary may initiate a regulatory proceeding on the Secretary’s own initiative or on petition of an interested person (including a State).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>