<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31309" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31309/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31309/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_31309"><akn:num>31309</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial driver’s license information system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 31309. Commercial driver’s license information system(a) General Requirement.—The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall maintain an information system (referred to in this section as the “information system”) that will serve as a clearinghouse and depository of information about the licensing, identification, and disqualification of operators of commercial motor vehicles. The information system shall be coordinated with activities carried out under section 31106. The Secretary shall consult with the States in carrying out this section.

(b) Contents.—(1) In general.—At a minimum, the information system shall include for each operator of a commercial motor vehicle—(A) information the Secretary considers appropriate to ensure identification of the operator;

(B) the name, address, and physical description of the operator;

(C) the social security account number of the operator or other number or information the Secretary considers appropriate to identify the operator;

(D) the name of the State that issued the license or learner’s permit to the operator;

(E) the dates between which the license or learner’s permit is valid; and

(F) whether the operator had a commercial motor vehicle driver’s license or learner’s permit revoked, suspended, or canceled by a State, lost the right to operate a commercial motor vehicle in a State for any period, or has been disqualified from operating a commercial motor vehicle.


(2) Requirement.—The information system must accommodate any unique identifiers required to minimize fraud or duplication of a commercial driver’s license or learner’s permit under section 31308(3).


(c) Availability of Information.—Information in the information system shall be made available and subject to review and correction in accordance with the policy developed under section 31106(e).

(d) Authorized Operator.—The Secretary may authorize a qualified entity (referred to in this section as the “authorized ope</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31309_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall maintain an information system (referred to in this section as the “information system”) that will serve as a clearinghouse and depository of information about the licensing, identification, and disqualification of operators of commercial motor vehicles. The information system shall be coordinated with activities carried out under section 31106. The Secretary shall consult with the States in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31309_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31309_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information in the information system shall be made available and subject to review and correction in accordance with the policy developed under section 31106(e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31309_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Operator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may authorize a qualified entity (referred to in this section as the “authorized operator”)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31309_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31309_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modernization Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31309_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) At the Secretary’s discretion, a State may use, subject to subsections (a)(2) and (b) of section 31313, the funds made available to the State under that section to modernize its commercial driver’s license information system to be compatible with the modernized information system under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>