<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_31306"><akn:num>31306</akn:num><akn:heading>Alcohol and controlled substances testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 31306. Alcohol and controlled substances testing(a) Definition.—In this section and section 31306a, “controlled substance” means any substance under section 102 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (21 U.S.C. 802) specified by the Secretary of Transportation.

(b) Testing Program for Operators of Commercial Motor Vehicles.—(1)(A) In the interest of commercial motor vehicle safety, the Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations that establish a program requiring motor carriers to conduct preemployment, reasonable suspicion, random, and post-accident testing of operators of commercial motor vehicles for the use of a controlled substance in violation of law or a United States Government regulation and to conduct reasonable suspicion, random, and post-accident testing of such operators for the use of alcohol in violation of law or a United States Government regulation.

(B) The regulations prescribed under subparagraph (A) shall permit motor carriers—(i) to conduct preemployment testing of commercial motor vehicle operators for the use of alcohol; and

(ii) to use hair testing as an acceptable alternative to urine testing—(I) in conducting preemployment testing for the use of a controlled substance; and

(II) in conducting random testing for the use of a controlled substance if the operator was subject to hair testing for preemployment testing.



(C) When the Secretary of Transportation considers it appropriate in the interest of safety, the Secretary may prescribe regulations for conducting periodic recurring testing of operators of commercial motor vehicles for the use of alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a Government regulation.


(2) In prescribing regulations under this subsection, the Secretary of Transportation—(A) shall require that post-accident testing of an operator of a commercial motor vehicle be conducted when loss of human life occurs in an accident involving a commercial motor vehicle;
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section and section 31306a, “controlled substance” means any substance under section 102 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (21 U.S.C. 802) specified by the Secretary of Transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing Program for Operators of Commercial Motor Vehicles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing and Laboratory Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out subsection (b) of this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall develop requirements that shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing as Part of Medical Examination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Transportation may provide that testing under subsection (a) of this section for operators subject to subpart E of part 391 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, be conducted as part of the medical examination required under that subpart.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations establishing requirements for rehabilitation programs that provide for the identification and opportunity for treatment of operators of commercial motor vehicles who are found to have used alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a Government regulation. The Secretary shall decide on the circumstances under which those operators shall be required to participate in a program. This section does not prevent a motor carrier from establishing a program under this section in cooperation with another motor carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Transportation shall decide on appropriate sanctions for a commercial motor vehicle operator who is found, based on tests conducted and confirmed under this section, to have used alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a Government regulation but who is not under the influence of alcohol or a controlled substance as provided in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on State and Local Government Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A State or local government may not prescribe or continue in effect a law, regulation, standard, or order that is inconsistent with regulations prescribed under this section. However, a regulation prescribed under this section may not be construed to preempt a State criminal law that imposes sanctions for reckless conduct leading to loss of life, injury, or damage to property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Obligations and Foreign Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In prescribing regulations under this section, the Secretary of Transportation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Regulations Allowed.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) This section does not prevent the Secretary of Transportation from continuing in effect, amending, or further supplementing a regulation prescribed before October 28, 1991, governing the use of alcohol or a controlled substance by commercial motor vehicle employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Penalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) This section does not supersede a penalty applicable to an operator of a commercial motor vehicle under this chapter or another law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>