<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31306a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31306a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31306a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_31306a"><akn:num>31306a</akn:num><akn:heading>National clearinghouse for controlled substance and alcohol test results of commercial motor vehicle</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 31306a. National clearinghouse for controlled substance and alcohol test results of commercial motor vehicle operators(a) Establishment.—(1) In general.—Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the Safe Roads Act of 2012, the Secretary of Transportation shall establish, operate, and maintain a national clearinghouse for records relating to alcohol and controlled substances testing of commercial motor vehicle operators.

(2) Purposes.—The purposes of the clearinghouse shall be—(A) to improve compliance with the Department of Transportation’s alcohol and controlled substances testing program applicable to commercial motor vehicle operators; and

(B) to enhance the safety of our United States roadways by reducing accident and injuries involving the misuse of alcohol or use of controlled substances by operators of commercial motor vehicles.


(3) Contents.—The clearinghouse shall function as a repository for records relating to the positive test results and test refusals of commercial motor vehicle operators and violations by such operators of prohibitions set forth in subpart B of part 382 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or any subsequent corresponding regulations).

(4) Electronic exchange of records.—The Secretary shall ensure that records can be electronically submitted to, and requested from, the clearinghouse by authorized users.

(5) Authorized operator.—The Secretary may authorize a qualified private entity to operate and maintain the clearinghouse and to collect fees on behalf of the Secretary under subsection (e). The entity shall operate and maintain the clearinghouse and permit access to driver information and records from the clearinghouse in accordance with this section.


(b) Design of Clearinghouse.—(1) Use of federal motor carrier safety administration recommendations.—In establishing the clearinghouse, the Secretary shall consider—(A) the findings and recommendations contained in the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration’</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Design of Clearinghouse.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard Formats.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall develop standard formats to be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A release of information from the clearinghouse shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting of Records.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Users.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Transportation Safety Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary shall establish a process for the National Transportation Safety Board to request and receive an individual’s record from the clearinghouse if the individual is involved in an accident that is under investigation by the National Transportation Safety Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31306a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to Clearinghouse by Individuals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>