<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/31313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_31313"><akn:num>31313</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial driver’s license program implementation financial assistance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 31313. Commercial driver’s license program implementation financial assistance program(a) Financial Assistance Program.—(1) In general.—The Secretary of Transportation shall administer a financial assistance program for commercial driver’s license program implementation for the purposes described in paragraphs (2) and (3).

(2) State commercial driver’s license program implementation grants.—In carrying out the program, the Secretary may make a grant to a State agency in a fiscal year—(A) to assist the State in complying with the requirements of section 31311; and

(B) in the case of a State that is making a good faith effort toward substantial compliance with the requirements of section 31311, to improve the State’s implementation of its commercial driver’s license program, including expenses—(i) for computer hardware and software;

(ii) for publications, testing, personnel, training, and quality control;

(iii) for commercial driver’s license program coordinators; and

(iv) to implement or maintain a system to notify an employer of an operator of a commercial motor vehicle of the suspension or revocation of the operator’s commercial driver’s license consistent with the standards developed under section 32303(b) of the Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Enhancement Act of 2012 (49 U.S.C. 31304 note).



(3) Priority activities.—The Secretary may make a grant to or enter into a cooperative agreement with a State agency, local government, or any person in a fiscal year for research, development and testing, demonstration projects, public education, and other special activities and projects relating to commercial drivers licensing and motor vehicle safety that—(A) benefit all jurisdictions of the United States;

(B) address national safety concerns and circumstances;

(C) address emerging issues relating to commercial driver’s license improvements;

(D) support innovative ideas and solutions to commercial driver’s license program issues;

(E) support, in addition to fu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial Assistance Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A recipient may not use financial assistance funds awarded under this section to rent, lease, or buy land or buildings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall issue an annual report on the activities carried out under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) All amounts made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year shall be apportioned to a recipient described in subsection (a)(3) according to criteria prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_31313_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) For fiscal years beginning after September 30, 2016, this section shall be funded under section 31104.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>