<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_32302"><akn:num>32302</akn:num><akn:heading>Passenger motor vehicle information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 32302. Passenger motor vehicle information(a) Information Program.—The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall maintain a program for developing the following information on passenger motor vehicles:(1) damage susceptibility.

(2) crashworthiness, crash avoidance, and any other areas the Secretary determines will improve the safety of passenger motor vehicles.

(3) the degree of difficulty of diagnosis and repair of damage to, or failure of, mechanical and electrical systems.


(b) Motor Vehicle Information.—To assist a consumer in buying a passenger motor vehicle, the Secretary shall provide to the public information developed under subsection (a) of this section. The information shall be in a simple and understandable form that allows comparison of the characteristics referred to in subsection (a)(1)–(3) of this section among the makes and models of passenger motor vehicles. The Secretary may require passenger motor vehicle dealers to distribute the information to prospective buyers. The Secretary, after providing an opportunity for public comment, shall study and report to Congress the most useful data, format, and method for providing simple and understandable damage susceptibility information to consumers.

(c) Crash Avoidance.—Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Safety Through Informed Consumers Act of 2015, the Secretary shall promulgate a rule to ensure that crash avoidance information is indicated next to crashworthiness information on stickers placed on motor vehicles by their manufacturers.

(d) Motor Vehicle Defect Reporting Information.—(1) Rulemaking required.—Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Motor Vehicle and Highway Safety Improvement Act of 2012, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations that require passenger motor vehicle manufacturers—(A) to affix, in the glove compartment or in another readily accessible location on the vehicle, a sticker, decal, or other d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall maintain a program for developing the following information on passenger motor vehicles:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motor Vehicle Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To assist a consumer in buying a passenger motor vehicle, the Secretary shall provide to the public information developed under subsection (a) of this section. The information shall be in a simple and understandable form that allows comparison of the characteristics referred to in subsection (a)(1)–(3) of this section among the makes and models of passenger motor vehicles. The Secretary may require passenger motor vehicle dealers to distribute the information to prospective buyers. The Secretary, after providing an opportunity for public comment, shall study and report to Congress the most useful data, format, and method for providing simple and understandable damage susceptibility information to consumers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crash Avoidance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Safety Through Informed Consumers Act of 2015, the Secretary shall promulgate a rule to ensure that crash avoidance information is indicated next to crashworthiness information on stickers placed on motor vehicles by their manufacturers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motor Vehicle Defect Reporting Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced Crash-avoidance Technologies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32302_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vulnerable Road User Safety.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>