<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_32304"><akn:num>32304</akn:num><akn:heading>Passenger motor vehicle country of origin labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 32304. Passenger motor vehicle country of origin labeling(a) Definitions.—In this section—(1) “allied supplier” means a supplier of passenger motor vehicle equipment that is wholly owned by the manufacturer, or if a joint venture vehicle assembly arrangement, a supplier that is wholly owned by one member of the joint venture arrangement.

(2)(A) “carline”—(i) means a name given a group of passenger motor vehicles that has a degree of commonality in construction such as body and chassis;

(ii) does not consider a level of decor or opulence; and

(iii) except for light duty trucks, is not generally distinguished by characteristics such as roof line, number of doors, seats, or windows; and


(B) light duty trucks are different carlines than passenger motor vehicles.


(3) “country of origin”, when referring to the origin of an engine or transmission, means the country from which the largest share of the dollar value added to an engine or transmission has originated—(A) with the United States and Canada treated as separate countries; and

(B) the estimate of the percentage of the dollar value shall be based on the purchase price of direct materials, as received at individual engine or transmission plants, of engines of the same displacement and transmissions of the same transmission type, plus the assembly and labor costs incurred for the final assembly of such engines and transmissions.


(4) “dealer” means a person residing or located in the United States, including the District of Columbia or a territory or possession of the United States, and engaged in selling or distributing new passenger motor vehicles to the ultimate purchaser.

(5) “final assembly place” means the plant, factory, or other place at which a new passenger motor vehicle is produced or assembled by a manufacturer, and from which the vehicle is delivered to a dealer or importer with all component parts necessary for the mechanical operation of the vehicle included with the vehicle, whether or not t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturer Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vehicle Content Percentage by Assembly Plant.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A manufacturer may display separately on the label required by subsection (b) the domestic content of a vehicle based on the assembly plant. Such display shall occur after the matter required to be in the label by subsection (b)(1)(A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32304_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value Added Determination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If a manufacturer or allied supplier requests information in a timely manner from one or more of its outside suppliers concerning the United States/Canadian content of particular equipment, but does not receive that information despite a good faith effort to obtain it, the manufacturer or allied supplier may make its own good faith value added determinations, subject to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32304_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small Parts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The country of origin of nuts, bolts, clips, screws, pins, braces, gasoline, oil, blackout, phosphate rinse, windshield washer fluid, fasteners, tire assembly fluid, rivets, adhesives, and grommets, of any system, subassembly, or component installed in a vehicle shall be considered to be the country in which such parts were included in the final assembly of such vehicle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32304_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dealer Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Each dealer engaged in the sale or distribution of a new passenger motor vehicle manufactured after September 30, 1994, shall cause to be maintained on that vehicle the label required to be attached to that vehicle under subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32304_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and Content of Label.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe by regulation the form and content of the label required under subsection (b) of this section and the manner and location in which the label is attached. The Secretary shall permit a manufacturer to comply with this section by allowing the manufacturer to disclose the information required under subsection (b)(1) on the label required by section 3 of the Automobile Information Disclosure Act (15 U.S.C. 1232), on the label required by section 32908 of this title, or on a separate label that is readily visible. A manufacturer may add to the label required under subsection (b) a line stating the country in which vehicle assembly was completed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32304_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In consultation with the Secretaries of Commerce and the Treasury, the Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe regulations necessary to carry out this section, including regulations establishing a procedure to verify the label information required under subsection (b)(1) of this section. Those regulations shall provide the ultimate purchaser of a new passenger motor vehicle with the best and most understandable information possible about the foreign content and United States/Canadian origin of the equipment of the vehicles without imposing costly and unnecessary burdens on the manufacturers. The Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe the regulations promptly to provide adequate lead time for each manufacturer to comply with this section. The regulations shall include provisions applicable to outside suppliers and allied suppliers to require those suppliers to certify whether passenger motor vehicle equipment provided by those suppliers is of United States origin, of United</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32304_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>