<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_32904"><akn:num>32904</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation of average fuel economy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 32904. Calculation of average fuel economy(a) Method of Calculation.—(1) The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall calculate the average fuel economy of a manufacturer subject to—(A) section 32902(a) of this title in a way prescribed by the Administrator; and

(B) section 32902(b)–(d) of this title by dividing—(i) the number of passenger automobiles manufactured by the manufacturer in a model year; by

(ii) the sum of the fractions obtained by dividing the number of passenger automobiles of each model manufactured by the manufacturer in that model year by the fuel economy measured for that model.



(2)(A) In this paragraph, “electric vehicle” means a vehicle powered primarily by an electric motor drawing electrical current from a portable source.

(B) If a manufacturer manufactures an electric vehicle, the Administrator shall include in the calculation of average fuel economy under paragraph (1) of this subsection equivalent petroleum based fuel economy values determined by the Secretary of Energy for various classes of electric vehicles. The Secretary shall review those values each year and determine and propose necessary revisions based on the following factors:(i) the approximate electrical energy efficiency of the vehicle, considering the kind of vehicle and the mission and weight of the vehicle.

(ii) the national average electrical generation and transmission efficiencies.

(iii) the need of the United States to conserve all forms of energy and the relative scarcity and value to the United States of all fuel used to generate electricity.

(iv) the specific patterns of use of electric vehicles compared to petroleum-fueled vehicles.




(b) Separate Calculations for Passenger Automobiles Manufactured Domestically and Not Domestically.—(1)(A) Except as provided in paragraphs (6) and (7) of this subsection, the Administrator shall make separate calculations under subsection (a)(1)(B) of this section for—(i) passenger automobiles manufacture</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32904_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of Calculation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32904_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate Calculations for Passenger Automobiles Manufactured Domestically and Not Domestically.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32904_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing and Calculation Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator shall measure fuel economy for each model and calculate average fuel economy for a manufacturer under testing and calculation procedures prescribed by the Administrator. However, except under section 32908 of this title, the Administrator shall use the same procedures for passenger automobiles the Administrator used for model year 1975 (weighted 55 percent urban cycle and 45 percent highway cycle), or procedures that give comparable results. A measurement of fuel economy or a calculation of average fuel economy (except under section 32908) shall be rounded off to the nearest .1 of a mile a gallon. The Administrator shall decide on the quantity of other fuel that is equivalent to one gallon of gasoline. To the extent practicable, fuel economy tests shall be carried out with emissions tests under section 206 of the Clean Air Act (42 U.S.C. 7525).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32904_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Date of Procedure or Amendment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Administrator shall prescribe a procedure under this section, or an amendment (except a technical or clerical amendment) in a procedure, at least 12 months before the beginning of the model year to which the procedure or amendment applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32904_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and Consultation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administrator shall report measurements and calculations under this section to the Secretary of Transportation and shall consult and coordinate with the Secretary in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>