<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/32905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_32905"><akn:num>32905</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturing incentives for alternative fuel automobiles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 32905. Manufacturing incentives for alternative fuel automobiles(a) Dedicated Automobiles.—Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section or section 32904(a)(2) of this title, for any model of dedicated automobile manufactured by a manufacturer after model year 1992, the fuel economy measured for that model shall be based on the fuel content of the alternative fuel used to operate the automobile. A gallon of a liquid alternative fuel used to operate a dedicated automobile is deemed to contain .15 gallon of fuel.

(b) Dual Fueled Automobiles.—Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section or section 32904(a)(2) of this title, for any model of dual fueled automobile manufactured by a manufacturer in model years 1993 through 2019, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall measure the fuel economy for that model by dividing 1.0 by the sum of—(1) .5 divided by the fuel economy measured under section 32904(c) of this title when operating the model on gasoline or diesel fuel; and

(2) .5 divided by the fuel economy—(A) measured under subsection (a) when operating the model on alternative fuel; or

(B) measured based on the fuel content of B20 when operating the model on B20, which is deemed to contain 0.15 gallon of fuel.



(c) Gaseous Fuel Dedicated Automobiles.—For any model of gaseous fuel dedicated automobile manufactured by a manufacturer after model year 1992, the Administrator shall measure the fuel economy for that model based on the fuel content of the gaseous fuel used to operate the automobile. One hundred cubic feet of natural gas is deemed to contain .823 gallon equivalent of natural gas. The Secretary of Transportation shall determine the appropriate gallon equivalent of other gaseous fuels. A gallon equivalent of gaseous fuel is deemed to have a fuel content of .15 gallon of fuel.

(d) Gaseous Fuel Dual Fueled Automobiles.—For any model of gaseous fuel dual fueled automobile manufactured by a manufacturer in model years 19</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dedicated Automobiles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section or section 32904(a)(2) of this title, for any model of dedicated automobile manufactured by a manufacturer after model year 1992, the fuel economy measured for that model shall be based on the fuel content of the alternative fuel used to operate the automobile. A gallon of a liquid alternative fuel used to operate a dedicated automobile is deemed to contain .15 gallon of fuel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dual Fueled Automobiles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section or section 32904(a)(2) of this title, for any model of dual fueled automobile manufactured by a manufacturer in model years 1993 through 2019, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall measure the fuel economy for that model by dividing 1.0 by the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gaseous Fuel Dedicated Automobiles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) For any model of gaseous fuel dedicated automobile manufactured by a manufacturer after model year 1992, the Administrator shall measure the fuel economy for that model based on the fuel content of the gaseous fuel used to operate the automobile. One hundred cubic feet of natural gas is deemed to contain .823 gallon equivalent of natural gas. The Secretary of Transportation shall determine the appropriate gallon equivalent of other gaseous fuels. A gallon equivalent of gaseous fuel is deemed to have a fuel content of .15 gallon of fuel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gaseous Fuel Dual Fueled Automobiles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For any model of gaseous fuel dual fueled automobile manufactured by a manufacturer in model years 1993 through 2019, the Administrator shall measure the fuel economy for that model by dividing 1.0 by the sum of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electric Dual Fueled Automobiles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32905_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fuel Economy Calculations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Administrator shall calculate the manufacturer’s average fuel economy under section 32904(a)(1) of this title for each model described under subsections (a)–(d) of this section by using as the denominator the fuel economy measured for each model under subsections (a)–(d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_32905_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fuel Economy Incentive Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In order for any model of dual fueled automobile to be eligible to receive the fuel economy incentives included in section 32906(a) and (b), a label shall be attached to the fuel compartment of each dual fueled automobile of that model, notifying that the vehicle can be operated on an alternative fuel and on gasoline or diesel, with the form of alternative fuel stated on the notice. This requirement applies to dual fueled automobiles manufactured on or after September 1, 2006.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>