<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/330" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/330/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/330/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_330"><akn:num>330</akn:num><akn:heading>Research activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 330. Research activities(a) In General.—The Secretary of Transportation may make contracts with educational institutions, public and private agencies and organizations, and persons for scientific or technological research into a problem related to programs carried out by the Secretary. Before making a contract, the Secretary must require the institution, agency, organization, or person to show that it is able to carry out the contract.

(b) Responsibilities.—In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—(1) give advice and assistance the Secretary believes will best carry out the duties and powers of the Secretary;

(2) participate in coordinating all research started under this section;

(3) indicate the lines of inquiry most important to the Secretary; and

(4) encourage and assist in establishing and maintaining cooperation by and between contractors and between them and other research organizations, the Department of Transportation, and other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government.


(c) Publications.—The Secretary may distribute publications containing information the Secretary considers relevant to research carried out under this section.

(d) Duties.—The Secretary shall provide for the following:(1) Coordination, facilitation, and review of Department of Transportation research and development programs and activities.

(2) Advancement, and research and development, of innovative technologies, including intelligent transportation systems.

(3) Comprehensive transportation statistics research, analysis, and reporting.

(4) Education and training in transportation and transportation-related fields.

(5) Activities of the Volpe National Transportation Systems Center.

(6) Coordination in support of multimodal and multidisciplinary research activities.


(e) Additional Authorities.—The Secretary may—(1) enter into grants and cooperative agreements with Federal agencies, State and local government agencies, other public e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_330_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation may make contracts with educational institutions, public and private agencies and organizations, and persons for scientific or technological research into a problem related to programs carried out by the Secretary. Before making a contract, the Secretary must require the institution, agency, organization, or person to show that it is able to carry out the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_330_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_330_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may distribute publications containing information the Secretary considers relevant to research carried out under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_330_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall provide for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_330_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_330_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_330_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Evaluation and Oversight.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For each of fiscal years 2016 through 2020, the Secretary is authorized to expend not more than 1 ½ percent of the amounts authorized to be appropriated for the coordination, evaluation, and oversight of the programs administered by the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Research and Technology.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_330_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Technology.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The research, development, or use of a technology under a contract, grant, cooperative research and development agreement, or other agreement entered into under this section, including the terms under which the technology may be licensed and the resulting royalties may be distributed, shall be subject to the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (15 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_330_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of Advertising Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Section 6101 of title 41 shall not apply to a contract, grant, or other agreement entered into under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>