<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/33106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/33106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/33106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_33106"><akn:num>33106</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption for passenger motor vehicles equipped with anti-theft devices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 33106. Exemption for passenger motor vehicles equipped with anti-theft devices(a) Definitions.—In this section—(1) “anti-theft device” means a device to reduce or deter theft that—(A) is in addition to the theft-deterrent devices required by motor vehicle safety standard numbered 114 in section 571.114 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations;

(B) the manufacturer believes will be effective in reducing or deterring theft of motor vehicles; and

(C) does not use a signaling device reserved by State law for use on police, emergency, or official vehicles, or on schoolbuses.


(2) “standard equipment” means equipment already installed in a motor vehicle when it is delivered from the manufacturer and not an accessory or other item that the first purchaser customarily has the option to have installed.


(b) Granting Exemptions and Limitations.—(1) A manufacturer may petition the Secretary of Transportation for an exemption from a requirement of a standard prescribed under section 33102 or 33103 of this title for a line of passenger motor vehicles equipped as standard equipment with an anti-theft device that the Secretary decides is likely to be as effective in reducing and deterring motor vehicle theft as compliance with the standard.

(2) The Secretary may grant an exemption—(A) for model year 1987, for not more than 2 lines of a manufacturer;

(B) for each of the model years 1988–1996, for not more than 2 additional lines of a manufacturer;

(C) for each of the model years 1997–2000, for not more than one additional line of a manufacturer; and

(D) for each of the model years after model year 2000, for the number of lines that the Attorney General decides under section 33103(d)(3) of this title.


(3) An additional exemption granted under paragraph (2)(B) or (C) of this subsection does not affect an exemption previously granted.


(c) Petitioning Procedure.—A petition must be filed not later than 8 months before the start of production for the first model year covere</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Granting Exemptions and Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petitioning Procedure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A petition must be filed not later than 8 months before the start of production for the first model year covered by the petition. The petition must include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisions and Approvals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall make a decision about a petition filed under this section not later than 120 days after the date the petition is filed. A decision approving a petition must be based on substantial evidence. The Secretary may approve a petition in whole or in part. If the Secretary does not make a decision within the 120-day period, the petition shall be deemed to be approved and the manufacturer shall be exempt from the standard for the line covered by the petition for the subsequent model year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rescissions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may rescind an exemption if the Secretary decides that the anti-theft device has not been as effective in reducing and deterring motor vehicle theft as compliance with the standard. A rescission may be effective only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>