<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/33103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/33103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/33103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_33103"><akn:num>33103</akn:num><akn:heading>Theft prevention standard for other lines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 33103. Theft prevention standard for other lines(a) General.—Not later than October 25, 1994, the Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe a vehicle theft standard that conforms to the requirements of this chapter for covered major parts that manufacturers install in passenger motor vehicles (except light duty trucks) in not more than 50 percent of the lines not designated under section 33104 of this title as high theft lines.

(b) Extension of Application.—(1) Not later than 3 years after the standard is prescribed under subsection (a) of this section and based on the finding of the Attorney General under subsection (c) of this section to apply the standard, the Secretary shall apply that standard to covered major parts and major replacement parts for covered parts that manufacturers install in the lines of passenger motor vehicles (except light duty trucks)—(A) not designated under section 33104 of this title as high theft lines; and

(B) not covered by the standard prescribed under subsection (a) of this section.


(2) The Secretary shall include as part of the regulatory proceeding under this subsection the finding of, and the record developed by, the Attorney General under subsection (c) of this section.


(c) Initial Review of Effectiveness.—Before the Secretary begins a regulatory proceeding under subsection (b) of this section, the Attorney General shall make a finding that the Secretary shall apply the standard prescribed under subsection (a) of this section unless the Attorney General finds, based on information collected and analyzed under section 33112 11 See References in Text note below. of this title and other information the Attorney General develops after providing notice and an opportunity for a public hearing, that applying the standard prescribed in subsection (a) to the remaining lines of passenger motor vehicles (except light duty trucks) not covered by that standard would not substantially inhibit chop shop operations and motor vehicle th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than October 25, 1994, the Secretary of Transportation shall prescribe a vehicle theft standard that conforms to the requirements of this chapter for covered major parts that manufacturers install in passenger motor vehicles (except light duty trucks) in not more than 50 percent of the lines not designated under section 33104 of this title as high theft lines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of Application.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial Review of Effectiveness.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Before the Secretary begins a regulatory proceeding under subsection (b) of this section, the Attorney General shall make a finding that the Secretary shall apply the standard prescribed under subsection (a) of this section unless the Attorney General finds, based on information collected and analyzed under section 33112 11 See References in Text note below. of this title and other information the Attorney General develops after providing notice and an opportunity for a public hearing, that applying the standard prescribed in subsection (a) to the remaining lines of passenger motor vehicles (except light duty trucks) not covered by that standard would not substantially inhibit chop shop operations and motor vehicle thefts. The Attorney General also shall consider and include in the record additional costs, effectiveness, competition, and available alternative factors. The Attorney General shall submit to the Secretary the finding and record on which the finding is based.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Long Range Review of Effectiveness.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33103_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Date of Standard.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A standard prescribed under this section takes effect at least 6 months after the date the standard is prescribed, except that the Secretary may prescribe an earlier effective date if the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_33103_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary and the Attorney General shall inform the appropriate legislative committees of Congress with jurisdiction over this part and section 2322 of title 18 of actions taken or planned under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>