<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/354" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/354/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/354/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_354"><akn:num>354</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigative authority of Inspector General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 354. Investigative authority of Inspector General(a) In General.—The statutory authority of the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation includes authority to conduct, pursuant to Federal criminal statutes, investigations of allegations that a person or entity has engaged in fraudulent or other criminal activity relating to the programs and operations of the Department or its operating administrations.

(b) Regulated Entities.—The authority to conduct investigations referred to in subsection (a) extends to any person or entity subject to the laws and regulations of the Department or its operating administrations, whether or not they are recipients of funds from the Department or its operating administrations.

(Added and amended Pub. L. 108–168, § 8(a), (b)(1), Dec. 6, 2003, 117 Stat. 2034.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The text of section 228 of Pub. L. 106–159, formerly set out as a note under section 4 of the Inspector General Act of 1978, Pub. L. 95–452, formerly set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, which was transferred to this section, redesignated as text of section, and amended by Pub. L. 108–168, § 8(a), (b)(1), was based on Pub. L. 106–159, title II, § 228, Dec. 9, 1999, 113 Stat. 1773.

Amendments2003—Pub. L. 108–168 renumbered section 228 of Pub. L. 106–159 as this section and substituted “Investigative authority of Inspector General” for “DOT Authority” in section catchline. See Codification note above.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Deposit of Forfeited FundsPub. L. 113–235, div. K, title I, Dec. 16, 2014, 128 Stat. 2724, provided in part: “That hereafter funds transferred to the Office of the Inspector General through forfeiture proceedings or from the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund or the Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund, as a participating agency, as an equitable share from the forfeiture of property in investigations in which the Office of Inspector General par</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_354_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The statutory authority of the Inspector General of the Department of Transportation includes authority to conduct, pursuant to Federal criminal statutes, investigations of allegations that a person or entity has engaged in fraudulent or other criminal activity relating to the programs and operations of the Department or its operating administrations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_354_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulated Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The authority to conduct investigations referred to in subsection (a) extends to any person or entity subject to the laws and regulations of the Department or its operating administrations, whether or not they are recipients of funds from the Department or its operating administrations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>