<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/355" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/355/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/355/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_355"><akn:num>355</akn:num><akn:heading>Motorcyclist Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 355. Motorcyclist Advisory Council(a) Establishment.—Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish a council, to be known as the “Motorcyclist Advisory Council” (referred to in this section as the “Council”).

(b) Membership.—(1) In general.—The Council shall be comprised of 13 members, to be appointed by the Secretary, of whom—(A) 5 shall be representatives of units of State or local government with expertise relating to highway engineering and safety issues, including—(i) motorcycle and motorcyclist safety;

(ii) barrier and road design, construction, and maintenance; or

(iii) intelligent transportation systems;


(B) 1 shall be a motorcyclist who serves as a State or local—(i) traffic and safety engineer;

(ii) design engineer; or

(iii) other transportation department official;


(C) 1 shall be a representative of a national association of State transportation officials;

(D) 1 shall be a representative of a national motorcyclist association;

(E) 1 shall be a representative of a national motorcyclist foundation;

(F) 1 shall be a representative of a national motorcycle manufacturing association;

(G) 1 shall be a representative of a motorcycle manufacturing company headquartered in the United States;

(H) 1 shall be a roadway safety data expert with expertise relating to crash testing and analysis; and

(I) 1 shall be a member of a national safety organization that represents the traffic safety systems industry.


(2) Term.—(A) In general.—Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), each member shall serve on the Council for a single term of 2 years.

(B) Additional term.—If a successor is not appointed for a member of the Council before the expiration of the term of service of the member, the member may serve on the Council for a second term of not longer than 2 years.

(C) Appointment of replacements.—If a member of the Council resigns before th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_355_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish a council, to be known as the “Motorcyclist Advisory Council” (referred to in this section as the “Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_355_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_355_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_355_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_355_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Council shall terminate on the date that is 6 years after the date on which the Council is established under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>