<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40105"><akn:num>40105</akn:num><akn:heading>International negotiations, agreements, and obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40105. International negotiations, agreements, and obligations(a) Advice and Consultation.—The Secretary of State shall advise the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Secretaries of Transportation and Commerce, and consult with them as appropriate, about negotiations for an agreement with a government of a foreign country to establish or develop air navigation, including air routes and services. The Secretary of Transportation shall consult with the Secretary of State in carrying out this part to the extent this part is related to foreign air transportation.

(b) Actions of Secretary and Administrator.—(1) In carrying out this part, the Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator—(A) shall act consistently with obligations of the United States Government under an international agreement;

(B) shall consider applicable laws and requirements of a foreign country; and

(C) may not limit compliance by an air carrier with obligations or liabilities imposed by the government of a foreign country when the Secretary takes any action related to a certificate of public convenience and necessity issued under chapter 411 of this title.


(2) This subsection does not apply to an agreement between an air carrier or an officer or representative of an air carrier and the government of a foreign country, if the Secretary of Transportation disapproves the agreement because it is not in the public interest. Section 40106(b)(2) of this title applies to this subsection.


(c) Consultation on International Air Transportation Policy.—In carrying out section 40101(e) of this title, the Secretaries of State and Transportation, to the maximum extent practicable, shall consult on broad policy goals and individual negotiations with—(1) the Secretaries of Commerce and Defense;

(2) airport operators;

(3) scheduled air carriers;

(4) charter air carriers;

(5) airline labor;

(6) consumer interest groups;

(7) travel agents and tour organizers; and

(8) other gr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advice and Consultation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of State shall advise the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Secretaries of Transportation and Commerce, and consult with them as appropriate, about negotiations for an agreement with a government of a foreign country to establish or develop air navigation, including air routes and services. The Secretary of Transportation shall consult with the Secretary of State in carrying out this part to the extent this part is related to foreign air transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions of Secretary and Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation on International Air Transportation Policy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out section 40101(e) of this title, the Secretaries of State and Transportation, to the maximum extent practicable, shall consult on broad policy goals and individual negotiations with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40105_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Observers at International Aviation Negotiations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The President shall grant to at least one representative of each House of Congress the privilege of attending international aviation negotiations as an observer if the privilege is requested in advance in writing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>