<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40101"><akn:num>40101</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40101. Policy(a) Economic Regulation.—In carrying out subpart II of this part and those provisions of subpart IV applicable in carrying out subpart II, the Secretary of Transportation shall consider the following matters, among others, as being in the public interest and consistent with public convenience and necessity:(1) assigning and maintaining safety as the highest priority in air commerce.

(2) before authorizing new air transportation services, evaluating the safety implications of those services.

(3) preventing deterioration in established safety procedures, recognizing the clear intent, encouragement, and dedication of Congress to further the highest degree of safety in air transportation and air commerce, and to maintain the safety vigilance that has evolved in air transportation and air commerce and has come to be expected by the traveling and shipping public.

(4) the availability of a variety of adequate, economic, efficient, and low-priced services without unreasonable discrimination or unfair or deceptive practices.

(5) coordinating transportation by, and improving relations among, air carriers, and encouraging fair wages and working conditions.

(6) placing maximum reliance on competitive market forces and on actual and potential competition—(A) to provide the needed air transportation system; and

(B) to encourage efficient and well-managed air carriers to earn adequate profits and attract capital, considering any material differences between interstate air transportation and foreign air transportation.


(7) developing and maintaining a sound regulatory system that is responsive to the needs of the public and in which decisions are reached promptly to make it easier to adapt the air transportation system to the present and future needs of—(A) the commerce of the United States;

(B) the United States Postal Service; and

(C) the national defense.


(8) encouraging air transportation at major urban areas through secondary or satellite airports if</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Economic Regulation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In carrying out subpart II of this part and those provisions of subpart IV applicable in carrying out subpart II, the Secretary of Transportation shall consider the following matters, among others, as being in the public interest and consistent with public convenience and necessity:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>All-Cargo Air Transportation Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In carrying out subpart II of this part and those provisions of subpart IV applicable in carrying out subpart II, the Secretary of Transportation shall consider the following matters, among others and in addition to the matters referred to in subsection (a) of this section, as being in the public interest for all-cargo air transportation:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Safety Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out subpart III of this part and those provisions of subpart IV applicable in carrying out subpart III, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall consider the following matters:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40101_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safety Considerations in Public Interest.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In carrying out subpart III of this part and those provisions of subpart IV applicable in carrying out subpart III, the Administrator shall consider the following matters, among others, as being in the public interest:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40101_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Air Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In formulating United States international air transportation policy, the Secretaries of State and Transportation shall develop a negotiating policy emphasizing the greatest degree of competition compatible with a well-functioning international air transportation system, including the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40101_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strengthening Competition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In selecting an air carrier to provide foreign air transportation from among competing applicants, the Secretary of Transportation shall consider, in addition to the matters specified in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the strengthening of competition among air carriers operating in the United States to prevent unreasonable concentration in the air carrier industry.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>