<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40110" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40110/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40110/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40110"><akn:num>40110</akn:num><akn:heading>General procurement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40110. General procurement authority(a) General.—In carrying out this part, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration—(1) to the extent that amounts are available for obligation, may acquire services or, by condemnation or otherwise, an interest in property, including an interest in airspace immediately adjacent to and needed for airports and other air navigation facilities owned by the United States Government and operated by the Administrator;

(2) may construct and improve laboratories and other test facilities; and

(3) may dispose of any interest in property for adequate compensation, and the amount so received shall—(A) be credited to the appropriation current when the amount is received;

(B) be merged with and available for the purposes of such appropriation; and

(C) remain available until expended.



(b) Purchase of Housing Units.—(1) Authority.—In carrying out this part, the Administrator may purchase a housing unit (including a condominium or a housing unit in a building owned by a cooperative) that is located outside the contiguous United States if the cost of the unit is $300,000 or less.

(2) Adjustments for inflation.—For fiscal years beginning after September 30, 1997, the Administrator may adjust the dollar amount specified in paragraph (1) to take into account increases in local housing costs.

(3) Continuing obligations.—Notwithstanding section 1341 of title 31, the Administrator may purchase a housing unit under paragraph (1) even if there is an obligation thereafter to pay necessary and reasonable fees duly assessed upon such unit, including fees related to operation, maintenance, taxes, and insurance.

(4) Certification to congress.—The Administrator may purchase a housing unit under paragraph (1) only if, at least 30 days before completing the purchase, the Administrator transmits to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40110_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In carrying out this part, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40110_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of Housing Units.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40110_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and Powers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) When carrying out subsection (a) of this section, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40110_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition Management System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40110_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Release of Offeror Proposals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>