<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40117" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40117/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40117/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40117"><akn:num>40117</akn:num><akn:heading>Passenger facility charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40117. Passenger facility charges(a) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Airport, commercial service airport, and public agency.—The terms “airport”, “commercial service airport”, and “public agency” have the meaning those terms have under section 47102.

(2) Eligible agency.—The term “eligible agency” means a public agency that controls a commercial service airport.

(3) Eligible airport-related project.—The term “eligible airport-related project” means any of the following projects:(A) A project for airport development or airport planning under subchapter I of chapter 471.

(B) A project for terminal development described in section 47119(a).

(C) A project for costs of terminal development referred to in subparagraph (B) incurred after August 1, 1986, at an airport that did not have more than .25 percent of the total annual passenger boardings in the United States in the most recent calendar year for which data is available and at which total passenger boardings declined by at least 16 percent between calendar year 1989 and calendar year 1997.

(D) A project for airport noise capability planning under section 47505.

(E) A project to carry out noise compatibility measures eligible for assistance under section 47504, whether or not a program for those measures has been approved under section 47504.

(F) A project for constructing gates and related areas at which passengers board or exit aircraft. In the case of a project required to enable additional air service by an air carrier with less than 50 percent of the annual passenger boardings at an airport, the project for constructing gates and related areas may include structural foundations and floor systems, exterior building walls and load-bearing interior columns or walls, windows, door and roof systems, building utilities (including heating, air conditioning, ventilation, plumbing, and electrical service), and aircraft fueling facilities adjacent to the gate.

(G) A project for c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Approving Applications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may approve an application that an eligible agency has submitted under subsection (c) of this section to finance a specific project only if the Secretary finds, based on the application, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Imposing Charges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Contracts, Leases, and Use Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Revenue.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations necessary to carry out this section. The regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40117_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Certain Actions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) A State, political subdivision of a State, or authority of a State or political subdivision that is not the eligible agency may not tax, regulate, or prohibit or otherwise attempt to control in any manner, the imposition or collection of a passenger facility charge or the use of the revenue from the passenger facility charge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>