<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40116" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40116/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40116/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40116"><akn:num>40116</akn:num><akn:heading>State taxation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40116. State taxation(a) Definition.—In this section, “State” includes the District of Columbia, a territory or possession of the United States, and a political authority of at least 2 States.

(b) Prohibitions.—Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section and section 40117 of this title, a State, a political subdivision of a State, and any person that has purchased or leased an airport under section 47134 of this title may not levy or collect a tax, fee, head charge, or other charge on—(1) an individual traveling in air commerce;

(2) the transportation of an individual traveling in air commerce;

(3) the sale of air transportation; or

(4) the gross receipts from that air commerce or transportation.


(c) Aircraft Taking Off or Landing in State.—A State or political subdivision of a State may levy or collect a tax on or related to a flight of a commercial aircraft or an activity or service on the aircraft only if the aircraft takes off or lands in the State or political subdivision as part of the flight.

(d) Unreasonable Burdens and Discrimination Against Interstate Commerce.—(1) In this subsection—(A) “air carrier transportation property” means property (as defined by the Secretary of Transportation) that an air carrier providing air transportation owns or uses.

(B) “assessment” means valuation for a property tax levied by a taxing district.

(C) “assessment jurisdiction” means a geographical area in a State used in determining the assessed value of property for ad valorem taxation.

(D) “commercial and industrial property” means property (except transportation property and land used primarily for agriculture or timber growing) devoted to a commercial or industrial use and subject to a property tax levy.


(2)(A) A State, political subdivision of a State, or authority acting for a State or political subdivision may not do any of the following acts because those acts unreasonably burden and discriminate against interstate commerce:(i) assess air carrie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40116_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, “State” includes the District of Columbia, a territory or possession of the United States, and a political authority of at least 2 States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40116_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section and section 40117 of this title, a State, a political subdivision of a State, and any person that has purchased or leased an airport under section 47134 of this title may not levy or collect a tax, fee, head charge, or other charge on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40116_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aircraft Taking Off or Landing in State.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A State or political subdivision of a State may levy or collect a tax on or related to a flight of a commercial aircraft or an activity or service on the aircraft only if the aircraft takes off or lands in the State or political subdivision as part of the flight.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40116_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unreasonable Burdens and Discrimination Against Interstate Commerce.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40116_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Allowable Taxes and Charges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, a State or political subdivision of a State may levy or collect—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40116_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pay of Air Carrier Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>