<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40118" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40118/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40118/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40118"><akn:num>40118</akn:num><akn:heading>Government-financed air transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40118. Government-financed air transportation(a) Transportation by Air Carriers Holding Certificates.—A department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government shall take necessary steps to ensure that the transportation of passengers and property by air is provided by an air carrier holding a certificate under section 41102 of this title if—(1) the department, agency, or instrumentality—(A) obtains the transportation for itself or in carrying out an arrangement under which payment is made by the Government or payment is made from amounts provided for the use of the Government; or

(B) provides the transportation to or for a foreign country or international or other organization without reimbursement;


(2) the transportation is authorized by the certificate or by regulation or exemption of the Secretary of Transportation; and

(3) the air carrier is—(A) available, if the transportation is between a place in the United States and a place outside the United States; or

(B) reasonably available, if the transportation is between 2 places outside the United States.



(b) Transportation by Foreign Air Carriers.—This section does not preclude the transportation of passengers and property by a foreign air carrier if the transportation is provided under a bilateral or multilateral air transportation agreement to which the Government and the government of a foreign country are parties if the agreement—(1) is consistent with the goals for international aviation policy of section 40101(e) of this title; and

(2) provides for the exchange of rights or benefits of similar magnitude.


(c) Proof.—The Administrator of General Services shall prescribe regulations under which agencies may allow the expenditure of an appropriation for transportation in violation of this section only when satisfactory proof is presented showing the necessity for the transportation.

(d) Certain Transportation by Air Outside the United States.—Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (c) o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40118_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation by Air Carriers Holding Certificates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government shall take necessary steps to ensure that the transportation of passengers and property by air is provided by an air carrier holding a certificate under section 41102 of this title if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40118_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation by Foreign Air Carriers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) This section does not preclude the transportation of passengers and property by a foreign air carrier if the transportation is provided under a bilateral or multilateral air transportation agreement to which the Government and the government of a foreign country are parties if the agreement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40118_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proof.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator of General Services shall prescribe regulations under which agencies may allow the expenditure of an appropriation for transportation in violation of this section only when satisfactory proof is presented showing the necessity for the transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40118_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Transportation by Air Outside the United States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (c) of this section, any amount appropriated to the Secretary of State or the Administrator of the Agency for International Development may be used to pay for the transportation of an officer or employee of the Department of State or one of those agencies, a dependent of the officer or employee, and accompanying baggage, by a foreign air carrier when the transportation is between 2 places outside the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40118_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) This section does not affect the application of the antidiscrimination provisions of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40118_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of Certification or Contract Clause.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40118_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Administrator of General Services shall ensure that any contract entered into for provision of air transportation with a domestic carrier under this section requires that the contracting air carrier submits to the Administrator of General Services, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, the Secretary of Labor and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection an annual report regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>