<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40112"><akn:num>40112</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiyear procurement contracts for property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40112. Multiyear procurement contracts for property(a) General Authority.—Notwithstanding section 1341(a)(1)(B) of title 31 and to the extent that amounts otherwise are available for obligation, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make a contract of more than one but not more than 5 fiscal years to purchase property, except a contract to construct, alter, or make a major repair or improvement to real property.

(b) Required Findings.—The Administrator may make a contract under this section if the Administrator finds that—(1) the contract will promote the safety or efficiency of the national airspace system and will result in reduced total contract costs;

(2) the minimum need for the property to be purchased is expected to remain substantially unchanged during the proposed contract period in terms of production rate, procurement rate, and total quantities;

(3) there is a reasonable expectation that throughout the proposed contract period the Administrator will request appropriations for the contract at the level required to avoid cancellation;

(4) there is a stable design for the property to be acquired and the technical risks associated with the property are not excessive; and

(5) the estimates of the contract costs and the anticipated savings from the contract are realistic.


(c) Regulations.—The Administrator shall prescribe regulations for acquiring property under this section to promote the use of contracts under this section in a way that will allow the most efficient use of those contracts. The regulations may provide for a cancellation provision in the contract to the extent the provision is necessary and in the best interest of the United States. The provision may include consideration of recurring and nonrecurring costs of the contractor associated with producing the item to be delivered under the contract. The regulations shall provide that, to the extent practicable—(1) to broaden the aviation industrial base—(A) a contract</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notwithstanding section 1341(a)(1)(B) of title 31 and to the extent that amounts otherwise are available for obligation, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make a contract of more than one but not more than 5 fiscal years to purchase property, except a contract to construct, alter, or make a major repair or improvement to real property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Findings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator may make a contract under this section if the Administrator finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator shall prescribe regulations for acquiring property under this section to promote the use of contracts under this section in a way that will allow the most efficient use of those contracts. The regulations may provide for a cancellation provision in the contract to the extent the provision is necessary and in the best interest of the United States. The provision may include consideration of recurring and nonrecurring costs of the contractor associated with producing the item to be delivered under the contract. The regulations shall provide that, to the extent practicable—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40112_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40112_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation Payment and Notice of Cancellation Ceiling.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40112_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ending Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A contract made under this section shall be ended if amounts are not made available to continue the contract into a subsequent fiscal year. The cost of ending the contract may be paid from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>