<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/40111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40111"><akn:num>40111</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiyear procurement contracts for services and related items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40111. Multiyear procurement contracts for services and related items(a) General Authority.—Notwithstanding section 1341(a)(1)(B) of title 31, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make a contract of not more than 5 years for the following types of services and items of supply related to those services for which amounts otherwise would be available for obligation only in the fiscal year for which appropriated:(1) operation, maintenance, and support of facilities and installations.

(2) operation, maintenance, and modification of aircraft, vehicles, and other highly complex equipment.

(3) specialized training requiring high quality instructor skills, including training of pilots and aircrew members and foreign language training.

(4) base services, including ground maintenance, aircraft refueling, bus transportation, and refuse collection and disposal.


(b) Required Findings.—The Administrator may make a contract under this section only if the Administrator finds that—(1) there will be a continuing requirement for the service consistent with current plans for the proposed contract period;

(2) providing the service will require a substantial initial investment in plant or equipment, or will incur a substantial contingent liability for assembling, training, or transporting a specialized workforce; and

(3) the contract will promote the best interests of the United States by encouraging effective competition and promoting economies in operation.


(c) Considerations.—When making a contract under this section, the Administrator shall be guided by the following:(1) The part of the cost of a plant or equipment amortized as a cost of contract performance may not be more than the ratio between the period of contract performance and the anticipated useful commercial life (instead of physical life) of the plant or equipment, considering the location and specialized nature of the plant or equipment, obsolescence, and other similar factors.

(2) The A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notwithstanding section 1341(a)(1)(B) of title 31, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make a contract of not more than 5 years for the following types of services and items of supply related to those services for which amounts otherwise would be available for obligation only in the fiscal year for which appropriated:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Findings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator may make a contract under this section only if the Administrator finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40111_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) When making a contract under this section, the Administrator shall be guided by the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40111_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ending Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A contract made under this section shall be ended if amounts are not made available to continue the contract into a subsequent fiscal year. The cost of ending the contract may be paid from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>