<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41113"><akn:num>41113</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans to address needs of families of passengers involved in aircraft accidents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41113. Plans to address needs of families of passengers involved in aircraft accidents(a) Submission of Plans.—Each air carrier holding a certificate of public convenience and necessity under section 41102 of this title shall submit to the Secretary and the Chairman of the National Transportation Safety Board a plan for addressing the needs of the families of passengers involved in any aircraft accident involving an aircraft of the air carrier and resulting in any loss of life.

(b) Contents of Plans.—A plan to be submitted by an air carrier under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following:(1) A plan for publicizing a reliable, toll-free telephone number, and for providing staff, to handle calls from the families of the passengers.

(2) A process for notifying the families of the passengers, before providing any public notice of the names of the passengers, either by utilizing the services of the organization designated for the accident under section 1136(a)(2) of this title or the services of other suitably trained individuals.

(3) An assurance that the notice described in paragraph (2) will be provided to the family of a passenger as soon as the air carrier has verified that the passenger was aboard the aircraft (whether or not the names of all of the passengers have been verified) and, to the extent practicable, in person.

(4) An assurance that the air carrier will provide to the director of family support services designated for the accident under section 1136(a)(1) of this title, and to the organization designated for the accident under section 1136(a)(2) of this title, immediately upon request, a list (which is based on the best available information at the time of the request) of the names of the passengers aboard the aircraft (whether or not such names have been verified), and will periodically update the list.

(5) An assurance that the family of each passenger will be consulted about the disposition of all remains and personal effects of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each air carrier holding a certificate of public convenience and necessity under section 41102 of this title shall submit to the Secretary and the Chairman of the National Transportation Safety Board a plan for addressing the needs of the families of passengers involved in any aircraft accident involving an aircraft of the air carrier and resulting in any loss of life.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A plan to be submitted by an air carrier under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may not approve an application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity under section 41102 of this title unless the applicant has included as part of such application a plan that meets the requirements of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Liability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An air carrier shall not be liable for damages in any action brought in a Federal or State court arising out of the performance of the air carrier in preparing or providing a passenger list, or in providing information concerning a preliminary passenger manifest, pursuant to a plan submitted by the air carrier under subsection (b), unless such liability was caused by conduct of the air carrier which was grossly negligent or which constituted intentional misconduct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aircraft Accident and Passenger Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section, the terms “aircraft accident” and “passenger” have the meanings such terms have in section 1136 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section may be construed as limiting the actions that an air carrier may take, or the obligations that an air carrier may have, in providing assistance to the families of passengers involved in an aircraft accident.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>