<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41511" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41511/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41511/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41511"><akn:num>41511</akn:num><akn:heading>Special prices for foreign air transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41511. Special prices for foreign air transportation(a) Free and Reduced Pricing.—This chapter does not prohibit an air carrier or foreign air carrier, under terms the Secretary of Transportation prescribes, from issuing or interchanging tickets or passes for free or reduced-price foreign air transportation to or for the following:(1) a director, officer, or employee of the carrier (including a retired director, officer, or employee who is receiving retirement benefits from an air carrier or foreign air carrier).

(2) a parent or the immediate family of such an officer or employee or the immediate family of such a director.

(3) a widow, widower, or minor child of an employee of the carrier who died as a direct result of a personal injury sustained when performing a duty in the service of the carrier.

(4) a witness or attorney attending a legal investigation in which the air carrier is interested.

(5) an individual injured in an aircraft accident and a physician or nurse attending the individual.

(6) a parent or the immediate family of an individual injured or killed in an aircraft accident when the transportation is related to the accident.

(7) an individual or property to provide relief in a general epidemic, pestilence, or other emergency.

(8) other individuals under other circumstances the Secretary prescribes by regulation.


(b) Space-Available Basis.—Under terms the Secretary prescribes, an air carrier or foreign air carrier may grant reduced-price foreign air transportation on a space-available basis to the following:(1) a minister of religion.

(2) an individual who is at least 60 years of age and no longer gainfully employed.

(3) an individual who is at least 65 years of age.

(4) an individual who has severely impaired vision or hearing or another physical or mental disability and an accompanying attendant needed by that individual.


(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 1139; Pub. L. 118–63, title V, § 550(b), May 16, 2024, 138 Stat.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41511_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free and Reduced Pricing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) This chapter does not prohibit an air carrier or foreign air carrier, under terms the Secretary of Transportation prescribes, from issuing or interchanging tickets or passes for free or reduced-price foreign air transportation to or for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41511_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Space-Available Basis.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under terms the Secretary prescribes, an air carrier or foreign air carrier may grant reduced-price foreign air transportation on a space-available basis to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>