<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41706" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41706/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41706/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41706"><akn:num>41706</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions against smoking on passenger flights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41706. Prohibitions against smoking on passenger flights(a) Smoking Prohibition in Interstate and Intrastate Air Transportation.—An individual may not smoke—(1) in an aircraft in scheduled passenger interstate or intrastate air transportation; or

(2) in an aircraft in nonscheduled passenger interstate or intrastate air transportation, if a flight attendant is a required crewmember on the aircraft (as determined by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration).


(b) Smoking Prohibition in Foreign Air Transportation.—The Secretary of Transportation shall require all air carriers and foreign air carriers to prohibit smoking—(1) in an aircraft in scheduled passenger foreign air transportation; and

(2) in an aircraft in nonscheduled passenger foreign air transportation, if a flight attendant is a required crewmember on the aircraft (as determined by the Administrator or a foreign government).


(c) Limitation on Applicability.—(1) In general.—If a foreign government objects to the application of subsection (b) on the basis that subsection (b) provides for an extraterritorial application of the laws of the United States, the Secretary shall waive the application of subsection (b) to a foreign air carrier licensed by that foreign government at such time as an alternative prohibition negotiated under paragraph (2) becomes effective and is enforced by the Secretary.

(2) Alternative prohibition.—If, pursuant to paragraph (1), a foreign government objects to the prohibition under subsection (b), the Secretary shall enter into bilateral negotiations with the objecting foreign government to provide for an alternative smoking prohibition.


(d) Electronic Cigarettes.—(1) Inclusion.—The use of an electronic cigarette shall be treated as smoking for purposes of this section.

(2) Electronic cigarette defined.—In this section, the term “electronic cigarette” means a device that delivers nicotine to a user of the device in the form of a vapor that is inhaled to simu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41706_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Smoking Prohibition in Interstate and Intrastate Air Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An individual may not smoke—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41706_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Smoking Prohibition in Foreign Air Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Transportation shall require all air carriers and foreign air carriers to prohibit smoking—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41706_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Applicability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41706_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic Cigarettes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41706_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>