<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41733" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41733/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41733/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41733"><akn:num>41733</akn:num><akn:heading>Level of basic essential air service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41733. Level of basic essential air service(a) Decisions Made Before October 1, 1988.—For each eligible place for which a decision was made before October 1, 1988, under section 419 of the Federal Aviation Act of 1958, establishing the level of essential air transportation, the level of basic essential air service for that place shall be the level established by the Secretary of Transportation for that place by not later than December 29, 1988.

(b) Decisions Not Made Before October 1, 1988.—(1) The Secretary shall decide on the level of basic essential air service for each eligible place for which a decision was not made before October 1, 1988, establishing the level of essential air transportation, when the Secretary receives notice that service to that place will be provided by only one air carrier. The Secretary shall make the decision by the last day of the 6-month period beginning on the date the Secretary receives the notice. The Secretary may impose notice requirements necessary to carry out this subsection. Before making a decision, the Secretary shall consider the views of any interested community and the appropriate State authority of the State in which the community is located.

(2) Until the Secretary has made a decision on a level of basic essential air service for an eligible place under this subsection, the Secretary, on petition by an appropriate representative of the place, as defined by the Secretary, shall prohibit an air carrier from ending, suspending, or reducing air transportation to that place that appears to deprive the place of basic essential air service.


(c) Availability of Compensation.—(1) If the Secretary decides that basic essential air service will not be provided to an eligible place without compensation, the Secretary shall provide notice that an air carrier may apply to provide basic essential air service to the place for compensation under this section. In selecting an applicant, the Secretary shall consider, among other fac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41733_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisions Made Before October 1, 1988.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For each eligible place for which a decision was made before October 1, 1988, under section 419 of the Federal Aviation Act of 1958, establishing the level of essential air transportation, the level of basic essential air service for that place shall be the level established by the Secretary of Transportation for that place by not later than December 29, 1988.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41733_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisions Not Made Before October 1, 1988.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41733_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41733_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall pay compensation under this section at times and in the way the Secretary decides is appropriate. The Secretary shall end payment of compensation to an air carrier for providing basic essential air service to an eligible place when the Secretary decides the compensation is no longer necessary to maintain basic essential air service to the place.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41733_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall review periodically the level of basic essential air service for each eligible place. Based on the review and consultations with an interested community and the appropriate State authority of the State in which the community is located, the Secretary may make appropriate adjustments in the level of service, to the extent such adjustments are to a level not less than the basic essential air service level established under subsection (a) for the airport that serves the community.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41733_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Communities Prior to Termination of Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41733_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposals of State and Local Governments to Restore Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41733_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsidy Cap Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “subsidy cap” means the subsidy-per-passenger cap established under section 41731(a)(1)(C).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41733_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community Petition for Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>