<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41763" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41763/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/41763/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_41763"><akn:num>41763</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal credit instruments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 41763. Federal credit instruments(a) In General.—Subject to this section and section 41766, the Secretary of Transportation may enter into agreements with one or more obligors to make available Federal credit instruments, the proceeds of which shall be used to finance aircraft purchases.

(b) Secured Loans.—(1) Terms and limitations.—(A) In general.—A secured loan under this section with respect to an aircraft purchase shall be on such terms and conditions and contain such covenants, representatives, warranties, and requirements (including requirements for audits) as the Secretary determines appropriate.

(B) Maximum amount.—No secured loan may be made under this section—(i) that extends to more than 50 percent of the purchase price (including the value of any manufacturer credits, post-purchase options, or other discounts) of the aircraft, including spare parts, to be purchased; or

(ii) that, when added to the remaining balance on any other Federal credit instruments made under this subchapter, provides more than $100,000,000 of outstanding credit to any single obligor.


(C) Final payment date.—The final payment on the secured loan shall not be due later than 18 years after the date of execution of the loan agreement.

(D) Subordination.—The secured loan may be subordinate to claims of other holders of obligations in the event of bankruptcy, insolvency, or liquidation of the obligor as determined appropriate by the Secretary.

(E) Fees.—The Secretary, subject to appropriations, may establish fees at a level sufficient to cover all or a portion of the administrative costs to the United States Government of making a secured loan under this section. The proceeds of such fees shall be deposited in an account to be used by the Secretary for the purpose of administering the program established under this subchapter and shall be available upon deposit until expended.


(2) Repayment.—(A) Schedule.—The Secretary shall establish a repayment schedule for each secured loa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41763_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to this section and section 41766, the Secretary of Transportation may enter into agreements with one or more obligors to make available Federal credit instruments, the proceeds of which shall be used to finance aircraft purchases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41763_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secured Loans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41763_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan Guarantees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41763_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lines of Credit.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41763_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk Assessment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Before entering into an agreement under this section to make available a Federal credit instrument, the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall determine an appropriate capital reserve subsidy amount for the Federal credit instrument based on such credit evaluations as the Secretary deems necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41763_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Subject to subsection (h), the Secretary may only make a Federal credit instrument available under this section if the Secretary finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41763_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Combined Amount of Federal Credit Instruments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall not allow the combined amount of Federal credit instruments available for any aircraft purchase under this section to exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41763_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Subject to subsection (i), no Federal credit instrument may be made under this section for the purchase of any regional jet aircraft that does not comply with the stage 3 noise levels of part 36 of title 14 of the Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_41763_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) No Federal credit instrument shall be made by the Secretary under this section for the purchase of a regional jet aircraft unless the commuter air carrier or new entrant air carrier enters into a legally binding agreement that requires the carrier to provide scheduled passenger air transportation to the underserved market for which the aircraft is purchased for a period of not less than 36 consecutive months after the date that aircraft is placed in service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>