<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/42301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/42301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/42301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_42301"><akn:num>42301</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency contingency plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 42301. Emergency contingency plans(a) Submission of Air Carrier and Airport Plans.—Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, each of the following air carriers and airport operators shall submit to the Secretary of Transportation for review and approval an emergency contingency plan in accordance with the requirements of this section:(1) An air carrier providing covered air transportation at a commercial airport.

(2) An operator of a commercial airport.

(3) An operator of an airport used by an air carrier described in paragraph (1) for diversions.


(b) Air Carrier Plans.—(1) Plans for individual airports.—An air carrier shall submit an emergency contingency plan under subsection (a) for—(A) each airport at which the carrier provides covered air transportation; and

(B) each airport at which the carrier has flights for which the carrier has primary responsibility for inventory control.


(2) Contents.—An emergency contingency plan submitted by an air carrier for an airport under subsection (a) shall contain a description of how the carrier will—(A) provide adequate food, potable water, restroom facilities, comfortable cabin temperatures, and access to medical treatment for passengers onboard an aircraft at the airport when the departure of a flight is delayed or the disembarkation of passengers is delayed;

(B) share facilities and make gates available at the airport in an emergency; and

(C) allow passengers to deplane following an excessive tarmac delay in accordance with paragraph (3).


(3) Deplaning following an excessive tarmac delay.—For purposes of paragraph (2)(C), an emergency contingency plan submitted by an air carrier under subsection (a) shall incorporate the following requirements:(A) A passenger shall have the option to deplane an aircraft and return to the airport terminal when there is an excessive tarmac delay.

(B) The option described in subparagraph (A) shall be offered to a passenger even if a flight in covered ai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42301_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of Air Carrier and Airport Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, each of the following air carriers and airport operators shall submit to the Secretary of Transportation for review and approval an emergency contingency plan in accordance with the requirements of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42301_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Air Carrier Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42301_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Airport Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An emergency contingency plan submitted by an airport operator under subsection (a) shall contain a description of how the operator, to the maximum extent practicable, will—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42301_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42301_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42301_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall establish, as necessary or desirable, minimum standards for elements in an emergency contingency plan required to be submitted under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42301_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Access.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) An air carrier or airport operator required to submit an emergency contingency plan under this section shall ensure public access to the plan after its approval under this section on the Internet Web site of the carrier or operator or by such other means as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42301_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Not later than 30 days after any flight experiences an excessive tarmac delay, the air carrier responsible for such flight shall submit a written description of the incident and its resolution to the Aviation Consumer Protection Division of the Department of Transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_42301_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>