<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44106"><akn:num>44106</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation of aircraft certificates for controlled substance violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44106. Revocation of aircraft certificates for controlled substance violations(a) Definition.—In this section, “controlled substance” has the same meaning given that term in section 102 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (21 U.S.C. 802).

(b) Revocations.—(1) The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue an order revoking the certificate of registration for an aircraft issued to an owner under section 44103 of this title and any other certificate of registration that the owner of the aircraft holds under section 44103, if the Administrator finds that—(A) the aircraft was used to carry out, or facilitate, an activity that is punishable by death or imprisonment for more than one year under a law of the United States or a State related to a controlled substance (except a law related to simple possession of a controlled substance); and

(B) the owner of the aircraft permitted the use of the aircraft knowing that the aircraft was to be used for the activity described in clause (A) of this paragraph.


(2) An aircraft owner that is not an individual is deemed to have permitted the use of the aircraft knowing that the aircraft was to be used for the activity described in paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection only if a majority of the individuals who control the owner of the aircraft or who are involved in forming the major policy of the owner permitted the use of the aircraft knowing that the aircraft was to be used for the activity described in paragraph (1)(A).


(c) Advice to Holders and Opportunity To Answer.—Before the Administrator revokes a certificate under subsection (b) of this section, the Administrator shall—(1) advise the holder of the certificate of the charges or reasons on which the Administrator bases the proposed action; and

(2) provide the holder of the certificate an opportunity to answer the charges and state why the certificate should not be revoked.


(d) Appeals.—(1) A person whose certificate </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, “controlled substance” has the same meaning given that term in section 102 of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 (21 U.S.C. 802).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advice to Holders and Opportunity To Answer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Before the Administrator revokes a certificate under subsection (b) of this section, the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquittal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>