<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44101"><akn:num>44101</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44101. Operation of aircraft(a) Registration Requirement.—Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person may operate an aircraft only when the aircraft is registered under section 44103 of this title.

(b) Exceptions.—A person may operate an aircraft in the United States that is not registered—(1) when authorized under section 40103(d) or 41703 of this title;

(2) when it is an aircraft of the national defense forces of the United States and is identified in a way satisfactory to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration; and

(3) for a reasonable period of time after a transfer of ownership, under regulations prescribed by the Administrator.


(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 1161.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


44101(a)49 App.:1401(a) (1st sentence words before proviso less words between parentheses).Aug. 23, 1958, Pub. L. 85–726, § 501(a), 72 Stat. 771.
44101(b)49 App.:1401(a) (1st sentence words between parentheses, proviso, last sentence).
 49 App.:1655(c)(1).Oct. 15, 1966, Pub. L. 89–670, § 6(c)(1), 80 Stat. 938; Jan. 12, 1983, Pub. L. 97–449, § 7(b), 96 Stat. 2444.


In this section, the word “navigate” is omitted as being included in the definition of “operate aircraft” in section 40102(a) of the revised title.
In subsection (a), the words “Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section” are added for clarity. The words “a person may . . . an aircraft only when the aircraft is registered under section 44103 of this title” are substituted for “It shall be unlawful . . . any aircraft eligible for registration if such aircraft is not registered by its owner as provided in this section, or . . . any aircraft not eligible for registration” for clarity and to eliminate unnecessary words.
In subsection (b), before clause (1), the words “A person may operate an aircraft in the United States that is not registered” are substituted for “may</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, a person may operate an aircraft only when the aircraft is registered under section 44103 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A person may operate an aircraft in the United States that is not registered—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>