<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44303" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44303/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44303/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44303"><akn:num>44303</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44303. Coverage(a) In General.—The Secretary of Transportation may provide insurance and reinsurance, or reimburse insurance costs, as authorized under sections 44302 and 44302a of this title for the following:(1) an American aircraft or foreign-flag aircraft engaged in aircraft operations the President decides are necessary in the interest of air commerce or national security or to carry out the foreign policy of the United States Government.

(2) property transported or to be transported on aircraft referred to in clause (1) of this section, including—(A) shipments by express or registered mail;

(B) property owned by citizens or residents of the United States;

(C) property—(i) imported to, or exported from, the United States; and

(ii) bought or sold by a citizen or resident of the United States under a contract putting the risk of loss or obligation to provide insurance against risk of loss on the citizen or resident; and


(D) property transported between—(i) a place in a State or the District of Columbia and a place in a territory or possession of the United States;

(ii) a place in a territory or possession of the United States and a place in another territory or possession of the United States; or

(iii) 2 places in the same territory or possession of the United States.



(3) the personal effects and baggage of officers and members of the crew of an aircraft referred to in clause (1) of this section and of other individuals employed or transported on that aircraft.

(4) officers and members of the crew of an aircraft referred to in clause (1) of this section and other individuals employed or transported on that aircraft against loss of life, injury, or detention.

(5) statutory or contractual obligations or other liabilities, customarily covered by insurance, of an aircraft referred to in clause (1) of this section or of the owner or operator of that aircraft.

(6) loss or damage of an aircraft manufacturer resulting from operation of an aircraft by an a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44303_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation may provide insurance and reinsurance, or reimburse insurance costs, as authorized under sections 44302 and 44302a of this title for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44303_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Air Carrier Liability for Third Party Claims Arising Out of Acts of Terrorism.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For acts of terrorism committed on or to an air carrier during the period beginning on September 22, 2001, and ending on December 11, 2014, the Secretary may certify that the air carrier was a victim of an act of terrorism and in the Secretary’s judgment, based on the Secretary’s analysis and conclusions regarding the facts and circumstances of each case, shall not be responsible for losses suffered by third parties (as referred to in section 205.5(b)(1) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations) that exceed $100,000,000, in the aggregate, for all claims by such parties arising out of such act. If the Secretary so certifies, the air carrier shall not be liable for an amount that exceeds $100,000,000, in the aggregate, for all claims by such parties arising out of such act, and the Government shall be responsible for any liability above such amount. No punitive damages may be awarded against an air carrier (or the Government taking responsibility for an air carrier under this subsect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>