<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44511" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44511/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44511/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44511"><akn:num>44511</akn:num><akn:heading>Aviation research grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44511. Aviation research grants(a) General Authority.—The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make grants to institutions of higher education and nonprofit research organizations to conduct aviation research in areas the Administrator considers necessary for the long-term growth of civil aviation.

(b) Applications.—An institution of higher education or nonprofit research organization interested in receiving a grant under this section may submit an application to the Administrator. The application must be in the form and contain the information the Administrator requires.

(c) Solicitation, Review, and Evaluation Process.—The Administrator shall establish a solicitation, review, and evaluation process that ensures—(1) providing grants under this section for proposals having adequate merit and relevancy to the mission of the Administration;

(2) a fair geographical distribution of grants under this section; and

(3) the inclusion of historically black institutions of higher education and other minority nonprofit research organizations for grant consideration under this section.


(d) Records.—Each person receiving a grant under this section shall maintain records that the Administrator requires as being necessary to facilitate an effective audit and evaluation of the use of money provided under the grant.

(e) Annual Report.—The Administrator shall submit an annual report to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on carrying out this section.

(f) Airport Cooperative Research Program.—(1) Establishment.—The Secretary of Transportation shall maintain an airport cooperative research program to—(A) identify problems that are shared by airport operating agencies and can be solved through applied research but that are not being adequately addressed by existing Federal research programs; and

(B) fund research to address those problems.


(2) Governance.—The Se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44511_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may make grants to institutions of higher education and nonprofit research organizations to conduct aviation research in areas the Administrator considers necessary for the long-term growth of civil aviation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44511_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An institution of higher education or nonprofit research organization interested in receiving a grant under this section may submit an application to the Administrator. The application must be in the form and contain the information the Administrator requires.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44511_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation, Review, and Evaluation Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator shall establish a solicitation, review, and evaluation process that ensures—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44511_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Each person receiving a grant under this section shall maintain records that the Administrator requires as being necessary to facilitate an effective audit and evaluation of the use of money provided under the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44511_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administrator shall submit an annual report to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44511_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Airport Cooperative Research Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>