<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44701"><akn:num>44701</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44701. General requirements(a) Promoting Safety.—The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall promote safe flight of civil aircraft in air commerce by prescribing—(1) minimum standards required in the interest of safety for appliances and for the design, material, construction, quality of work, cybersecurity, and performance of aircraft, aircraft engines, and propellers;

(2) regulations and minimum standards in the interest of safety for—(A) inspecting, servicing, and overhauling aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, and appliances;

(B) equipment and facilities for, and the timing and manner of, the inspecting, servicing, and overhauling; and

(C) a qualified private person, instead of an officer or employee of the Administration, to examine and report on the inspecting, servicing, and overhauling;


(3) regulations required in the interest of safety for the reserve supply of aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, appliances, and aircraft fuel and oil, including the reserve supply of fuel and oil carried in flight;

(4) regulations in the interest of safety for the maximum hours or periods of service of airmen and other employees of air carriers; and

(5) regulations and minimum standards for cybersecurity and other practices, methods, and procedures the Administrator finds necessary for safety in air commerce and national security.


(b) Prescribing Minimum Safety Standards.—The Administrator may prescribe minimum safety standards for—(1) an air carrier to whom a certificate is issued under section 44705 of this title; and

(2) operating an airport serving any passenger operation of air carrier aircraft designed for at least 31 passenger seats.


(c) Reducing and Eliminating Accidents.—The Administrator shall carry out this chapter in a way that best tends to reduce or eliminate the possibility or recurrence of accidents in air transportation. However, the Administrator is not required to give preference either to air transportation or to o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44701_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting Safety.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall promote safe flight of civil aircraft in air commerce by prescribing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44701_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prescribing Minimum Safety Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator may prescribe minimum safety standards for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44701_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reducing and Eliminating Accidents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator shall carry out this chapter in a way that best tends to reduce or eliminate the possibility or recurrence of accidents in air transportation. However, the Administrator is not required to give preference either to air transportation or to other air commerce in carrying out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44701_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations and Classification of Regulations and Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) When prescribing a regulation or standard under subsection (a) or (b) of this section or any of sections 44702–44716 of this title, the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44701_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bilateral Exchanges of Safety Oversight Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44701_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Administrator may grant an exemption from a requirement of a regulation prescribed under subsection (a) or (b) of this section or any of sections 44702–44716 of this title if the Administrator finds the exemption is in the public interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44701_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive Rulemaking Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in section 40131, the Administrator, in consultation with the heads of such other agencies as the Administrator determines necessary, shall have exclusive authority to prescribe regulations for purposes of assuring the cybersecurity of civil aircraft, aircraft engines, propellers, and appliances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44701_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policies, Orders, and Guidance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>