<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44730" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44730/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44730/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44730"><akn:num>44730</akn:num><akn:heading>Helicopter air ambulance operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44730. Helicopter air ambulance operations(a) Compliance Regulations.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2), a part 135 certificate holder providing air ambulance services shall comply, whenever medical personnel are onboard the aircraft, with regulations pertaining to weather minimums and flight and duty time under part 135.

(2) Exception.—If a certificate holder described in paragraph (1) is operating, or carrying out training, under instrument flight rules, the weather reporting requirement at the destination shall not apply if authorized by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.


(b) Final Rule.—Not later than June 1, 2012, the Administrator shall issue a final rule, with respect to the notice of proposed rulemaking published in the Federal Register on October 12, 2010 (75 Fed. Reg. 62640), to improve the safety of flight crewmembers, medical personnel, and passengers onboard helicopters providing air ambulance services under part 135.

(c) Matters To Be Addressed.—In conducting the rulemaking proceeding under subsection (b), the Administrator shall consider, or address through other means, the following:(1) Flight request and dispatch procedures, including performance-based flight dispatch procedures.

(2) Pilot training standards, including establishment of training standards in—(A) preventing controlled flight into terrain; and

(B) recovery from inadvertent flight into instrument meteorological conditions.


(3) Safety-enhancing technology and equipment, including—(A) helicopter terrain awareness and warning systems;

(B) radar altimeters; and

(C) devices that perform the function of flight data recorders and cockpit voice recorders, to the extent feasible.


(4) Such other matters as the Administrator considers appropriate.


(d) Minimum Requirements.—In issuing a final rule under subsection (b), the Administrator, at a minimum, shall consider, or address through other means, the following:(1) Flight risk evaluation pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44730_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44730_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final Rule.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Not later than June 1, 2012, the Administrator shall issue a final rule, with respect to the notice of proposed rulemaking published in the Federal Register on October 12, 2010 (75 Fed. Reg. 62640), to improve the safety of flight crewmembers, medical personnel, and passengers onboard helicopters providing air ambulance services under part 135.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44730_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters To Be Addressed.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In conducting the rulemaking proceeding under subsection (b), the Administrator shall consider, or address through other means, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44730_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In issuing a final rule under subsection (b), the Administrator, at a minimum, shall consider, or address through other means, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44730_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent Actions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44730_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>