<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44733" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44733/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44733/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44733"><akn:num>44733</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight of repair stations located outside the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44733. Oversight of repair stations located outside the United States(a) In General.—The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall establish and implement a safety assessment system for all part 145 repair stations based on the type, scope, and complexity of work being performed. The system shall—(1) ensure that repair stations located outside the United States are subject to appropriate inspections based on identified risks and consistent with existing United States requirements;

(2) consider inspection results and findings submitted by foreign civil aviation authorities operating under a maintenance safety or maintenance implementation agreement with the United States; and

(3) require all maintenance safety or maintenance implementation agreements to provide an opportunity for the Administration to conduct independent inspections of part 145 repair stations when safety concerns warrant such inspections.


(b) Notice to Congress of Negotiations.—The Administrator shall notify the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives not later than 30 days after initiating formal negotiations with foreign aviation authorities or other appropriate foreign government agencies on a new maintenance safety or maintenance implementation agreement.

(c) Annual Report.—The Administrator shall publish an annual report on the Administration’s oversight of part 145 repair stations and implementation of the safety assessment system required under subsection (a). The report shall—(1) describe in detail any improvements in the Administration’s ability to identify and track where part 121 air carrier repair work is performed;

(2) include a staffing model to determine the best placement of inspectors and the number of inspectors needed;

(3) describe the training provided to inspectors; and

(4) include an assessment of the quality of monitoring and surveillance b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall establish and implement a safety assessment system for all part 145 repair stations based on the type, scope, and complexity of work being performed. The system shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Congress of Negotiations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator shall notify the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives not later than 30 days after initiating formal negotiations with foreign aviation authorities or other appropriate foreign government agencies on a new maintenance safety or maintenance implementation agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator shall publish an annual report on the Administration’s oversight of part 145 repair stations and implementation of the safety assessment system required under subsection (a). The report shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alcohol and Controlled Substances Testing Program Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Inspections.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administrator shall ensure that part 145 repair stations located outside the United States are inspected annually, without prior notice to such repair stations, by Federal Aviation Administration safety inspectors, without regard to where the station is located, in a manner consistent with United States obligations under international agreements and the applicable laws of the country in which the repair station is located. The Administrator may carry out announced or unannounced inspections in addition to the annual unannounced inspection required under this subsection based on identified risks and in a manner consistent with United States obligations under international agreements and the applicable laws of the country in which the part 145 repair station is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk-Based Oversight.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data Analysis.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications and Prohibition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum Qualifications for Mechanics and Others Working on U.S. Registered Aircraft.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Minimum Qualifications for Mechanics and Others Working on U.S. Registered Aircraft.—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44733_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>