<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44745" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44745/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44745/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44745"><akn:num>44745</akn:num><akn:heading>Don Young Alaska Aviation Safety Initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44745. Don Young Alaska Aviation Safety Initiative(a) In General.—The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall redesignate the FAA Alaska Aviation Safety Initiative of the Administration as the Don Young Alaska Aviation Safety Initiative (in this section referred to as the “Initiative”), under which the Administrator shall carry out the provisions of this section and take such other actions as the Administrator determines appropriate to improve aviation safety in Alaska and covered locations.

(b) Objective.—The objective of the Initiative shall be to work cooperatively with aviation stakeholders and other stakeholders towards the goal of—(1) reducing the rate of fatal aircraft accidents in Alaska and covered locations by 90 percent from 2019 to 2033; and

(2) by January 1, 2033, eliminating fatal accidents of aircraft operated by an air carrier that operates under part 135 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.


(c) Leadership.—(1) In general.—The Administrator shall designate the Regional Administrator for the Alaskan Region of the Administration to serve as the Director of the Initiative.

(2) Covered locations.—The Administrator shall select a designee within the Aviation Safety Organization to implement relevant requirements of this section in covered locations.

(3) Reporting chain.—In all matters relating to the Initiative, the Director of the Initiative shall report directly to the Administrator.

(4) Coordination.—The Director of the Initiative shall coordinate with the heads of other offices and lines of business of the Administration, including the other regional administrators, to carry out the Initiative.


(d) Automated Weather Systems.—(1) Requirement.—The Administrator shall ensure, to the greatest extent practicable, that a covered automated weather system is installed and operated at each covered airport not later than December 31, 2030.

(2) Waiver.—In complying with the requirement under paragraph (1), the Administrator ma</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall redesignate the FAA Alaska Aviation Safety Initiative of the Administration as the Don Young Alaska Aviation Safety Initiative (in this section referred to as the “Initiative”), under which the Administrator shall carry out the provisions of this section and take such other actions as the Administrator determines appropriate to improve aviation safety in Alaska and covered locations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objective.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The objective of the Initiative shall be to work cooperatively with aviation stakeholders and other stakeholders towards the goal of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leadership.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Automated Weather Systems.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Weather Cameras.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation With Other Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall cooperate with the heads of other Federal or State agencies with responsibilities affecting aviation safety in Alaska and covered locations, including the collection and dissemination of weather data.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surveillance and Communication.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Director shall continue to build upon other initiatives recommended in the reports of the FAA Alaska Aviation Safety Initiative of the Administration published before the date of enactment of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44745_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>