<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44809" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44809/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44809/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44809"><akn:num>44809</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for limited recreational operations of unmanned aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44809. Exception for limited recreational operations of unmanned aircraft(a) In General.—Except as provided in subsection (e), and notwithstanding chapter 447 of title 49, United States Code, a person may operate a small unmanned aircraft without specific certification or operating authority from the Federal Aviation Administration if the operation adheres to all of the following limitations:(1) The aircraft is flown strictly for recreational purposes.

(2) The aircraft is operated in accordance with or within the programming of a community-based organization’s set of safety guidelines that are developed in coordination with the Federal Aviation Administration.

(3) The aircraft is flown within the visual line of sight of the person operating the aircraft or a visual observer co-located and in direct communication with the operator.

(4) The aircraft is operated in a manner that does not interfere with and gives way to any manned aircraft.

(5) In Class B, Class C, or Class D airspace or within the lateral boundaries of the surface area of Class E airspace designated for an airport, the operator obtains prior authorization from the Administrator or designee before operating and complies with all airspace restrictions and prohibitions.

(6) Except for circumstances when the Administrator establishes alternative altitude ceilings or as otherwise authorized in section (c), in Class G airspace, the aircraft is flown from the surface to not more than 400 feet above ground level and complies with all airspace and flight restrictions and prohibitions established under this subtitle, such as special use airspace designations and temporary flight restrictions.

(7) The operator has passed an aeronautical knowledge and safety test described in subsection (g) and maintains proof of test passage to be made available to the Administrator or law enforcement upon request.

(8) The aircraft is registered and marked in accordance with chapter 441 of this title and proof of registr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44809_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (e), and notwithstanding chapter 447 of title 49, United States Code, a person may operate a small unmanned aircraft without specific certification or operating authority from the Federal Aviation Administration if the operation adheres to all of the following limitations:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44809_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Operations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Unmanned aircraft operations that do not conform to the limitations in subsection (a) must comply with all statutes and regulations generally applicable to unmanned aircraft and unmanned aircraft systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44809_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operations at Fixed Sites.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44809_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as expanding the authority of the Administrator to require a person operating an unmanned aircraft under this section to seek permissive authority of the Administrator, beyond that required in this section, prior to operation in the national airspace system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44809_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Administrator to pursue an enforcement action against a person operating any unmanned aircraft who endangers the safety of the national airspace system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44809_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section prohibits the Administrator from promulgating rules generally applicable to unmanned aircraft, including those unmanned aircraft eligible for the exception set forth in this section, relating to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44809_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aeronautical Knowledge and Safety Test.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44809_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community-based Organization Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “community-based organization” means a membership-based association entity that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44809_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition of Community-based Organizations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In collaboration with aeromodelling stakeholders, the Administrator shall publish an advisory circular within 180 days of the date of enactment of this section that identifies the criteria and process required for recognition of community-based organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>