<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44804" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44804/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44804/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44804"><akn:num>44804</akn:num><akn:heading>Unmanned aircraft in the Arctic</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44804. Unmanned aircraft in the Arctic(a) In General.—The Secretary of Transportation shall develop a plan and initiate a process to work with relevant Federal agencies and national and international communities to designate permanent areas in the Arctic where unmanned aircraft may operate 24 hours per day for research and commercial purposes.

(b) Plan Contents.—The plan under subsection (a) shall include the development of processes to facilitate the safe operation of unmanned aircraft beyond the visual line of sight.

(c) Requirements.—Each permanent area designated under subsection (a) shall enable over-water flights from the surface to at least 2,000 feet in altitude, with ingress and egress routes from selected coastal launch sites.

(d) Agreements.—To implement the plan under subsection (a), the Secretary may enter into an agreement with relevant national and international communities.

(e) Aircraft Approval.—(1) In general.—Subject to paragraph (2), not later than 1 year after the entry into force of an agreement necessary to effectuate the purposes of this section, the Secretary shall work with relevant national and international communities to establish and implement a process for approving the use of a unmanned aircraft in the designated permanent areas in the Arctic without regard to whether the unmanned aircraft is used as a public aircraft, a civil aircraft, or a model aircraft.

(2) Existing process.—The Secretary may implement an existing process to meet the requirements under paragraph (1).


(Added Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title III, § 344(a), Oct. 5, 2018, 132 Stat. 3290; amended Pub. L. 118–63, title IX, § 902(a), May 16, 2024, 138 Stat. 1341.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in section 332(d) of Pub. L. 112–95, which was set out in a note under section 40101 of this title, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title III, § 341(b)(2), Oct. 5, 2018, 132 Stat. 3287. The remainder o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44804_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation shall develop a plan and initiate a process to work with relevant Federal agencies and national and international communities to designate permanent areas in the Arctic where unmanned aircraft may operate 24 hours per day for research and commercial purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44804_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan Contents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The plan under subsection (a) shall include the development of processes to facilitate the safe operation of unmanned aircraft beyond the visual line of sight.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44804_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each permanent area designated under subsection (a) shall enable over-water flights from the surface to at least 2,000 feet in altitude, with ingress and egress routes from selected coastal launch sites.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44804_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) To implement the plan under subsection (a), the Secretary may enter into an agreement with relevant national and international communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44804_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aircraft Approval.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>