<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44803"><akn:num>44803</akn:num><akn:heading>Unmanned aircraft system test ranges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44803. Unmanned aircraft system test ranges(a) Test Ranges.—(1) In general.—The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall carry out and update, as appropriate, a program for the use of unmanned aircraft system (in this section referred to as UAS) test ranges to—(A) enable a broad variety of development, testing, and evaluation activities related to UAS and associated technologies; and

(B) the extent consistent with aviation safety and efficiency, support the safe integration of unmanned aircraft systems into the national airspace system.


(2) Designations.—(A) Existing test ranges.—Test ranges designated under this section shall include the 7 test ranges established under the following:(i) Section 332(c) of the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012 (49 U.S.C. 40101 note), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 (Public Law 115–254).

(ii) Any other test ranges designated pursuant to the amendment made by section 2201(b) of the FAA Extension, Safety, and Security Act of 2016 (49 U.S.C. 40101 note) after the date of enactment of such Act.


(B) New test ranges.—If the Administrator finds that it is in the best interest of enabling safe UAS integration into the national airspace system, the Administrator may select and designate as a test range under this section up to 2 additional test ranges in accordance with the requirements of this section through a competitive selection process.

(C) Limitation.—Not more than 9 test ranges designated under this section shall be part of the program established under this section at any given time.


(3) Eligibility.—Test ranges selected by the Administrator pursuant to (2)(B) shall—(A) be an instrumentality of a State, local, Tribal, or territorial government or other public entity;

(B) be approved by the chief executive officer of the State, local, territorial, or Tribal government for the principal place of business of the applicant, prior to seeking de</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Test Ranges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Airspace Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Administrator—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Except as provided in subsection (f), the requirements of section 44711, including any related implementing regulations, shall not apply to persons approved by the test range sponsor for operation at a test range designated by the Administrator under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44803_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Test Range Sponsors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The sponsor of each test range designated by the Administrator under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44803_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44803_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaborative Research and Development Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Administrator may use the transaction authority under section 106(l)(6), including in coordination with the Center of Excellence for Unmanned Aircraft Systems, to enter into collaborative research and development agreements or to direct research, development, testing, and evaluation related to unmanned aircraft systems, including activities conducted pursuant to section 1042 of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024, as appropriate, at any test range designated under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44803_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44803_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The program under this section shall terminate on September 30, 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>