<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44901"><akn:num>44901</akn:num><akn:heading>Screening passengers and property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44901. Screening passengers and property(a) In General.—The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall provide for the screening of all passengers and property, including United States mail, cargo, carry-on and checked baggage, and other articles, that will be carried aboard a passenger aircraft operated by an air carrier or foreign air carrier in air transportation or intrastate air transportation. In the case of flights and flight segments originating in the United States, the screening shall take place before boarding and shall be carried out by a Federal Government employee (as defined in section 2105 of title 5), except as otherwise provided in section 44920 and except for identifying passengers and baggage for screening under the CAPPS and known shipper programs and conducting positive bag-match programs.

(b) Supervision of Screening.—All screening of passengers and property at airports in the United States where screening is required under this section shall be supervised by uniformed Federal personnel of the Transportation Security Administration who shall have the power to order the dismissal of any individual performing such screening.

(c) Checked Baggage.—A system must be in operation to screen all checked baggage at all airports in the United States as soon as practicable.

(d) Explosives Detection Systems.—(1) In general.—The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall take all necessary action to ensure that—(A) explosives detection systems are deployed as soon as possible to ensure that all United States airports described in section 44903(c) have sufficient explosives detection systems to screen all checked baggage, and that as soon as such systems are in place at an airport, all checked baggage at the airport is screened by those systems; and

(B) all systems deployed under subparagraph (A) are fully utilized; and

(C) if explosives detection equipment at an airport is unavailable, all checked baggage</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall provide for the screening of all passengers and property, including United States mail, cargo, carry-on and checked baggage, and other articles, that will be carried aboard a passenger aircraft operated by an air carrier or foreign air carrier in air transportation or intrastate air transportation. In the case of flights and flight segments originating in the United States, the screening shall take place before boarding and shall be carried out by a Federal Government employee (as defined in section 2105 of title 5), except as otherwise provided in section 44920 and except for identifying passengers and baggage for screening under the CAPPS and known shipper programs and conducting positive bag-match programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of Screening.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) All screening of passengers and property at airports in the United States where screening is required under this section shall be supervised by uniformed Federal personnel of the Transportation Security Administration who shall have the power to order the dismissal of any individual performing such screening.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Checked Baggage.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A system must be in operation to screen all checked baggage at all airports in the United States as soon as practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Explosives Detection Systems.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory Screening Where EDS Not Yet Available.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) As soon as practicable and until the requirements of subsection (b)(1)(A) are met, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall require alternative means for screening any piece of checked baggage that is not screened by an explosives detection system. Such alternative means may include 1 or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cargo Deadline.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A system must be in operation to screen, inspect, or otherwise ensure the security of all cargo that is to be transported in all-cargo aircraft in air transportation and intrastate air transportation as soon as practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Air Cargo on Passenger Aircraft.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deployment of Armed Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions and Advising Congress on Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44901_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Blast-Resistant Cargo Containers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>