<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44903"><akn:num>44903</akn:num><akn:heading>Air transportation security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44903. Air transportation security(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Administrator.—The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.

(2) Law enforcement personnel.—The term “law enforcement personnel” means individuals—(A) authorized to carry and use firearms;

(B) vested with the degree of the police power of arrest the Administrator considers necessary to carry out this section; and

(C) identifiable by appropriate indicia of authority.



(b) Protection Against Violence and Piracy.—The Administrator shall prescribe regulations to protect passengers and property on an aircraft operating in air transportation or intrastate air transportation against an act of criminal violence or aircraft piracy. When prescribing a regulation under this subsection, the Administrator shall—(1) consult with the Secretary of Transportation, the Attorney General, the heads of other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the United States Government, and State and local authorities;

(2) consider whether a proposed regulation is consistent with—(A) protecting passengers; and

(B) the public interest in promoting air transportation and intrastate air transportation;


(3) to the maximum extent practicable, require a uniform procedure for searching and detaining passengers and property to ensure—(A) their safety; and

(B) courteous and efficient treatment by an air carrier, an agent or employee of an air carrier, and Government, State, and local law enforcement personnel carrying out this section; and


(4) consider the extent to which a proposed regulation will carry out this section.


(c) Security Programs.—(1) The Administrator shall prescribe regulations under subsection (b) of this section that require each operator of an airport regularly serving an air carrier holding a certificate issued by the Secretary of Transportation to establish an air transportation security program that provides a law enforcement presence and ca</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection Against Violence and Piracy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator shall prescribe regulations to protect passengers and property on an aircraft operating in air transportation or intrastate air transportation against an act of criminal violence or aircraft piracy. When prescribing a regulation under this subsection, the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizing Individuals To Carry Firearms and Make Arrests.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) With the approval of the Attorney General and the Secretary of State, the Administrator may authorize an individual who carries out air transportation security duties—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive Responsibility Over Passenger Safety.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administrator has the exclusive responsibility to direct law enforcement activity related to the safety of passengers on an aircraft involved in an offense under section 46502 of this title from the moment all external doors of the aircraft are closed following boarding until those doors are opened to allow passengers to leave the aircraft. When requested by the Administrator, other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Government shall provide assistance necessary to carry out this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government and Industry Consortia.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Administrator may establish at airports such consortia of government and aviation industry representatives as the Administrator may designate to provide advice on matters related to aviation security and safety. Such consortia shall not be considered Federal advisory committees for purposes of chapter 10 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement of Secured-Area Access Control.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved Airport Perimeter Access Security.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Arm Flight Deck Crew With Less-Than-Lethal Weapons.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44903_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short-Term Assessment and Deployment of Emerging Security Technologies and Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>