<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44920" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44920/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44920/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44920"><akn:num>44920</akn:num><akn:heading>Screening partnership program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44920. Screening partnership program(a) In General.—An airport operator may submit to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration an application to carry out the screening of passengers and property at the airport under section 44901 by personnel of a qualified private screening company pursuant to a contract entered into with the Transportation Security Administration.

(b) Approval of Applications.—(1) In general.—Not later than 60 days after the date of receipt of an application submitted by an airport operator under subsection (a), the Administrator shall approve or deny the application.

(2) Standards.—The Administrator shall approve an application submitted by an airport operator under subsection (a) if the Administrator determines that the approval would not compromise security or detrimentally affect the cost-efficiency or the effectiveness of the screening of passengers or property at the airport.

(3) Reports on denials of applications.—(A) In general.—If the Administrator denies an application submitted by an airport operator under subsection (a), the Administrator shall provide to the airport operator, not later than 60 days following the date of the denial, a written report that sets forth—(i) the findings that served as the basis for the denial;

(ii) the results of any cost or security analysis conducted in considering the application; and

(iii) recommendations on how the airport operator can address the reasons for the denial.


(B) Submission to congress.—The Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives a copy of any report provided to an airport operator under subparagraph (A).



(c) Qualified Private Screening Company.—A private screening company is qualified to provide screening services at an airport under this section if the company will only employ individuals to provide such services who meet all</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An airport operator may submit to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration an application to carry out the screening of passengers and property at the airport under section 44901 by personnel of a qualified private screening company pursuant to a contract entered into with the Transportation Security Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of Applications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified Private Screening Company.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A private screening company is qualified to provide screening services at an airport under this section if the company will only employ individuals to provide such services who meet all the requirements of this chapter applicable to Federal Government personnel who perform screening services at airports under this chapter and will provide compensation and other benefits to such individuals that are not less than the level of compensation and other benefits provided to such Federal Government personnel in accordance with this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of Contracts and Standards for Private Screening Companies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of Screening Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination or Suspension of Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Administrator may suspend or terminate, as appropriate, any contract entered into with a private screening company to provide screening services at an airport under this section if the Administrator finds that the company has failed repeatedly to comply with any standard, regulation, directive, order, law, or contract applicable to the hiring or training of personnel to provide such services or to the provision of screening at the airport.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operator of Airport.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an operator of an airport shall not be liable for any claims for damages filed in State or Federal court (including a claim for compensatory, punitive, contributory, or indemnity damages) relating to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of Screening Company Proposals for Award.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>22 So in original. Two subsecs. (i) have been enacted. Innovative Screening Approaches and Technologies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Administrator shall encourage an airport operator to whom screening services are provided under this section to recommend to the Administrator innovative screening approaches and technologies. Upon receipt of any such recommendations, the Administrator shall review and, if appropriate, test, conduct a pilot project, and, if appropriate, deploy such approaches and technologies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44920_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>2 Definition of Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section, the term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>