<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44933" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44933/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44933/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44933"><akn:num>44933</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Security Managers 11 So in original. Probably should be “Directors”.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44933. Federal Security Managers 11 So in original. Probably should be “Directors”.(a) Establishment, Designation, and Stationing.—The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall establish the position of Federal Security Director at each airport in the United States described in section 44903(c). The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall designate individuals as Federal Security Directors for, and station those Federal Security Directors at, those airports.

(b) Duties and Powers.—The Federal Security Director at each airport shall—(1) oversee the screening of passengers and property at the airport; and

(2) carry out other duties prescribed by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.


(c) Information Sharing.—Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the TSA Modernization Act, the Administrator shall—(1) require each Federal Security Director of an airport to meet at least quarterly with the airport director, airport security coordinator, and law enforcement agencies serving each such airport to discuss incident management protocols, including the resolution of screening anomalies at passenger screening checkpoints; and

(2) require each Federal Security Director at an airport to inform, consult, and coordinate, as appropriate, with the respective airport security coordinator in a timely manner on security matters impacting airport operations and to establish and maintain operational protocols with such airport operators to ensure coordinated responses to security matters.


(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 1216; Pub. L. 107–71, title I, §§ 101(f)(4), 103, Nov. 19, 2001, 115 Stat. 603, 605; Pub. L. 115–254, div. K, title I, §§ 1989(a), 1991(d)(24), Oct. 5, 2018, 132 Stat. 3624, 3637.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


44933(a)49 App.:1358b(a)(1), (2), (4).Aug. 23, 1958, Pub. L. 85–726, 72</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44933_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment, Designation, and Stationing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall establish the position of Federal Security Director at each airport in the United States described in section 44903(c). The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall designate individuals as Federal Security Directors for, and station those Federal Security Directors at, those airports.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44933_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and Powers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Federal Security Director at each airport shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44933_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Sharing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the TSA Modernization Act, the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>