<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44936" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44936/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44936/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44936"><akn:num>44936</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment investigations and restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44936. Employment investigations and restrictions(a) Employment Investigation Requirement.—(1)(A) The Administrator shall require by regulation that an employment investigation, including a criminal history record check and a review of available law enforcement data bases and records of other governmental and international agencies to the extent determined practicable by the Administrator, shall be conducted of each individual employed in, or applying for, a position as a security screener under section 44935(e) or a position in which the individual has unescorted access, or may permit other individuals to have unescorted access, to—(i) aircraft of an air carrier or foreign air carrier; or

(ii) a secured area of an airport in the United States the Administrator designates that serves an air carrier or foreign air carrier.


(B) The Administrator shall require by regulation that an employment investigation (including a criminal history record check and a review of available law enforcement data bases and records of other governmental and international agencies to the extent determined practicable by the Administrator) be conducted for—(i) individuals who are responsible for screening passengers or property under section 44901 of this title;

(ii) supervisors of the individuals described in clause (i);

(iii) individuals who regularly have escorted access to aircraft of an air carrier or foreign air carrier or a secured area of an airport in the United States the Administrator designates that serves an air carrier or foreign air carrier; and

(iv) such other individuals who exercise security functions associated with baggage or cargo, as the Administrator determines is necessary to ensure air transportation security.


(C) Exemption.—An employment investigation, including a criminal history record check, shall not be required under this subsection for an individual who is exempted under section 107.31(m)(1) or (2) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, as in eff</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44936_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment Investigation Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44936_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited Employment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44936_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fingerprinting and Record Check Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44936_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and Charges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Administrator and the Attorney General shall establish reasonable fees and charges to pay expenses incurred in carrying out this section. The employer of the individual being investigated shall pay the costs of a record check of the individual. Money collected under this section shall be credited to the account in the Treasury from which the expenses were incurred and are available to the Administrator and the Attorney General for those expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44936_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>When Investigation or Record Check Not Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) This section does not require an investigation or record check when the investigation or record check is prohibited by a law of a foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44936_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>