<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44935" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44935/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44935/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44935"><akn:num>44935</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment standards and training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44935. Employment standards and training(a) Employment Standards.—The Administrator shall prescribe standards for the employment and continued employment of, and contracting for, air carrier personnel and, as appropriate, airport security personnel. The standards shall include—(1) minimum training requirements for new employees;

(2) retraining requirements;

(3) minimum staffing levels;

(4) minimum language skills; and

(5) minimum education levels for employees, when appropriate.


(b) Review and Recommendations.—In coordination with air carriers, airport operators, and other interested persons, the Administrator shall review issues related to human performance in the aviation security system to maximize that performance. When the review is completed, the Administrator shall recommend guidelines and prescribe appropriate changes in existing procedures to improve that performance.

(c) Security Program Training, Standards, and Qualifications.—(1) The Administrator—(A) may train individuals employed to carry out a security program under section 44903(c) of this title; and

(B) shall prescribe uniform training standards and uniform minimum qualifications for individuals eligible for that training.


(2) The Administrator may authorize reimbursement for travel, transportation, and subsistence expenses for security training of non-United States Government domestic and foreign individuals whose services will contribute significantly to carrying out civil aviation security programs. To the extent practicable, air travel reimbursed under this paragraph shall be on air carriers.


(d) Education and Training Standards for Security Coordinators, Supervisory Personnel, and Pilots.—(1) The Administrator shall prescribe standards for educating and training—(A) ground security coordinators;

(B) security supervisory personnel; and

(C) airline pilots as in-flight security coordinators.


(2) The standards shall include initial training, retraining, and continuing education re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator shall prescribe standards for the employment and continued employment of, and contracting for, air carrier personnel and, as appropriate, airport security personnel. The standards shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and Recommendations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In coordination with air carriers, airport operators, and other interested persons, the Administrator shall review issues related to human performance in the aviation security system to maximize that performance. When the review is completed, the Administrator shall recommend guidelines and prescribe appropriate changes in existing procedures to improve that performance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security Program Training, Standards, and Qualifications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education and Training Standards for Security Coordinators, Supervisory Personnel, and Pilots.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security Screeners.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment Standards for Screening Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technological Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Right To Strike.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) An individual that screens passengers or property, or both, at an airport under this section may not participate in a strike, or assert the right to strike, against the person (including a governmental entity) employing such individual to perform such screening.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44935_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniforms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Administrator shall require any individual who screens passengers and property pursuant to section 44901 to be attired while on duty in a uniform approved by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>