<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44946" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44946/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44946/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44946"><akn:num>44946</akn:num><akn:heading>Aviation Security Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44946. Aviation Security Advisory Committee(a) Establishment.—The Administrator shall establish within the Transportation Security Administration an aviation security advisory committee.

(b) Duties.—(1) In general.—The Administrator shall consult the Advisory Committee, as appropriate, on aviation security matters, including on the development, refinement, and implementation of policies, programs, rulemaking, and security directives pertaining to aviation security, while adhering to sensitive security guidelines.

(2) Recommendations.—(A) In general.—The Advisory Committee shall develop, at the request of the Administrator, recommendations for improvements to aviation security.

(B) Recommendations of subcommittees.—Recommendations agreed upon by the subcommittees established under this section shall be approved by the Advisory Committee before transmission to the Administrator.


(3) Periodic reports.—The Advisory Committee shall periodically submit to the Administrator—(A) reports on matters identified by the Administrator; and

(B) reports on other matters identified by a majority of the members of the Advisory Committee.


(4) Annual report.—The Advisory Committee shall submit to the Administrator an annual report providing information on the activities, findings, and recommendations of the Advisory Committee, including its subcommittees, for the preceding year. Not later than 6 months after the date that the Administrator receives the annual report, the Administrator shall publish a public version describing the Advisory Committee’s activities and such related matters as would be informative to the public consistent with the policy of section 552(b) of title 5.

(5) Feedback.—Not later than 90 days after receiving recommendations transmitted by the Advisory Committee under paragraph (2) or (4), the Administrator shall respond in writing to the Advisory Committee with feedback on each of the recommendations, an action plan to implement any of the recommendati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44946_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator shall establish within the Transportation Security Administration an aviation security advisory committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44946_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44946_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44946_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subcommittees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44946_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subject Matter Experts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Each subcommittee under this section shall include subject matter experts with relevant expertise who are appointed by the respective subcommittee chairpersons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44946_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of Chapter 10 of Title 5.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the Advisory Committee and its subcommittees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44946_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>