<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44940" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44940/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/44940/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_44940"><akn:num>44940</akn:num><akn:heading>Security service fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 44940. Security service fee(a) General Authority.—(1) Passenger fees.—The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall impose a uniform fee, on passengers of air carriers and foreign air carriers in air transportation and intrastate air transportation originating at airports in the United States, to pay for the following costs of providing civil aviation security services:(A) Salary, benefits, overtime, retirement and other costs of screening personnel, their supervisors and managers, and Federal law enforcement personnel deployed at airport security screening locations under section 44901.

(B) The costs of training personnel described in subparagraph (A), and the acquisition, operation, and maintenance of equipment used by such personnel.

(C) The costs of performing background investigations of personnel described in subparagraphs (A), (D), (F), and (G).

(D) The costs of the Federal air marshals program.

(E) The costs of performing civil aviation security research and development under this title.

(F) The costs of Federal Security Managers under section 44903.

(G) The costs of deploying Federal law enforcement personnel pursuant to section 44903(h).

(H) The costs of security-related capital improvements at airports.

(I) The costs of training pilots and flight attendants under sections 44918 and 44921.


(2) Determination of costs.—(A) In general.—The amount of the costs under paragraph (1) shall be determined by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration and shall not be subject to judicial review.

(B) Definition of federal law enforcement personnel.—For purposes of paragraph (1)(A), the term “Federal law enforcement personnel” includes State and local law enforcement officers who are deputized under section 44922.



(b) Schedule of Fees.—In imposing fees under subsection (a), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall ensure that the fees are reasonably related to the Transportation S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44940_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44940_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Schedule of Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In imposing fees under subsection (a), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall ensure that the fees are reasonably related to the Transportation Security Administration’s costs of providing services rendered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44940_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Fee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44940_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of Fee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44940_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44940_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipts Credited as Offsetting Collections.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, any fee collected under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44940_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refunds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration may refund any fee paid by mistake or any amount paid in excess of that required.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44940_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration may exempt from the passenger fee imposed under subsection (a)(1) any passenger enplaning at an airport in the United States that does not receive screening services under section 44901 for that segment of the trip for which the passenger does not receive screening.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_44940_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of Receipts in General Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>