<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/45105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/45105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/45105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_45105"><akn:num>45105</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 45105. Rehabilitation(a) Program for Employees of Air Carriers and Foreign Air Carriers.—The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall prescribe regulations establishing requirements for rehabilitation programs that at least provide for the identification and opportunity for treatment of employees of air carriers and foreign air carriers referred to in section 45102(a)(1) of this title who need assistance in resolving problems with the use of alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a United States Government regulation. Each air carrier and foreign air carrier is encouraged to make such a program available to all its employees in addition to the employees referred to in section 45102(a)(1). The Administrator shall decide on the circumstances under which employees shall be required to participate in a program. This subsection does not prevent an air carrier or foreign air carrier from establishing a program under this subsection in cooperation with another air carrier or foreign air carrier.

(b) Program for Employees of the Federal Aviation Administration.—The Administrator shall establish and maintain a rehabilitation program that at least provides for the identification and opportunity for treatment of employees of the Administration whose duties include responsibility for safety-sensitive functions who need assistance in resolving problems with the use of alcohol or a controlled substance.

(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 1223; Pub. L. 103–429, § 6(58), Oct. 31, 1994, 108 Stat. 4385.)











Historical and Revision Notes



Pub. L. 103–272


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


45105(a)49 App.:1434(c)(1).Aug. 23, 1958, Pub. L. 85–726, 72 Stat. 731, § 614(c); added Oct. 28, 1991, Pub. L. 102–143, § 3(a), 105 Stat. 954.
45105(b)49 App.:1434(c)(2).


In subsection (a), the words “of air carriers and foreign air carriers” are added for clarity.

Pub. L. 103–429This amends 49:45105(a) to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program for Employees of Air Carriers and Foreign Air Carriers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall prescribe regulations establishing requirements for rehabilitation programs that at least provide for the identification and opportunity for treatment of employees of air carriers and foreign air carriers referred to in section 45102(a)(1) of this title who need assistance in resolving problems with the use of alcohol or a controlled substance in violation of law or a United States Government regulation. Each air carrier and foreign air carrier is encouraged to make such a program available to all its employees in addition to the employees referred to in section 45102(a)(1). The Administrator shall decide on the circumstances under which employees shall be required to participate in a program. This subsection does not prevent an air carrier or foreign air carrier from establishing a program under this subsection in cooperation with another air carrier or foreign air carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_45105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program for Employees of the Federal Aviation Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator shall establish and maintain a rehabilitation program that at least provides for the identification and opportunity for treatment of employees of the Administration whose duties include responsibility for safety-sensitive functions who need assistance in resolving problems with the use of alcohol or a controlled substance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>