<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_46105"><akn:num>46105</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 46105. Regulations and orders(a) Effectiveness of Orders.—Except as provided in this part, a regulation prescribed or order issued by the Secretary of Transportation (or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration with respect to security duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to aviation safety duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration) takes effect within a reasonable time prescribed by the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration. The regulation or order remains in effect under its own terms or until superseded. Except as provided in this part, the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may amend, modify, or suspend an order in the way, and by giving the notice, the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration decides.

(b) Contents and Service of Orders.—An order of the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall include the findings of fact on which the order is based and shall be served on the parties to the proceeding and the persons affected by the order.

(c) Emergencies.—When the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration is of the opinion that an emergency exists related to safety in air commerce and requires immediate action, the Administrator, on the initiative of the Administrator or on complaint, may prescribe regulations and issue orders immediately to meet the emergency, with or without notice and without regard to this part and subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effectiveness of Orders.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in this part, a regulation prescribed or order issued by the Secretary of Transportation (or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration with respect to security duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to aviation safety duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration) takes effect within a reasonable time prescribed by the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration. The regulation or order remains in effect under its own terms or until superseded. Except as provided in this part, the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may amend, modify, or suspend an order in the wa</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents and Service of Orders.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An order of the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall include the findings of fact on which the order is based and shall be served on the parties to the proceeding and the persons affected by the order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) When the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration is of the opinion that an emergency exists related to safety in air commerce and requires immediate action, the Administrator, on the initiative of the Administrator or on complaint, may prescribe regulations and issue orders immediately to meet the emergency, with or without notice and without regard to this part and subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5. The Administrator shall begin a proceeding immediately about an emergency under this subsection and give preference, when practicable, to the proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>