<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_46104"><akn:num>46104</akn:num><akn:heading>Evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 46104. Evidence(a) General.—In conducting a hearing or investigation under this part, the Secretary of Transportation (or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration with respect to security duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to aviation safety duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration) may—(1) subpoena witnesses and records related to a matter involved in the hearing or investigation from any place in the United States to the designated place of the hearing or investigation;

(2) administer oaths;

(3) examine witnesses; and

(4) receive evidence at a place in the United States the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration designates.


(b) Compliance With Subpoenas.—If a person disobeys a subpoena, the Secretary, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, or a party to a proceeding before the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may petition a court of the United States to enforce the subpoena. A judicial proceeding to enforce a subpoena under this section may be brought in the jurisdiction in which the proceeding or investigation is conducted. The court may punish a failure to obey an order of the court to comply with the subpoena as a contempt of court.

(c) Depositions.—(1) In a proceeding or investigation, the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may order a person to give testimony by deposition and to produce records. If a person fails to be deposed or to produce records, the order </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In conducting a hearing or investigation under this part, the Secretary of Transportation (or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration with respect to security duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration or the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration with respect to aviation safety duties and powers designated to be carried out by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration) may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance With Subpoenas.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If a person disobeys a subpoena, the Secretary, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, or a party to a proceeding before the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may petition a court of the United States to enforce the subpoena. A judicial proceeding to enforce a subpoena under this section may be brought in the jurisdiction in which the proceeding or investigation is conducted. The court may punish a failure to obey an order of the court to comply with the subpoena as a contempt of court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Depositions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Witness Fees and Mileage and Certain Foreign Country Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A witness summoned before the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration or whose deposition is taken under this section and the individual taking the deposition are each entitled to the same fee and mileage that the witness and individual would have been paid for those services in a court of the United States. Under regulations of the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall pay the necessary expenses incident to executing, in another country, a commission or letter rogatory issued at the initiative of the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46104_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designating Employees To Conduct Hearings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) When designated by the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, an employee appointed under section 3105 of title 5 may conduct a hearing, subpoena witnesses, administer oaths, examine witnesses, and receive evidence at a place in the United States the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration designates. On request of a party, the Secretary, Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, or Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall hear or receive argument.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>