<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_46111"><akn:num>46111</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate actions in response to a security threat</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 46111. Certificate actions in response to a security threat(a) Orders.—The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue an order amending, modifying, suspending, or revoking any part of a certificate issued under this title if the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration is notified by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration that the holder of the certificate poses, or is suspected of posing, a risk of air piracy or terrorism or a threat to airline or passenger safety. If requested by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, the order shall be effective immediately.

(b) Hearings for Citizens.—An individual who is a citizen of the United States who is adversely affected by an order of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under subsection (a) is entitled to a hearing on the record.

(c) Hearings.—When conducting a hearing under this section, the administrative law judge shall not be bound by findings of fact or interpretations of laws and regulations of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.

(d) Appeals.—An appeal from a decision of an administrative law judge as the result of a hearing under subsection (b) shall be made to the Transportation Security Oversight Board established by section 115. The Board shall establish a panel to review the decision. The members of this panel (1) shall not be employees of the Transportation Security Administration, (2) shall have the level of security clearance needed to review the determination made under this section, and (3) shall be given access to all relevant documents that support that determination. The panel may affirm, modify, or reverse the decision.

(e) Review.—A person substantially affected by an action of a panel under subsection (d), or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration when the Administrator of the T</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Orders.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall issue an order amending, modifying, suspending, or revoking any part of a certificate issued under this title if the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration is notified by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration that the holder of the certificate poses, or is suspected of posing, a risk of air piracy or terrorism or a threat to airline or passenger safety. If requested by the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration, the order shall be effective immediately.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings for Citizens.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An individual who is a citizen of the United States who is adversely affected by an order of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration under subsection (a) is entitled to a hearing on the record.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46111_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) When conducting a hearing under this section, the administrative law judge shall not be bound by findings of fact or interpretations of laws and regulations of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46111_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An appeal from a decision of an administrative law judge as the result of a hearing under subsection (b) shall be made to the Transportation Security Oversight Board established by section 115. The Board shall establish a panel to review the decision. The members of this panel (1) shall not be employees of the Transportation Security Administration, (2) shall have the level of security clearance needed to review the determination made under this section, and (3) shall be given access to all relevant documents that support that determination. The panel may affirm, modify, or reverse the decision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46111_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A person substantially affected by an action of a panel under subsection (d), or the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration when the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration decides that the action of the panel under this section will have a significant adverse impact on carrying out this part, may obtain review of the order under section 46110. The Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall be made a party to the review proceedings. Findings of fact of the panel are conclusive if supported by substantial evidence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46111_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Explanation of Decisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) An individual who commences an appeal under this section shall receive a written explanation of the basis for the determination or decision and all relevant documents that support that determination to the maximum extent that the national security interests of the United States and other applicable laws permit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46111_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classified Evidence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>