<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46318" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46318/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/46318/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_46318"><akn:num>46318</akn:num><akn:heading>Interference with cabin or flight crew</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 46318. Interference with cabin or flight crew(a) General Rule.—An individual who physically or sexually assaults or threatens to physically or sexually assault a member of the flight crew or cabin crew of a civil aircraft or any other individual on the aircraft, or takes any action that poses an imminent threat to the safety of the aircraft or other individuals on the aircraft is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $35,000.

(b) Compromise and Setoff.—(1) Compromise.—The Secretary may compromise the amount of a civil penalty imposed under this section.

(2) Setoff.—The United States Government may deduct the amount of a civil penalty imposed or compromised under this section from amounts the Government owes the person liable for the penalty.


(Added Pub. L. 106–181, title V, § 511(a), Apr. 5, 2000, 114 Stat. 142; amended Pub. L. 115–254, div. B, title III, § 339(a), Oct. 5, 2018, 132 Stat. 3282.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 115–254 inserted “or sexually” after “physically” in two places and substituted “$35,000” for “$25,000”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable only to fiscal years beginning after Sept. 30, 1999, see section 3 of Pub. L. 106–181, set out as an Effective Date of 2000 Amendments note under section 106 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46318_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Rule.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An individual who physically or sexually assaults or threatens to physically or sexually assault a member of the flight crew or cabin crew of a civil aircraft or any other individual on the aircraft, or takes any action that poses an imminent threat to the safety of the aircraft or other individuals on the aircraft is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $35,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_46318_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise and Setoff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>