<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47108"><akn:num>47108</akn:num><akn:heading>Project grant agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47108. Project grant agreements(a) Offer and Acceptance.—On approving a project grant application under this subchapter, the Secretary of Transportation shall offer the sponsor a grant to pay the United States Government’s share of the project costs allowable under section 47110 of this title. The Secretary may impose terms on the offer that the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this subchapter and regulations prescribed under this subchapter. An offer shall state the obligations to be assumed by the sponsor and the maximum amount the Government will pay for the project from the amounts authorized under chapter 481 of this title (except sections 48102(e), 48106, 48107, and 48110). At the request of the sponsor, an offer of a grant for a project that will not be completed in one fiscal year shall provide for the obligation of amounts apportioned or to be apportioned to a sponsor under section 47114(c) or 47114(d)(2)(A) for the fiscal years necessary to pay the Government’s share of the cost of the project. An offer that is accepted in writing by the sponsor is an agreement binding on the Government and the sponsor. The Government may pay or be obligated to pay a project cost only after a grant agreement for the project is signed.

(b) Increasing Government Share.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraph (2) or (3), the amount stated in an offer as the maximum amount the Government will pay may not be increased when the offer has been accepted in writing.

(2) Exception.—For a project receiving assistance under a grant approved under this chapter or chapter 475, the amount may be increased—(A) for an airport development project, by not more than 15 percent; and

(B) to acquire an interest in land for an airport (except a primary airport), based on creditable appraisals at the time of the acquisition or a court award in a condemnation proceeding, by not more than the greater of—(i) 15 percent; or

(ii) 25 percent of the total increase in allowable pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offer and Acceptance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) On approving a project grant application under this subchapter, the Secretary of Transportation shall offer the sponsor a grant to pay the United States Government’s share of the project costs allowable under section 47110 of this title. The Secretary may impose terms on the offer that the Secretary considers necessary to carry out this subchapter and regulations prescribed under this subchapter. An offer shall state the obligations to be assumed by the sponsor and the maximum amount the Government will pay for the project from the amounts authorized under chapter 481 of this title (except sections 48102(e), 48106, 48107, and 48110). At the request of the sponsor, an offer of a grant for a project that will not be completed in one fiscal year shall provide for the obligation of amounts apportioned or to be apportioned to a sponsor under section 47114(c) or 47114(d)(2)(A) for the fiscal years necessary to pay the Government’s share of the cost of the project. An offer that is accept</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increasing Government Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changing Workscope.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) With the consent of the sponsor, the Secretary may amend a grant agreement made under this subchapter to change the workscope of a project financed under the grant if the amendment does not result in an increase in the maximum amount the Government may pay under subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47108_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change in Airport Status.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>