<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47117" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47117/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47117/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47117"><akn:num>47117</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of apportioned amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47117. Use of apportioned amounts(a) Grant Purpose.—Except as provided in this section, an amount apportioned under section 47114(c)(1) or (d)(2) of this title is available for making grants for any purpose for which amounts are made available under section 48103 of this title.

(b) Period of Availability.—(1) In general.—An amount apportioned under section 47114 of this title is available to be obligated for grants under the apportionment only during the fiscal year for which the amount was apportioned and the 2 fiscal years immediately after that year or the 3 fiscal years immediately following that year in the case of a nonhub airport or any airport that is not a commercial service airport. Except as provided in paragraph (2), if the amount is not obligated under the apportionment within that time, it shall be added to the discretionary fund.

(2) Expired amounts apportioned for general aviation airports.—(A) In general.—Except as provided in subparagraph (B), if an amount apportioned under section 47114(d) is not obligated within the time specified in paragraph (1), that amount shall be added to the discretionary fund under section 47115 of this title, provided that—(i) amounts made available under paragraph (2)(A) shall be used for grants for projects in accordance with section 47115(d)(2) at airports eligible to receive an apportionment under section 47114(d)(2); and

(ii) amounts made available under paragraph (2)(A) that are not obligated by July 1 of the fiscal year in which the funds will expire shall be made available for all projects in accordance with section 47115(d)(2).


(B) State block grant program.—If an amount apportioned to an airport under section 47114(d)(2)(A) is not obligated within the time specified in paragraph (1), and the airport is located in a State participating in the State block grant program under section 47128, the amount shall be made available to that State under the same conditions as if the State had been apportioned the am</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47117_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in this section, an amount apportioned under section 47114(c)(1) or (d)(2) of this title is available for making grants for any purpose for which amounts are made available under section 48103 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47117_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of Availability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47117_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Primary Airports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47117_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An amount apportioned to a State under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47117_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Apportionment Categories.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47117_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretionary Use of Apportionments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47117_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limiting Authority of Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The authority of the Secretary to make grants during a fiscal year from amounts that were apportioned for a prior fiscal year and remain available for approved airport development project grants under subsection (b) of this section may be impaired only by a law enacted after September 3, 1982, that expressly limits that authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>