<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47112"><akn:num>47112</akn:num><akn:heading>Carrying out airport development projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47112. Carrying out airport development projects(a) Construction Work.—The Secretary of Transportation may inspect and approve construction work for an airport development project carried out under a grant agreement under this subchapter. The construction work must be carried out in compliance with regulations the Secretary prescribes. The regulations shall require the sponsor to make necessary cost and progress reports on the project. The regulations may amend or modify a contract related to the project only if the contract was made with actual notice of the regulations.

(b) Prevailing Wages.—A contract for more than $2,000 involving labor for an airport development project carried out under a grant agreement under this subchapter must require contractors to pay labor minimum wage rates as determined by the Secretary of Labor under sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40. The minimum rates must be included in the bids for the work and in the invitation for those bids.

(c) Veterans’ Preference.—(1) In this subsection—(A) “disabled veteran” has the same meaning given that term in section 2108 of title 5.

(B) “Vietnam-era veteran” means an individual who served on active duty (as defined in section 101 of title 38) in the armed forces for more than 180 consecutive days, any part of which occurred after August 4, 1964, and before May 8, 1975, and who was discharged or released from active duty in the armed forces under honorable conditions.

(C) “Afghanistan-Iraq war veteran” means an individual who served on active duty (as defined in section 101 of title 38) in the armed forces in support of Operation Enduring Freedom, Operation Iraqi Freedom, Operation New Dawn, Operation Inherent Resolve, Operation Freedom’s Sentinel, or any successor contingency operation to such operations for more than 180 consecutive days, any part of which occurred after September 11, 2001, and before the date prescribed by presidential proclamation or by law as the last day of Ope</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction Work.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation may inspect and approve construction work for an airport development project carried out under a grant agreement under this subchapter. The construction work must be carried out in compliance with regulations the Secretary prescribes. The regulations shall require the sponsor to make necessary cost and progress reports on the project. The regulations may amend or modify a contract related to the project only if the contract was made with actual notice of the regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevailing Wages.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A contract for more than $2,000 involving labor for an airport development project carried out under a grant agreement under this subchapter must require contractors to pay labor minimum wage rates as determined by the Secretary of Labor under sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40. The minimum rates must be included in the bids for the work and in the invitation for those bids.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterans’ Preference.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>