<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47129" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47129/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47129/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47129"><akn:num>47129</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolution of disputes concerning airport fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47129. Resolution of disputes concerning airport fees(a) Authority To Request Secretary’s Determination.—(1) In general.—The Secretary of Transportation shall issue a determination as to whether a fee imposed upon one or more air carriers or foreign air carriers (as those terms are defined in section 40102) by the owner or operator of an airport is reasonable if—(A) a written request for such determination is filed with the Secretary by such owner or operator; or

(B) a written complaint requesting such determination is filed with the Secretary by an affected air carrier or foreign air carrier within 60 days after such carrier receives written notice of the establishment or increase of such fee.


(2) Calculation of fee.—A fee subject to a determination of reasonableness under this section may be calculated pursuant to either a compensatory or residual fee methodology or any combination thereof.

(3) Secretary not to set fee.—In determining whether a fee is reasonable under this section, the Secretary may only determine whether the fee is reasonable or unreasonable and shall not set the level of the fee.

(4) Fees imposed by privately-owned airports.—In evaluating the reasonableness of a fee imposed by an airport receiving an exemption under section 47134 of this title, the Secretary shall consider whether the airport has complied with section 47134(c)(4).


(b) Procedural Regulations.—Not later than 90 days after August 23, 1994, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register final regulations, policy statements, or guidelines establishing—(1) the procedures for acting upon any written request or complaint filed under subsection (a)(1); and

(2) the standards or guidelines that shall be used by the Secretary in determining under this section whether an airport fee is reasonable.


(c) Decisions By Secretary.—The final regulations, policy statements, or guidelines required in subsection (b) shall provide the following:(1) Not more than 120 days after an air c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47129_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Request Secretary’s Determination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47129_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedural Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Not later than 90 days after August 23, 1994, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register final regulations, policy statements, or guidelines establishing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47129_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisions By Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The final regulations, policy statements, or guidelines required in subsection (b) shall provide the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47129_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment Under Protest; Guarantee of Air Carrier and Foreign Air Carrier Access.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47129_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) This section does not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47129_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect On Existing Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section shall adversely affect—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47129_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section, the term “fee” means any rate, rental charge, landing fee, or other service charge for the use of airport facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>