<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47124a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47124a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47124a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47124a"><akn:num>47124a</akn:num><akn:heading>Accessibility of certain flight data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47124a. Accessibility of certain flight data(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Administration.—The term “Administration” means the Federal Aviation Administration.

(2) Administrator.—The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.

(3) Applicable individual.—The term “applicable individual” means an individual who is the subject of an investigation initiated by the Administrator related to a covered flight record.

(4) Contract tower.—The term “contract tower” means an air traffic control tower providing air traffic control services pursuant to a contract with the Administration under section 47124.

(5) Covered flight record.—The term “covered flight record” means any air traffic data (as defined in section 2(b)(4)(B) of the Pilot’s Bill of Rights (49 U.S.C. 44703 note)), created, maintained, or controlled by any program of the Administration, including any program of the Administration carried out by employees or contractors of the Administration, such as contract towers, flight service stations, and controller training programs.


(b) Provision of Covered Flight Record to Administration.—(1) Requests.—Whenever the Administration receives a written request for a covered flight record from an applicable individual and the covered flight record is not in the possession of the Administration, the Administrator shall request the covered flight record from the contract tower or other contractor of the Administration in possession of the covered flight record.

(2) Provision of records.—Any covered flight record created, maintained, or controlled by a contract tower or another contractor of the Administration that maintains covered flight records shall be provided to the Administration if the Administration requests the record pursuant to paragraph (1).

(3) Notice of proposed certificate action.—If the Administrator has issued, or subsequently issues, a Notice of Proposed Certificate Action relying on evidence contained in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of Covered Flight Record to Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of Certain Data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration may withhold information that would otherwise be required to be made available under section 11 So in original. Probably should be “this section”. only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>