<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47124" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47124/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47124/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47124"><akn:num>47124</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements for State and local operation of airport facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47124. Agreements for State and local operation of airport facilities(a) Government Relief From Liability.—The Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that an agreement under this subchapter with a qualified entity (as determined by the Secretary), State, or a political subdivision of a State to allow the entity, State, or subdivision to operate an airport facility relieves the United States Government from any liability arising out of, or related to, acts or omissions of employees of the entity, State, or subdivision in operating the airport facility.

(b) Air Traffic Control Contract Program.—(1) Contract tower program.—(A) Continuation.—The Secretary shall continue the low activity (Visual Flight Rules) level I air traffic control tower contract program established under subsection (a) of this section for towers existing on December 30, 1987, and extend the program to other towers as practicable.

(B) Special rule.—If the Secretary determines that a tower already operating under the Contract Tower Program has a benefit-to-cost ratio of less than 1.0, the airport sponsor or State or local government having jurisdiction over the airport shall not be required to pay the portion of the costs that exceeds the benefit—(i) for the 1-year period after such determination is made; or

(ii) if an appeal of such determination is requested, for the 1-year period described in subsection (d)(4)(D).


(C) Use of excess funds.—If the Secretary finds that all or part of an amount made available to carry out the program continued under this paragraph is not required during a fiscal year, the Secretary may use, during such fiscal year, the amount not so required to carry out the Cost-share Program.


(2) General authority.—(A) In general.—The Secretary may make a contract with a qualified entity (as determined by the Secretary) or, on a sole source basis, with a State or a political subdivision of a State to allow the entity, State, or subdivision to operate an airport traffic co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government Relief From Liability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that an agreement under this subchapter with a qualified entity (as determined by the Secretary), State, or a political subdivision of a State to allow the entity, State, or subdivision to operate an airport facility relieves the United States Government from any liability arising out of, or related to, acts or omissions of employees of the entity, State, or subdivision in operating the airport facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Air Traffic Control Contract Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safety Audits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall establish uniform standards and requirements for regular safety assessments of air traffic control towers that receive funding under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria To Evaluate Participants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improving Controller Situational Awareness.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability Insurance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47124_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Milestones for Design Approval of Remote Towers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>