<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47136" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47136/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47136/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47136"><akn:num>47136</akn:num><akn:heading>Zero-emission airport vehicles and infrastructure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47136. Zero-emission airport vehicles and infrastructure(a) In General.—The Secretary of Transportation may establish a pilot program under which the sponsors of public-use airports may use funds made available under this chapter or section 48103 for use at such airports to carry out—(1) activities associated with the acquisition, by purchase or lease, and operation of eligible zero-emission vehicles and equipment, including removable power sources for such vehicles; and

(2) the construction or modification of infrastructure to facilitate the delivery of fuel, power or services necessary for the use of such vehicles.


(b) Eligibility.—A public-use airport is eligible for participation in the program if the eligible vehicles or equipment are—(1) used exclusively on airport property; or

(2) used exclusively to transport passengers and employees between the airport and—(A) nearby facilities which are owned or controlled by the airport or which otherwise directly support the functions or services provided by the airport; or

(B) an intermodal surface transportation facility adjacent to the airport.



(c) Selection Criteria.—In selecting from among applicants for participation in the program, the Secretary shall give priority consideration to applicants that—(1) will achieve the greatest air quality benefits measured by the amount of emissions reduced per dollar of funds expended under the program; and

(2) provide a long-term management plan for eligible vehicles and equipment that includes the existing and future infrastructure requirements of the airport related to such vehicles and equipment.


(d) Federal Share.—The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under the program shall be the Federal share specified in section 47109.

(e) Technical Assistance.—(1) In general.—The sponsor of a public-use airport may use not more than 10 percent of the amounts made available to the sponsor under the program in any fiscal year for—(A) technical assistance; an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation may establish a pilot program under which the sponsors of public-use airports may use funds made available under this chapter or section 48103 for use at such airports to carry out—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A public-use airport is eligible for participation in the program if the eligible vehicles or equipment are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In selecting from among applicants for participation in the program, the Secretary shall give priority consideration to applicants that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Federal share of the cost of a project carried out under the program shall be the Federal share specified in section 47109.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Materials Identifying Best Practices.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary may create and make available materials identifying best practices for carrying out activities funded under the program based on previous related projects and other sources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowable Project Cost.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The allowable project cost for the acquisition of a zero-emission vehicle shall be the total cost of purchasing or leasing the vehicle, including the cost of technical assistance or project management support described in subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexible Procurement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) A sponsor of a public-use airport may use funds made available under the program to acquire, by purchase or lease, a zero-emission vehicle and a removable power source in separate transactions, including transactions by which the airport purchases the vehicle and leases the removable power source.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47136_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>