<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47137" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47137/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47137/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47137"><akn:num>47137</akn:num><akn:heading>Airport security program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47137. Airport security program(a) General Authority.—To improve security at public airports in the United States, the Secretary of Transportation shall carry out not less than one project to test and evaluate innovative aviation security systems and related technology.

(b) Priority.—In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall give the highest priority to a request from an eligible sponsor for a grant to undertake a project that—(1) evaluates and tests the benefits of innovative aviation security systems or related technology, including explosives detection systems, for the purpose of improving aviation and aircraft physical security, access control, and passenger and baggage screening; and

(2) provides testing and evaluation of airport security systems and technology in an operational, testbed environment.


(c) Matching Share.—Notwithstanding section 47109, the United States Government’s share of allowable project costs for a project under this section shall be 100 percent.

(d) Terms and Conditions.—The Secretary may establish such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate for carrying out a project under this section, including terms and conditions relating to the form and content of a proposal for a project, project assurances, and schedule of payments.

(e) Administration.—The Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall administer the program authorized by this section.

(f) Eligible Sponsor Defined.—In this section, the term “eligible sponsor” means a nonprofit corporation composed of a consortium of public and private persons, including a sponsor of a primary airport, with the necessary engineering and technical expertise to successfully conduct the testing and evaluation of airport and aircraft related security systems.

(g) Authorization of Appropriations.—Of the amounts made available to the Secretary under section 47115 in a fiscal year, the Secretary shall make available not less than $5,000,000 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47137_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To improve security at public airports in the United States, the Secretary of Transportation shall carry out not less than one project to test and evaluate innovative aviation security systems and related technology.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47137_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall give the highest priority to a request from an eligible sponsor for a grant to undertake a project that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47137_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding section 47109, the United States Government’s share of allowable project costs for a project under this section shall be 100 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47137_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may establish such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate for carrying out a project under this section, including terms and conditions relating to the form and content of a proposal for a project, project assurances, and schedule of payments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47137_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall administer the program authorized by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47137_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Sponsor Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the term “eligible sponsor” means a nonprofit corporation composed of a consortium of public and private persons, including a sponsor of a primary airport, with the necessary engineering and technical expertise to successfully conduct the testing and evaluation of airport and aircraft related security systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47137_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Of the amounts made available to the Secretary under section 47115 in a fiscal year, the Secretary shall make available not less than $5,000,000 for the purpose of carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>