<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47146" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47146/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47146/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47146"><akn:num>47146</akn:num><akn:heading>General aviation program runway extension pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47146. General aviation program runway extension pilot program(a) Establishment.—The Secretary of Transportation shall establish and carry out a pilot program to provide grants to general aviation airports to increase the usable runway length capability at such airports in order to—(1) expand access to such airports for larger aircraft; and

(2) support the development and economic viability of such airports.


(b) Grants.—(1) In general.—For the purpose of carrying out the pilot program established in subsection (a), the Secretary shall make grants to not more than 2 sponsors of general aviation airports per fiscal year.

(2) Use of funds.—A sponsor of a general aviation airport shall use a grant awarded under this section to plan, design, or construct a project to extend an existing primary runway by not greater than 1,000 feet in order to accommodate large turboprop or turbojet aircraft that cannot be accommodated with the existing runway length.

(3) Eligibility.—To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a sponsor of a general aviation airport shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.

(4) Selection.—In selecting an applicant for a grant under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize projects that demonstrate that the existing runway length at the airport is—(A) inadequate to support the near-term operations of 1 or more business entities operating at the airport as of the date of submission of such application;

(B) a direct aircraft operational impediment to airport economic viability, job creation or retention, or local economic development; and

(C) not located within 20 miles of another National Plan of Integrated Airport Systems airport with comparable runway length.



(c) Project Justification.—A project that demonstrates the criteria described in subsection (b) shall be considered a justified cost with respect to the pilot program, notwithstand</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47146_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation shall establish and carry out a pilot program to provide grants to general aviation airports to increase the usable runway length capability at such airports in order to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47146_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47146_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Justification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A project that demonstrates the criteria described in subsection (b) shall be considered a justified cost with respect to the pilot program, notwithstanding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47146_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Government’s share of allowable project costs for a project carried out with a grant under this section shall be the Government’s share of allowable project costs specified under section 47109.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47146_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than 5 years after the establishment of the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that evaluates the pilot program, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47146_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) For each of fiscal years 2025 through 2028, the Secretary may use funds under section 47116(b)(2) to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>