<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47171" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47171/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47171/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47171"><akn:num>47171</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited, coordinated environmental review process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47171. Expedited, coordinated environmental review process(a) Aviation Project Review Process.—The Secretary of Transportation shall implement an expedited and coordinated environmental review process for airport capacity enhancement projects, terminal development projects, general aviation airport construction or improvement projects, and aviation safety projects that—(1) provides for streamlined coordination among the Federal, regional, State, and local agencies concerned with the preparation of environmental impact statements or environmental assessments under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.);

(2) provides that all environmental reviews, analyses, opinions, permits, licenses, and approvals that must be issued or made by a Federal agency or airport sponsor for such a project will be conducted concurrently, to the maximum extent practicable; and

(3) provides that any environmental review, analysis, opinion, permit, license, or approval that must be issued or made by a Federal agency or airport sponsor for such a project will be completed within a time period established by the Secretary, in cooperation with the agencies identified under subsection (d) with respect to the project.


(b) Aviation Projects Subject to a Streamlined Environmental Review Process.—(1) In general.—Any airport capacity enhancement project, terminal development project, or general aviation airport construction or improvement project shall be subject to the coordinated and expedited environmental review process requirements set forth in this section.

(2) Project designation criteria.—(A) In general.—The Secretary may designate an aviation safety project for priority environmental review.

(B) Requirements.—A designated project shall be subject to the coordinated and expedited environmental review process requirements set forth in this section.

(C) Guidelines.—(i) In general.—The Secretary shall establish guidelines for the designation of an aviation</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aviation Project Review Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation shall implement an expedited and coordinated environmental review process for airport capacity enhancement projects, terminal development projects, general aviation airport construction or improvement projects, and aviation safety projects that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aviation Projects Subject to a Streamlined Environmental Review Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>High Priority of and Agency Participation in Coordinated Reviews.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of Jurisdictional Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) With respect to a project described or designated under subsection (b), the Secretary shall identify, as soon as practicable, all Federal and State agencies that may have jurisdiction over environmental-related matters that may be affected by the project or may be required by law to conduct an environmental-related review or analysis of the project or determine whether to issue an environmental-related permit, license, or approval for the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Under a coordinated review process being implemented under this section by the Secretary with respect to a project at an airport within the boundaries of a State, the Governor of the State, consistent with State law, may choose to participate in such process and provide that all State agencies that have jurisdiction over environmental-related matters that may be affected by the project or may be required by law to conduct an environmental-related review or analysis of the project or determine whether to issue an environmental-related permit, license, or approval for the project, be subject to the process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Memorandum of Understanding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The coordinated review process developed under this section may be incorporated into a memorandum of understanding for a project between the Secretary and the heads of other Federal and State agencies identified under subsection (d) with respect to the project and, if applicable, the airport sponsor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Interagency Environmental Impact Statement Teams.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lead Agency Responsibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Federal Aviation Administration shall be the lead agency for projects described in subsection (b)(1) and shall be responsible for defining the scope and content of the environmental impact statement, consistent with regulations issued by the Council on Environmental Quality. Any other Federal agency or State agency that is participating in a coordinated environmental review process under this section shall give substantial deference, to the extent consistent with applicable law and policy, to the aviation expertise of the Federal Aviation Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Failure To Meet Deadline.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47171_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and Need.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>