<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47528" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47528/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/47528/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_47528"><akn:num>47528</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on operating certain aircraft not complying with stage 3 noise levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 47528. Prohibition on operating certain aircraft not complying with stage 3 noise levels(a) Prohibition.—Except as provided in subsection (b) or (f) of this section and section 47530 of this title, a person may operate after December 31, 1999, a civil subsonic turbojet (for which an airworthiness certificate other than an experimental certificate has been issued by the Administrator) with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds to or from an airport in the United States only if the Secretary of Transportation finds that the aircraft complies with the stage 3 noise levels.

(b) Waivers.—(1) If, not later than July 1, 1999, at least 85 percent of the aircraft used by an air carrier or foreign air carrier to provide air transportation comply with the stage 3 noise levels, the carrier may apply for a waiver of subsection (a) of this section for the remaining aircraft used by the carrier to provide air transportation. The application must be filed with the Secretary not later than January 1, 1999, or, in the case of a foreign air carrier, the 15th day following the date of the enactment of the Wendell H. Ford Aviation Investment and Reform Act for the 21st Century and must include a plan with firm orders for making all aircraft used by the carrier to provide air transportation comply with the noise levels not later than December 31, 2003.

(2) The Secretary may grant a waiver under this subsection if the Secretary finds it would be in the public interest. In making the finding, the Secretary shall consider the effect of granting the waiver on competition in the air carrier industry and on small community air service.

(3) A waiver granted under this subsection may not permit the operation of stage 2 aircraft in the United States after December 31, 2003.


(c) Schedule for Phased-In Compliance.—The Secretary shall establish by regulation a schedule for phased-in compliance with subsection (a) of this section. The phase-in period shall begin on November 5, 1990, and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47528_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (b) or (f) of this section and section 47530 of this title, a person may operate after December 31, 1999, a civil subsonic turbojet (for which an airworthiness certificate other than an experimental certificate has been issued by the Administrator) with a maximum weight of more than 75,000 pounds to or from an airport in the United States only if the Secretary of Transportation finds that the aircraft complies with the stage 3 noise levels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47528_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47528_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Schedule for Phased-In Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall establish by regulation a schedule for phased-in compliance with subsection (a) of this section. The phase-in period shall begin on November 5, 1990, and end before December 31, 1999. The regulations shall establish interim compliance dates. The schedule for phased-in compliance shall be based on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47528_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Beginning with calendar year 1992—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47528_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hawaiian Operations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47528_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aircraft Modification, Disposal, Scheduled Heavy Maintenance, or Leasing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_47528_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nothing in this section may be construed as interfering with, nullifying, or otherwise affecting determinations made by the Federal Aviation Administration, or to be made by the Administration with respect to applications under part 161 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, that were pending on November 1, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>