<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/48114" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/48114/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/48114/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_48114"><akn:num>48114</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding for aviation programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 48114. Funding for aviation programs(a) Authorization of Appropriations.—(1) Airport and airway trust fund guarantee.—(A) In general.—The total budget resources made available from the Airport and Airway Trust Fund each fiscal year pursuant to sections 48101, 48102, 48103, and 106(k) shall—(i) in fiscal year 2013, be equal to 90 percent of the estimated level of receipts plus interest credited to the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for that fiscal year; and

(ii) in fiscal years 2014 through 2018, be equal to the sum of—(I) 90 percent of the estimated level of receipts plus interest credited to the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for that fiscal year; and

(II) the actual level of receipts plus interest credited to the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for the second preceding fiscal year minus the total amount made available for obligation from the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for the second preceding fiscal year.



Such amounts may be used only for the aviation investment programs listed in subsection (b)(1).

(B) Guarantee.—No funds may be appropriated or limited for aviation investment programs listed in subsection (b)(1) unless the amount described in subparagraph (A) has been provided.


(2) Additional authorizations of appropriations from the general fund.—In any fiscal year through fiscal year 2018, if the amount described in paragraph (1) is appropriated, there is further authorized to be appropriated from the general fund of the Treasury such sums as may be necessary for the Federal Aviation Administration Operations account.


(b) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Total budget resources.—The term “total budget resources” means the total amount made available from the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for the sum of obligation limitations and budget authority made available for a fiscal year for the following budget accounts that are subject to the obligation limitation on contract authority provided in this title and for which appr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48114_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48114_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_48114_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of Guarantees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>