<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/49104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/49104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/49104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_49104"><akn:num>49104</akn:num><akn:heading>Lease of Metropolitan Washington Airports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 49104. Lease of Metropolitan Washington Airports(a) General.—The lease between the Secretary of Transportation and the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority under section 6005(a) of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Act of 1986 (Public Law 99–500; 100 Stat. 1783–375; Public Law 99–591; 100 Stat. 3341–378), for the Metropolitan Washington Airports must provide during its 50-year term at least the following:(1) The Airports Authority shall operate, maintain, protect, promote, and develop the Metropolitan Washington Airports as a unit and as primary airports serving the Metropolitan Washington area.

(2)(A) In this paragraph, “airport purposes” means a use of property interests (except a sale) for—(i) aviation business or activities;

(ii) activities necessary or appropriate to serve passengers or cargo in air commerce;

(iii) nonprofit, public use facilities that are not inconsistent with the needs of aviation; or

(iv) a business or activity not inconsistent with the needs of aviation that has been approved by the Secretary.


(B) During the period of the lease, the real property constituting the Metropolitan Washington Airports shall be used only for airport purposes.

(C) If the Secretary decides that any part of the real property leased to the Airports Authority under this chapter is used for other than airport purposes, the Secretary shall—(i) direct that the Airports Authority take appropriate measures to have that part of the property be used for airport purposes; and

(ii) retake possession of the property if the Airports Authority fails to have that part of the property be used for airport purposes within a reasonable period of time, as the Secretary decides.



(3) The Airports Authority is subject to section 47107(a)–(c) and (e) of this title and to the assurances and conditions required of grant recipients under the Airport and Airway Improvement Act of 1982 (Public Law 97–248; 96 Stat. 671) as in effect on June 7, 1987. Notwithstanding section 4</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The lease between the Secretary of Transportation and the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority under section 6005(a) of the Metropolitan Washington Airports Act of 1986 (Public Law 99–500; 100 Stat. 1783–375; Public Law 99–591; 100 Stat. 3341–378), for the Metropolitan Washington Airports must provide during its 50-year term at least the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of Lease Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The district courts of the United States have jurisdiction to compel the Airports Authority and its officers and employees to comply with the terms of the lease. The Attorney General or an aggrieved party may bring an action on behalf of the Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_49104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of Lease.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary and the Airports Authority may at any time negotiate an extension of the lease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>