<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/50104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/50104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/50104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50104"><akn:num>50104</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on airport projects using products or services of foreign countries denying fair market </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50104. Restriction on airport projects using products or services of foreign countries denying fair market opportunities(a) Definition and Rules for Construing Section.—In this section—(1) “project” has the same meaning given that term in section 47102 of this title.

(2) each foreign instrumentality and each territory and possession of a foreign country administered separately for customs purposes is a separate foreign country.

(3) an article substantially produced or manufactured in a foreign country is a product of the country.

(4) a service provided by a person that is a national of a foreign country or that is controlled by a national of a foreign country is a service of the country.


(b) Limitation on Use of Available Amounts.—(1) An amount made available under subchapter I of chapter 471 of this title may not be used for a project that uses a product or service of a foreign country during any period the country is on the list maintained by the United States Trade Representative under subsection (d)(1) of this section.

(2) Paragraph (1) of this subsection does not apply when the Secretary of Transportation decides that—(A) applying paragraph (1) to the product, service, or project is not in the public interest;

(B) a product or service of the same class or type and of satisfactory quality is not produced or offered in the United States, or in a foreign country not listed under subsection (d)(1) of this section, in a sufficient and reasonably available amount; and

(C) the project cost will increase by more than 20 percent if the product or service is excluded.



(c) Decisions on Denial of Fair Market Opportunities.—Not later than 30 days after a report is submitted to Congress under section 181(b) of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2241(b)), the Trade Representative, for a construction project of more than $500,000 for which the government of a foreign country supplies any part of the amount, shall decide whether the foreign country denies fair market</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition and Rules for Construing Section.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Use of Available Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisions on Denial of Fair Market Opportunities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Not later than 30 days after a report is submitted to Congress under section 181(b) of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2241(b)), the Trade Representative, for a construction project of more than $500,000 for which the government of a foreign country supplies any part of the amount, shall decide whether the foreign country denies fair market opportunities for products and suppliers of the United States in procurement or for United States bidders. In making the decision, the Trade Representative shall consider information obtained in preparing the report and other information the Trade Representative considers relevant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of Countries Denying Fair Market Opportunities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>