<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/50101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/50101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/50101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50101"><akn:num>50101</akn:num><akn:heading>Buying goods produced in the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50101. Buying goods produced in the United States(a) Preference.—The Secretary of Transportation may obligate an amount that may be appropriated to carry out section 106(k), 44502(a)(2), or 44509, subchapter I of chapter 471, or chapter 481 (except sections 48102(e), 48106, 48107, and 48110) of this title for a project only if steel and manufactured goods used in the project are produced in the United States.

(b) Waiver.—The Secretary may waive subsection (a) of this section if the Secretary finds that—(1) applying subsection (a) would be inconsistent with the public interest;

(2) the steel and goods produced in the United States are not produced in a sufficient and reasonably available amount or are not of a satisfactory quality;

(3) when procuring a facility or equipment under section 44502(a)(2) or 44509, subchapter I of chapter 471, or chapter 481 (except sections 48102(e), 48106, 48107, and 48110) of this title—(A) the cost of components and subcomponents produced in the United States is more than 60 percent of the cost of all components of the facility or equipment; and

(B) final assembly of the facility or equipment has occurred in the United States; or


(4) including domestic material will increase the cost of the overall project by more than 25 percent.


(c) Labor Costs.—In this section, labor costs involved in final assembly are not included in calculating the cost of components.

(d) Limitation on Certain Rolling Stock Procurements.—(1) In general.—Financial assistance made available under the provisions described in subsection (a) shall not be used in awarding a contract or subcontract to an entity on or after the date of enactment of this subsection for the procurement of rolling stock for use in an airport-related project if the manufacturer of the rolling stock—(A) is incorporated in or has manufacturing facilities in the United States; and

(B) is owned or controlled by, is a subsidiary of, or is otherwise related legally or financially to a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation may obligate an amount that may be appropriated to carry out section 106(k), 44502(a)(2), or 44509, subchapter I of chapter 471, or chapter 481 (except sections 48102(e), 48106, 48107, and 48110) of this title for a project only if steel and manufactured goods used in the project are produced in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may waive subsection (a) of this section if the Secretary finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labor Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section, labor costs involved in final assembly are not included in calculating the cost of components.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50101_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Certain Rolling Stock Procurements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>