<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5107" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5107/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5107/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5107"><akn:num>5107</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazmat employee training requirements and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5107. Hazmat employee training requirements and grants(a) Training Requirements.—The Secretary shall prescribe by regulation requirements for training that a hazmat employer must give hazmat employees of the employer on the safe loading, unloading, handling, storing, and transporting of hazardous material and emergency preparedness for responding to an accident or incident involving the transportation of hazardous material. The regulations—(1) shall establish the date, as provided by subsection (b) of this section, by which the training shall be completed; and

(2) may provide for different training for different classes or categories of hazardous material and hazmat employees.


(b) Beginning and Completing Training.—A hazmat employer shall begin the training of hazmat employees of the employer not later than 6 months after the Secretary prescribes the regulations under subsection (a) of this section. The training shall be completed within a reasonable period of time after—(1) 6 months after the regulations are prescribed; or

(2) the date on which an individual is to begin carrying out a duty or power of a hazmat employee if the individual is employed as a hazmat employee after the 6-month period.


(c) Certification of Training.—After completing the training, each hazmat employer shall certify, with documentation the Secretary may require by regulation, that the hazmat employees of the employer have received training and have been tested on appropriate transportation areas of responsibility, including at least one of the following:(1) recognizing and understanding the Department of Transportation hazardous material classification system.

(2) the use and limitations of the Department hazardous material placarding, labeling, and marking systems.

(3) general handling procedures, loading and unloading techniques, and strategies to reduce the probability of release or damage during or incidental to transporting hazardous material.

(4) health, safety, and risk fac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall prescribe by regulation requirements for training that a hazmat employer must give hazmat employees of the employer on the safe loading, unloading, handling, storing, and transporting of hazardous material and emergency preparedness for responding to an accident or incident involving the transportation of hazardous material. The regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Beginning and Completing Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A hazmat employer shall begin the training of hazmat employees of the employer not later than 6 months after the Secretary prescribes the regulations under subsection (a) of this section. The training shall be completed within a reasonable period of time after—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) After completing the training, each hazmat employer shall certify, with documentation the Secretary may require by regulation, that the hazmat employees of the employer have received training and have been tested on appropriate transportation areas of responsibility, including at least one of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of Training Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary shall ensure that the training requirements prescribed under this section do not conflict with or duplicate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training of Certain Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall ensure that maintenance-of-way employees and railroad signalmen receive general awareness and familiarization training and safety training pursuant to section 172.704 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing Effort.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No grant under subsection (e) shall supplant or replace existing employer-provided hazardous materials training efforts or obligations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5107_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community Safety Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary shall establish a competitive program for making grants to nonprofit organizations for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>