<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5108"><akn:num>5108</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5108. Registration(a) Persons Required to File.—(1) A person shall file a registration statement with the Secretary under this subsection if the person is transporting or causing to be transported in commerce any of the following:(A) a highway-route-controlled quantity of radioactive material.

(B) more than 25 kilograms of a Division 1.1, 1.2, or 1.3 explosive material in a motor vehicle, rail car, or transport container.

(C) more than one liter in each package of a hazardous material the Secretary designates as extremely toxic by inhalation.

(D) hazardous material in a bulk packaging, container, or tank, as defined by the Secretary, if the bulk packaging, container, or tank has a capacity of at least 3,500 gallons or more than 468 cubic feet.

(E) a shipment of at least 5,000 pounds (except in a bulk packaging) of a class of hazardous material for which placarding of a vehicle, rail car, or freight container is required under regulations prescribed under this chapter.


(2) The Secretary may require any of the following persons to file a registration statement with the Secretary under this subsection:(A) a person transporting or causing to be transported hazardous material in commerce and not required to file a registration statement under paragraph (1) of this subsection.

(B) a person designing, manufacturing, fabricating, inspecting, marking, maintaining, reconditioning, repairing, or testing a package, container, or packaging component that is represented, marked, certified, or sold as qualified for use in transporting hazardous material in commerce.


(3) A person required to file a registration statement under this subsection may transport or cause to be transported, or design, manufacture, fabricate, inspect, mark, maintain, recondition, repair, or test a package, container packaging component, or container for use in transporting, hazardous material, only if the person has a statement on file as required by this subsection.

(4) The Secretary may waive</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons Required to File.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form, Contents, and Limitation on Filings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each person required to file a registration statement under subsection (a) shall file the statement in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5108_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Simplifying the Registration Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may take necessary action to simplify the registration process under subsections (a)–(c) of this section and to minimize the number of applications, documents, and other information a person is required to file under this chapter and other laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5108_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation With Administrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall assist the Secretary in carrying out subsections (a)–(g)(1) and (h) of this section by providing the Secretary with information the Secretary requests to carry out the objectives of subsections (a)–(g)(1) and (h).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5108_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Statements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall make a registration statement filed under subsection (a) of this section available for inspection by any person for a fee the Secretary establishes. However, this subsection does not require the release of information described in section 552(b) of title 5 or otherwise protected by law from disclosure to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5108_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5108_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintaining Proof of Filing and Payment of Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary may prescribe regulations requiring a person required to file a registration statement under subsection (a) of this section to maintain proof of the filing and payment of fees imposed under subsection (g) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5108_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>