<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5112"><akn:num>5112</akn:num><akn:heading>Highway routing of hazardous material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5112. Highway routing of hazardous material(a) Application.—(1) This section applies to a motor vehicle only if the vehicle is transporting hazardous material in commerce for which placarding of the vehicle is required under regulations prescribed under this chapter. However, the Secretary by regulation may extend application of this section or a standard prescribed under subsection (b) of this section to—(A) any use of a vehicle under this paragraph to transport any hazardous material in commerce; and

(B) any motor vehicle used to transport hazardous material in commerce.


(2) Except as provided by subsection (d) of this section and section 5125(c) of this title, each State and Indian tribe may establish, maintain, and enforce—(A) designations of specific highway routes over which hazardous material may and may not be transported by motor vehicle; and

(B) limitations and requirements related to highway routing.



(b) Standards for States and Indian Tribes.—(1) The Secretary, in consultation with the States, shall prescribe by regulation standards for States and Indian tribes to use in carrying out subsection (a) of this section. The standards shall include—(A) a requirement that a highway routing designation, limitation, or requirement of a State or Indian tribe shall enhance public safety in the area subject to the jurisdiction of the State or tribe and in areas of the United States not subject to the jurisdiction of the State or tribe and directly affected by the designation, limitation, or requirement;

(B) minimum procedural requirements to ensure public participation when the State or Indian tribe is establishing a highway routing designation, limitation, or requirement;

(C) a requirement that, in establishing a highway routing designation, limitation, or requirement, a State or Indian tribe consult with appropriate State, local, and tribal officials having jurisdiction over areas of the United States not subject to the jurisdiction of that State or tri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for States and Indian Tribes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of Route Designations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5112_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute Resolution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5112_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) This section and regulations prescribed under this section do not affect sections 31111 and 31113 of this title or section 127 of title 23.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5112_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing Radioactive Material Routing Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary is not required to amend or again prescribe regulations related to highway routing designations over which radioactive material may and may not be transported by motor vehicles, and limitations and requirements related to the routing, that were in effect on November 16, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>