<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5116" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5116/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5116/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5116"><akn:num>5116</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning and training grants, monitoring, and review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5116. Planning and training grants, monitoring, and review(a) Planning and Training Grants.—(1) The Secretary shall make grants to States and Indian tribes—(A) to develop, improve, and carry out emergency plans under the Emergency Planning and Community Right-To-Know Act of 1986 (42 U.S.C. 11001 et seq.), including ascertaining flow patterns of hazardous material on lands under the jurisdiction of a State or Indian tribe, and between lands under the jurisdiction of a State or Indian tribe and lands of another State or Indian tribe;

(B) to decide on the need for regional hazardous material emergency response teams; and

(C) to train public sector employees to respond to accidents and incidents involving hazardous material.


(2) To the extent that a grant is used to train emergency responders under paragraph (1)(C), the State or Indian tribe shall provide written certification to the Secretary that the emergency responders who receive training under the grant will have the ability to protect nearby persons, property, and the environment from the effects of accidents or incidents involving the transportation of hazardous material in accordance with existing regulations or National Fire Protection Association standards for competence of responders to accidents and incidents involving hazardous materials.

(3) The Secretary may make a grant to a State or Indian tribe under paragraph (1) of this subsection only if—(A) the State or Indian tribe certifies that the total amount the State or Indian tribe expends (except amounts of the Federal Government) for the purpose of the grant will at least equal the average level of expenditure for the last 5 years; and

(B) any emergency response training provided under the grant shall consist of—(i) a course developed or identified under section 5115 of this title; or

(ii) any other course the Secretary determines is consistent with the objectives of this section.



(4) A State or Indian tribe receiving a grant under this subse</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning and Training Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance With Certain Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may make a grant to a State under this section in a fiscal year only if the State certifies that the State complies with sections 301 and 303 of the Emergency Planning and Community Right-To-Know Act of 1986 (42 U.S.C. 11001, 11003).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A State or Indian tribe interested in receiving a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary. The application must be submitted at the time, and contain information, the Secretary requires by regulation to carry out the objectives of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government’s Share of Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A grant under this section is for 80 percent of the cost the State or Indian tribe incurs in the fiscal year to carry out the activity for which the grant is made. Amounts of the State or tribe under subsection (a)(3)(A) of this section are not part of the non-Government share under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring and Technical Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In coordination with the Secretaries of Transportation and Energy, Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall monitor public sector emergency response planning and training for an accident or incident involving hazardous material. Considering the results of the monitoring, the Secretaries, Administrators, and Director each shall provide technical assistance to a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe for carrying out emergency response training and planning for an accident or incident involving hazardous material and shall coordinate the assistance using the existing coordinating mechanisms of the National Response Team and, for radioactive material, the Federal Radiological Preparedness Coordinating Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) To minimize administrative costs and to coordinate Federal financial assistance for emergency response training and planning, the Secretary may delegate to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and Secretaries of Labor and Energy any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimizing Duplication of Effort and Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretaries of Transportation, Labor, and Energy, Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, and Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall review periodically, with the head of each department, agency, or instrumentality of the Government, all emergency response and preparedness training programs of that department, agency, or instrumentality to minimize duplication of effort and expense of the department, agency, or instrumentality in carrying out the programs and shall take necessary action to minimize duplication.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Registration Fee Account and Its Uses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish an account in the Treasury (to be known as the “Hazardous Materials Emergency Preparedness Fund”) into which the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit amounts the Secretary of Transportation transfers to the Secretary of the Treasury under section 5108(g)(2)(C) of this title. Without further appropriation, amounts in the account are available—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental Training Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alert Grant Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>