<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5119" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5119/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5119/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5119"><akn:num>5119</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniform forms and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5119. Uniform forms and procedures(a) Establishment of Working Group.—The Secretary shall establish a working group of State and local government officials, including representatives of the National Governors’ Association, the National Association of Counties, the National League of Cities, the United States Conference of Mayors, the National Conference of State Legislatures, and the Alliance for Uniform Hazmat Transportation Procedures.

(b) Purpose of Working Group.—The purpose of the working group shall be to develop uniform forms and procedures for a State to register, and to issue permits to, persons that transport, or cause to be transported, hazardous material by motor vehicle in the State.

(c) Limitation on Working Group.—The working group may not propose to define or limit the amount of a fee a State may impose or collect.

(d) Procedure.—The Secretary shall develop a procedure for the working group to employ in developing recommendations for the Secretary to harmonize existing State registration and permit laws and regulations relating to the transportation of hazardous materials, with special attention paid to each State’s unique safety concerns and interest in maintaining strong hazmat safety standards.

(e) Report of Working Group.—Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the working group shall transmit to the Secretary a report containing recommendations for establishing uniform forms and procedures described in subsection (b).

(f) Regulations.—Not later than 18 months after the date the working group’s report is delivered to the Secretary, the Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out such recommendations of the working group as the Secretary considers appropriate. In developing such regulations, the Secretary shall consider the State needs associated with the transition to and implementation of a uniform forms and procedures program.

(g) Limitation on Statutory Construction.—Nothing in this section shall be </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5119_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Working Group.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall establish a working group of State and local government officials, including representatives of the National Governors’ Association, the National Association of Counties, the National League of Cities, the United States Conference of Mayors, the National Conference of State Legislatures, and the Alliance for Uniform Hazmat Transportation Procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5119_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of Working Group.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The purpose of the working group shall be to develop uniform forms and procedures for a State to register, and to issue permits to, persons that transport, or cause to be transported, hazardous material by motor vehicle in the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5119_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Working Group.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The working group may not propose to define or limit the amount of a fee a State may impose or collect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5119_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall develop a procedure for the working group to employ in developing recommendations for the Secretary to harmonize existing State registration and permit laws and regulations relating to the transportation of hazardous materials, with special attention paid to each State’s unique safety concerns and interest in maintaining strong hazmat safety standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5119_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report of Working Group.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the working group shall transmit to the Secretary a report containing recommendations for establishing uniform forms and procedures described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5119_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Not later than 18 months after the date the working group’s report is delivered to the Secretary, the Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out such recommendations of the working group as the Secretary considers appropriate. In developing such regulations, the Secretary shall consider the State needs associated with the transition to and implementation of a uniform forms and procedures program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5119_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Statutory Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting a State from voluntarily participating in a program of uniform forms and procedures until such time as the Secretary issues regulations under subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>