<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5125" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5125/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5125/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5125"><akn:num>5125</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5125. Preemption(a) General.—Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (e) of this section and unless authorized by another law of the United States, a requirement of a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe is preempted if—(1) complying with a requirement of the State, political subdivision, or tribe and a requirement of this chapter, a regulation prescribed under this chapter, or a hazardous materials transportation security regulation or directive issued by the Secretary of Homeland Security is not possible; or

(2) the requirement of the State, political subdivision, or tribe, as applied or enforced, is an obstacle to accomplishing and carrying out this chapter, a regulation prescribed under this chapter, or a hazardous materials transportation security regulation or directive issued by the Secretary of Homeland Security.


(b) Substantive Differences.—(1) Except as provided in subsection (c) of this section and unless authorized by another law of the United States, a law, regulation, order, or other requirement of a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe about any of the following subjects, that is not substantively the same as a provision of this chapter, a regulation prescribed under this chapter, or a hazardous materials transportation security regulation or directive issued by the Secretary of Homeland Security, is preempted:(A) the designation, description, and classification of hazardous material.

(B) the packing, repacking, handling, labeling, marking, and placarding of hazardous material.

(C) the preparation, execution, and use of shipping documents related to hazardous material and requirements related to the number, contents, and placement of those documents.

(D) the written notification, recording, and reporting of the unintentional release in transportation of hazardous material and other written hazardous materials transportation incident reporting involving State or local emergency responders in the i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5125_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (e) of this section and unless authorized by another law of the United States, a requirement of a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe is preempted if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5125_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantive Differences.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5125_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance With Section 5112(b) Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5125_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisions on Preemption.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5125_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of Preemption.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe may apply to the Secretary for a waiver of preemption of a requirement the State, political subdivision, or tribe acknowledges is preempted by subsection (a), (b)(1), or (c) of this section or section 5119(f). Under a procedure the Secretary prescribes by regulation, the Secretary may waive preemption on deciding the requirement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5125_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5125_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Each Preemption Standard.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Each standard for preemption in subsection (a), (b)(1), or (c), and in section 5119(f), is independent in its application to a requirement of a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5125_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal Enforcement Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) This section does not apply to any procedure, penalty, required mental state, or other standard utilized by a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe to enforce a requirement applicable to the transportation of hazardous material.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>