<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5309" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5309/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5309/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5309"><akn:num>5309</akn:num><akn:heading>Fixed guideway capital investment grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5309. Fixed guideway capital investment grants(a) Definitions.—In this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Applicant.—The term “applicant” means a State or local governmental authority that applies for a grant under this section.

(2) Core capacity improvement project.—The term “core capacity improvement project” means a substantial corridor-based capital investment in an existing fixed guideway system that increases the capacity of a corridor by not less than 10 percent. The term does not include project elements designed to maintain a state of good repair of the existing fixed guideway system.

(3) Corridor-based bus rapid transit project.—The term “corridor-based bus rapid transit project” means a small start project utilizing buses in which the project represents a substantial investment in a defined corridor as demonstrated by features that emulate the services provided by rail fixed guideway public transportation systems, including defined stations; traffic signal priority for public transportation vehicles; short headway bidirectional services for a substantial part of weekdays; and any other features the Secretary may determine support a long-term corridor investment, but the majority of which does not operate in a separated right-of-way dedicated for public transportation use during peak periods.

(4) Fixed guideway bus rapid transit project.—The term “fixed guideway bus rapid transit project” means a bus capital project—(A) in which the majority of the project operates in a separated right-of-way dedicated for public transportation use during peak periods;

(B) that represents a substantial investment in a single route in a defined corridor or subarea; and

(C) that includes features that emulate the services provided by rail fixed guideway public transportation systems, including—(i) defined stations;

(ii) traffic signal priority for public transportation vehicles;

(iii) short headway bidirectional services for a substantial part of wee</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may make grants under this section to State and local governmental authorities to assist in financing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>New Fixed Guideway Grants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Core Capacity Improvement Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financing Sources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Advancement and Ratings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small Start Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs of Interrelated Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5309_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Previously Issued Letter of Intent or Full Funding Grant Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Subsections (d) and (e) shall not apply to projects for which the Secretary has issued a letter of intent, approved entry into final design, entered into a full funding grant agreement, or entered into a project construction grant agreement before the date of enactment of the Federal Public Transportation Act of 2012.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>