<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5311"><akn:num>5311</akn:num><akn:heading>Formula grants for rural areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5311. Formula grants for rural areas(a) Definitions.—As used in this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) Recipient.—The term “recipient” means a State or Indian tribe that receives a Federal transit program grant directly from the Government.

(2) Subrecipient.—The term “subrecipient” means a State or local governmental authority, a nonprofit organization, or an operator of public transportation or intercity bus service that receives Federal transit program grant funds indirectly through a recipient.


(b) General Authority.—(1) Grants authorized.—Except as provided by paragraph (2), the Secretary may award grants under this section to recipients located in rural areas for—(A) planning, provided that a grant under this section for planning activities shall be in addition to funding awarded to a State under section 5305 for planning activities that are directed specifically at the needs of rural areas in the State;

(B) public transportation capital projects;

(C) operating costs of equipment and facilities for use in public transportation;

(D) job access and reverse commute projects; and

(E) the acquisition of public transportation services, including service agreements with private providers of public transportation service.


(2) State program.—(A) In general.—A project eligible for a grant under this section shall be included in a State program for public transportation service projects, including agreements with private providers of public transportation service.

(B) Submission to secretary.—Each State shall submit to the Secretary annually the program described in subparagraph (A).

(C) Approval.—The Secretary may not approve the program unless the Secretary determines that—(i) the program provides a fair distribution of amounts in the State, including Indian reservations; and

(ii) the program provides the maximum feasible coordination of public transportation service assisted under this section with transportation service assisted by other</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) As used in this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use for Local Transportation Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A State may use an amount apportioned under this section for a project included in a program under subsection (b) of this section and eligible for assistance under this chapter if the project will provide local transportation service, as defined by the Secretary of Transportation, in a rural area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use for Administration, Planning, and Technical Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may allow a State to use not more than 10 percent of the amount apportioned under this section to administer this section and provide technical assistance to a subrecipient, including project planning, program and management development, coordination of public transportation programs, and research the State considers appropriate to promote effective delivery of public transportation to a rural area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intercity Bus Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government Share of Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of Facilities and Equipment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) With the consent of the recipient currently having a facility or equipment acquired with assistance under this section, a State may transfer the facility or equipment to any recipient eligible to receive assistance under this chapter if the facility or equipment will continue to be used as required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5311_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formula Grants for Public Transportation on Indian Reservations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>