<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5324" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5324/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5324/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5324"><akn:num>5324</akn:num><akn:heading>Public transportation emergency relief program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5324. Public transportation emergency relief program(a) Definition.—In this section the following definitions shall apply:(1) Eligible operating costs.—The term “eligible operating costs” means costs relating to—(A) evacuation services;

(B) rescue operations;

(C) temporary public transportation service; or

(D) reestablishing, expanding, or relocating public transportation route service before, during, or after an emergency.


(2) Emergency.—The term “emergency” means a natural disaster affecting a wide area (such as a flood, hurricane, tidal wave, earthquake, severe storm, or landslide) or a catastrophic failure from any external cause, as a result of which—(A) the Governor of a State has declared an emergency and the Secretary has concurred; or

(B) the President has declared a major disaster under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5170).



(b) General Authority.—The Secretary may make grants and enter into contracts and other agreements (including agreements with departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Government) for—(1) capital projects to protect, repair, reconstruct, or replace equipment and facilities of a public transportation system operating in the United States or on an Indian reservation that the Secretary determines is in danger of suffering serious damage, or has suffered serious damage, as a result of an emergency; and

(2) eligible operating costs of public transportation equipment and facilities in an area directly affected by an emergency during—(A) the 1-year period beginning on the date of a declaration described in subsection (a)(2); or

(B) if the Secretary determines there is a compelling need, the 2-year period beginning on the date of a declaration described in subsection (a)(2).



(c) Coordination of Emergency Funds.—(1) Use of funds.—Funds appropriated to carry out this section shall be in addition to any other funds available under this chapter.

(2) No effect </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may make grants and enter into contracts and other agreements (including agreements with departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Government) for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of Emergency Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A grant awarded under this section or under section 5307 or 5311 that is made to address an emergency defined under subsection (a)(2) shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government Share of Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5324_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Before receiving a grant under this section following an emergency, an applicant shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>