<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5326" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5326/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5326/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5326"><akn:num>5326</akn:num><akn:heading>Transit asset management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5326. Transit asset management(a) Definitions.—In this section the following definitions shall apply:(1) Capital asset.—The term “capital asset” includes equipment, rolling stock, infrastructure, and facilities for use in public transportation and owned or leased by a recipient or subrecipient of Federal financial assistance under this chapter.

(2) Transit asset management plan.—The term “transit asset management plan” means a plan developed by a recipient of funding under this chapter that—(A) includes, at a minimum, capital asset inventories and condition assessments, decision support tools, and investment prioritization; and

(B) the recipient certifies complies with the rule issued under this section.


(3) Transit asset management system.—The term “transit asset management system” means a strategic and systematic process of operating, maintaining, and improving public transportation capital assets effectively throughout the life cycle of such assets.


(b) Transit Asset Management System.—The Secretary shall establish and implement a national transit asset management system, which shall include—(1) a definition of the term “state of good repair” that includes objective standards for measuring the condition of capital assets of recipients, including equipment, rolling stock, infrastructure, and facilities;

(2) a requirement that recipients and subrecipients of Federal financial assistance under this chapter develop a transit asset management plan;

(3) a requirement that each designated recipient of Federal financial assistance under this chapter report on the condition of the system of the recipient and provide a description of any change in condition since the last report;

(4) an analytical process or decision support tool for use by public transportation systems that—(A) allows for the estimation of capital investment needs of such systems over time; and

(B) assists with asset investment prioritization by such systems; and


(5) technical assistance to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5326_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5326_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transit Asset Management System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall establish and implement a national transit asset management system, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5326_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance Measures and Targets.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5326_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the Federal Public Transportation Act of 2012, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to implement the transit asset management system described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>