<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5332" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5332/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5332/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5332"><akn:num>5332</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5332. Nondiscrimination(a) Definition.—In this section, “person” includes a governmental authority, political subdivision, authority, legal representative, trust, unincorporated organization, trustee, trustee in bankruptcy, and receiver.

(b) Prohibitions.—A person may not be excluded from participating in, denied a benefit of, or discriminated against under, a project, program, or activity receiving financial assistance under this chapter because of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, disability, or age.

(c) Compliance.—(1) The Secretary shall take affirmative action to ensure compliance with subsection (b) of this section.

(2) When the Secretary decides that a person receiving financial assistance under this chapter is not complying with subsection (b) of this section, a civil rights law of the United States, or a regulation or order under that law, the Secretary shall notify the person of the decision and require action be taken to ensure compliance with subsection (b).


(d) Authority of Secretary for Noncompliance.—If a person does not comply with subsection (b) of this section within a reasonable time after receiving notice, the Secretary shall—(1) direct that no further financial assistance of the United States Government under this chapter be provided to the person;

(2) refer the matter to the Attorney General with a recommendation that a civil action be brought;

(3) proceed under title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.); or

(4) take any other action provided by law.


(e) Civil Actions by Attorney General.—The Attorney General may bring a civil action for appropriate relief when—(1) a matter is referred to the Attorney General under subsection (d)(2) of this section; or

(2) the Attorney General believes a person is engaged in a pattern or practice in violation of this section.


(f) Application and Relationship to Other Laws.—This section applies to an employment or business opportunity and is in addition to title </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5332_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, “person” includes a governmental authority, political subdivision, authority, legal representative, trust, unincorporated organization, trustee, trustee in bankruptcy, and receiver.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5332_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A person may not be excluded from participating in, denied a benefit of, or discriminated against under, a project, program, or activity receiving financial assistance under this chapter because of race, color, religion, national origin, sex, disability, or age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5332_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5332_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary for Noncompliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If a person does not comply with subsection (b) of this section within a reasonable time after receiving notice, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5332_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Actions by Attorney General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Attorney General may bring a civil action for appropriate relief when—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5332_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application and Relationship to Other Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) This section applies to an employment or business opportunity and is in addition to title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>