<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5340" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5340/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/49/5340/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5340"><akn:num>5340</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionments based on growing States and high density States formula factors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5340. Apportionments based on growing States and high density States formula factors(a) Definition.—In this section, the term “State” shall mean each of the 50 States of the United States.

(b) Allocation.—The Secretary shall apportion the amounts made available under section 5338(b)(2)(N) 11 So in original. Probably should have been “section 5338(a)(2)(N)” in original. See References in Text note below. in accordance with subsection (c) and subsection (d).

(c) Growing State Apportionments.—(1) Apportionment among states.—The amounts apportioned under subsection (b)(1) shall provide each State with an amount equal to the total amount apportioned multiplied by a ratio equal to the population of that State forecast for the year that is 15 years after the most recent decennial census, divided by the total population of all States forecast for the year that is 15 years after the most recent decennial census. Such forecast shall be based on the population trend for each State between the most recent decennial census and the most recent estimate of population made by the Secretary of Commerce.

(2) Apportionments between urbanized areas and other than urbanized areas in each state.—(A) In general.—The Secretary shall apportion amounts to each State under paragraph (1) so that urbanized areas in that State receive an amount equal to the amount apportioned to that State multiplied by a ratio equal to the sum of the forecast population of all urbanized areas in that State divided by the total forecast population of that State. In making the apportionment under this subparagraph, the Secretary shall utilize any available forecasts made by the State. If no forecasts are available, the Secretary shall utilize data on urbanized areas and total population from the most recent decennial census.

(B) Remaining amounts.—Amounts remaining for each State after apportionment under subparagraph (A) shall be apportioned to that State and added to the amount made available for grants u</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5340_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the term “State” shall mean each of the 50 States of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5340_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall apportion the amounts made available under section 5338(b)(2)(N) 11 So in original. Probably should have been “section 5338(a)(2)(N)” in original. See References in Text note below. in accordance with subsection (c) and subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5340_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Growing State Apportionments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5340_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>High Density State Apportionments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amounts to be apportioned under subsection (b)(2) shall be apportioned as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>